<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25C56-FFJ-W1-T6F"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2200 IS: First Responders Emergency Assistance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2200</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250626" legis-day="20250624">June 26 (legislative day, June 24), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a law enforcement grant program to help law enforcement agencies respond to rapid increases in the arrival or presence of aliens who have recently entered the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>First Responders Emergency Assistance Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idb31e3b7cb59e4df5ae5f46d4151c93dc"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id9fc2b02570be44ccbab9cb677599ea81"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id46dce8ac3cf74e92b350b46950b0e361"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id22c991202cdf4a5cb6a6c128446d4bff"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id86d8557d2c824ebe81637c6f7200186d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0c99536338f64b1aba04af2598c31d3a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide7422324534d4b75a3411f96a3a1bbc7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8861faee6e9e4736a348ab2d97812f45"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9f418ab84cac4ea4b6a1586445f9ceca"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State, Tribal, territorial, or local law enforcement agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc0e36c3916874f8086048dda97be47be"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an emergency operations center; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id723795554174493ea55a12c504ee5e6e"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">another State, Tribal, territorial, or local first responder agency.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc5c6cee0d9714ed99245bfa9c9514234"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Emergency operation center</header><text>The term <term>emergency operation center</term> means a physical or virtual location from which leaders of a jurisdiction or organization coordinate and provide policy direction related to an emergency, including—</text><subparagraph id="id34e3c82d4e7c4494b551aa333affead4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coordinating information and resources to support resource needs and requests, including allocation and tracking;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddfdcee2743eb43bdb52514d9efca2766"><enum>(B)</enum><text>collecting, analyzing, and sharing information; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ab8346efbdc4d05a6cfee386db969af"><enum>(C)</enum><text>coordinating plans and determining current and future needs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb871362f45ad4d87b966bd297d28d3ab"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Firefighter</header><text>The term <term>firefighter</term> has the meaning given the term <term>employee in fire protection activities</term> under section 3(y) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203(y)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7b4ff53aefcd41a6bbaa38c721091a33"><enum>(6)</enum><header>First responder</header><text>The term <term>first responder</term> includes a firefighter, law enforcement officer, paramedic, emergency medical technician, or other individual (including an employee of a legally organized and recognized volunteer organization, whether or not compensated), who—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4553c5706ca24a5296f08c31e13a3c92"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the course of his or her professional duties, responds to fire, medical, hazardous material, or similar emergencies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3d828e3cf1ba4a118fa499465f5ac826"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an employee of a State, Indian Tribe, or unit of local government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida3db5cf7f4d9448f89421f586f3f59e5" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given such term in section 4(e) of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304(e)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc4c0aebe68ad451788a311b2854caa00"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Law enforcement officer</header><text>The term <term>law enforcement officer</term> means an employee of a governmental or public agency who is authorized by law—</text><subparagraph id="id14ea9298e0f641b387ce6fb74a6725ae"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to engage in or supervise the prevention, detection, or investigation of any criminal violation of law; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idac4fb61bd71448198a52458fda29ec93"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to engage in or supervise the detention or incarceration of any person for any criminal violation of law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id73ebdec2b52641678abbf2d44012c27a"><enum>(9)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recently</header><text>The term <term>recently</term> means during the 4-year period immediately preceding the public release of a Notice of Funding Opportunity.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id45f0b1cc2b524fea9338f1d39805a931"><enum>(10)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id22e846b097504e1298232118706ea937"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Unit of local government</header><text>The term <term>unit of local government</term> means any city, county, township, town, borough, parish village, special district, fire authority, county improvement district, or other general purpose political subdivision of a State, and any entity jointly created by 2 or more public employers.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id7bd71d16c993445684740d23b22b8ec4"><enum>3.</enum><header>First responders grant program</header><subsection id="id99f3aa00351745009a4ad441e5782e65"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>The Administrator may award grants to eligible entities for the purpose of funding direct costs associated with responding to a substantial and rapid increase in the arrival or presence of aliens who have recently entered the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb91c22dc80804a54ade4ac688cbb3e7c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Permitted uses</header><text>Funds received under the grant program authorized by this section may be used by an eligible entity for—</text><paragraph id="id5acf2faa9522458fbacacc2740120ef1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>equipment, including maintenance and sustainment costs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id25642e463bcc4a8a9f8da9f965b85b36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>allowable and approved personnel costs, including salaries, overtime pay, fringe benefits, and backfill positions for law enforcement and first responder personnel; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id013de8a40ea04237ba7c124be1569f6c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any other appropriate activity or cost that was incurred in the eligible entity’s jurisdiction, as determined by the Secretary of Homeland Security, to respond directly to a substantial and rapid increase in the arrival or presence of aliens who have recently entered the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8d06ae6660be429ba5e88180cdc25cf4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Geographic distribution</header><text>The Administrator shall award not less than 25 percent of the funds appropriated for grants under this section to eligible entities located in States that share a border with Canada or with Mexico.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc753c5cbf8c846f69195b0629d1206ee"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Collection of information</header><text>For each fiscal year during which grants are awarded pursuant to this section that begins on or after the date that is 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall separately collect and maintain financial information with respect to grants awarded under this section, including—</text><paragraph id="id645b4d43eeef46c6b60083d3acac9c16"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the amount of such awards;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id59e922d687ed42fbb1109a907661b50b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount obligated for such awards;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbae856ad8a33454fa3d5949d8e11aca6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the amount of outlays expended for such awards;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9a7cfac9365149d0a37980d5938883ca"><enum>(4)</enum><text>financial plans with respect to the use of such awards;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4f60139e70e8417991b71f573a96375d"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any funding transfers or reallocations related to such awards; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idead43a0b71a04d00adc8db1ecf27d45d"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any adjustments to spending plans or reprogramming related to such awards.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide816b8e6afba415884ec4475db412529"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administrator oversight</header><paragraph id="id4ceecc4eeb5743169c84308f350ddd21"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text>The Administrator shall establish and implement guidelines that—</text><subparagraph id="id3a0fc5d21fdd4174a425a68d43f148b4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure amounts made available for grants under this section are used in accordance with grant guidance and applicable laws;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id580fca43134645b9b1a5c4d4757048a2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increase the proportion of each grant made under this section that is used for operational expenses by the ultimate grantee;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idce4b3f3dea824ecb837fac093a4c4a71"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improve program performance reporting and program performance measurements to facilitate designing, implementing, and enforcing procedures under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3b84490ed8a24d119e562f8496fd0370"><enum>(D)</enum><text>require the recording of standardized performance data regarding program output.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbbf4cde4dbea4072be2accca139cc783"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit the guidelines established pursuant to paragraph (1) to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide6e455ab1f16472f816653e85ac82bdd"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports and briefings</header><text>During the 5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator, in coordination with the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and the Director of U.S. Customs and Immigration Enforcement, shall submit an annual report and provide an annual briefing to the appropriate congressional committees that includes, for the period covered by each such report—</text><paragraph id="ide5f85a9813ad49348018874260284473"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information regarding how each recipient of grant funds under this section expended amounts received under such grant;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0eb4ccbbf2794735a631e8769ce63238"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information regarding the nature of operations carried out using such grant funds; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id59c9307cbcdf46819a1baf63a3272001"><enum>(3)</enum><text>with respect to the first report submitted pursuant to this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="id7861bdbd7d5344b7889acf18b67792d6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an examination of the effects that changing the grant program established under this section to award multi-year grants would have on its mission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd85b2ab22bc14a71b413e7f428938473"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any findings and recommendations regarding changes that could improve the grant program, which may include feedback from grant recipients.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6bc976ae128b4ee79fec847d5b562b7e"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaad3cace5ec6427a89ba577ac0c962ce"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such amounts as may be necessary to carry out this Act.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf6660cf4d497488bb51211c8a8a138be"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (a) may not be expended to reimburse eligible entities for costs relating to the enforcement of Federal immigration laws.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

