<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H46BC3F31B0E7443781D3B1037AE3F671" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 423 IH: Expressing support for the designation of May 2025 as “National Physical Fitness and Sports Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 423</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250515">May 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of May 2025 as <quote>National Physical Fitness and Sports Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States obesity prevalence was 41.9 percent in 2017 through March 2020;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas non-Hispanic Black adults had the highest age-adjusted prevalence of obesity (49.9 percent), followed by Hispanic adults (45.6 percent), non-Hispanic White adults (41.4 percent), and non-Hispanic Asian adults (16.1 percent);</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas for children and adolescents aged 2–19 years in 2017 through 2020 the prevalence of obesity was 19.7 percent and affected about 14,700,000 children and adolescents;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the obesity prevalence was 26.2 percent among Hispanic children, 24.8 percent among non-Hispanic Black children, 16.6 percent among non-Hispanic White children, and 9.0 percent among non-Hispanic Asian children;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas studies indicate that obese children are more likely to become obese adults and suffer lifelong physical and mental health problems;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas unhealthy eating habits and lack of physical activity have contributed to the obesity epidemic in the United States;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas a poor diet is associated with major health risks that can cause illness and even death;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas obesity-related conditions include high blood pressure, high cholesterol, type 2 diabetes, breathing problems such as asthma and sleep apnea, and joint problems;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, in addition to healthy eating, people in the United States can experience positive health benefits and be on the path for a better future by incorporating physical activity into daily life, including 30 minutes for adults and 60 minutes for children;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas physical activity can help reduce the risk of chronic conditions such as heart disease, many types of cancer, type 2 diabetes, depression and anxiety, and dementia;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas being physically active can improve brain health, help manage weight, strengthen bones and muscles, and improve sleep quality; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas May 2025, would be an appropriate month to designate as <quote>National Physical Fitness and Sports Month</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HB6C74186BD894A7E8CC2190DDB5DD148"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H12E0DAA2B3454210808A76832FBF2661"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H712F7F4A7DFE4BF38247DC21F08EC513"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National Physical Fitness and Sports Month</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7F0103431E354A92B62236533C8C7236"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports efforts to educate the people of the United States on the importance of a healthy and nutritious lifestyle.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

