<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H14EA9DF7BA534E6E8A377406A6EC1977" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1638 IH: Creating a Respectful and Open World for Natural Hair Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1638</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250226">February 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000489">Mr. Turner of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001136">Mr. Conaway</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit discrimination based on an individual’s texture or style of hair.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9A2C9D33F31F4FC2BF0ABD90B26E86D4" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H4B91DAB3CC464BB885940A2C207EB717"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Creating a Respectful and Open World for Natural Hair Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CROWN Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H07ED1C3E8F444DF2B81F772AB440002E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress; purpose</header><subsection id="H115A4AF78B124A6796C5EEE854F529C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H4081ACFF77DA47C0A7431663EA9E3F40"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Throughout United States history, society has used (in conjunction with skin color) hair texture and hairstyle to classify individuals on the basis of race.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB71A053086704FE286AB04990F06BA78"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Like one’s skin color, one’s hair has served as a basis of race and national origin discrimination.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H304E6884FACC4EBDB780393ED47363F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Racial and national origin discrimination can and do occur because of longstanding racial and national origin biases and stereotypes associated with hair texture and style.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6E464CD1A594C96BC2AE473ECCF2432"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For example, people of African descent have been deprived of educational and employment opportunities because they are adorned with natural or protective hairstyles in which hair is tightly coiled or tightly curled, or worn in locs, cornrows, twists, braids, Bantu knots, or Afros.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CA0F7D13C1D426EBFB449F9A0BD4E1C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Racial and national origin discrimination is reflected in school and workplace policies and practices that bar natural or protective hairstyles commonly worn by people of African descent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA68ADE657114D7E867E8F0F85D050E8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>For example, as recently as 2018, the United States Armed Forces had grooming policies that barred natural or protective hairstyles that servicewomen of African descent commonly wear and that described these hairstyles as <quote>unkempt</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BF6E258E0184802B8A0AC38B8B5813D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In 2018, the United States Armed Forces rescinded these policies and recognized that this description perpetuated derogatory racial stereotypes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CFAA455B5D74137BE157B3E431D918B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The United States Armed Forces also recognized that prohibitions against natural or protective hairstyles that African-American servicewomen are commonly adorned with are racially discriminatory and bear no relationship to African-American servicewomen’s occupational qualifications and their ability to serve and protect the Nation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A8FED86ED144B098028F500F3F78F6C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Some Federal courts have narrowly interpreted the protections against discrimination on the basis of race or national origin found in existing Federal civil rights laws, including provisions of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000a">42 U.S.C. 2000a et seq.</external-xref>), section 1977 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1981">42 U.S.C. 1981</external-xref>), and the Fair Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3601">42 U.S.C. 3601 et seq.</external-xref>), thereby permitting, for example, employers to discriminate against people of African descent who wear natural or protective hairstyles, even though the employment policies involved are not related to workers’ ability to perform their jobs. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD97E2C40F8E46A7BB978594A1F7C235"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Applying these narrow interpretations has resulted in a lack of Federal civil rights protection for individuals who are discriminated against on the basis of characteristics that are commonly associated with race and national origin.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5BC9DF2CCE649348CEF11C415624647"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Starting in 2019, State legislatures and municipal bodies throughout the United States have introduced and passed legislation that rejects certain Federal courts’ restrictive interpretation of race and national origin, and expressly classifies race and national origin discrimination as inclusive of discrimination on the basis of natural or protective hairstyles commonly associated with race and national origin.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H06699BD7FBC24EA5896B3C8C8A8312E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H42338EB9DD584F65BA5F7120C99A8C65"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Federal Government should acknowledge that individuals who have hair texture or wear a hairstyle that is historically and contemporarily associated with African Americans or persons of African descent have suffered harmful discrimination in schools, workplaces, and other contexts based upon longstanding race and national origin stereotypes and biases;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C239AD9D1964AA797EFE8E7E792C9A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a clear and comprehensive law should address the deprivation of educational, employment, and other opportunities on the basis of hair texture and hairstyle that are commonly associated with race or national origin;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H568C584646354CFB9C9AD3C5E7993D57"><enum>(3)</enum><text>clear, consistent, and enforceable legal standards must be provided to redress the widespread incidences of race and national origin discrimination based upon hair texture and hairstyle in schools, workplaces, housing, federally funded institutions, and other contexts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4749AF6B0BA44FDCA14FB494592F652F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>it is necessary to prevent educational, employment, and other decisions, practices, and policies generated by or reflecting negative biases and stereotypes related to race or national origin;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF1D1019BABF4E4C9E4408B3C290E187"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Federal Government must play a key role in enforcing Federal civil rights laws in a way that secures equal educational, employment, and other opportunities for all individuals regardless of their race or national origin;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8426B5A5B0C04FFFA113F658314D3B5E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Federal Government must play a central role in enforcing the standards established under this Act on behalf of individuals who suffer race or national origin discrimination based upon hair texture and hairstyle;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7E983AC287C4EA2B258C9C03E81436F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>it is necessary to prohibit and provide remedies for the harms suffered as a result of race or national origin discrimination on the basis of hair texture and hairstyle; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB058351C8AA24906BF59B823B1A7A8E8"><enum>(8)</enum><text>it is necessary to mandate that school, workplace, and other applicable standards be applied in a nondiscriminatory manner and to explicitly prohibit the adoption or implementation of grooming requirements that disproportionately impact people of African descent.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H63B7EFCA8B3B4735BF80E13A38FD34F5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to institute definitions of race and national origin for Federal civil rights laws that effectuate the comprehensive scope of protection Congress intended to be afforded by such laws and Congress’ objective to eliminate race and national origin discrimination in the United States.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB673BB1D06454166A3266CA9F7261F06"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federally assisted programs</header><subsection id="H6D11DB3CC69B46309E80FF0EEFA695BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No individual in the United States shall be excluded from participation in, be denied the benefits of, or be subjected to discrimination under, any program or activity receiving Federal financial assistance, based on the individual’s hair texture or hairstyle, if that hair texture or that hairstyle is commonly associated with a particular race or national origin (including a hairstyle in which hair is tightly coiled or tightly curled, locs, cornrows, twists, braids, Bantu knots, and Afros).</text></subsection><subsection id="H9BB3BDB3140B4A05A10E396B44B67A9D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>Subsection (a) shall be enforced in the same manner and by the same means, including with the same jurisdiction, as if such subsection was incorporated in title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>), and as if a violation of subsection (a) was treated as if it was a violation of section 601 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H35B59EACCDC74D8FBFBBDD390C5CFDBE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="H4012CAC381654645A5DDB2C5E793AAD4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>program or activity</term> has the meaning given the term in section 606 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d-4a">42 U.S.C. 2000d–4a</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB927C098E534C5790ED9D3C05B27CBD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the terms <term>race</term> and <term>national origin</term> mean, respectively, <quote>race</quote> within the meaning of the term in section 601 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref>) and <quote>national origin</quote> within the meaning of the term in that section 601.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H89751B13D673458E840C46BF45132CBB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Housing programs</header><subsection id="HD1265A9E45164B6E94BD75CA280805A8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No person in the United States shall be subjected to a discriminatory housing practice based on the person’s hair texture or hairstyle, if that hair texture or that hairstyle is commonly associated with a particular race or national origin (including a hairstyle in which hair is tightly coiled or tightly curled, locs, cornrows, twists, braids, Bantu knots, and Afros).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84833E653CEB48ABA771E53153B30AA0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>Subsection (a) shall be enforced in the same manner and by the same means, including with the same jurisdiction, as if such subsection was incorporated in the Fair Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3601">42 U.S.C. 3601 et seq.</external-xref>), and as if a violation of subsection (a) was treated as if it was a discriminatory housing practice.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5D8B33B320484D7C91E92FC5F51B06DD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC410289E926F428199C58D649968C10C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the terms <quote>discriminatory housing practice</quote> and <quote>person</quote> have the meanings given the terms in section 802 of the Fair Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3602">42 U.S.C. 3602</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A2B954E6FF143CAAE5FD4F964FE95D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the terms <quote>race</quote> and <quote>national origin</quote> mean, respectively, <quote>race</quote> within the meaning of the term in section 804 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3604">42 U.S.C. 3604</external-xref>) and <quote>national origin</quote> within the meaning of the term in that section 804.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8AEA72F051764EA19D90E07D4DCFC868"><enum>5.</enum><header>Public accommodations</header><subsection id="HE874370C602A4F718DA266B4D71ED434"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No person in the United States shall be subjected to a practice prohibited under section 201, 202, or 203 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000a">42 U.S.C. 2000a et seq.</external-xref>), based on the person’s hair texture or hairstyle, if that hair texture or that hairstyle is commonly associated with a particular race or national origin (including a hairstyle in which hair is tightly coiled or tightly curled, locs, cornrows, twists, braids, Bantu knots, and Afros).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4BC44A012C84B72932A95013DA2EFA5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>Subsection (a) shall be enforced in the same manner and by the same means, including with the same jurisdiction, as if such subsection was incorporated in title II of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, and as if a violation of subsection (a) was treated as if it was a violation of section 201, 202, or 203, as appropriate, of such Act.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H88401896630D4D238113CF2ADDCFB71E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the terms <quote>race</quote> and <quote>national origin</quote> mean, respectively, <quote>race</quote> within the meaning of the term in section 201 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000a">42 U.S.C. 2000a</external-xref>) and <quote>national origin</quote> within the meaning of the term in that section 201.</text></subsection></section><section id="HF5635C9BA2B741CFBF9A83FC520BF98B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Employment</header><subsection id="HB6B1B2A6DE0E4A719B593575D087B1A9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>It shall be an unlawful employment practice for an employer, employment agency, labor organization, or joint labor-management committee controlling apprenticeship or other training or retraining (including on-the-job training programs) to fail or refuse to hire or to discharge any individual, or otherwise to discriminate against an individual, based on the individual’s hair texture or hairstyle, if that hair texture or that hairstyle is commonly associated with a particular race or national origin (including a hairstyle in which hair is tightly coiled or tightly curled, locs, cornrows, twists, braids, Bantu knots, and Afros).</text></subsection><subsection id="H3DD6DE6B480643F69CABB09ABC599C60"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>Subsection (a) shall be enforced in the same manner and by the same means, including with the same jurisdiction, as if such subsection was incorporated in title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e et seq.</external-xref>), and as if a violation of subsection (a) was treated as if it was a violation of section 703 or 704, as appropriate, of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e-2">42 U.S.C. 2000e–2</external-xref>, 2000e–3).</text></subsection><subsection id="H6A1EB96562D44B72AE07869188774643"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section the terms <term>person</term>, <term>race</term>, and <term>national origin</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 701 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="HE01138B531AD4A508A55CFAEE32A8DB1"><enum>7.</enum><header>Equal rights under the law</header><subsection id="HCB2802A0B13841E5BA28F03837D704DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No person in the United States shall be subjected to a practice prohibited under section 1977 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1981">42 U.S.C. 1981</external-xref>), based on the person’s hair texture or hairstyle, if that hair texture or that hairstyle is commonly associated with a particular race or national origin (including a hairstyle in which hair is tightly coiled or tightly curled, locs, cornrows, twists, braids, Bantu knots, and Afros).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48BB4FF2CB4D4AC7B8CB9FBAACE81C27"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>Subsection (a) shall be enforced in the same manner and by the same means, including with the same jurisdiction, as if such subsection was incorporated in section 1977 of the Revised Statutes, and as if a violation of subsection (a) was treated as if it was a violation of that section 1977.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA5484757EC7241B7AD5A093DA1F8C3BA"><enum>8.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit definitions of race or national origin under the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000a">42 U.S.C. 2000a et seq.</external-xref>), the Fair Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3601">42 U.S.C. 3601 et seq.</external-xref>), or section 1977 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1981">42 U.S.C. 1981</external-xref>).</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

