<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8E0FC46135584788B1A9B0899869AAB2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 301 IH: Geothermal Energy Opportunity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 301</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250109">January 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001228">Ms. Maloy</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 to establish a deadline for processing applications related to geothermal leasing.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2E74B34D8D5F4914BF17B3FB172A3CAE" style="OLC"><section id="H017EAE97C3024069A08F712F92F11126" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Geothermal Energy Opportunity Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GEO Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H231A5BDD0E394D05AEEF3505B43B8885" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Effect of pending civil actions on processing applications related to geothermal leasing</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 4 of the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1003">30 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8A4A7739184B4418829E14ED28CF0B42"><subsection id="H837A05C3809343EB85090AAE185E8154" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effect of pending civil actions on processing applications related to geothermal leasing</header><paragraph id="H18816BD6B8DE4DD5B1E8E546B872AEDF" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement to process applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the existence of any pending civil action that affects an application for a geothermal drilling permit, sundry notice, notice to proceed, right-of-way, or any other authorization under a valid existing geothermal lease, the Secretary shall, unless a United States Federal court vacates or provides injunctive relief for the applicable geothermal lease, geothermal drilling permit, sundry notice, notice to proceed, right-of-way, or other authorization, approve and issue, or deny, each such application not later than 60 days after completing all requirements under applicable Federal laws and regulations, including the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, the Endangered Species Act of 1973, and division A of subtitle III of title 54, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7AF75796892F44D2BC1DEB3FED88E63B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No new authority for Federal courts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as modifying any existing authority of a Federal court to vacate or provide injunctive relief for a geothermal lease, geothermal drilling permit, sundry notice, notice to proceed, right-of-way, or other authorization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5ACA7D6FDA884E2FAEB44484E8A3D415" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definition of authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>authorization</term> means any license, permit, approval, finding, determination, or other administrative decision issued by a Federal agency, or any interagency consultation, that is required or authorized under Federal law or regulations in order to site, construct, reconstruct, or commence operations of a geothermal project administered by a Federal agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

