<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H98455468A20844889AC4FEE7AC8A9E5C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 3029 IH: Nucleic Acid Standards for Biosecurity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3029</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250428">April 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act to support nucleic acid screening, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEA1950B122CF4D7687FC12A1F341812B" style="OLC"><section id="H45A5399098BE4D4291F98CDA815FE4A9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited <quote><short-title>Nucleic Acid Standards for Biosecurity Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H309DE6BBE8744A018E25ABBE4262BB96"><enum>2.</enum><header>Supporting nucleic acid screening</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 10221 of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18931">42 U.S.C. 18931</external-xref>; enacted as part of title II of division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/167">Public Law 117–167</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H85C74CACB9AC4CA88B6120CE15516F5D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="H81CAFC08DDA24DD8A7C49103259DEB60"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1313127793D4B938F94E6A89177E119" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (D) as subparagraph (E); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA51CAE374A8B47EE931EF18756331AD3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block id="H704169DEFCAF4ABF81EC1C959BAE8703" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H6953DE8A311E4063908C6900F08E6C24"><enum>(D)</enum><text>best practices, guidelines, and technical standards for risk management associated with engineering biology and biomanufacturing, including risks associated with the use of artificial intelligence; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF56E67B31FEC47A1BF527DAC20E010D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b) and (c) as subsections (c) and (d), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37509897613346B9A6D88C027AB09AA1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="HEEFEF812D92E47AFA464777FDFB84DCB" style="OLC"><subsection id="H8A92E4A595984CB5B08041A708624163"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Nucleic acid synthesis screening tools and standards</header><paragraph id="HB5E10797DFAB4E19BBA2D3F3DCC40922"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director, in consultation with heads of Federal agencies the Director considers appropriate, shall carry out measurement research to support the development and improvement of best practices and technical standards for biosecurity measures related to nucleic acid synthesis, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="H63D974AAE6EF44AFBAAF866D90B9E951"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Testing to improve the accuracy, efficacy, and reliability of screening for nucleic acid synthesis.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0295958595834C1D879AD132377468F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Best practices, including security and access controls, for operational security and managing sequence-of-concern databases to support such screening.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9118D9DCBCF34B5B99942B4CFC2E0FA6" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Technical implementation guidance to ensure such screening is effective and secure.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0159E7FE53094B7C906D8D09E9653D17" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conformity-assessment best practices and technical standards.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBAA5397F03BD46C5A3EC350F382F2E57"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Methods to evaluate the impact and effectiveness of the implementation of subparagraphs (A) through (D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF0ABB499BAD44088D7088332FE5B833"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consortium</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this subsection, the Director shall convene a consortium of stakeholders, including industry, institutions of higher education, nonprofit organizations, and customers to carry out the following:</text><subparagraph id="H33EE9AD0B0DD4A559DABA50906EDB11B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Develop and periodically update consensus priorities and best practices, as appropriate, for synthetic nucleic acid procurement screening mechanisms.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDE640D45AAA4680A547D2DCF960759F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Develop roadmaps to inform the activities carried out under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFDB5FB3F88444F19EBCA60A2A952A50"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the first meeting of the consortium under paragraph (2), the Director shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report summarizing the findings of the consortium.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC4028B192CF42CBB43F99BBA8AB5BED"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>Of the funds authorized to be appropriated for the National Institute of Standards and Technology pursuant to this section for scientific and technical research and services laboratory activities, there is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030 to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

