<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25E19-V55-MN-3CS"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2212 IS: Visible Identification Standards for Immigration-Based Law Enforcement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2212</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250708">July 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend section 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act to require all immigration enforcement officers to display visible identification during public-facing immigration enforcement actions and to promote transparency and accountability.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short titles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Visible Identification Standards for Immigration-Based Law Enforcement Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>VISIBLE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id1a0b1f4a5ee342fda9c7e83147c113ff"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id60b21b3f1b1e4d40a746c0a9cbc312ce"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transparency and accountability in public immigration enforcement are essential to maintaining public trust and upholding constitutional governance; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id54b556c31aac47b08fa5c1bd464f3ee7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">immigration enforcement officers should be visibly identifiable during any civil immigration enforcement activity at which members of the public may be directly engaged or present, including actions involving civil and criminal authority, unless the activity is truly covert and not observable by the public.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id269ca9de644c4e92b74918eec89b1728"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Requirement for visible identification during immigration enforcement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1357">8 U.S.C. 1357</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1d28ee3c267d43d6b4af083d0340614e"><subsection id="id496656b1deed409baaae8850ace62b97"><enum>(i)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id95d7cce20de94842894b6b0fa9b4d57b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id6d54e34d3a56481ebcf8f076436aa938"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered immigration officer</term> means any individual who is—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id65c760468ff24c54ae6ffafbe4a237a4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authorized to perform immigration enforcement functions; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddc5419f040ad4204bd3a13b3ba912706"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id6806e428661d4e46b1a7b5d7afa7835a"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an officer or employee of U.S. Customs and Border Protection;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id228114d8637b413d819db02ee205199e"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an officer or employee of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id3e2e5983ff8247e5be9a45224393fc6b"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individual authorized, deputized, or designated under Federal law, regulation, or agreement to perform immigration enforcement functions, including pursuant to section 287(g) or any other delegation or agreement with the Department of Homeland Security.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbfff1b8c98a945d599a5fc73d0493b3a" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>public immigration enforcement function</term>—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1f4fc7a45a8f45f58ca5f4e799232bb2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any activity that involves the direct exercise of Federal immigration authority through public-facing actions, including a patrol, a stop, an arrest, a search, an interview to determine immigration status, a raid, a checkpoint inspection, or the service of a judicial or administrative warrant; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf23d1d7fca6e471f8d5a566f9e08aca0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include covert, non-public operations or non-enforcement activities.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id5a2125d7d3a043dcbce03cec737ee038"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>visible identification</term> means a display of an immigration officer’s agency and name or badge number in a size and format that complies with the requirements under paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id30741d30f2b24ac3a75990f1028e75cc"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each covered immigration officer who directly engages in a public immigration enforcement function within the United States shall, at all times during such engagement, wear visible identification, which shall include—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id307ab820db0b438faed07b1e27bade7f"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the full name or widely recognized initials of the officer’s employing agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd594716e71c1415f928aaadb48ca1034"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id3fd4e6e7c3df45578ee8f18bb4361b15"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the officer’s last name; or </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id61973eb034d042d09459e93c636d2225"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the officer’s unique badge or identification number.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id246a969541a845a989a57c6f6df5c18e" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The identifying information described in this paragraph shall be—</text><subparagraph id="id4a56a187e3ed431681afbcdc9e1a3901"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for the immigration officer’s agency, displayed in a size and format that is clearly legible from a distance of not less than 25 feet, using materials or markings suitable for visibility in both daylight and low-light conditions, under normal operation conditions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd63fc98472364496b1ecf7d1310c4f40"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for the officer’s name or badge number, displayed in a manner that is clearly visible and readable during direct engagement with the public; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0a28559f5ead44ee9efe03e53f46c994"><enum>(C)</enum><text>displayed on the outermost garment or gear and not obscured by tactical equipment, body armor, or accessories.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbf3a7cb7b96c4faab4dadac389f8d3d8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Covered immigration officers may not wear non-medical face coverings, including masks or balaclavas, that impair the visibility of the identifying information required under this subsection or obscure the officer’s face unless such face coverings are operationally necessary—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc509b8a6e56044f19c4fd1745ad3b446"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to protect the integrity of a covert, non-public operation; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide7d7be477c144d03a12dd404fffc2d78"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to guard against hazardous environmental conditions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id7a5845a48373446eab8840d0874395e3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Compliance and reporting</header><subsection id="id78cab871e2c141dbb75d627813b7e9b7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Internal accountability</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that any covered immigration officer who fails to comply with the requirements under section 287(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by section 3, receive appropriate administrative discipline, including written reprimand, suspension, or other personnel actions, consistent with agency policy and any applicable collective bargaining agreement.</text></subsection><subsection id="id9d95f56369c24685a7f38ca2a5d46f84"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report to Congress</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit a report to the Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department of Homeland Security, the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that includes—</text><paragraph id="id15a7523138174f3facd287e5bf77e27f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the total number of public immigration enforcement functions conducted during the reporting period;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf02a6eda0cd147079eb79395442838cf"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of documented instances of noncompliance with section 287(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by section 3; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idab137efc94b244229e32a4a5e6e70158"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a summary of disciplinary or remedial actions taken against those responsible for such instances of noncompliance.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idef23387309bf4faf8e515041f471d1da"><enum>5.</enum><header>Role of the Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department of Homeland Security shall—</text><paragraph id="id9213bbc21a8c44e498a6732efceaad7a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>receive and investigate complaints from the public concerning violations of section 287(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by section 3;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb04a1ab3473e466ea42ca11585de7472"><enum>(2)</enum><text>issue recommendations to relevant Department of Homeland Security components concerning compliance and corrective actions that should be taken;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id28828f67f42245ed9f7da11133df386d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include findings and actions taken pursuant to this Act, including information contained in the report received pursuant to section 4(b), in its annual public report submitted pursuant to section 705(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/345">6 U.S.C. 345(b)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0e6874f70fc34ca58df61434f9980ff6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>carry out the responsibilities under this section in accordance with its statutory authorities, which may include coordination with the Office of Inspector General of the Department, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

