<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H404D51C0C02147E1B7AF5CBEC6820D40" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3382 IH: Small Entity Update Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3382</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250514">May 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Securities and Exchange Commission to carry out a study and rulemaking on the definition of the term <quote>small entity</quote> under the securities laws for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/6">chapter 6</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC0760039053E4EDDBBA93936E5A2CF63" style="OLC"><section id="H10EB8AADEA7345B9A86B5D43C20FCD93" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Small Entity Update Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H6A85A999CFE64AC7981556928BD75B15" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Studies, reports, and rules regarding small entities</header><subsection id="HDAAEA3F5093D4EE4809CBF387794B4D9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="HEE1BA21DBC3E454392E9B5DE4F520569"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>Commission</term> means the Securities and Exchange Commission; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3271376BF511454DBE85D568FD9A22EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>small entity</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H03A40BD539DC4D0192488136DD81A75F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given the term in section 601 of title 5, United States Code, with respect to the activities of the Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41DFC3BBA6534F64AB5475F4B12E828D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any definition established by the Commission of the term <term>small business</term>, <quote>small entity</quote>, <term>small organization</term>, or <term>small governmental jurisdiction</term> under paragraph (3), (4), or (5), respectively, of section 601 of title 5, United States Code, with respect to the activities of the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9647FEBE59B0460C8236D735CC68A387"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Studies and reports</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and again 5 years thereafter, the Commission shall— </text><paragraph id="HF9CCC4B1C0554EB8BF222D628F74AFF3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a study of the definition of the term <term>small entity</term> with respect to the activities of the Commission for the purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/6">chapter 6</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, which shall consider—</text><subparagraph id="H8D167B2F973A476292D82B37A2718934"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the extent to which the definition of the term <term>small entity</term>, as in effect during the period in which the study is conducted, aligns with the findings and declarations made under section 2(a) of the Regulatory Flexibility Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68D9985233754E9293D88AD64DEFF3F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount by which financial markets in the United States have grown since the last time the Commission amended the definition of the term <term>small entity</term>, if applicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E3DA99B027C48ABA66B2B2FBF31962D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>how the Commission should define the term <term>small entity</term> to ensure that a meaningful number of entities would fall under that definition; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D0D98295F394E0A8C3AC67FF58253BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to Congress a report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H2ACCB09962BB487495DB866E01809EA2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the results of the applicable study conducted under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A252F07C8424ED4B7DA4EA89D82069F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specific and detailed recommendations on the ways in which the Commission could amend the definition of the term <term>small entity</term> to—</text><clause id="H889E70A9D84B4D72BDE04BBF4B063A0E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be consistent with the results described in subparagraph (A); and</text></clause><clause id="H89580E432F5F4ACAB6502D049AD2B489"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>expand the number of entities covered by such definition.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9BEF35AB866B4CA493FDB262FBC7E2AC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Concurrently with, or after the completion of, each study required under subsection (b), the Commission shall, subject to public notice and comment, revise the rules of the Commission consistent with the results of such study.</text></subsection><subsection id="H577DCCDAFBB541AFAC7E3B7FE9D1098B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Inflation adjustments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the Commission issued the final rule revisions required under subsection (c), and every 5 years thereafter, the Commission shall adjust any dollar figures under the definition of small entity established by the Commission to reflect the change in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

