<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF8D8F8A2E3F94F80BFC49AEAF072BF9B" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 362 IH: Expressing support for the designation of April 30, 2025, as “National Adult Hepatitis B Vaccination Awareness Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 362</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250430">April 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of April 30, 2025, as <quote>National Adult Hepatitis B Vaccination Awareness Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas up to 2.4 million individuals in the United States are chronically infected with hepatitis B, and up to two-thirds of individuals with chronic hepatitis B are unaware of their infection status; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas hepatitis B is a viral infection of the liver transmitted via infected blood and other body fluids, including through mother-to-child transmission and injection drug use;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas hepatitis B is associated with significant disparities among communities of color (including Asian Americans, Pacific Islanders, and African immigrants), sexual and gender minority communities, and those affected by the opioid crisis;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas individuals with chronic diseases such as diabetes, HIV, hepatitis C, and chronic liver disease, and individuals on hemodialysis are at an increased risk for hepatitis B co-infection;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there is no cure for hepatitis B and individuals with chronic hepatitis B require lifelong medical care;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas chronic hepatitis B represents one of the most common causes of liver cancer;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 1 in every 4 individuals with unmanaged chronic hepatitis B will develop liver cancer, cirrhosis, or liver failure, with liver cancer having a 5-year survival rate of only 18 percent in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas safe and highly effective vaccines to protect against hepatitis B are available;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in accordance with universal childhood hepatitis B vaccination recommendations in the United States, infants and children have been routinely vaccinated against hepatitis B since the 1990s;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas all adults aged 19 to 59, and adults 60 and older with hepatitis B risk factors, are recommended to be vaccinated against hepatitis B;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the hepatitis B vaccine, which is 95 percent effective and was the first anticancer vaccine to be developed, is projected to have prevented 310 million cases of hepatitis B worldwide from 1990 to 2020;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas only 30 percent of adults in the United States are vaccinated against hepatitis B;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the number of reported acute hepatitis B cases increased by 11 percent nationwide between 2014 and 2018;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as a result of the drug use epidemic, there have been significant regional increases in acute hepatitis B cases in the United States, including—</text><paragraph id="HD6F82A433C004DE2A83009EEBFCFD2DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a 489 percent increase in acute hepatitis B infections from 2015 to 2016 in Maine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02C4A60E88D34923BB18F804A78138FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a reported 114 percent increase from 2009 to 2013 in Kentucky, West Virginia, and Tennessee; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F43F71DDF924392AB3BCF18BBE53206"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a reported 78 percent increase in 2017 in southeastern Massachusetts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77CD8D405CBA4074A0D2F2643B2A4A0F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a reported 56 percent increase from 2014 to 2016 in North Carolina;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 36 percent of new hepatitis B cases are among people who inject drugs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, hepatitis B is 50 to 100 times more infectious than HIV and 5 to 10 times more infectious than hepatitis C; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there are significant opportunities, particularly within the setting of the drug use epidemic, to prevent new hepatitis B infections and thereby reduce the incidence of liver cancer and cirrhosis through efforts to—</text><paragraph id="HB97C1D9F38D94B6B9A1D19B4F7646A86"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase adult hepatitis B vaccination; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB522E61C799047099B54728D80B154F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>maintain childhood hepatitis B vaccination: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H666CD295AD5544E7A579604C2058B796"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HD8669B84034C4FAC839A004350976626"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HDD566C07B977487FAAF7A1E9AB3A819E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National Adult Hepatitis B Vaccination Awareness Day</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6AF5FA454EB94A99A25FE6707F3065B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of providing support and encouragement—</text><subparagraph id="H858C93960C7E4051B247CC6D3D2866FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for all adults aged 18 and older to be tested for hepatitis B at least once in their lifetime in accordance with recommendations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE85A5CFB587A4A598B71CB247565A3AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for individuals susceptible to infection to be vaccinated against hepatitis B; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2042E700193C443CAA8CF0015D3C794D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for individuals diagnosed with hepatitis B to be linked to appropriate care; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DC071A2E95945279A57E50B6AE836AD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in order to reduce the number of new hepatitis B infections and hepatitis B-related deaths, encourages a commitment to—</text><subparagraph id="H07453CB2E1364728B85E2DE300C1E672"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increasing adult hepatitis B vaccination rates;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4E2D1F7BF124C3C9FB6BEE689E1A376"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintaining childhood hepatitis B vaccination rates; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H984CB3A2C12F470D9C2C07AD4B2E381D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promoting provider and community awareness of adult hepatitis B vaccination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

