<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8B303E9212A04B6AB7791F4D918AD627" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 815 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that immigration enforcement operations must be transparent, accountable, and consistent with constitutional protections for all persons within the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 815</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251017">October 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that immigration enforcement operations must be transparent, accountable, and consistent with constitutional protections for all persons within the United States.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), through United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) and United States Customs and Border Protection (CBP), exercises significant enforcement powers that directly affect civil liberties and public trust;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas ICE agents have reportedly detained individuals using unmarked vehicles and while wearing plain clothes and facial coverings which has fueled impersonation of immigration officers;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in a Chicago raid in September 2025, children, many without clothing, were forcibly removed from their beds and separated from their parents, with at least four United States citizen children temporarily taken into custody;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas reports and court records show that United States citizens detained during immigration operations have declared their citizenship but were ignored, with some held overnight and denied access to counsel;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas at least fifteen United States citizens have been arrested, detained, or questioned about their citizenship since January 2025 by immigration or cooperating local officers, but inadequate reporting and recordkeeping prevent real transparency or accountability;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in Illinois, ICE arrested 160 people in January 2025, of whom 31 percent had no criminal charge, and by June 2025 that share rose to 61 percent of 333 arrests;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas lack of transparency prompted several Members of Congress to seek access to ICE’s Broadview facility, but were denied entry despite asserting Congress’s right to inspect facilities it funds;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas advocates have described conditions at Broadview as secretive and restrictive, making it difficult for attorneys to advise detainees of their legal rights and exacerbating concerns about due process;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in September 2025, California enacted the No Secret Police Act (S.B. 627), prohibiting officers from concealing their identity and requiring visible name, badge, or agency identification;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas recent Federal funding increases for ICE enforcement and detention have expanded the agency’s reach, heightening the need for transparency and oversight;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in June 2025, aggressive ICE raids in Los Angeles led to protests after reports that masked agents in unmarked vehicles used less lethal munitions and clashed with civilians and journalists;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas federally compiled documents submitted to Congress in July 2025, showed ICE agents wearing face coverings during residential raids in Los Angeles, with similar tactics reported in New York, Chicago, and other cities;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas there are existing legislative efforts to address each of these issues;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Immigration Enforcement Staff Body Camera Accountability Act (H.R. 4651), would require ICE and CBP personnel engaged in enforcement activities to wear body cameras to ensure transparency and accountability;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the CLEAR ID Act (H.R. 4843), would establish uniform identification standards for Federal law enforcement officers, promoting consistency and public trust;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the ICE Badge Visibility Act of 2025 (H.R. 4298), mandates that ICE officers display visible badges and identifying information during enforcement operations;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the No Anonymity in Immigration Enforcement Act of 2025 (H.R. 4004), prohibits ICE agents from concealing their identity during public operations, except in limited, safety-related circumstances;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Preventing Fraudulent ICE Impersonation Act of 2025 (H.R. 4652), strengthens penalties for individuals who impersonate immigration enforcement officers, thereby protecting the public from fraud and abuse;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the No Secret Police Act of 2025 (H.R. 4176), prohibits the use of facial coverings by law enforcement officers that conceal their identity, ensuring transparency during interactions with the public; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Homeland Security Improvement Act (H.R. 1678), promotes enhanced oversight, accountability, and training within DHS agencies to safeguard civil rights and ensure fair enforcement practices: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H24BBD37249FB45B883DCFB2C5FCDD434"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA7A56DEEC36E48809BF9EC361961573D"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H83E7B228345A48C8A28A4E7E0939EFE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses the sense of the House that the Department of Homeland Security should require all personnel engaged in enforcement operations for United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement and United States Customs and Border Protection to wear body cameras that record interactions with the public, with footage preserved for oversight and investigatory purposes;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7DDC445C30C64166BD58BD27134AC002"><enum>(2)</enum><text>believes that the Department should prohibit the use of masks, face coverings, or other obstructions of identity by enforcement personnel during public operations except in cases of demonstrable, immediate threat to officer safety;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE64136B8DEB248528A40F14B41DAC453"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports the requirement that all enforcement officers visibly display their name, badge number, and agency affiliation during public operations, consistent with the goals of H.R. 4298, H.R. 4004, and H.R. 4176;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H02470A65B3DC42FF9FF00F9E09385B4F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>urges the Department of Homeland Security to establish independent civilian oversight boards empowered to receive complaints, review enforcement actions, and recommend disciplinary measures or policy changes;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC124AD5D31F64BE29733D3D15B9F5882"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages the implementation of mandatory de-escalation training for all ICE and CBP officers and agents, consistent with the principles of H.R. 1678; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2612BB62F7F044BA9C3FE40E0127CC9E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>calls for the Justice Department to oversee ICE, thereby enabling more robust civil rights oversight and integration with existing civil liberties enforcement functions.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

