<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAF5107A373404C1793EF136ADC1A905C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4972 IH: Create Accountable Respectful Environments (CARE) for Children Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4972</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250815">August 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001039">Mrs. Cammack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. Scott Franklin of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000235">Mr. Ezell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001216">Mr. Mills</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend part E of title IV of the Social Security Act to address or assist in resolving the shortage of appropriate foster homes for children, to develop resources to keep sibling groups together, and to provide for a system of checks and balances to ensure a child’s ongoing safety and well-being, by providing for the placement of a foster child in cottage family homes and making a child so placed eligible for foster care maintenance payments.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD70BB6C5C3B2407AABBD6AAA4DE76672" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H72B4BA61E34A402DB6113EF922812221" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Create Accountable Respectful Environments (CARE) for Children Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6848BCD44A034B2A922AE733CE3AEB66"><enum>2.</enum><header>Placement of foster children in cottage family homes</header> <subsection id="HD9F2B88749CC426EA9F9BDB79D8231C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State plan requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 471(a)(37) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/671">42 U.S.C. 671(a)(37)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or a cottage family home</quote> before the comma.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H81B620FEC3F3454BB3B68A419194E67F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility of cottage family homes for foster care maintenance payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 472(a)(2)(C) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/672">42 U.S.C. 672(a)(2)(C)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>a cottage family home,</quote> before <quote>with a parent</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFF12482B20BB4BB88DAD1F98DEE0604A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition of cottage family home</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 472(c) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/672">42 U.S.C. 672(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB9CA710D74A04A42AD6BF6D5E66552F0"> 
<paragraph id="HA5A7A0C1012F4179A8C0B372DF69FC8B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cottage family home</header> 
<subparagraph id="HDCF9AE0F3BCB4148B51FC55CE6B39F55"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>cottage family home</term> means a home—</text> <clause id="HA847DE4041D542B1AB05204E35D6B173"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>that is operated by a public or private child care agency licensed or approved by the State in which the home is situated as an agency that meets the standards established for the licensing or approval;</text>
              </clause> 
<clause id="HCBEE32C611E64E94A9679AF942C6F98F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that encourages and supports the child and the family of the child in maintaining a strong connection through regular contact and involvement in a plan of care, except to the extent otherwise directed by a court of law;</text></clause> <clause id="H5C982653DF8343C5934D423C12D577FB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that is able to serve as a resource to facilitate sibling groups being placed together where daily contact and interaction strengthens family ties;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8C82191DEE3F4C54A2070FC67FA4BA94">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that provides children access to activities or items that are age or developmentally-appropriate, including the ability to participate in extracurricular, social, or other home and community activities with the same freedom afforded to their peers who are living at home with their families;</text>
              </clause> 
<clause id="H2B10CC30A7434D1297F512F2E119092E"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that has and implements a trauma-informed approach in the care of children;</text></clause> <clause id="H0F4EF3A81012414FBE6010F1202B77B9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>that prohibits the use of seclusion or mechanical or chemical restraints and permits only short-term physical restraint if approved in the policies of the agency to prevent injury to self or others, and prohibits any prone physical restraint;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE9507D1EAD5C4410BD3F5AD82555D659"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>that provides a system for a child to alert a staff member if the child has a concern, feels unfairly denied rights, or is subject to a threat of mistreatment;</text></clause> <clause id="HE0F20E84912249B3A0F3D277F6662CDB"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>that has a continuous quality improvement methodology that regularly solicits information from children concerning their perceptions of the quality of care and opinions about the strengths and weaknesses of the program;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCD31BFCA98EA4ED285404FB920AE88C3"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>that is in a single-family style residence with no more than 2 children per bedroom unless it is in the best interest of the children; and</text></clause> <clause id="H58A2DF1A47084A21B934013039643B86"><enum>(x)</enum><text>in which the children are under the care of live-in parents that use the reasonable and prudent parent standard and provide 24-hour substitute care of children placed away from their parents or other caretakers.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H12EDB52C0F6D455A8F87EC9882952C83"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Preservation of State flexibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not prohibit, limit, or penalize, by regulation or order, or bring an action in any court to challenge, any action or determination of a State or political subdivision of a State to—</text> <clause id="H2C4F69A796FA4BCDB08FBB4165ED1116"><enum>(i)</enum><text>treat a cottage family home as a foster family home for purposes of this part; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0E01FFE871404AC68D9C055D7F87C64C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">treat an entity as a cottage family care home for purposes of this part, as the State deems necessary to serve the best interests of children or families.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HB16B7EC390D34A8282A0AFADBB7A0637"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No time limit on foster care maintenance payments for children placed in a cottage family home</header><text>Section 472(k)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/672">42 U.S.C. 672(k)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4262C2A23B18488ABC11B60B14EF5664" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H6062676BE59B4CF595D4DA7A851982AD"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A cottage family home.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HF02973145B634ED9A25D518EADF3B623"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header> <paragraph id="HC99564CB8F7F45C3B77F365EE14D9637"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act, and shall apply to payments under part E of title IV of the Social Security Act for calendar quarters beginning on or after such date.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC63BDC23D2AB47DDAF69B6CE264ED342"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Delay permitted if State legislation required</header><text>If the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines that State legislation (other than legislation appropriating funds) is required in order for a State plan under part E of title IV of the Social Security Act to meet the additional requirements imposed by the amendments made by this section, the plan shall not be regarded as failing to meet any of the additional requirements before the date that is 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

