<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H07A214D2491B4FFAA97904C2941EBD30" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5063 IH: Safe Beaches, Safe Swimmers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5063</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250829">August 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure continuity of staffing at Federal beaches, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2EA2E7A6BF814EF8BC4DFD8182B0233D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCC4766CF1ADE40A7BD8C6FE39846734A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe Beaches, Safe Swimmers Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4E22E34387C546B69F91708CE3EB564E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Adequate lifeguard staffing at Federal swimming areas and beaches</header> <subsection id="HBA26DBD96ACD4E48B9FD1C81024F3E27"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines there is a staffing shortage with respect to a designated swim location, the Secretary shall seek to enter into an agreement with one or more local government agencies to enable lifeguards employed by those local government agencies to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H690F58267D314F029E3DCEE61C4A24C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>adequately staff such designated swim location during normal seasonal operating hours; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF88CF645A4304B529632D87CE1D686C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure visitor safety and provide rescue and first aid services at the designated swim location as necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB9014553A33347DC81B70AB586144F88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reimbursement</header> 
<paragraph id="HCB2E35EA079648FCA676D950DB80001A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In entering into an agreement under subsection (a), the Secretary shall ensure that the local government agency providing the lifeguard services is reimbursed for all reasonable costs incurred by the local government agency in carrying out the agreement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8F9D7517F524480387A0DAA93246CDA3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Current agreements</header><text>If an agreement has been entered into by the Secretary and a local government agency for lifeguard services at a designated swim location on or before the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall amend such agreement as necessary to provide for the reimbursement of the local government agency for all reasonable costs incurred by the local government agency in carrying out the agreement, regardless of the terms of the original agreement relating to cost sharing.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5D5542F4607E48E2A6A23F2522A6BBF4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H4B1EBDE3D5B4429EACA93CA8106A7A1A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designated swim location</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>designated swim location</term> means a swimming area or swimming beach—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H99000CC5D9EE447CB86430FBC111A148"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on lands and waters managed by the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, the Bureau of Land Management, or the Bureau of Reclamation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4EB0CF014D7F4389A37B9DC5218DA38B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is typically monitored by federally employed lifeguards during normal seasonal operating hours.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFA4F85359EA04F86AC1A318C071F8185"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Staffing shortage</header> 
<subparagraph id="HC879CE192FF64C9D94DB491B4E354999"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>staffing shortage</term> means a level of staffing that negatively impacts the ability to adequately staff a designated swim location with federally employed lifeguards and will likely result or has resulted in a designated swim location being left unmonitored by federally employed lifeguards during normal seasonal operating hours.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H505AC13D32A845B2B5A616AFCA6048B2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>staffing shortage</term> does not refer to short-term staffing shortages caused by temporary absences, such as an employee taking annual or sick leave.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H09AE4C8E430D41FCA6B4D12207929B03"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

