<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H60704A79B0C74DC5B7492E0D1CEDA98D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4544 RH: American Access to Banking Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 210</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4544</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–253]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250908">September 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on July 17, 2025</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct certain Federal banking and credit union agencies to promote the formation of de novo regulated institutions through the review of application processes, the review of capital raising by de novo regulated institutions, and the establishment of various outreach programs, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HBA00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HF196ACD68DA14F7B8E99689965D7F554"><section id="H8F28353F1D5E4956ACCC3BA89BF780B2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Access to Banking Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8378796D02824FDDB82C4F7E284D0C1A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Streamlining application process and review of capital raising by de novo regulated institutions</header><subsection id="HE9BD6AEA04A848B9B948B4E48BE0094B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each of the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies shall—</text><paragraph id="HEF86F2C672B444E28D26D12F9A8D8554"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the purpose of streamlining the process of applying to become a de novo regulated institution, conduct a review of any application forms related to such process;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEFA3AE5FA294012827A782CA875FC5F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent practicable, gather information needed from applicants seeking to become a de novo regulated institution from other Federal Government agencies or public sources to minimize information requests of such applicants; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D608838276F4F4996FCF758C9F64E8B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in consultation with the Securities and Exchange Commission, review how de novo regulated institutions raise capital while maintaining investor protections, including the impact of—</text><subparagraph id="HBCCF6B3EF27C4087BF45D54D9250DAD5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>general capital raising restrictions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E5C929D710C4FDFBA17B67FBC7F2FCD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>capital raising restrictions related to individuals who are not accredited investors.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0C8597561CB9434CB2FAF8F78FB6BDEB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, and annually for 5 years thereafter, each of the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies shall submit to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and publish on a public website of such agency a report that contains—</text><paragraph id="HF01F7296B03240AF87001346D615A418"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the actions taken by such agency pursuant to subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9C9A9027D9348BA986E67DECF5D04B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as appropriate, any administrative or legislative recommendations with respect to the purpose described in subsection (a)(3).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H938D6C9136B045E2949BD2C65FD864EC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improving communication with de novo regulated institutions</header><subsection id="H7DF1D9CCA28A48C7809E1E2FAE09C417"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each of the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies shall, at the request of an applicant to become a de novo regulated institution, designate an employee of the agency as a caseworker, who may perform such duty in addition to the other duties of the employee.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5BA094407DA74D2ABFC652D0ECEC51C2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Caseworker duties</header><text>Each caseworker described in subsection (a) shall, to the maximum extent practicable—</text><paragraph id="H29F73809B1DC433C883F2E5B3CE93CF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meet with the lead organizers applying to become a de novo regulated institution to provide a tutorial with respect to the application process; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7ADD25F883314E41B99F88DDDF1621E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be the primary point of contact of the respective Federal financial institutions regulatory agency for such organizers during the application process.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9995569BEFF242E5AE15F8458009CABF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>New caseworker</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each agency described in subsection (a) may designate a new caseworker, as appropriate, to support continuity based on staffing and responsibilities assigned to the current caseworker. </text></subsection></section><section id="H7343F17664D44BA6AAB94BD086A00986"><enum>4.</enum><header>De Novo Mentor-Protégé partnerships</header><subsection id="H7984791824A24A5AADB9827DD03F104B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the request of an institution that seeks to become a de novo regulated institution, each of the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies shall, to the maximum extent practicable, provide a list to such institution of similar types of institutions that—</text><paragraph id="HE76DC7702B2A4B0ABE0FF22543BAF4C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">were recently approved to become a de novo regulated institution; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC41838B9B8C4C31A3013662C6288458"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are interested in volunteering to serve as a mentor to provide advice about the de novo application process. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE565C56652864289AD231056B2866873"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mentorship information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, each of the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies shall provide public information and directions on how an institution may request a mentor or serve as a mentor as described in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="H6E42B93F4CE14078AD0871EA1FAD1D30"><enum>5.</enum><header>State and stakeholder engagement plan</header><subsection id="H4DEBFDE1E8AC4A40872509A87592D943"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each of the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies shall develop a plan to—</text><paragraph id="HA34CF9EAC41342E8B400AC09C798BA2D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regularly consult with State regulators to promote cooperation between State and Federal banking and credit union agencies in the creation of de novo regulated institutions, including responding to any State regulator that requests assistance on how a State-chartered financial institution can request Federal insurance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56E09E13BD2841A7B3E3C64CF301CF58"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regularly consult with stakeholders, including applicants to become de novo regulated institutions and recently approved regulated institutions, to inform any reforms that may support the creation of de novo regulated institutions, including rural institutions, community development financial institutions, and minority depository institutions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C765BD4A46A4842A9B7CB19DA1BBA3A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide guidance, training material, and regular workshops to assist any interested parties to understand such agencies processes. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H708A3FD8F3404964ABC239DF73B41181"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><paragraph id="H578B4BF5C12D429B804918DF867BD496"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section, and every 5 years thereafter, each of the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies shall submit to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate the respective plan of such agency described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D8F61232A6C4029A3D1C2B0365A6DFD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public comment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to developing the plan described in subsection (a), each of the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies shall—</text><subparagraph id="HD1BBDEE2CF894C4BABD03692E601C0A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide an opportunity for public comments; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB821E8A35E34510919C49DE3FECFF69"><enum>(B)</enum><text>take such public comments into consideration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H954B628491AE4A6BB62CBBE83E2129FC" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><subsection id="H85FE2A0D84B9400BBD9B29623CC4D977"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H751483EDE118413D9B0D62EE35514B36"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal banking agency</header><text>The term <quote>Federal banking agency</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A57A98C7AEA40B5A8E7F329910D5C72"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 1003 of the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/3302">12 U.S.C. 3302</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27B80219C2BE49C2A465A808F33D6647"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Regulated institution</header><text>The term <quote>regulated institution</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H32949A2B4707416C95713FD9827EE852"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a Federal banking agency, a depository institution (as such term is defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>)) for which the Federal banking agency is the appropriate Federal banking agency (as such term is defined in such section 3); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41E9211211F24A45A889C850D5627CD4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the National Credit Union Administration, an insured credit union (as such term is defined in section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1752">12 U.S.C. 1752</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF474579D499749488DB9D18CB8BE489A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means each of the several States, the District of Colombia, and each territory of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H265EBE95CA3F49D783F2791E81F123BC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State regulator</header><text>The term <quote>State regulator</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H49973E88319C492697BF42DAFAE98A3E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to a Federal banking agency, a State banking regulator; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F8E62F32730499BA32FE42D0A15B5B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the National Credit Union Administration, the State regulatory agency having jurisdiction over a State credit union (as such term is defined in section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1752">12 U.S.C. 1752</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D5C7E4EFBDE4F1AA1E46BB80FD03F14"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, the process of applying to become a de novo regulated institution shall include the process of applying for Federal deposit insurance, Federal share insurance, or membership of a Federal reserve bank.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20250908">September 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

