<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6B2CD35DD57A46C7932C66D61EFF66C4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1016 IH: Protecting Women’s Private Spaces Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1016</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250205">February 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000619">Mr. Rulli</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001235">Mr. Moore of West Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit individuals from accessing or using single-sex facilities on Federal property other than those corresponding to their biological sex, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA5C02941B16C43A49175F3DE2F43D9A8" style="OLC"><section id="H76BED8EB69934C5086BC978C7B98C5A1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Women’s Private Spaces Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H093F9A3D0C4D43A499550198EECCC4F0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on the use of single-sex facilities on Federal property other than those corresponding to the biological sex of an individual</header><subsection id="HA1978EB9F3B743DF8689FE9CB0D184EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, except as provided in subsection (c), no person may access or use a single-sex facility on Federal property, other than those corresponding to the biological sex of such person.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1961C43E66DB444091A2D42A2B08F2E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="H3D2613751B8C4833885AD2AE44D96ECF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Single-sex facility</header><text>The term <quote>single-sex facility</quote> means a space intended for the use of one biological sex (male or female), including a—</text><subparagraph id="HB3A7F8CEAAE448069BB21EC3E524AFDB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>restroom;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED757644EE014014A1005602A427949C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>locker room; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE83BB92C884D49BABE2BF56F451C62AF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>changing room.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H54B1FA90951E45E99DC36ECCF3FC3BCA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal property</header><text>The term <quote>Federal property</quote> means any building, land, or other real property owned, leased, or occupied by any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States (including the Department of Defense and the United States Postal Service), or any other instrumentality wholly owned by the United States, or by any department or agency of the District of Columbia or any territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3D2FD0077134FCD90ABD2184E31450E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Biological sex</header><text>The term <quote>biological sex</quote> means the biological determination as to whether an individual is male or female, as such terms are defined in this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E841FDDFFBC430493E6D27EECC3A495"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Female</header><text>The term <quote>female</quote> means an individual who naturally has, had, will have, or would have, but for a developmental or genetic anomaly or historical accident, the reproductive system that at some point produces, transports, and utilizes eggs for fertilization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6976BF7858641EA92B0220D9121E22A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Male</header><text>The term <quote>male</quote> means an individual who naturally has, had, will have, or would have, but for a developmental or genetic anomaly or historical accident, the reproductive system that at some point produces, transports, and utilizes sperm for fertilization.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0927CB32502A4A0FB57B82931FD1B097"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The prohibition in subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to—</text><paragraph id="H3E31DFF8355949B2BAAE0A9B0C37C4A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>emergency medical personnel responding to a medical emergency; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB009D8E9320A4F31A04F57EA0C9F1BF5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>law enforcement officers in active pursuit of a suspect, or as part of an active investigation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

