<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H488C04BC4E994655921E0048255E9E05" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-joint" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HJ 71 IH: Providing for congressional disapproval of the proposed foreign military sale to Israel of certain defense articles and services.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 71</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250303">March 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) submitted the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing for congressional disapproval of the proposed foreign military sale to Israel of certain defense articles and services.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HA26C1457F5BE4697841D20377EC68286"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HCB8B7B6736F7427199AF3F697D10842C"><enum/><text>That the following proposed foreign military sale to Israel is prohibited:</text><paragraph id="HFB948CB07DCA46139645D50EBD827527"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The sale of the following defense articles and services, described in Transmittal No. 24–104, submitted to Congress pursuant to section 36(b)(1) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2776">22 U.S.C. 2776(b)(1)</external-xref>), and published in the Congressional Record on February 10, 2025: three thousand (3,000) AGM–114 Hellfire Air-to-Ground Missiles, to include one or any combination of the R3, F, F/A, K1, K1A, K2, K3, K3A, KA, N, N3, and/or R variants. The following non-MDE items will also be included: support and test equipment; integration and test support; spare and repair parts; software delivery and support; publications and technical documentation; personnel training and training equipment; U.S. Government and contractor engineering; technical and logistics support services; storage; and other related elements of logistics and program support. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

