<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H159C17389B6940ABBB579EFA8FDAC38B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4190 IH: the Defining Humanitarian Demining Assistance Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4190</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250626">June 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000598">Mr. LaLota</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to modify the definitions relating to humanitarian demining assistance and stockpiled conventional munitions assistance.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3271D125B7AE4378B4DE6AD08782938B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8EF18F13C3E245E5BF6871BD61441CDB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>the Defining Humanitarian Demining Assistance Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section>
<section id="HED59CBB419D64275A83A705754906451"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions relating to humanitarian demining assistance and stockpiled conventional munitions assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (e) of section 407 of title 10, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H1FBBF492867B46548213C9A58263258F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HB5BB9B826E4F46C99184F6E861F548B0"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE19DDDE7B11B4965850EB5B2425DED58"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>humanitarian demining assistance</quote>, as it relates to training and support—</text> <subparagraph id="H7594169C0E2F4BB0A9039FFE15C595E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means detection and clearance of landmines, unexploded explosive ordnance, and other explosive remnants of war; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7ADF7FB8A4EC43A5A28D61F0766FCE73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes activities related to the use of competencies prescribed by the International Mine Action Standards to furnish education, training, technical assistance, and infrastructure development with respect to, and equipment for—</text> <clause id="HE7439BB913F442EEB910CCFB04ED5D61"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the detection and clearance of landmines, unexploded explosive ordnance, and other explosive remnants of war.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAD4E67FF224D4066B46BEED549C5AD0C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the development of national standards and standard operating procedures for such detection and clearance; and</text></clause> <clause id="H9CE6FEACB5FF4A7E9F7DC10D005F652F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>explosive safety.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD0752788472E4E039BCBF5391C064202"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>stockpiled conventional munitions assistance</quote>, as it relates to the support of humanitarian assistance efforts—</text> <subparagraph id="H744C56F947D44731B27814887C8E892D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means training and support in the disposal, demilitarization, physical security of stockpiles, and lifecycle stockpile management of potentially dangerous stockpiles of explosive ordnance, small arms, and light weapons, including man-portable air-defense systems; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9FEA59B636FD4B82842AF513614C64FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes activities related to the use of International Ammunition Technical Guidelines to support the capacity building of a foreign security institution by furnishing education, training, technical assistance, and infrastructure development with respect to, and equipment for—</text> <clause id="HC898113223444C39A5CC84FC90435D96"><enum>(i)</enum><text>explosive safety, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF8E5C40F44C84A948FF185AA50F2DB59"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the disposal, demilitarization, physical security of stockpiles, stockpile management, national standards and standard operating procedure development of potentially dangerous stockpiles of explosive ordnance, small arms, and light weapons, including man-portable air-defense systems.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> </legis-body></bill>

