<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H56F2D73EC113491B9BAE3772D1F8C800" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 993 : Emerging Innovative Border Technologies Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 993</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250311" legis-day="20250310">March 11 (legislative day, March 10), 2025</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to develop a plan to identify, integrate, and deploy new, innovative, disruptive, or other emerging or advanced technologies to enhance, or address capability gaps in, border security operations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAABB87E2B3E64D8193CF1FACB42C1592" style="OLC"><pagebreak></pagebreak><section id="HD6C2BAB66CB94930AA13204C1D73704C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Emerging Innovative Border Technologies Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9A42A782854A453F8C6773BA567A46F1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Innovative and emerging border technology plan</header><subsection id="HC5D65E3D56EF40C7AE23C160B5D3965C" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) and the Under Secretary for Science and Technology of the Department of Homeland Security, shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a plan to identify, integrate, and deploy new, innovative, disruptive, or other emerging or advanced technologies that may incorporate artificial intelligence, machine-learning, automation, fiber-optic sensing technology, nanotechnology, optical and cognitive radar, modeling and simulation technology, hyperspectral and LIDAR sensors, imaging, identification, and categorization systems, or other emerging or advanced technologies, to enhance, or address capability gaps in, border security operations.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCF7134511F3348E784EF0A65206571A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The plan required under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H5603CCA9C8454F689EBAED3843D8E183" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Information regarding how CBP utilizes CBP Innovation Team authority under subsection (c) and other mechanisms to carry out the purposes specified in subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC84738FBF5104545AE02DB4CE5052E66" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the contributions directly attributable to such utilization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BAF5B707B094F3C96E704A8A54AF1F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information regarding the composition of each CBP Innovation Team, and how each such Team coordinates and integrates efforts with the CBP acquisition program office and other partners within CBP and the Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEDD8D453AEF494D9E4579E8C32B1EAB"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identification of technologies used by other Federal departments or agencies not in use by CBP that could assist in enhancing, or addressing capability gaps in, border security operations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4390D7A8FFB143BAB9464E3001E7D3DF"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of authorities available to CBP to procure technologies referred to subsection (a), and an assessment as to whether additional or alternative authorities are needed to carry out the purposes specified in such subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22E0D95AD3EE4FD68B2ACEC43A68D312" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An explanation of how CBP plans to scale existing programs related to emerging or advanced technologies into programs of record.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H204F66AEE3734A1B96C67D6FCE9B3AFA" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of each planned security-related technology program, including objectives, goals, and timelines for each such program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F6A7E28C3D04487851A017F85F62368"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the privacy and security impact on border communities of security-related technology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9454B693BEB4F1DBB353C4EEB15C6D2"><enum>(9)</enum><text>An assessment of CBP legacy border technology programs that could be phased out and replaced by technologies referred to in subsection (a), and cost estimates relating to such phase out and replacement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A258DCBA919432FB3BCE4A114436B1E" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Information relating to how CBP is coordinating with the Department of Homeland Security’s Science and Technology Directorate to carry out the following:</text><subparagraph id="HA22439C8376844EDAA0F849DE6988A7B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Research and develop new, innovative, disruptive, or other emerging or advanced technologies to carry out the purposes specified in subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C2FE69B855C498D943D949FAFC4A585" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identify security-related technologies that are in development or deployed by the private and public sectors that may satisfy the mission needs of CBP, with or without adaptation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E5C7839FF15401C82BE77F1F4D0C6EF" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Incentivize the private sector to develop technologies that may help CBP meet mission needs to enhance, or address capability gaps in, border security operations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67C6F5AA3CF948B6853CB7A8199A1CE1" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identify and assess ways to increase opportunities for communication and collaboration with the private sector, small and disadvantaged businesses, intra-governmental entities, university centers of excellence, and Federal laboratories to leverage emerging technology and research within the public and private sectors.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFABCFDC37DB94D79BB4166F688348311" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Information on metrics and key performance parameters for evaluating the effectiveness of efforts to identify, integrate, and deploy new, innovative, disruptive, or other emerging or advanced technologies to carry out the purposes specified in subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C22E07A398A4761B44A54103E5EAB93"><enum>(12)</enum><text>An identification of recent technological advancements in the following:</text><subparagraph id="HFED032A158BF4BE280BF46E661555A72"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Manned aircraft sensor, communication, and common operating picture technology.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96E4C15412764DC28106B6E2E45B7351"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Unmanned aerial systems and related technology, including counter-unmanned aerial system technology.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCD0E2CE11EC422BACC225C0681A8915"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Surveillance technology, including the following:</text><clause id="H3B77BED3493F47E9BC39AF897E344A3D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Mobile surveillance vehicles.</text></clause><clause id="H85362A4454CA4ACD9DF97441DC2A263C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Associated electronics, including cameras, sensor technology, and radar.</text></clause><clause id="H7966186902064F3882D6FBCD1AC1FC30"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Tower-based surveillance technology.</text></clause><clause id="HB60404061D8743639422A71CB6946E76"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Advanced unattended surveillance sensors.</text></clause><clause id="HE521B063F79548B2A172CB0D957F48EB"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Deployable, lighter-than-air, ground surveillance equipment.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05618B72F75740B594A961FE103843F5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Nonintrusive inspection technology, including non-X-ray devices utilizing muon tomography and other advanced detection technology.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82F63FBB474146059236F9191E6DD24B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Tunnel detection technology.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCE4E1668B994C4583AC1CCE94F7B2A7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Communications equipment, including the following:</text><clause id="H2BD8A9D608E9402798C3ADE01E918C60"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Radios.</text></clause><clause id="H3A6414968BCC4B8CA95F1FD868431358"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Long-term evolution broadband.</text></clause><clause id="H5AC20DDCC22B4EDC91E3C45FAEE9F921"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Miniature satellites.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB9848204BCE4F5E80A32DC8CADEAE4F"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Any other information the Secretary determines relevant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA64CBE74AD0468C81C58EDB0E23E6EE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>CBP Innovation Team authority</header><paragraph id="HDF3C411B7A2142DD905BCD0E10D493CB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of CBP is authorized to maintain one or more CBP Innovation Teams to research and adapt commercial technologies that are new, innovative, disruptive, or otherwise emerging or advanced that may be used by CBP to enhance, or address capability gaps in, border security operations and urgent mission needs, and assess potential outcomes, including any negative consequences, of the introduction of emerging or advanced technologies with respect to which documented capability gaps in border security operations are yet to be determined.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD3BFCC3BE3F4ACF9B4033C8EF3CE434"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Operating procedures, planning, strategic goals</header><text>The Commissioner of CBP shall require each team maintained pursuant to paragraph (1) to establish the following:</text><subparagraph id="HCEAABA0C9E06419C8BFC398BBF8812D7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Operating procedures that include specificity regarding roles and responsibilities within each such team and with respect to Department of Homeland Security and non-Federal partners, and protocols for entering into agreements to rapidly transition such technologies to existing or new programs of record to carry out the purposes specified in subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBD4A9D1E5394A8B9884011B11F31D76" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Planning and strategic goals for each such team that includes projected costs, time frames, metrics, and key performance parameters relating to the achievement of identified strategic goals, including a metric to measure the rate at which technologies described in subsection (a) are transitioned to existing or new programs of record in accordance with subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2429B901DDD142B49A90BB496CE842BE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Commissioner of CBP shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate information relating to the activities of CBP Innovation Teams, including information regarding the following:</text><subparagraph id="HF2F1B6F78F99444C83DA407915C698B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Copies of operating procedures and protocols under paragraph (2)(A) and planning and strategic goals required under paragraph (2)(B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC90F6D6862D44D2A9A648337AD7E2692" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Descriptions of the technologies piloted by each such team over the immediately preceding fiscal year, including information regarding which such technologies are determined successful and an identification of documented capability gaps that are addressed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FB8FEC9E3094016B5D4204B4BB3ACB1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information on the status of efforts to rapidly transition technologies determined successful to existing or new programs of record.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250310" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives March 10, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

