<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H09B1FC32B08E424EB4FE23700FB88785" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 493 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States must take urgent, coordinated action to address the national housing crisis through preservation and production of affordable housing.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 493</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250610">June 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States must take urgent, coordinated action to address the national housing crisis through preservation and production of affordable housing.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States is experiencing a severe housing crisis, with an estimated shortage of more than 7,000,000 rental homes affordable and available to extremely low-income households, leaving millions without access to safe and stable housing;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas nearly half of all renter households are cost-burdened, with over 12,000,000 spending more than 50 percent of their income on housing, threatening their ability to afford other basic necessities;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas rental prices have increased by more than 35 percent since 2020, while median household incomes have grown by only 22 percent over the same period, contributing to rising homelessness and housing instability;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas shelter inflation continues to drive core services inflation, disproportionately impacting low- and moderate-income households and impeding economic mobility;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the private housing market alone cannot meet the needs of extremely low-income renters, and public investment in affordable housing has not kept pace with demand;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Federal rental assistance reaches only 1 in 4 eligible households, leaving millions without support despite meeting income qualifications;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas significant portions of the Nation’s subsidized housing stock are aging, with some properties facing mismanagement, disrepair, or loss from affordability requirements;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the housing crisis impacts every region and demographic, disproportionately harming communities of color, seniors, people with disabilities, low-wage workers, and single-parent households;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas solving the housing crisis requires coordinated action across Federal, State, and local governments, and the engagement of private, nonprofit, and philanthropic sectors to expand supply, preserve affordability, and ensure tenant protections; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas policies that encourage responsible development, incentivize preservation, and protect vulnerable renters are essential to stabilizing communities and promoting housing equity: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HB7CB531887AF40CDB743E0639189B92E"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H749FEB3955634A26BB7BABA9708981F8"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H9BC0BA24A93E4D38AD3CA72AEA3456AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affirms that housing is a foundational human need and economic necessity, and that the housing crisis is a national emergency;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0784DD78A8C84BD78C6B48593118743F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports comprehensive Federal, State, and local efforts to increase the supply of deeply affordable rental housing and preserve existing units;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H116D1822DF404A31871F0874B0BAC083"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges Congress to prioritize supporting rental assistance, housing preservation, and affordable housing development programs;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2BA30CFDBD3B435EA42A7953ED5F90EA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages private and nonprofit sector partners to invest in sensible housing solutions and collaborate on innovative, community-based models that are responsive to community needs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA3EE4F79B2434154915A30FCDBF9E998"><enum>(5)</enum><text>calls on policy makers across all levels of government to align housing, zoning, and infrastructure policies in support of affordability, availability, and preservation; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0235DF837F8E4F629888E60D380720BA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>commits to advancing solutions that ensure safe, affordable housing for all individuals, families, and communities across the United States.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

