<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H986B70165B984A13819D2EC4BCF35FEE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1220 IH: Fee Increases for Reckless Mismanagement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1220</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250211">February 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to direct the Secretary of State to increase the fee imposed on aliens filing an application abroad for a visa authorizing admission to the United States as a nonimmigrant described in section 101(a)(15)(B) who are nationals of certain countries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0AA3E033F81045CC8C1D1C1871ECA303" style="OLC"><section id="HB53D596A1B5B4B869AADA72EA667136C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fee Increases for Reckless Mismanagement Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or <quote><short-title>FIRM Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD6A7721D01774262A032F56AE81C1009"><enum>2.</enum><header>Fee increase for certain nonimmigrant visa applicants</header><subsection id="H68C2ED34BE3B4FB69FB25179926DCC44"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 281 the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H00147CDAB63344539749FF4F6E378B18" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H3E416DFAD9684B74915C89156794859A"><enum>281A.</enum><header>Fee increase for certain nonimmigrant visa applicants</header><subsection id="H8DADA31D6224405B8A2AD132B993B2EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Fee increase</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall increase the fee imposed under section 281 on an alien filing an application abroad for a visa authorizing admission to the United States as a nonimmigrant described in section 101(a)(15)(B) in accordance with subsection (b) for any alien who is a national of a country with respect to which the Secretary determines any of the following:</text><paragraph id="HAE9240E5CC0E42769107C0F7FA3C1FAA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security has reported to the Secretary of State under section 243(d) that the government of the country has denied or unreasonably delayed accepting an alien who is a citizen, subject, national, or resident of that country after the Secretary of Homeland Security asked whether the government would accept the alien. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BFB7040462F4F20AE771CE82CE077EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State has designated the country as a state sponsor of international terrorism (as such term is defined in section 214(c)(4)(F)(ii)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABACD34432D84459BBF42A2414460009"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The country is listed as a tier 3 country in the most recent Trafficking in Persons report of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons of the Department of State. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H71B7F3FA7F754B8689DA98E16B159FE5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amount of increase</header><text>The Secretary shall increase the fee described in subsection (a) as follows:</text><paragraph id="HA468352687614FAFA02F60FD69EE3CC6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If the Secretary determines that the country meets one of the criteria described in paragraphs (1) through (3) of subsection (a), the Secretary shall increase such fee by not less than 50 percent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9628E580AC8E471ABEB1AFBEB4E12EA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If the Secretary determines that the country meets two of the criteria described in paragraphs (1) through (3) of subsection (a), the Secretary shall increase such fee by not less than 100 percent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDF047CC17634218AA88BDB3CCC3A6B0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If the Secretary determines that the country meets three of the criteria described in paragraphs (1) through (3) of subsection (a), the Secretary shall increase such fee by not less than 150 percent. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9EB7948D80074E31A831A8343B780E62"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Periodic review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the first day of each month, the Secretary shall review the determinations under subsection (a), to determine whether any increase imposed should be reduced, or whether an increase should be imposed on nationals of any additional countries. </text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HCA9B66CCA4C9473FA3D90390812DFC64"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for the Immigration and Nationality Act is amended by inserting after the item related to section 281 the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9BEAEA6B55C44117BF42EA14140EEAC7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">281A. Fee increase for certain nonimmigrant visa applicants. </toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

