<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H7FCACB14604A434285C11EC4AF819F85">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4684 IH: Star-Spangled Summit Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4684</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000403">Mr. Kennedy of Utah</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to issue a special use permit with respect to the maintaining of a flagpole bearing the flag of the United States at Kyhv Peak Lookout Point, Utah, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H3E300033885D4E17A6AC4DB6E2D3F7B0">
<section section-type="section-one" id="H27F6C9790CE54220AFB8BAC8B24B6E38"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Star-Spangled Summit Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFF65746EF0554D80A4C209415DCF74D7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Special use permit for maintenance of covered flagpole at Kyhv Peak Lookout Point</header> <subsection id="HC7075286096F42BB8E6233988068B18A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="HCD4DFA8EA8064254B91988A43ED6EBF5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered flagpole</header><text>The term <term>covered flagpole</term> means a flagpole bearing the flag of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1E90A4BB7C544F278CAA5DC70ED7FE49"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Kyhv Peak Lookout Point</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Kyhv Peak Lookout Point</term> means the peak within the Uinta National Forest overlooking Utah Valley and located approximately at latitude 40°16′18.14″ N, longitude 111°36′58.57″ W.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2DA5CE1BAF834FFE9EA2DC7F77B09696"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified person</term> means an individual that resides in, or a nonprofit entity or volunteer organization that carries out operations of the entity or organization in, Utah County, Utah, that has—</text> <subparagraph id="H786C354F89714FDAB3241F9205DB2876"><enum>(A)</enum><text>experience placing, maintaining, or otherwise caring for a covered flagpole; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6A44C8D6A8AF4FA0B5A250BC34E025B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other experience determined relevant by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD299BAEFE854412A3EC6094BBD16FCA" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H818412C6E02E42E59D50AF20EE1C253C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special use permit</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue a special use permit for a period of 10 years for the placing, if necessary, and maintenance of a covered flagpole at Kyhv Peak Lookout Point—</text> <paragraph id="H3F02731DC399480C8B47A77BC1E8ECDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to Robert S. Collins of Provo, Utah; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9F60C34873AC4631A722CAD706627840"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the individual described in paragraph (1) declines such permit, to a qualified person in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13F9373FE5D64AD7A0A8CDA03BB38A3D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection and issuance</header> <paragraph id="H46226760EB5E4760B6566CC1FA75ACEB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b)(1), to be eligible to be selected for a special use permit under this section, a qualified person shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H384DEBD3A454454B92693C4233EC799B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority of issuance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b)(1), in selecting a qualified person to receive a special use permit under this section, the Secretary shall prioritize the following qualified persons:</text> <subparagraph id="H52AA18EBF17241EC8D7765D24947832C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>First, a qualified person that held a special use permit issued under this section for the preceding 10-year period.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H338EFDE411514C3AB6B9F9CEB7C35514"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Second, a qualified person that the prior special use permit holder identifies.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD92C45A9B28942619C61A84F1BF1AF2E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Third, any other qualified person that submits an application under paragraph (1) that the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H050DAF2567F44ABFB0360EE4E6422814"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may impose such terms and conditions on a holder of a special use permit under this section as the Secretary determines necessary to ensure the proper care and maintenance of a covered flagpole.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19389F057FCC4B69B122DE02217B614F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Land use fee exemption</header><text>The Secretary shall not assess any land use fees with respect to a special use permit issued under this section.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB785CB67A2B9488788BEE02590E18F4C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Notice of application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall publish notice of the availability of any special use permit under this section on the website of the Forest Service and in a local Utah County, Utah, newspaper of record.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7904E0F832044634ABA6A4C93F64F851"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Subsequent special use permits</header> <paragraph id="H630BDC89E681493F9086CBF627E6BBB0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall renew or issue a new 10-year special use permit not later than 180 days after the date that is the earliest of the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H4684785FEBB749D79CDB8297A992FF1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The date that is 10 years after the date on which the Secretary issued the preceding permit.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBCFABF880A2D4B1E882E5F3420585587"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The date on which the holder of the current special use permit requests termination of such permit.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1689C5E452DD4744A369E2E10533F873"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The date on which a special use permit is subject to early termination under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H661A174870214277A5721BF96BB5D8C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Early termination</header><text>If the Secretary determines that the holder of a special use permit under this section is not in compliance with the terms and conditions relating to such permit under subsection (c)(3), the Secretary may terminate the special use permit.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA78BD87B17D0428D80BE195FE6B958D9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitation on holders of special use permit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A holder of a special use permit under this section shall not accept anything of value in exchange for identifying a person under subsection (c)(2)(B).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2BE9C3BAC7014E5BA8159B00F08517AB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Applicability of NEPA</header><text>The National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) shall not apply to the issuance, renewal, or administration of a special use permit under this section, including any activities associated with the placing, maintenance, or removal of a covered flagpole at Kyhv Peak Lookout Point.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HB517DB41B37E4EFDA9F8DF591AD81608"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Access</header><text>The Secretary may authorize reasonable access to Kyhv Peak Lookout Point for the purpose of exercising rights under a special use permit issued under this section, subject to conditions necessary to protect public safety and natural resources.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill>

