<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H91D83F68C24D456D8CDAAA8C0FBAC47D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4744 IH: Community Mental Wellness and Resilience Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4744</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to promote mental wellness and resilience and prevent and heal mental health, behavioral health, and psychosocial conditions through developmentally and culturally appropriate community programs, and award grants for the purpose of establishing, operating, or expanding community-based mental wellness and resilience programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAA73FBD0D9D94474B01CB9BD0402C220" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H544536AE3C0F4E0F856252FAE635E173" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community Mental Wellness and Resilience Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE92AF20A04F54A97A56DD42468E045BC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program for community mental wellness and resilience programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title III of the Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 317V (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b-24">42 U.S.C. 247b–24</external-xref>) the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H15011D7769744D70B68FA9C996384C4E" style="OLC">
<section id="HB7B1969F26E946E7BB9C3EAE15B001F9"><enum>317W.</enum><header>Grant program for community mental wellness and resilience programs</header>
<subsection id="H67EBC158F011422A98205F9060951FEF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header>
<paragraph id="H2DD31B9A7A074FABBBD59D4D9DFFE7E2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Planning grants</header>
<subparagraph id="H8689115357CD455BAF8F72C335928614"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Awards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award grants to eligible organizations—</text> <clause id="H40053396EACE4C8F8826A70EDF89B6E0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to organize a mental wellness and resilience coordinating network;</text></clause>
<clause id="H0BD8695B0628452081A4C1E49D82A640"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to perform assessments of need with respect to community mental wellness and resilience; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB0C870078E384252B9DA0A941E985D83"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to prepare an application for a grant under paragraph (2).</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H715972D41378402C87E20458871B20BC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of a grant under subparagraph (A), with respect to any eligible organization seeking such a grant shall not exceed $250,000.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA381153B960E471B9CDBB359958A71B5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Eligible organization defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph, the term <quote>eligible organization</quote> means an organization that—</text>
<clause id="HAD0BB7C0E4F048C19681F5898A747F27"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a nonprofit or community-based entity eligible to be a part of the resilience coordinating network (as defined in subsection (c)); and</text></clause> <clause id="H5D54DC06B1074CE985EA1A241A960978"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has documented support from at least 3 other such entities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF9EDC778EAAB461C9D0C25F719DE5E66"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program grants</header>
<subparagraph id="H830C94A464184BD1A68EF6FEC1E7438F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Awards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out a program of awarding grants to mental wellness and resilience coordinating networks, on a competitive basis, for the purpose of establishing, operating, or expanding community mental wellness and resilience programs.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4232C5F4731842CE9A5114920A266902"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of a grant under subparagraph (A) shall not exceed $500,000 each year over a period not to exceed four years.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H903C36640C7D483985FB2738BD0C2F7E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rural set aside</header>
<clause id="H1CFB7DB294EC4A098DC973BC3F926A7B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Of the funds appropriated to carry out this section for a fiscal year, 20 percent of such funds shall be reserved to award grants to community mental wellness and resilience programs in rural areas.</text></clause> <clause id="H1FD6880BC7AF4B17B149450CC8AA5C5B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Rural area described</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), a rural area is a region outside of an urban or suburban area.</text></clause>
<clause id="H8D171EEE522346BB868E0F2D096D8290"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>For purposes of clause (ii), a rural area may include individuals and organizations from multiple towns in the county or region involved.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7765BDD6FCB8432D919013736AC08E3D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A program carried out using funds awarded under subsection (a)(2) shall take a public health approach to mental health prevention and promotion, using the best available evidence, to strengthen the entire community’s psychological and emotional wellness and resilience, including by—</text>
<paragraph id="H8B3C647383874728B59B23555CACAB3A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collecting and analyzing information from residents of the community as well as quantitative data to identify—</text> <subparagraph id="H499BBCF758C94DDC92C50938ADDC9F2E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">protective factors that enhance and sustain the community’s capacity for mental wellness and resilience; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H80A1892432354F56B7166D493011EB37"><enum>(B)</enum><text>risk factors that undermine such capacity;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC032505872424238845C835A046FFB8B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>strengthening such protective factors and addressing such risk factors;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB4402054615E4A88AC77BE98A73521CF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>building awareness, skills, tools, and leadership in the community to—</text> <subparagraph id="HD0FD8F4A34A24D7D95B23D749248DBB3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facilitate using a public health approach to mental health; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD2067AB938A5410798411CC6C8E87DD1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">detect, prevent, and heal mental health, behavioral health, and psychosocial conditions among all adults and youth; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BDCB461BCF44E4E89D6CC32A445BCC5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>developing, implementing, and continually evaluating and improving a comprehensive strategic plan for carrying out the activities described in paragraphs (1), (2) and (3) that includes utilizing developmentally, linguistically, and culturally appropriate evidence-based, evidence-informed, promising-best, or indigenous practices for—</text>
<subparagraph id="HB3FD12CC130D4663880BD34F45971E3B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engaging residents in building social connections, including across cultural, geographic, and economic boundaries;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4E197E37E4CA4C9E8122CEBB5FAC02FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enhancing local economic, social, and environmental conditions, including with respect to the built environment;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H31F999270BC14C1D80235736784F4F1D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>becoming trauma-informed and learning simple self-administrable mental wellness and resilience skills;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4EFA224E57894F16ACC21353BB2F0429"><enum>(D)</enum><text>engaging in community activities that strengthen mental wellness and resilience;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H87ACBC4887974398AD1DAB7127CE88AC"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">partaking in nonclinical group and community-minded prevention and recovery programs; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4845B6A03F4146FFB5244339462E7CDD"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other activities to promote mental wellness and resilience and prevent or heal individual and community traumas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H1A997F9D44CB4AE3A9D1159C38889838"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Resilience coordinating network</header>
<paragraph id="HAB00BDC7295E470E96865CB7890C9DBA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>resilience coordinating network</quote> means a network that is composed of 1 or more representatives from at least 5 of the categories listed in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H370D06F34912448CBADDE887AE5B092E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Categories</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The categories listed in this paragraph are the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="HFB2D1C7927564E41B99A190FAB1AB25E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grassroots groups, community-based organizations, neighborhood associations, and volunteer civic organizations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4FAFCDAFE1AD4FC488FBB02663175771"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Elementary and secondary schools, high-needs schools, institutions of higher education, including community colleges, job-training programs, and other education or training agencies or organizations.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEE74B707675D44219DF3B5D296BFC6D7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Youth serving organizations, such as youth after-school and summer programs.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H352C7CB6E40847108B01033C8F0E369B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Parental, family, and early childhood education programs.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4ADF9B9BEAF84C4498EFB3969AD327D7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Faith and spirituality organizations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H512DF7CA9CC04C6DB756E77A9233F0B0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Senior care organizations.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0C5443F5E6B64BB8A54DDDAB53F9632F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Climate change mitigation and adaptation, and environmental conservation, groups and organizations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H77B3E027B151426D9A474FE8708EB9A0"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Social and environmental justice groups and organizations.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF03922616913426E85809FB7CCCAA794"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Disaster preparedness and emergency response groups and organizations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAC62AF88F66648C4B6E8B3543AA54F52"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Businesses and business associations.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H642EAA14C7A74AE8A9298BC22D90488F"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Police, fire, and other agencies and organizations involved with community safety, security, and the justice system.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCEC165FFFC5D41D9B41D38ED352EC588"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Social work, mental health, behavioral health, substance use, physical health, public health, and other professionals, groups, organizations, agencies, and institutions in the human health and social services fields.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAD82B49C9C6943AFB19470C13EC66357"><enum>(M)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The general public, including individuals who have experienced adverse mental health or behavioral health conditions who can represent and engage with populations and sectors relevant to the community.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4D64A39CC9874CBB98FE4950840EF003"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide, directly or through grants to, or contracts with public or private entities, to eligible organizations and resilience coordinating networks technical assistance—</text>
<paragraph id="H0A299CF2998340F49F27A393F65384F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in developing applications for grants under paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE90E752B8F124864A18CEEF5D98F5411"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by sharing best practices learned from resilience coordinating networks.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB29CC4FB459D44B4A056E1E7DFA060AC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header>
<paragraph id="HF35417BF81614BA1BA38385EDD1151C3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31, 2030, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Congress on the results of the grants under subsection (a)(1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94A962E58B5248CA867F81FF0886C6F7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such report shall include a summary of the best practices used by grantees in establishing, operating, or expanding community mental wellness and resilience programs, and the outputs and outcomes achieved.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB206BA69B57A490BBD09548AB477A460"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H60D595869B57416A82B72A9BE9056825" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>public health approach to mental health</term> refers to methods that—</text>
<subparagraph id="HAEB64CAEC90741148E4E302A694EBB3E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">take a population-level approach to promote mental wellness and resilience to prevent problems before they emerge, intervene before they become more severe, and heal them when they do appear, not merely treating individuals one at a time after symptoms of pathology appear; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H26F5DC7620394A7B882741F6B3C895E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>address mental health and psychosocial problems by—</text>
<clause id="HD46595B6E4D34A5F972CBEBF1CAA69AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying and strengthening existing protective factors, and forming new ones, that buffer people from and enhance their capacity for psychological, emotional, and behavioral wellness and resilience for adversities;</text></clause> <clause id="HF7C8A6978F7B49CBB48865FB5B2F5D78"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">taking a holistic systems perspective that recognizes that most mental health, behavioral health, and psychosocial conditions result from numerous interrelated personal, family, social, economic, and environmental factors that require multipronged community-based interventions; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HC8F59CD5959941F8A85026BEE3371E2A" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">using the best available evidence to take action and implement strategies that support mental health prevention and recovery efforts.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6257F1C5016E480AAECE1F96F2B3C473"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>community</term> means people, groups, and organizations that reside in or work within a specific geographic area, such as a city, neighborhood, subdivision, or urban, suburban, or rural locale.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H116575D159C74106BBC2A339690F428E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community trauma</term> means a traumatic event or events that are shared by a community and that have lasting adverse effects on the health and well-being of the community.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1042CD37BEEC47AC87FAA2788C13728C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>protective factors</term> means strengths, skills, resources, and characteristics that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H022CB3C2D94D43B7A840044E9BC9FC81"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are associated with a lower likelihood of negative outcomes of adversities; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD78A897FC7FC4695AACCDA333DF2520E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reduce the impact on people of toxic stresses or a traumatic experience.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H45E609E61F4944F3BD299F5F850EDD3E" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>mental wellness</term> means a state of well-being in which an individual experiences positive emotional functioning, pursues self-defined goals, establishes and maintains meaningful relationships, and feels a sense of meaning and purpose. At the individual level, well-being is based on fundamental family, social, cognitive, and emotional skills and supports that help individuals react, cope, and adapt in healthy ways to stress, uncertainty, adversity, trauma, and change. At the community level, well-being is influenced by the social, economic, educational, and environmental factors and conditions that either enhance or diminish well-being within the community.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1B1D0B542FE940B59E3B8DD5E45CBFA7" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>psychosocial problem</term> refers to social and environmental structures and processes that adversely effect and influence an individual’s mental state or community health.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H85862C1ED25A42C5B215FC95DBC90005"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The term <term>resilience</term> means that people develop cognitive, psychological, emotional, and behavioral capabilities and social connections that enable them to calm their body, mind, emotions, and behaviors during toxic stresses or traumatic experiences in ways that enable them to—</text> <subparagraph id="HA5395544BDCC420493F021E6CD2A44D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>respond without negative consequences for themselves or others; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF38AC65FC56444B5B8A48586B76B0665"><enum>(B)</enum><text>use the experiences as catalysts to develop a constructive new sense of meaning, purpose, and hope.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20755145FAFB40909EBFAAC90B180272"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>toxic stress</term> means exposure to prolonged, severe, and stressful situations with no period of recovery or support.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD9496412005647E68D01BF31BDE5F9C6"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
<paragraph id="H56D982EBE0604BEC82B970449156B22D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $36,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2025 through 2029.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBA819C2756C429AB0F7DF4968780586"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amount made available to carry out this section for a fiscal year, not more than 5 percent of such funds may be used to carry out subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

