<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4C89203A9B564D9CAB4B5CBA65ABB517" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 319 IH: Recognizing the contributions of Clela Rorex, pioneering county clerk who advanced civil rights for all couples seeking to be married in 1975.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 319</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the contributions of Clela Rorex, pioneering county clerk who advanced civil rights for all couples seeking to be married in 1975.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Clela Ann Rorex was born in Denver on July 23, 1943, to Ruby Rorex, a dance and theater teacher, and Cecil Rorex, who served as Clerk of Routt County, Colorado, for 30 years, where Clela grew up in Steamboat Springs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Clela earned her bachelor’s degree from the University of Colorado Boulder in 1973 and a master’s degree in Public Administration from the University of Colorado Denver in 1981;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Clela, at the age of 31, became Boulder County Clerk and Recorder in January 1975;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1975, when a same-sex couple requested a marriage license in Boulder County, Clela consulted the assistant district attorney and learned that Colorado State laws did not specifically prohibit granting a marriage license to a same-sex couple;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as a newly elected county clerk, Clela issued a marriage license to Dave McCord and Dave Zamora, the first marriage license issued to a same-sex couple in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Clela was quoted in 2016 as saying, <quote>After having been so deeply involved in the women’s rights movements, who was I to then deny a right to anyone else? It wasn’t my job to legislate morality.</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, over the next month, Clela issued five more marriage licenses to same-sex couples;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas national news outlets circulated Clela’s groundbreaking story, after which she reported receiving a deluge of death threats and condemnation in hundreds of letters and phone calls to the Boulder County Clerk’s office;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Clela issued marriage licenses to six same-sex couples in Boulder County, Colorado, in April 1975, 40 years before the Supreme Court legalized same-sex marriage nationwide in 2015;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2014, a series of court rulings cleared the way for same-sex marriages in Colorado;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, despite the threats and for decades, Clela continued her advocacy efforts on behalf of the LGBTQ community including marching, volunteering, and donating to LGBTQ efforts;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Clela was 78 years old when she died on June 19, 2022, in Longmont, Colorado;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas due to her advocacy for human rights, Boulder County, Colorado, declared July 23, 2022, as <quote>Clela Rorex Day</quote>; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Clela should be recognized for her leadership as a national civil rights leader, paving the way for countless individuals: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H137326E4B4FA436E81B1E81C415EE88A"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HD3483E4EFF694FD5912C26FF8B1A9445"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H18CA8FD51B8F42438B0D5E7E68BC7634"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes—</text><subparagraph id="H48569770C4FE4D409BF3A69C4A481842"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the contributions of Clela Rorex as a pioneer for civil rights and same-sex marriage;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87190E9F99B042598479ACA62ACBA8F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the respect and bravery Clela had when issuing the first same-sex marriage license in the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3ADF760DA9A14BADB11A2AAD85F79655"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the courage Clela exhibited following the threats she received when she issued marriage licenses to same-sex couples; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC791C10D38E42579C986E6D010168E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses support for the designation of <quote>Clela Rorex Day</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

