<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25B52-DRH-31-CYX"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2236 IS: Young African Leaders Initiative Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2236</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250710">July 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a comprehensive United States Government initiative to build the capacity of young leaders and entrepreneurs in Africa, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="idfa4b999f-fa21-4487-82c0-bfa1fa7dfc5d" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short titles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Young African Leaders Initiative Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>YALI Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id83695585bc944749b4120b83311532af" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="iddd78ac4563594ed6a2ce58f400ca7b80" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Young African Leaders Initiative, launched in 2010, is a signature effort to invest in the next generation of African leaders;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id66dd052039704b7da3a5e446a96e6446" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Africa is a continent of strategic importance and it is vital for the United States to support strong and enduring partnerships with the next generation of African leaders;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida4174d98c13c4551bb1220c9e061b642" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States Government should prioritize investments to build the capacity of emerging young African leaders in sub-Saharan Africa, including through efforts that—</text><subparagraph id="idcc5ed94a3def4be0836925d7d73b3717" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enhance leadership skills;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3690ddfe1dc84d2d9db01b494191da16" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>encourage entrepreneurship;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8d18331dc03342ddbd780079c673d5f7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>strengthen public administration and the role of civil society;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id95063b12b8c74bd2a19b9bbcd39116e7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>enhance peace and security in their respective countries of origin and across Africa; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2e22cbaa29e640ddad2a5532d6470d79" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><text>connect young African leaders continentally and globally across the private, civic, and public sectors;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf3402194f0e342bead36087bdf468281" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>youth in Africa have a positive impact on efforts to foster economic growth, improve public sector transparency and governance, and counter extremism, and should be an area of focus for United States outreach on the African continent; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id88ce4454e42a41a18c2edf61a6081162" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Secretary of State should—</text><subparagraph id="idd4c736174218415aab9532a6d77b62e7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increase the number of fellows from Africa participating in the Mandela Washington Fellowship above the estimated 700 fellows who participated during fiscal year 2024; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideaf0ae4257bc4f5fb8cb9c6994af6b45" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify additional ways to connect YALI alumni to United States public and private resources and institutions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id02003aceed5745b090e5f6b63294be5c" changed="not-changed"><enum>3.</enum><header>Young African Leaders Initiative program</header><subsection id="id2d6c91af77ec4e20a6456104ead6bca5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established the Young African Leaders Initiative (referred to in this section as <quote>YALI</quote>), which shall be carried out by the Secretary of State.</text></subsection><subsection id="id22911fe6d75e4ce8ba0f9246a294f999" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>YALI shall seek to build the capacity of young African leaders in sub-Saharan Africa in the areas of business, civic engagement, or public administration, including through efforts that—</text><paragraph id="idff4d89055c3c47fd997ad3d42292919b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support young African leaders by offering professional development, training, and networking opportunities, particularly in the areas of leadership, innovation, civic engagement, elections, human rights, entrepreneurship, good governance, peace and security, and public administration; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idecce06d2d7c14e83b0642cad1302d883" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide increased economic and technical assistance to young African leaders to promote economic growth, strengthen ties between United States and African businesses, build resilience to predatory lending practices, and improve capacity in key economic areas such as tendering, bidding, and contract negotiations, budget management and oversight, anti-corruption, and establishment of clear policy and regulatory practices.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id63dab4bd031a4ef2b82e1fd2effe65f4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Fellowships</header><paragraph id="idd30cae3c075f4123bbef6eae9d258389" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>YALI shall support the participation in the United States in the Mandela Washington Fellowship for Young African Leaders of fellows from Africa who—</text><subparagraph id="ida3f7b955017c459f9eca8d30aca010bb" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are between 25 and 35 years of age;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5d6b195e369f4d8a95ca9224763966c0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have demonstrated strong capabilities in entrepreneurship, innovation, public service, and leadership; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id065471f1f1964b2cab24519211034f20" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>have had a positive impact in their communities, organizations, or institutions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idba23e9ff9c734698895b3f872bf077a7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Oversight</header><text>The fellowships described in paragraph (1) shall be overseen by the Secretary of State through the Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4433e9f181b545178d606fd53bfcfd7c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>The Secretary of State shall establish and publish—</text><subparagraph id="id8a2848f5e33044b5ac7a7a4bbd5046a3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>eligibility criteria for participation as a fellow under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddc64f886d97c44be8b8aceb2079305ea" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>criteria for determining which eligible applicants will be selected.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id793dc4e2237340fc8aa98e615069afdb" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reciprocal exchanges</header><text>Subject to the approval of the Secretary of State, United States citizens may—</text><paragraph id="id4a201097866e427586761505b1506024" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>engage in reciprocal exchanges in connection with alumni of the fellowship described in subsection (c); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9d3c3ed40eee46fc8a75da474ef82982" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>collaborate on projects with such fellowship alumni.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idcce9ea6acfeb4432b802bd8cc46dbf5b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regional leadership centers and networks</header><text>The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall establish—</text><paragraph id="id7055c6f6ed4f4b5ea13a7fe932f61958" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not fewer than 4 regional leadership centers in sub-Saharan Africa to offer in-person and online training throughout the year on business and entrepreneurship, civic leadership, and public management to young African leaders who—</text><subparagraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idead09003aeb84196b316c2a6be276390"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are between 18 and 35 years of age;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id671a26a87c0941a7a20c00adddf48202"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have demonstrated strong capabilities in entrepreneurship, innovation, public service and leadership, and peace-building and conflict resolution; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id54cc56b809304dee960f076b9b9709c2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have had a positive impact in their communities, organizations, or institutions; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide93fe778c9e64009ba095b71f138c4f0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an online network that provides information and courses on, and connections with leaders in, the private and public sectors of Africa.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0313dd2d424a4435aa0e7712edfcf3d5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Activities</header><paragraph id="ide3ec91aaebd24276ae698448d2ceccd3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>United states-based activities</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the heads of relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall oversee all United States-based activities carried out under YALI, including—</text><subparagraph id="id91dcd11fce7c4b9294a20b053dec4247" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the participation of Mandela Washington Fellows in a 6-week Leadership Institute at a United States educational institution in business, civic engagement, or public management, including academic sessions, site visits, professional networking opportunities, leadership training, community service, and organized cultural activities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7eaae909780549808a15745229f4907c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the participation by Mandela Washington fellows in an annual Mandela Washington Fellowship Summit, to provide such Fellows the opportunity to meet with United States leaders from the private, public, and nonprofit sectors.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3dd500a6fe2048529a6393825d7949a2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Africa-based activities</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator for the United States Agency for International Development and the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, should continue to support YALI activities in sub-Saharan Africa, including—</text><subparagraph id="id939a9a8b685f4b76ab64d95003351dad" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>continued leadership training and other professional development opportunities for Mandela Washington Fellowship for Young African Leaders alumni upon their return to their home countries, including online courses, technical assistance, and access to funding;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8b000b351f77400094e9db26284b678f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>training for young African leaders at regional leadership centers established pursuant to subsection (e), and through online and in-person courses offered by such centers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1c7aad0b35e04b29b5e290380d8203a8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>opportunities for networking and engagement with—</text><clause id="id0b9f14531a1945b8836ccf662edba63d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>alumni of the Mandela Washington Fellowship for Young African Leaders;</text></clause><clause id="id191d2e95f71e482f937e2fc88e407bcf" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>alumni of programs at regional leadership centers established pursuant to subsection (e);</text></clause><clause id="id443faa8ede9e4fcd87f9de66a0be66c5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>United States and like-minded diplomatic missions, business leaders, and others as appropriate; and</text></clause><clause id="id788ce7585cc942fcb895f7f4c836efb5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>where practicable and appropriate, other United States-funded regional leadership programs, including the Young Southeast Asian Leaders Initiative (YSEALI), the Young Leaders of the Americas Initiative (YLAI), the Young Pacific Leaders (YPL), and the Young Transatlantic Innovation Leaders Initiative (YTILI), and through Department of State programs such as the Community Engagement Exchange Program and other initiatives.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4a149029849a4f0da6f41e30f84e5f20" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development and the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall carry out this subsection by seeking to partner with the private sector—</text><subparagraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76adbf079e214e59ad8bc2ec12a9e0de"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to pursue public-private partnerships;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc7ffa9c48b1644188cb5b14083d50ee6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to leverage private sector expertise;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8635108882042f0b6f48ab49091e688"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to expand networking opportunities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id329d91ce3c14446483fd6477f9430906"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to identify funding opportunities and fellowship and employment opportunities for YALI.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7588ff50cde341229309041d2ffc02c7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Implementation plan</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development and the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall submit a plan to the appropriate congressional committees for implementing YALI, including—</text><paragraph id="idbcbe798458dd429db375e4035e22c0a9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of clearly defined program goals, targets, and planned outcomes for each year and for the duration of implementation of the program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf2b9aeace9c04a5a9ef59b412ddd92fa" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a strategy to monitor and evaluate the program and progress made toward achieving such goals, targets, and planned outcomes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8c1862b329924fbaa78f9ceebed5d0de" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a strategy to ensure the program is promoting United States foreign policy goals in Africa, including ensuring that the program is clearly branded, paired with robust public diplomacy efforts, and incorporates diversity among participants as practicable, including countries and communities in Africa facing economic distress, civil conflict, marginalization, and other challenges.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id128e3e1d6fe8493780b0256904c176b7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for the following 4 years, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees, and publish in a publicly accessible, internet-based form, a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="idd3218116b3254f678e4f26b812389975" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the progress made toward achieving the goals, targets, and planned outcomes described in subsection (g)(1), including an overview of the program implemented in the previous year and an estimated number of beneficiaries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0b40d55aa1ec459d9b1bc18c3c75f779" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assessment of how YALI is contributing to and promoting United States-Africa relations, particularly in areas of increased private sector investment, trade promotion, support to civil society, improved public administration, promoting peace and security, and fostering entrepreneurship and youth empowerment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id65d59b25915d43de8da2a257544bdb7b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations for improvements or changes to YALI and the implementation plan, if any, that would improve their effectiveness during subsequent years of YALI’s implementation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id04a209d57bce48ee98a8089c8d9e369d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>for the first report submitted under this subsection, an assessment of the feasibility of expanding YALI to Morocco, Algeria, Tunisia, Libya, and Egypt.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id13e70a4432c042e6a3e763b2bd29634d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="idd99c4c2d04f44696a9290840947f6a2d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id48cbc5a31c034476a5498694d7b14999" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id99d103d63bd64896b0a66d8ff1b16565" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id50878a88128f4058925b59197e5ba3f3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfcc14371ff3744f698cb8c62aaa9419f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall cease to have effect on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

