<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4063C93A452D4E3CADB47EC4028FCE49" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1845 IH: TAP Promotion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1845</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to include, in the Transition Assistance Program, a presentation that promotes the benefits available to veterans under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA66B1A747CBB48CABB6AF80989D32BFA" style="OLC"><section id="H940807DC313F4D579B210ECB5AFD9CFE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>TAP Promotion Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDED216320A2B4C83BD188C5471BF913D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transition assistance program: presentation in preseparation counseling to promote benefits available to veterans</header><subsection id="HD888CD3B126E41D4AF263088B26AFC48"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1142(b) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="HAFA23E8899E4404AB975DECD295CF5FD" style="USC"><paragraph id="H03FA901EFCAC4CCB9D51954947FE66B2"><enum>(20)</enum><text>A presentation that promotes the benefits available to veterans under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs. Such presentation—</text><subparagraph id="HB1FD52F49D72414898B208F106D0897E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be standardized;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB70D3DA642C4574951A23D895E66A14"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall, before implementation, be reviewed and approved by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs in collaboration with veterans service organizations that provide claims assistance under the benefits delivery at discharge program of the Department of Veterans Affairs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10D233BEFF9344829BA01EBC9558F279"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall be submitted by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives for review at least 90 days before implementation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8E00EC29BA749F6BBE3D8F8BCD2FB7C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>where available, shall be presented with the participation of—</text><clause id="H4132394B6C7B4D5FBD375C7FAD189B28"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a representative of a veterans service organization recognized under section 5902 of title 38; or</text></clause><clause id="H28BF778E064348178449B8C12132B7F4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an individual—</text><subclause id="H2DA6929328CB433B8EA893A5C7B2A17E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>recognized under section 5903 of such title; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HC06060B8D93A4D95934C4E59EBF115B6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>authorized by the Secretary concerned to so participate;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A387CF161714D0DA1D234B8B99FEBBA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>shall include information on how a veterans service organization may assist the member in filing a claim described in paragraph (19);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AC7D093B92D4518B05B19A56394D638"><enum>(F)</enum><text>may not encourage the member to join a particular veterans service organization; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66F968706C97468DAB985F27E9CC6C24"><enum>(G)</enum><text>may not be longer than one hour.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HB3DEC60061DF4CA6869BC42685FB94AE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not less frequently than once each year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit, to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives, and to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives, a report that—</text><paragraph id="H2A33C9F4B15F493D8C995692CF64D1B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies each veterans service organization that participated in a presentation under paragraph (20) of section 1142(b) of title 10, United States Code, as added by subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0D9522B5D2B41138B4A63809982469B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>contains the number of members of the Armed Forces who attended such presentations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE29D64133F1F42CE83746082C062B885"><enum>(3)</enum><text>includes any recommendations of the Secretary regarding changes to such presentation or to such paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

