<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA25432-N1T-NR-JLM" key="G"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 259 ATS: Recognizing June 2, 2025, as the 39th anniversary of C-SPAN chronicling democracy in the Senate.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 259</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250602">June 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><action><action-date date="20250618">June 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Committee discharged; considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing June 2, 2025, as the 39th anniversary of C-SPAN chronicling democracy in the Senate.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, for nearly 4 decades, Cable-Satellite Public Affairs Network (C-SPAN) has served as an essential conduit between the United States Senate and the American public;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since its launch on June 2, 1986, the channel C-SPAN2 has offered uninterrupted, unfiltered access to the debates, votes, and deliberations of the Senate;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, over the course of 39 years, C-SPAN2 has recorded more than 43,830 hours of Senate sessions, capturing more than 169,000 speeches that span the spectrum of political thoughts, policy debates, and personal testimony;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these recordings preserve the voices of 359 different Senators, including 185 Republicans, 167 Democrats, and 7 Independents, across nearly 4 decades of service;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas C-SPAN2 has documented more than 23,493 roll call votes, each a building block of American law and policy, a living ledger of Senate decision-making;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas C-SPAN operates without public funding or government oversight;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the continued availability and success of C-SPAN is due to the funding provided by cable and satellite television operators in the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas all television providers, including streaming services, should make delivery of C-SPAN a priority so Americans can watch Congress in action, in real time: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate recognizes—</text><paragraph id="idb82b2057218540eeb2e2a13cc03ed911"><enum>(1)</enum><text>June 2, 2025, as the 39th anniversary of C-SPAN chronicling democracy in the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3eba65b34c614f8480f3bab58f4acd58"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the importance of continuous Senate coverage for all Americans and the need for live coverage to be accessible on all platforms.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

