<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF44BBBA213424116BDA9A23F586E2D34" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 324 IH: Raising awareness of esophageal cancer by expressing support for the designation of April 2025 as “Esophageal Cancer Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 324</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Raising awareness of esophageal cancer by expressing support for the designation of April 2025 as <quote>Esophageal Cancer Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas esophageal cancer is the fastest increasing cancer among American men; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas esophageal cancer is 1 of the fastest growing cancer diagnoses among all Americans, increasing more than 700 percent in recent decades; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas esophageal cancer kills 1 American every 36 minutes every day; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas esophageal cancer is among the deadliest of cancers, with only about 1 in 5 patients surviving 5 years; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas esophageal cancer has tripled in incidence among younger Americans in recent decades; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas esophageal cancer has low survival rates because it is usually discovered at advanced stages when treatment outcomes are poor; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas esophageal cancer in the United States is most often caused by persistent heartburn or gastroesophageal reflux disease (GERD), yet many who are at risk are unaware of the potential danger GERD can present when it occurs over several weeks or months; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas esophageal cancer can be a silent killer with patients often unaware that the heartburn, cough, hoarse voice, sore throat, chest pain, or other symptoms they suffer can be signs of GERD and are reasons to discuss screening for esophageal cancer with their health care provider;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas esophageal cancer can develop from GERD when fluids from the stomach splash into the esophagus, creating cellular change resulting in a precancerous condition known as Barrett’s esophagus, which can lead to a 30-fold increase in a patient’s risk of developing esophageal cancer; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas raising awareness about esophageal cancer empowers individuals to seek preventive care, recognize symptoms, and pursue early detection strategies;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas survivors, caregivers, medical professionals, and researchers have made tremendous strides in advancing treatment options and improving the quality of life for those affected by the disease;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas designating April as <quote>Esophageal Cancer Awareness Month</quote> will encourage public education efforts, support ongoing research initiatives, and promote early screening and prevention strategies;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas esophageal cancer can be prevented through early detection of its precursor, Barrett’s esophagus, which can be eliminated with curative outpatient techniques; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas research indicates that patients diagnosed with early-stage esophageal cancer have a significantly higher 5-year survival rate of up to 49 percent compared to those diagnosed at later stages, underscoring the critical need for enhanced screening and awareness: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HE03A0666AA494CEBB4233C9768B813F5"><section id="H0A41416B950142EEBAB4286745D83D25" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HD333DED1CE4A4FEC9FF5E5AA3A31E661"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the designation of <quote>Esophageal Cancer Awareness Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98DDE7FBA06A4313A11F4A607E612BAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages the Federal Government, States, localities, nonprofit organizations, and the media to promote awareness of esophageal cancer;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C655FC5C49546DC808579C44C8D061B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of increased funding for research, improved treatment options, and the development of early detection methods for esophageal cancer;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H010EDBA77F624219A4669AF1A596052F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages individuals to learn about risk factors and symptoms of esophageal cancer and to consult health care professionals regarding potential screening options; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA032110BC59E43E9872F1E5C8AD6CF6F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>honors the courage and resilience of individuals affected by esophageal cancer and expresses support for their families and caregivers.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

