<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6AB979632E4A40DD8C53D5BD2B520F9B" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 612 IH: Celebrating 250 years of Army Medicine.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 612</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250725">July 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001051">Mr. Carter of Texas</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Celebrating 250 years of Army Medicine.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on July 27, 1775, the Continental Congress, recognizing that the fight for liberty demanded the preservation of life, established a formal medical service for an army of 20,000, marking the birth of United States Army Medicine led by Dr. Benjamin Church of Boston;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, from the battlefields of the Revolutionary War, where Army surgeons and medical personnel bravely tended to the wounded under the hail of musket fire, to the blood-soaked fields of Gettysburg, where the seeds of modern battlefield medicine were sown, Army Medicine has remained a constant presence, a source of solace and healing amidst the chaos of conflict;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, through the global struggles of the 20th century, the two World Wars, the chilling stalemate of the Cold War, and the jungles of Vietnam, Army medical professionals served with unwavering courage and compassion, facing down unimaginable horrors to save lives and alleviate suffering, their actions a testament to the enduring spirit of humanity amidst the depths of war;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in the face of new and evolving threats presented by the War on Terrorism, Army Medicine has once again risen to the occasion, adapting to the complexities of modern warfare, pioneering cutting-edge trauma care, and ensuring the health and resilience of United States forces deployed around the globe, proving that even in the most challenging of circumstances, their commitment to preserving life never wavers;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, throughout its storied history, Army Medicine has been at the forefront of medical innovation, achieving groundbreaking advancements that have not only revolutionized military medicine but also benefitted humanity as a whole, saving lives from yellow fever to the development of the polio vaccine, and then the development of telemedicine; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the highest ideals of courage, sacrifice, and unwavering dedication to duty are embodied by the 50 heroic individuals serving within the Army Medical Department who have been awarded the Medal of Honor, the Nation’s highest military decoration, their selfless actions in the face of unimaginable danger a testament to the extraordinary lengths to which Army Medicine personnel will go to save the lives of their comrades: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H3B9C6713C58E4E5893AB4C353C0C5461"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H45E1BE79135B4F7C8992323F9CF415F0"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HD8B04B8541DF410686043896629E0F7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>gathers to commemorate the 250th anniversary of the Army Medical Department, a beacon of unwavering dedication, innovation, and selfless service to the brave men and women of the United States Army;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCE091EB414FF4A53854BC483006C9705"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses its profound gratitude to the Army Medical Department for their—</text> <subparagraph id="H1C5622054BE74E639FBD9C5EE943E5BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>unwavering commitment to the health and well-being of United States soldiers, past and present;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9D4BC0B7F9D74B7FB9252B38AACEC2F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>legacy of service, sacrifice, and innovation which continues to inspire; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB75EB5054957458EBA2F947DB667BAAF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>dedication that ensures that the United States Army remains the most ready and capable fighting force in the world; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3DAFB1C22F1947F2B4DED5BD40A67985"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">remembers and honors the countless lives saved and forever changed by the compassionate care of Army Medicine.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

