<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3249B8ECAFDE4BE69F60E739ABF138A7" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 446 IH: Expressing support for the recognition of July 3 through July 10, 2025, as “National Extreme Heat Awareness Week”, a national event educating the public on the dangers of extreme heat and the risks of extreme heat events to public safety, infrastructure, agriculture, and much more, and supporting the goals of a National Extreme Heat Awareness Week.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 446</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250523">May 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the recognition of July 3 through July 10, 2025, as <quote>National Extreme Heat Awareness Week</quote>, a national event educating the public on the dangers of extreme heat and the risks of extreme heat events to public safety, infrastructure, agriculture, and much more, and supporting the goals of a National Extreme Heat Awareness Week.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas National Extreme Heat Awareness Week increases awareness of the risks posed by extreme heat events to public safety, infrastructure, agriculture, and much more;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas National Extreme Heat Awareness Week promotes educational initiatives, encourages community programming, and increases overall knowledge and preparedness;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas extreme heat poses numerous challenges to public health, quality of life, and economic activity;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas extreme heat risk varies by local geography, leading to unique challenges and health risks in regions across the country;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas extreme heat is the leading weather-related cause of death in the Nation;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas studies estimate that more than 1,300 people die in the United States every year as a result of extreme heat exposure, including over 570 in the State of New York and over 750 people in the State of Arizona as of 2024 reporting;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas extreme heat can cause life-threatening conditions among vulnerable populations, such as those who work outside, take part in outdoor activities, or lack refuge in the heat;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, over the 2021–2022 period, the trade, transportation, and utilities industry had 1,420 workplace injuries due to exposure to extreme environmental heat;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas heat-driven reductions in labor productivity cost the United States economy billions of dollars each year;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas more than 60 percent of annual heat-related deaths occur in the month of July;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas extreme heat deaths are largely preventable; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas preventative measures exist to help individuals and communities better weather extreme heat through—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB933246FA7E44556B7A2E360FDEEED85"><enum>(1)</enum><text>public safety campaigns to raise awareness on heat exhaustion, heatstroke, and how to avoid extreme heat exposure;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H62B28E2B07834A76BC000BD39E0B9948"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implementation of new technologies for cooling and heat resilience; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB14F5269FE3C45ECB0429365C20B4072"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improved Federal response to extreme heat, including the declaration of national extreme heat emergencies: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HBAC4F7143DF2473F924416E1E66111AC"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HCE8097330BE34EB1B63F671E23A4B957"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF645E767D44D4CFCB673302000E6B2B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of <quote>National Extreme Heat Awareness Week</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31B297DA76724E21A7F0DB5E13DC8A58"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the continued importance of research and policies to address extreme heat;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H895754D0FF364C07903FAA6B44D31024"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages increased efforts and resources to raise public awareness of the dangers of extreme heat; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0513977A68AD4263A9E59CCAC15F58AE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>invites the people of the United States to observe <quote>National Extreme Heat Awareness Week</quote> with appropriate ceremonies and activities to further raise public awareness of the dangers of extreme heat, through public entities and private organizations and in schools and other suitable places.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

