<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H927841E5740F413B904D3A1E1B23F5DB" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 448 IH: Establishing the Select Committee to Investigate the Cover-Up of President Joseph Robinette Biden, Jr.’s Cognitive and Physical Health Decline.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 448</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250529">May 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Establishing the Select Committee to Investigate the Cover-Up of
      President Joseph Robinette Biden, Jr.’s Cognitive and Physical Health
 Decline.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="OLC" id="HBB615A3F578D46F1B9C71951C247AB7D"><section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="HE44BF60B86804FFCAF94AEA26972BE72"><enum>1.</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is hereby established the Select Committee to Investigate the Cover-Up of President Joseph Robinette Biden, Jr.’s Cognitive and Physical Health Decline (hereinafter referred to as the <quote>Select Committee</quote>).</text></section><section id="H0B94FB6A66A046AC8E6A10F9D1253A33"><enum>2.</enum><header>Composition</header><subsection id="HC5D746A98A5E4D36817399818A31019D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appointment of members</header><text>The Speaker shall appoint 13 Members to the Select Committee, 5 of whom shall be appointed after consultation with the minority leader.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD75605E4AE284107B94402C7EF3545C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation of chair</header><text>The Speaker shall designate one Member to serve as chair of the Select Committee.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1B393A9AF94B4572BDDB729BE70A42F6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>Any vacancy in the Select Committee shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</text></subsection></section><section id="H93FCC54025674E258C33A35814DB3A3B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Functions</header><subsection id="H38903F432AC94FC7930C182C49EBC251"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The functions of the Select Committee are to—</text><paragraph id="HE8D74DCA56A84610807B6029607FB7C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>investigate and report upon the facts of President Joseph Robinette Biden, Jr.’s cognitive and physical health decline and the potential concealment of information from the American public;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91EDFBBB01AB406EB74F77C16E995005"><enum>(2)</enum><text>investigate President Joseph Robinette Biden, Jr.’s cancer diagnosis and whether the President’s administration concealed information from the American public;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H163482DC2E904C1B8AB151921E952869"><enum>(3)</enum><text>examine, investigate, and report on Vice President Kamala Harris, Jill Biden, and others’ roles in the cover up of President Joseph Robinette Biden, Jr.’s cognitive and physical health decline;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E893AE54B76447CA433C29E629A9F92"><enum>(4)</enum><text>investigate and report on the role of fake news and legacy media outlets in spreading false or misleading narratives of President Joseph Robinette Biden, Jr.’s cognitive and physical health;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FF34A8121CB4C158B6584BFFA6EA6B7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>examine President Joseph Robinette Biden, Jr.’s use of autopen for official Presidential acts as well as who was controlling such actions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H159AD9F8DDFA4D62BB93175307796829"><enum>(6)</enum><text>investigate and report on the existence, content, and suppression of Special Counsel Robert Hur’s tapes and related evidence;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FE51A34079C4CA68EF4CD177729A2E0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>examine President Joseph Robinette Biden, Jr.’s mishandling of classified documents; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8CC45B9627B74BF7B8B2EC81CDB2C300"><enum>(8)</enum><text>issue a final report to the House containing such findings, conclusions, and recommendations for corrective measures described as it may deem necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB09E0A3A4725474AAEE32B9228D2D015" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interim reports</header><text>In addition to the final report addressing issued under subsection (a)(7), the Select Committee may report to the House or any committee of the House from time to time the results of its investigations, together with such detailed findings, policy recommendations, and legislative proposals as it may deem advisable.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0DCB65E8FE7E4874AC95C44253B245DD" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><paragraph id="H3C956A217EF043369D43B99052C10D28" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No legislative jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Select Committee shall not have legislative jurisdiction and shall have no authority to take legislative action on any bill or resolution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB61EA0A14EBE48B4A1E43B9564470C9F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Investigative jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sole authority of the Select Committee shall be to investigate and report on President Joseph Robinette Biden, Jr.’s cognitive and physical health decline and the potential concealment of information from the American public, and to make policy recommendations and legislative proposals in response to its investigation and report. The Select Committee may, at its discretion, hold public hearings in connection with any aspect of its investigative functions.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAB15CCAB07A147E28852F23ED7E20CCD" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Staff; funding</header><paragraph id="HC407F541CC8A431BA6C12FFB5F18C4C1" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The appointment and the compensation of staff for the Select Committee shall be subject to regulations issued by the Committee on House Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57404B39F69D4BA7BF946C7328718155" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3BB65DDCE5B541EEB53425F5F7160FCF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Staff of employing entities of the House or a joint committee may be detailed to the Select Committee to carry out this resolution and shall be deemed to be staff of the Select Committee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11A09A784687441FA7595A85BD827433" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Select Committee may request the head of any Federal agency to detail, on a nonreimbursable basis, any of the personnel of the agency to the Select Committee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD433DA769E64C1E8651C49EA1F0CE78" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 202(i) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4301">2 U.S.C. 4301(i)</external-xref>) shall apply with respect to the Select Committee in the same manner as such section applies with respect to a standing committee, except that the selection of any consultant or organization under such section shall be subject to approval by the Speaker.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H75F0EF8122A3493DBA1E3C3D3514D7D8" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Deadlines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Select Committee shall submit all of its reports to the House by December 31, 2025. All policy recommendations and legislative proposals shall be submitted to the relevant standing committees not later than December 31, 2025. The Select Committee shall submit all legislative proposals to the relevant standing committees not later than 30 days after their adoption by the Select Committee.</text></subsection></section><section id="HFD9E60A7AD81468490745C63EDE8680B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Procedure</header><subsection id="H48666B1684904243809FB1C6EEE2029F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Access to information from Intelligence Community</header><text>Notwithstanding clause 3(m) of rule X of the Rules of the House of Representatives, the Select Committee is authorized to study the sources and methods of entities described in clause 11(b)(1)(A) of rule X insofar as such study is related to the matters described in sections 3 and 4.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8058D9D90E0944F3AF7B1360BED5DC00"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of classified information</header><text>Clause 11(b)(4), clause 11(e), and the first sentence of clause 11(f) of rule X of the Rules of the House of Representatives shall apply to the Select Committee.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5F5B02FB592044CB91A506F8F056A77B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability of rules governing procedures of committees</header><text>Rule XI of the Rules of the House of Representatives shall apply to the Select Committee except as follows:</text><paragraph id="HB90A7BBE5B6A455DBE4A98EB7E279041"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Clause 2(a) of rule XI shall not apply to the Select Committee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H910CB8DC08264756B05091C9893DC9BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Clause 2(g)(2)(D) of rule XI shall apply to the Select Committee in the same manner as it applies to the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A4E6C5D09174A13A2E85848DB38F8D4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Pursuant to clause 2(h) of rule XI, two Members of the Select Committee shall constitute a quorum for taking testimony or receiving evidence and one-third of the Members of the Select Committee shall constitute a quorum for taking any action other than one for which the presence of a majority of the Select Committee is required.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F2D36C47959457EA4F39BF49AC8214C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The chair of the Select Committee may authorize and issue subpoenas pursuant to clause 2(m) of rule XI in the investigation and study conducted pursuant to sections 3 and 4 of this resolution, including for the purpose of taking depositions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8149D8B3428465C8AF4218335ADCBBB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The chair of the Select Committee is authorized to compel by subpoena the furnishing of information by interrogatory.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE4E1B37AF2440CC9BA950C7C7F49454"><enum>(6)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H36AFE177363D4F7B9EC2A3F652475A3A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The chair of the Select Committee, upon consultation with the ranking minority member, may order the taking of depositions, including pursuant to subpoena, by a Member or counsel of the Select Committee, in the same manner as a standing committee pursuant to section 3(t) of House Resolution 5, One Hundred Nineteenth Congress.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A26BC4ED8494AC7B74C2F6551007575" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Depositions taken under the authority prescribed in this paragraph shall be governed by the most recent procedures submitted by the chair of the Committee on Rules for printing in the Congressional Record.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB66FDD7518E047578AD501E693297E79"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Subpoenas authorized pursuant to this resolution may be signed by the chair of the Select Committee or a designee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0609F160E5564B9EBA23BC9982E7ABAD"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The chair of the Select Committee may, after consultation with the ranking minority member, recognize—</text><subparagraph id="H6A361B2C3168420688A89CB5F48F4814"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Members of the Select Committee to question a witness for periods longer than five minutes as though pursuant to clause 2(j)(2)(B) of rule XI; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9561DB604194E8B9243D208B1EE5610"><enum>(B)</enum><text>staff of the Select Committee to question a witness as though pursuant to clause 2(j)(2)(C) of rule XI.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF37BA9CC85BE4D8C85E662F9E2E15FAD"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The chair of the Select Committee may postpone further proceedings when a record vote is ordered on questions referenced in clause 2(h)(4) of rule XI, and may resume proceedings on such postponed questions at any time after reasonable notice. Notwithstanding any intervening order for the previous question, an underlying proposition shall remain subject to further debate or amendment to the same extent as when the question was postponed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF25A0F0AB0B4A9B908A67634D75FA5C"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The provisions of paragraphs (f)(1) through (f)(12) of clause 4 of rule XI shall apply to the Select Committee.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H25BE83AF90BA4E239F6D32A8ED0E30EE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Select Committee shall terminate 30 days after filing the final report under section 3(a)(7).</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

