<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAD0BB278BB804ACFAF572BAC4F66FF7E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4864 IH: Ethanol for America Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4864</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250801">August 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000301">Mr. Johnson of South Dakota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000474">Mr. Flood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000446">Mr. Feenstra</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Environmental Protection Agency to finalize a proposed rule with respect to E15 fuel dispenser labeling and compatibility with underground storage tanks with modifications, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H24D7A02AA03C4B00A15267D0242D7262" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD4AB99BFC4874DEB8F1E88AA2F557908" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ethanol for America Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6509928C347F4BCFABE770DBEBC6E6EA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Finalization of proposed rule required</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H40240D3AD385434A8881DB9D6DAA85CF"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H036438700D424448A2FE5237EF4A73B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC0017931A4C4975B3EE5322796285E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Proposed rule</header><text>The term <term>proposed rule</term> means the proposed rule of the Administrator entitled <quote>E15 Fuel Dispenser Labeling and Compatibility with Underground Storage Tanks</quote> (86 Fed. Reg. 5094 (January 19, 2021)).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H66888D40AAB14A9EB9C9264A6BEB5352"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Finalization required</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall finalize the proposed rule in accordance with this section.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H15A16208573F4A4E996563E91169BAEB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>E15 labeling requirements</header><text>In finalizing the proposed rule pursuant to subsection (b) with respect to E15 labeling, the Administrator shall finalize the first co-proposal described in the proposed rule.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H107704466CD14891AC4B1B82B77E4DA6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>E15 compatibility with underground storage tanks</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E5DE295CBBF4A8AA42EE1AC89727B67"><enum>(1)</enum><header>E15 compatibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In finalizing the proposed rule pursuant to subsection (b) with respect to the compatibility of underground storage tanks with fuel blends with up to 15 percent ethanol, the Administrator shall ensure that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9B8278BDF446477C841EB2CB78B583EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>existing underground storage tank systems are deemed to be compliant with fuel blends with up to 15 percent ethanol, regardless of whether the owners or operators of those systems are able to locate installation or compatibility documentation for those systems;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H56E9FA59BC934B73A143D66F7A3E18B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>steel and fiberglass underground storage tanks manufactured after July 2005 and all fiberglass reinforced plastic piping are considered compatible with fuel blends of up to 15 percent ethanol; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H07FEA6C4EC694E36B8FE162615214922"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if owners or operators of underground storage tank systems can demonstrate the compatibility of certain components of those systems (such as gaskets or seals) with fuel blends with up to 15 percent ethanol, those owners or operators are not required to replace other equipment to achieve full system compatibility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H80B1AB1F9E8F4FE5AE64FCEF9CA0004E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Future storage flexibility</header><text>For purposes of ensuring that gasoline and diesel underground storage tank systems have future flexibility in fuel storage, the Administrator, in finalizing the proposed rule pursuant to subsection (b), shall require owners and operators of underground storage tank systems that store motor fuel for on-road vehicles to ensure that those systems and the components of those systems, including components such as pipe dopes and sealants, that are installed or replaced after the effective date of the proposed rule are compatible with fuel blends with up to 100 percent ethanol, regardless of the types of fuel blends currently being stored in those systems.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

