<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H64D2400518BB40AB91EA08BF4834D168" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HRES 115 IH: Supporting the goals and ideals of “Career and Technical Education Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 115</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250205">February 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001051">Mr. Carter of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001314">Mr. Bean of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000600">Ms. Perez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001213">Mr. Steil</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001306">Mr. Balderson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000478">Mr. Fry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000595">Ms. Letlow</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of <quote>Career and Technical Education Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the competitiveness of the United States within the global economy requires workers who are prepared with the requisite academic knowledge and technical and employability skills needed for career success;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 1,700,000 workers annually are projected to leave jobs supporting the infrastructure sector of the United States through 2031, including designing, building, and operating transportation, housing, utilities, and telecommunications, leading to massive replacement needs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas advancements in technology have fundamentally changed critical economic sectors of the United States and the global economy, creating significant, new demand for high-wage, high-quality, and efficient education and training opportunities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas career and technical education (referred to in this preamble as <quote>CTE</quote>) ensures that a competitive and skilled workforce is ready, willing, and capable of holding jobs in high-wage, high-skill, and in-demand career fields;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CTE helps the United States meet the very real and immediate challenges of economic development, student academic achievement, and global competitiveness;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the United States, it is forecast that by 2031 nearly <fraction>1/3</fraction> of all jobs will require some level of postsecondary education but less than a bachelor’s degree;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 11,100,000 students are enrolled in CTE programs across the United States at the secondary and postsecondary levels, with CTE programs in thousands of comprehensive high schools, technical high schools, area technical centers, career academies, and over 1,000 two-year colleges;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CTE aligns with labor market demand and provides employability skills and relevant academic and technical coursework leading to credentials of value for secondary and postsecondary education students and adult learners;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CTE affords students the opportunity to cultivate the knowledge and skills to earn the credentials needed to secure careers in growing, high-demand fields;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas secondary CTE has statistically significant positive impacts on the academic achievement, high school completion, employability skills, and college readiness of students;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to a recent national survey conducted by the Hunt Institute and Lake Research Partners, 94 percent of parents and voters favor increased opportunities for students to access workforce training and related opportunities to cultivate skills needed for a career;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas about 77 percent of employers from in-demand industries report hiring an employee because of knowledge and skills gained from their CTE experience;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2018, Congress affirmed on a wide bipartisan basis the importance of CTE by passing the Strengthening Career and Technical Education for the 21st Century Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/224">Public Law 115–224</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 1563), which supports investment and improvement in secondary and postsecondary CTE programs in all 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, and outlying areas; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas February 23, 2025, marks the 108<superscript>th</superscript> anniversary of the signing of the Act of February 23, 1917 (39 Stat. 929, chapter 114, commonly known as the <quote>Smith-Hughes Vocational Education Act of 1917</quote>), which was the first major Federal investment in secondary CTE and laid the foundation for the bipartisan, bicameral support for CTE that continues as of February 2025: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HE73E4BE4E6AC4C868AE8A18CC7D1C603"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HB8BB94B046D344A2A5B184D184B3C58A"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H62962983F2CF49249128840D87200149"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>Career and Technical Education Month</quote> to celebrate career and technical education across the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEBE5F462D3B4BF29A541E63F8D55B37"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of Career and Technical Education Month;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52927B1E986F4DCD99CFDFBF218BA250"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of career and technical education in preparing a well-educated and skilled workforce in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2CB35E94142416E963D7F37B918C239"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages educators, school counselors, guidance and career development professionals, administrators, and parents to promote career and technical education as a respected educational pathway for students. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

