<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-NEW25811-G2L-03-TFD"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 400 ATS: Expressing support for designation of the week of September 14 through 20, 2025, as “National Adult Education and Family Literacy Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 400</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250917" legis-day="20250916">September 17 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for designation of the week of September 14 through 20, 2025, as <quote>National Adult Education and Family Literacy Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas new data released in December 2024 by the Program for the International Assessment of Adult Competencies reported that nearly 59,000,000 adults in the United States lack the basic literacy, numeracy, and digital skills necessary to succeed at home, in the workplace, and in society;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas data from the 2023 American Community Survey indicated that nearly 21,000,000 adults in the United States lack a high school credential and another 20,000,000 adults in the United States lack adequate English-language skills;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the literacy of the people of the United States is essential for the economic and societal well-being and the national security of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States reaps the economic benefits of individuals who improve their literacy, numeracy, and English-language skills;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas literacy, numeracy, and digital skills are necessary for individuals to fully benefit from the range of opportunities available in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the economy and position of the United States in the world marketplace depend on having a literate, skilled population;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the unemployment rate in the United States is highest among those without a high school diploma or an equivalent credential, demonstrating that education is essential for economic recovery;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the educational skills of the parents of a child and the practice of reading to a child have a direct impact on the educational success of the child;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas parental involvement in the education of a child is a key predictor of the success of a child, and the level of parental involvement in the education of a child increases as the educational level of the parent increases;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas parents who participate in family literacy programs become more involved in the education of their children and gain the tools necessary to obtain a job or find better employment;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as a result of family literacy programs, the lives of children become more stable and the success of children in the classroom and in future endeavors becomes more likely;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas adults need to be part of a long-term solution to the educational challenges faced by the people of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many older individuals in the United States lack the reading, numeracy, or English-language skills necessary to read a prescription and follow medical instructions, which endangers the lives of older individuals and the lives of their loved ones;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many individuals who are unemployed, underemployed, or receive public assistance lack the literacy skills necessary to obtain and retain employment, to continue their education, or to participate in job training and career development programs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many high school dropouts do not have the literacy skills necessary to complete their education, transition to postsecondary education or career and technical training, or obtain work that provides a living wage;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a large portion of individuals in prison have low educational skills, and individuals without educational skills are more likely to return to prison once released;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many immigrants in the United States do not have the literacy skills necessary to succeed in the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas National Adult Education and Family Literacy Week highlights the need to ensure that each individual in the United States has the literacy, numeracy, and digital skills necessary to succeed at home, at work, and in society: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="iddef67870dbb74e59acc86de39c95fc21"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of the week of September 14 through 20, 2025, as <quote>National Adult Education and Family Literacy Week</quote>, to raise public awareness about the importance of adult education, workforce skills, and family literacy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4a906e06470447a8a205ded41d7fafc9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages people across the United States to support programs that assist individuals in need of adult education, workforce skills, and family literacy programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3b997e0fc7e14cf6a91e5eca72427a72"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of adult education, workforce skills, and family literacy programs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3af016921c5040bbb0a2e70939d0579c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>calls on public, private, and nonprofit entities to support increased access to adult education and family literacy programs to ensure a fully literate society.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

