<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-GAI25143-546-W5-M2X"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S452 IS: Barcode Automation for Revenue Collection to Organize Disbursement and Enhance Efficiency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 452</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250206" legis-day="20250205">February 6 (legislative day, February 5), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require electronically prepared tax returns to include scannable code when submitted on paper, and to require the use of optical character recognition technology for paper documents received by the Internal Revenue Service.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Barcode Automation for Revenue Collection to Organize Disbursement and Enhance Efficiency Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BARCODE Efficiency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id2C03A85614634783AB3A36A2BAD77752"><enum>2.</enum><header>Scanning and digitization of tax returns and correspondence</header><subsection commented="no" id="id147F00E5FDA844F68B84BEA898F170CD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Returns prepared electronically and submitted on paper</header><text>With respect to any Federal tax return which is prepared electronically, but is printed and filed on paper—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb6cba7c812f94d42961b5da9bdd6092e"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such return shall bear a code which, when scanned, converts the data included in such return to electronic format, and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id431992c8dc544d5b8368a13873cb0de1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject to subsection (b)(1)(B), the Internal Revenue Service shall use barcode scanning technology to convert the data included in such returns to electronic format.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id131E2EA6FA1D41128123471754ED192E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Optical character recognition software</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc80362c492e34d1cbc2eb30d883ac045"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any Federal tax return which—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e0dcb3116ae4098a298440b1cbcf444"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not prepared electronically and is printed and filed on paper, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc6afd61b6a2444b9b64a5f103b78b5d8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is described in subsection (a)(1) but, for any reason, the data included in such return cannot be accurately converted into electronic format, or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc1bbc49817394433b3c31c21a1b66aa6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any correspondence which is received by the Internal Revenue Service in a paper form (with the exception of any such correspondence which has been received by the Internal Revenue Service in electronic format),</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">the Internal Revenue Service shall use optical character recognition technology (or any functionally similar technology) to transcribe such return or correspondence.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id51FB2898568C4E3196B71799F82F38FC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8469f926f58b471386e26cf8cfc4bc2f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) or (b) shall not apply to the extent that the Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary’s delegate determines that the technology described in such subsection is slower or less reliable than— </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbb1e7e25ddac4391955612ec142942d7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the process of manually transcribing returns or correspondence received in a paper form, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5cfcb12e715e4f9d9d89cf921fc8bb20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other process that the Internal Revenue Service is using or would otherwise use.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4f379384d006454e9730e3c854f1371c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any exception to the application of subsection (a) or (b) pursuant to paragraph (1) shall not take effect unless the Secretary provides a report to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate regarding the determination made by the Secretary under such paragraph within 30 days of such determination.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id98447574E0BB4EDF90B432F6A5F11A20"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall apply to—</text><paragraph id="idF9BBA5D1D34D4A148BDF69C1637EDABE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any individual income tax return (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6011">section 6011(e)(3)(C)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) received on or after January 1 of the first calendar year beginning more than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id184CFA0E497D4679AF09BDFAF08B7071"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any estate tax return (as described in section 6018 of such Code) or gift tax return (as described in section 6019 of such Code) received on or after January 1 of the first calendar year beginning more than 24 months after the date of enactment of this Act, and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd056d4452f61427fb68a9a00997d6c28"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other return or correspondence received on or after January 1 of the first calendar year beginning more than 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

