<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H785A446F034544E0A3356CCBA4C91AF3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3856 IH: Runaway and Homeless Youth and Trafficking Prevention Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3856</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20250610">June 10, 2025</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To reauthorize the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H07782992307A4787A0ED1D13ED5ECD1F" style="OLC"> 
<section commented="no" section-type="section-one" id="H31D66F937EAB4CDB9A49D9D67D67D010"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Runaway and Homeless Youth and Trafficking Prevention Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5FDD64DD8F1B4312BC50BA4FAA9221C8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 302 of the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/11201">34 U.S.C. 11201</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B8EC0FBF0A74AE6AB2686633E946C0E"> 
<section id="H5B1E52E02E7D441AB32EA1B26646DADC"><enum>302.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="H5B0250F455734E0E93BDAB25FA90D225"><enum>(1)</enum><text>youth who have become homeless or who leave and remain away from home without parental permission are at risk of developing, and have a disproportionate share of, trauma, substance use disorders, and serious health, behavioral, social, and emotional challenges because they lack sufficient resources to obtain care and may live on the street for extended periods of time, thereby endangering themselves;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF80BE0F2F3ED4BF6A85B7FC32E2BA041"><enum>(2)</enum><text>many such young people, because of their age and situation, are urgently in need of temporary shelter and services, including services that consider their age, gender, and social and developmental needs, are culturally and linguistically appropriate, and acknowledge the environment of youth seeking these services;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H4B6FC0D797B54A2B9E83302FBB9123A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>research has documented the fluid experiences of homelessness of youth, where many youth experience 2 or more different types of homelessness, including couch surfing, living in motels, and staying on the streets;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HDD75B613FF084FB0BDEC9B0F1241550E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>research has documented that persons who are members of historically marginalized and underserved communities of color, LGBTQ youth, youth who do not complete high school or achieve a high school equivalency, youth involved in the child welfare system, youth who have been involved with the criminal justice system, and pregnant and parenting youth are most likely to experience homelessness in the United States while unaccompanied by a parent or adult;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HC02914A6B52648E28151C31441E2E855"><enum>(5)</enum><text>services to such young people should be developed and provided using a positive youth development approach that ensures a young person a sense of—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H3CABCC7F43BA436AB9D72E7EA2993FDA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>safety and structure;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H0C876488ABF14881A09DC7F174B8A958"><enum>(B)</enum><text>belonging and membership;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H1C4E1B15FD7F48DCA5D692A4F815636F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>self-worth, empowerment, voice, and choice;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HB0ACA5B964174D6190368BD2F1F592A7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>independence and control over one’s life; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H72FD21C2AAB647D28C1A7C4C17E47FB1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>closeness in interpersonal relationships;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A53E6FA63B5496BB4F98B0ACA5B2201"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in view of the interstate nature of the problem, it is the responsibility of the Federal Government to develop an accurate national reporting system to report the prevalence of youth homelessness, and to assist in the development of an effective system of care (including prevention services and aftercare services, short-term housing with services, extended housing with supportive services, and street outreach services) outside the welfare system and the law enforcement system, in collaboration with public assistance systems, the education system, and the child welfare system;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H8C63BD9882BB4317B19C92893A4A633A"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to make a successful transition to adulthood, youth who run away, youth experiencing homelessness, and youth living in the street need a safe and stable place to live, connections to caring adults, and opportunities to complete high school or earn a general equivalency degree, learn job skills, and obtain employment;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D06A306439A42D8AF3444B589E6EB41"><enum>(8)</enum><text>improved coordination and collaboration at the Federal level between programs that serve runaway and homeless youth are necessary for the development of a long-term strategy for responding to the needs of this population;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H6B4E3FBA892E4102A3765E7E7A413CBB"><enum>(9)</enum><text>runaway and homeless youth are at a high risk of substance use disorders and becoming victims of sexual exploitation and trafficking;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HFC537DE5E1E4408CAB19738A25905DDD"><enum>(10)</enum><text>since research has shown that the prevalence of homelessness among youth is similar in rural and urban communities, runaway and homeless youth programs, such as those funded under this title, are integral services that every community should provide, regardless of the size of the community; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H71B6C5775A18471B9CCAA41B242037FD"><enum>(11)</enum><text>runaway and homeless youth programs, such as those funded under this title—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C21EDD5E76F4D39A2D16FA627CF5525"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are expert adolescent service providers and integral community partners for the child welfare and juvenile justice systems as many youth exit these systems to homelessness; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H49EFF24A2D1B4026B68E014367F67961"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">work to reunify youth with their family when safe and appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H8FA084BEBAD34D5EBD4149E356986379"><enum>3.</enum><header>Basic center grant program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part A of the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/11211">34 U.S.C. 11211 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC9D111CF61CC4D0CB377E44AE1DDC6C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 311, by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H89F18325EF064AD38B64EE4D3B9B34A5"> <subsection id="HED4281AAA9D8498CB88742CCEC7EEF62"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants for centers and services</header> <paragraph id="HC3C014AC6007478F8B5B66B72180CDD6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall— </text> 
<subparagraph id="H9526FBEED6DB479580E2C5FF00F09022"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 90 days before the start date of the grant, award 5-year grants to public and nonprofit private entities, and combinations of such entities, to establish, operate, and maintain (including renovate) local centers to provide— </text> <clause id="HCC4BB201D67E4BC8B5CB872A5542A81F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>safe shelter and services for runaway and homeless youth, including trauma-informed services; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAD819367D73A4A418C215E299095C304"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if appropriate, services for the families of such youth, including individuals identified by such youth as family; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8EFAE79CAED44710A0DD2A3BBE215D6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish an appeal process for grantees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H232F391D88174EE2BF8CC46A72EBD029"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Services provided</header><text>Services provided under paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="HC4265A7CB63A4C4CA543D8EDA9841FA6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be provided to runaway youth, street youth, homeless youth, or youth at risk of separation from the family;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0E7D6039EB22482A81DC1A90AEAEAD5C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall include—</text> <clause id="H439E6969B188437EB706012F3271EAB6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>safe and appropriate shelter for not more than 30 days or the maximum allowed by the State, whichever is greater;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1B5B23AE8CBB4D659A9DDF7809255A6A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>individual, family, or group counseling, as appropriate, including counseling for individuals identified by such youth as family, that considers the age, gender, and social and developmental needs of such youth, and is culturally and linguistically appropriate; and </text></clause> <clause id="HB98D23432BB04548A3199F58E53F1F51"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>suicide prevention services; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3E7C0D7DEB65433899CC35E126224E35"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may include—</text> <clause id="HDE92D5773B4442E1905E0FD618400713"><enum>(i)</enum><text>street-based services;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE072AAC58E5344B59B96C1EA22AD6005"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>home-based services for families with youth at risk of separation from the family, to the extent practicable, that consider the ages, genders, and social and developmental needs of the family, and are culturally and linguistically appropriate;</text></clause> <clause id="HFE8074FA660A428A96E755C573D07CB6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prevention services;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H099B5596E4E8418AB25515ABD84060DD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>substance use disorder education and prevention services;</text></clause> <clause id="H63F02D7F9CFF4BE5A53F6A85E10B8911"><enum>(v)</enum><text>at the request of runaway youth or homeless youth, testing for sexually transmitted infections;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA09F814A5D984417B7C74EB4BE1CFC76"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>trauma-informed services, including for such youth who are victims of trafficking; and</text></clause> <clause id="H743858D6E2AB415D95CD22201BA37DD7"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>an assessment of—</text> 
<subclause id="H332F8B40D32D4F08A9C2DBFF299737D0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>family engagement in support and reunification, if reunification is appropriate;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H842724E87A564B4A8A969BA2D5DC261C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>interventions; and </text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2A08EA1ECEC443F5A0C0400704B5BDFA"><enum>(III)</enum><text>services for parents or legal guardians of such youth or, if appropriate, individuals identified by such youth as family.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H468360B69B6D456BA9D70FD1B0EF3DBA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 312—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8AE4F696795745A3A074C55E53078A59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <clause id="H60603F320FBD4EB28AADA3CEB8C15252"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7EFBF8632FC948DC9E9F5AD41F224CE0"> 
<paragraph id="H2888FEF7C15D4A38955293F813A157A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall use such assistance to establish, strengthen, or fund a runaway and homeless youth center that provides temporary shelter or a locally controlled project, including a host family home, that has—</text> <subparagraph id="HE83C7C0AC4184551BD4A45C09ABAA191"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a minimum capacity of not less than 4 youth, except if there is an established minimum number of beds per youth shelter or project location;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC816BDEEC6CB4153A70C12A8A5FE83D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a maximum capacity of not more than 20 youth, except where the applicant demonstrates that the State where the center or locally controlled project is located has a State or local law or regulation that allows a higher maximum to comply with licensure requirements for child and youth serving centers or projects;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE72B9F871F4B41DA8889CEF980E38964"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a ratio of staff to youth that is sufficient to ensure adequate supervision and treatment; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8971CB5AA302463082C847326685D30E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>if it is a mixed project, not more than 20 youth per project, except where the applicant demonstrates that the project has a State or local law or regulation that allows a higher maximum to comply with licensure requirements for child and youth serving projects;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> <clause id="H99AEADF03B524EF18E2C607E5BEDF28E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>or legal guardians</quote> and inserting <quote>, legal guardians, or individuals identified by such youth as family, if appropriate,</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1816552DC7094F39870D649411CB07A2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (6), (7), and (8), and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC1E93D428914C55B72D0191F3C6D239"> <paragraph id="H5C72B59F132A4CCAABE1CFBC50DD13B9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>shall develop an adequate plan, which may include the use of online resources to reach and engage youth, for establishing or coordinating with outreach programs designed to attract persons, including persons who are members of underserved populations, who are eligible to receive services for which a grant under section 311(a) may be expended;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H44238A85F512499FACCEBB7632FD65DB"><enum>(7)</enum><text>shall keep adequate statistical records profiling the runaway youth or homeless youth and family members of such youth whom the applicant serves, including demographic information and the number of such youth who—</text> <subparagraph id="HC6868B7D7BAA4EF5A43A005E7A4AC2F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are not referred to out-of-home shelter services;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H641A2B461D184C3D80C50EF9AA70DACA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are members of vulnerable or underserved populations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H47E0B8B78BC0432FAF8325FEBDEE868A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>are victims of trafficking;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H04E5C2BFEBC04D36BFD61CD01A8A5D7F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>are pregnant or parenting;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H95B5BE6305F14352B5662FB440A4B260"><enum>(E)</enum><text>have been involved in the child welfare system; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF96B609258FF40C38D0A6E972E68F5AE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>have been involved in the juvenile justice system;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H42610449564B481D836B15A301192DEC"><enum>(8)</enum><text>shall ensure that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H128609ACFE3A4907B348BCA5784D0ED0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the information maintained on individual runaway youth or homeless youth contained in the records described in paragraph (7) shall not be disclosed without the consent of the individual youth and the parent of the youth, the legal guardian of the youth, or an individual identified by such youth as family, to anyone other than an agency compiling statistical records or a government agency involved in the disposition of criminal charges against such youth; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H371BAA2232B84DE8B1BD73536F99CE1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reports or other documents based on the statistics described in paragraph (7) shall not disclose the identity of any individual runaway youth or homeless youth;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> 
<clause id="HA8F9BE34E704498485DF54BDEA5E9A69"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in paragraph (12), by striking subparagraphs (B) and (C) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD37A86A570014E2696E7E7940AE135E0"> <subparagraph id="H71EBAFDBF0CD403D94F6C104F91752E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>detailed information on how the applicant has been able to meet the goals of the plan of the applicant; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE3EB78C134F24FC28FCD2257DDF2A165"><enum>(C)</enum><text>statistical summaries describing—</text> <clause id="H4394423BB8EE4098B0501B5967CD360E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the data the Secretary requires to be collected;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4FEA1B765D35454DA4ABABDE16EBA230"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number and characteristics of runaway youth, homeless youth, street youth, and youth at risk of separation from the family, who participate in the project, including information on such youth who—</text> <subclause id="H22ADD77251CE4036B223ACD201EEFED9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are victims of trafficking;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8E2306B1321A4908840E4343A76CFB57"><enum>(II)</enum><text>are pregnant or parenting;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H74A1FAC2652442B1897815C891953EF7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>have been involved in the child welfare system; or </text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HDCBD82F6D6F3435E9438BEB546BA7C61"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>have been involved with the criminal justice system; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H2A01D41E429C4730B66B554C867704EF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the services provided to such youth by the project;</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> 
<clause id="H6732E61793B94067A1DD7806D5B69840"><enum>(v)</enum><text>in paragraph (13), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>for natural disasters, inclement weather, and public health emergencies;</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC8968B3183D946BF8F9838E1C32756DF"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A74D93AEE1349009C2E3322A96A0B75"> 
<paragraph id="H14623F93D3F8483BA1B44919AFCE6369"><enum>(14)</enum><text>shall provide services to runaway youth and homeless youth that consider the age, gender, and social and developmental needs of such youth, and are culturally and linguistically appropriate, to the extent practicable; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2B1D92B7276D47FB853E56213EB2CD80"><enum>(15)</enum><text>shall inform youth of their status as independent students under section 480 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087vv">20 U.S.C. 1087vv</external-xref>), provide verification of such status for the purposes of the Free Application for Federal Student Aid described in section 483 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1090">20 U.S.C. 1090</external-xref>), and assist youth in completing this application at the request of the youth.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB643A3D4AFD0442E940E71C0FB0A4E6C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <clause id="H548256A578B040F295571D0BE784BB25"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA1B3780F94224DD0A549C19266FFF2C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H2154AD0B73C14104BE56FDD99E30DC35"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCABC4195CBA74AAC872EA3AAFF00FC95"> 
<paragraph id="HDBD9E0982CB743408FDC8E37B8EF7C21"><enum>(5)</enum><text>develop a plan, consistent with local needs, for the use of online resources, if appropriate, to reach and engage youth.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H150E46163659401C8CAC0C8E6E40BBE4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text> 
<clause id="HC363469DBCC5439E9D1740139ED0B9BC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E6CBA1B84B447B8901125A38B3B6C6B"> <paragraph id="H37A004E0EE9A4DC8AE2E4ADF1DBEC64E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide counseling and information that consider the age, gender, and social and developmental needs of such youth, and are culturally and linguistically appropriate, to the extent practicable, to youth and the families of such youth (including unrelated individuals in the family households of such youth and individuals identified by such youth as family), including services relating to basic life skills, interpersonal skill building, educational advancement, job attainment skills, mental and physical health care, suicide prevention, parenting skills, financial planning, and referral to sources of other needed services;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> 
<clause id="H6231A953BE614A6EAD9720C366A5534F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by inserting <quote>, including training on trauma-informed care</quote> before the semicolon at the end; and</text></clause> <clause id="H08217264F3014F14B4F0350140381D14"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)—</text> 
<subclause id="H0CACF9482F6447DEBA6E809798BAA8C9"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H172292A3D85744E99ABD1DADF7C7932D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HDF38C31C8D5947BEAAA116FB4EFC1F95"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9B69FA842B54106935AC36C0AA7575D"> <subparagraph id="H106C31DA25664BFBAA51998AB393063A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>youth are eligible for home-based services when determined by the applicant to be at risk of separation from family.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H26E6A7C25D714195B6B788E646AC760A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by striking the subsection enumerator and all that follows through <quote>(b)—</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H43D6694C3FBB4E97B5D64FF18A0816DB"> <subsection id="H5D8293D73AFA49D294836CC2C0DD08E8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applicants providing substance use disorder education and prevention services</header><text>To be eligible to use assistance under section 311(a) to provide substance use disorder education and prevention services, an applicant shall include in the plan required by subsection (b)—</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H35CDAACCB00F4C32AF890B7D962B0DFA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6784F697DFCC4DA685EDED6B98832735"> <subsection id="H1BC2093EC2104B0C8223A727F50FF5C0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Online resources for outreach</header><text>An applicant may develop a plan, consistent with local needs, for the use of online resources to reach and engage youth.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4B5027A4DC9F4FB2AC287CEF2E45FB45"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definition of underserved populations</header><text>In this section, the term <term>underserved populations</term> means victims of homelessness or trafficking or runaway youth, who disproportionately face barriers in accessing and using victim services, including populations who are underserved due to limited English proficiency or are historically marginalized and underserved communities of color, and any other population determined to be underserved by the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6D86981C94A04DB89CFD970802D5A297"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 313, by striking subsection (b) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8CAD9148BDF84294921661E917D7F00E"> 
<subsection id="HDD81EC05D0424474A03F9DBDF8B3E0C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting applications for grants under section 311(a), the Secretary shall give priority to eligible applicants who have demonstrated experience in providing services to runaway youth and homeless youth.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="HD4234848CB28438F97A3F40D2FE54EA1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Transitional Living Grant Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/11221">34 U.S.C. 11221 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6553F29B0CCE4083BD654AB06867F308"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 321—</text> <subparagraph id="H09326D81362C4E84BDA5622A77A5C2DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>5-year</quote> after <quote>to make</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2FFA62EFB37A43A0A0279D69BEA5010D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and runaway youth. The Secretary shall award such grants not later than 90 days before the start date of the grant and establish an appeal process for grantees</quote> after <quote>homeless youth</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB44EA8CD0765490AA00033CC85859FB0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 322—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H91AAF30444FC453FA017E9E22DC630B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <clause id="H44E5FFBF09C24FE8A4603EC949A2A851"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13EC4BDF834249CDA60A1548FBDF5AA7"> 
<paragraph id="HFB0E24664BAF4CAFB214E71A717106B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide to homeless youth, by grant, agreement, or contract—</text> <subparagraph id="HF1ADF3F988E544E7AD15BA482C44CDE7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shelter, such as group homes, maternity group homes, host family homes, and supervised apartments; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H991FC08A389744F688142D66BFD74AFF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">services, such as information and counseling services in basic life skills, which consider the age, gender, and social and developmental needs of such youth, and are culturally and linguistically appropriate, including topics on money management, budgeting, consumer education, use of credit, parenting skills, interpersonal skill building, educational advancement, job attainment skills, mental and physical health care, and suicide prevention services;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> <clause id="HA94DC40F79BE4F63AAE51BB9085475E9" commented="no"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>and runaway</quote> after <quote>to provide such shelter and such services to individual homeless</quote>;</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H251B64FE04AD42DABD96768CFA03C277"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (4) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0D129BAF06F04B8E95AEE4662B3B1949"> <paragraph id="H0EE1AC321EC74F5B87F08766C2F8B84E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>that such shelter project used to carry out such project shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5C68786788AA4115AB4FB3B08FA5228B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have a minimum project capacity of not fewer than 4 youth, except if there is an established minimum number of beds per individual shelter or project location;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3F77B22CCF7B4925A7DFA89D8EC5C180"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have the capacity to accommodate not more than 20 individuals, excluding staff, within a single project, except where the applicant demonstrates that the State where the project is located has a State or local law or regulation that allows a higher maximum to comply with licensure requirements for child and youth serving projects; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H92443ED765194FF694E6773A592F4F87"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if it is a mixed project, limit runaway and homeless youth shelter beds to 20 youth per project with segregated access and programming, except where the applicant demonstrates that the State where the project is located has a State or local law or regulation that allows a higher maximum to comply with licensure requirements for child and youth serving projects;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> <clause id="H0B5EC7D52DF9438C8C18CCB68167077B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (6), (7), (8), and (9), and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8D470730EF444BDAC58F0A1A176A235"> 
<paragraph id="H62EE3C6FFB954DB6BF4515B4A934F4FD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to develop a written transitional living plan in partnership with each youth based on an assessment of the needs of each youth, designed to help the transition from supervised participation in such project to independent living or another appropriate living arrangement;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA24C77CCE7124C91B9AA3A3514D5EF54"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to develop an adequate plan to ensure proper coordination, integration, and referral of homeless youth and runaway youth, which considers the age, gender, and social and developmental needs of such youth, and are culturally and linguistically appropriate, to the extent practicable, to— </text> 
<subparagraph id="HEC6F6413A34648EF9D35D0E4A940687D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>social service;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD1A49EDB5B414CB0A43097924CFD2B86"><enum>(B)</enum><text>law enforcement;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H045F099474BC4ED0969174913618375F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>educational training, including postsecondary education;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCB2FE4BC61CB4691A4022FCE799B94CB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>vocational training, including services and programs for youth available under the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3101">29 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H342048FD23B9464D897C2DDB08F973F3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>welfare, including programs amended under the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/193">Public Law 104–193</external-xref>); </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3B43029DB170490980FD76955FF69272"><enum>(F)</enum><text>legal service;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDE714082B00448EFAC39C2D7BA933D56"><enum>(G)</enum><text>mental health service and health care programs;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD2285B21194C4C2CB76232D7EB82EEB2"><enum>(H)</enum><text>substance use disorder treatment; and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8E380BBA0C8347E48BF478FED37E0B18"><enum>(I)</enum><text>programs providing wrap-around services to victims of trafficking and gender-based violence;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF8322F67FC1A4EA6AAF453B8EE4F443D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to provide for the establishment of outreach programs designed to attract individuals who are eligible to participate in the project, which may include the use of online and social media engagements;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H188B512BB1CD428D8CB47C140F4891BC"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to submit to the Secretary an annual report that includes information regarding the activities carried out with funds under this part, the achievements of the project under this part carried out by the applicant and statistical summaries describing the number, characteristics, and demographic information of the homeless youth and runaway youth who participate in such project, including the prevalence of trafficking of such youth, and the services provided to such youth by such project, in the year for which the report is submitted;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> <clause id="H9F1049864FE34323ABA7DE476986F6F7"><enum>(v)</enum><text>in paragraph (15), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H48C346CD811844AAB32198764BB22C61"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (16) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA235A2B583FB45E1B9FD6477036BAC25"> <paragraph id="HDAEA003E20624D3EB0AAC90AE499C5BC"><enum>(16)</enum><text>to develop an adequate emergency preparedness and management plan regarding responses to natural disasters, inclement weather, and mental health emergencies; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> 
<clause id="H904D63C5B7E04F509163D9AFDDD6186C"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating paragraphs (3) through (5) and (6) through (16), as paragraphs (5) through (7) and (9) through (19), respectively;</text></clause> <clause id="H06834DDD6A0E4030B84B5336A5B7E1C1"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD892BD498FE247E09F4B02C4EB758978"> 
<paragraph id="HD1112F97BEA943979ABDF768A70C2AFD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to provide counseling to homeless and runaway youth and to encourage, if appropriate, the involvement in such counseling of their parents, legal guardians, or individuals identified by such youth as family;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF0FFBD07C004AE2B213584114AE1D12"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide aftercare services, if possible, to homeless and runaway youth who have received shelter and services from a transitional living youth project, including, to the extent practicable, such youth who, after receiving such shelter and services, relocate to a geographic area or State other than the geographic area or State in which such project is located;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> 
<clause id="H5F14310A7CED409DAB6584D1505C651D"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after paragraph (7), as redesignated by clause (vii), the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1EAA0A2E29534F068866B852A7F21AF4"> <paragraph id="H859991211F424A70BC2D8A8E5F7C879C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to develop a plan to provide services, which consider the age, gender, and social and developmental needs of such youth, and are culturally and linguistically appropriate, that address the needs of runaway, homeless, and street youth;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> 
<clause id="H8289B7E9EC2C4E9EB0043A059F682AC7"><enum>(x)</enum><text>by adding at end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H487E2118E0424296B9F5C9E6BB8B79FA"> <paragraph id="H7D3AF9193E174A92858890EAFDC171A9"><enum>(20)</enum><text>to inform youth of their status as independent students under section 480 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087vv">20 U.S.C. 1087vv</external-xref>), provide verification of such status for the purposes of the Free Application for Federal Student Aid described in section 483 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1090">20 U.S.C. 1090</external-xref>), and assist the youth in completing this application at the request of the youth.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF9D04886918146B59109D0C1A03913C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCEED043BDD404C7EABFBA88C67F467E3"> <subsection id="HA542498B7DE34A3C8A32AA7649EF69DD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In selecting eligible applicants to receive grants under this part, the Secretary shall give priority to entities that have experience in providing to homeless youth shelter and services of the types described in subsection (a)(1).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB3113BB139414B2EA0DD3680362AC473"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC4CAB5259C6946978288C23AEB698C10"> <subsection id="H7932A9D5793A483B9385E09D7FC84A32" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority for homeless youth less than 22 years of age</header><text>An entity that receives a grant under this part—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F62D6C53E834549BB9C6C292DF07FE7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall, in carrying out activities under the grant, prioritize service to homeless youth who are less than 22 years of age, but not less than 15 years of age; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5AC7A3A4983C4FDBAC6AA0CE022D3882"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may use grant funds to serve homeless youth who are ages 22 to less than 26.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H8B7959899F4342DBB261926511B98E8A"><enum>5.</enum><header>National communications system</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 331 of the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/11231">34 U.S.C. 11231</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, online, and social media</quote> after <quote>telephone</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H55EB5E7CFCD94FAB8A0F83A111953398"><enum>6.</enum><header>Coordinating, training, research, and other activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part D of the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/11241">34 U.S.C. 11241 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFFF5450BC2264088A5C709D1FC9A289D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 341—</text> <subparagraph id="H54B09721124F4199A3468C43D79762BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>safety, well-being,</quote> after <quote>health,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB99F2E8D0976494885358D37E7998767"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2) by striking <quote>other Federal entities</quote> and inserting <quote>the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the Department of Education, the Department of Labor, and the Department of Justice</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D385A438826421396C113B937AE3533"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 342—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H06D729CF911E4A2891ADBDAD260F56C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>5-year</quote> after <quote>make</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H892C9AA008824DCDA35F5D8DEFB99413"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(including onsite and web-based techniques, such as on-demand and online learning)</quote> after <quote>training</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6157BD672D92495D8C6D05E37CAB6FB1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>carrying out</quote> and inserting <quote>implementing in a trauma-informed manner</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H672B2E8AEE624AE4B7D45E7E818183E4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 343(b)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDE723C9AFFFF445AB970BECA3A4834C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)—</text> <clause id="H6376A0990E0B4190B1F5883207EFA17F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>abuse</quote> and all that follows through the semicolon at the end and inserting <quote>abuse, sexual assault, and trafficking;</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAFF71ACAD1F34CE2A132334CC30D88CE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>abuse</quote> and all that follows through <quote>; and</quote> and inserting <quote>abuse, sexual assault, and trafficking;</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="HD6ECA578F84745668DCEA22541F3FB7C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>who have been sexually victimized</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCEB57ADA5A8D4CC4B35C3855E31278C4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by adding at end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0678A6C3992048AEAC93653229D8A162"> <subparagraph id="HE34B0357044F4D46A2528756A2B280EA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>best practices for identifying and providing services that consider the age, gender, and social and developmental background of an individual, and are culturally and linguistically appropriate, to the extent practicable, to—</text> 
<clause id="HDE6490704C2646098735E6E37B6B0EA9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>vulnerable and underserved youth populations; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA172540A788749DC8F00F83B00D7F85C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>youth who are victims of trafficking; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H426DF109BAEF4375AE0D01742018F654"><enum>(E)</enum><text>informing youth of their status as independent students under section 480 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087vv">20 U.S.C. 1087vv</external-xref>), providing verification of such status for the purposes of the Free Application for Federal Student Aid described in section 483 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1090">20 U.S.C. 1090</external-xref>), and assisting youth in completing this application at the request of the youth;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H06666F396ABD49FB84F89C61057B6C46"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE0F73AD518CF4C8C8704C2D030587706"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (10), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF7AE9306C096493793C8463A77E678D5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H682D3B205A004F70A2525808D9954179"> 
<paragraph id="H62C5A83CF5F142D897A9483A99D75175"><enum>(11)</enum><text>examining the intersection between the runaway and homeless youth populations and trafficking, including noting whether such youth who are victims of trafficking were previously involved in the child welfare system or juvenile justice system.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H505274B9BDB941EEB265C3E851B56EAE"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>in section 344(a)(2)(A), by striking <quote>$100,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$200,000</quote>; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5FA239DAD4C04C40B622A6E4408C52D3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 345—</text> <subparagraph id="H5B1F1F1303DA4415AAF0023BDB2B2938"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> 
<clause id="H6D45090E96FB43EE99351AB3F67BC5B1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Not later than</quote> and all that follows through <quote>Homelessness</quote> and inserting <quote>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Runaway and Homeless Youth and Trafficking Prevention Act of 2025</short-title>, and at 3-year intervals thereafter, the Secretary, acting through the Associate Commissioner of the Family and Youth Services Bureau</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H65E1C3FC959F406383797833B0317BB6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> 
<subclause id="H2C2A03FF0DE54C139B53C1453944D28F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>13</quote> and inserting <quote>12</quote>; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC9677234F4EC41DC906DCFA31CDDA3BF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HD9B8D11C095B410B94324BCD9E63DB17"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></clause> <clause id="H15D8AE8634894091A95F8799051D3881"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by adding at end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9B8E336AC06E43C2B2CD43B87725C6A4"> 
<paragraph id="HDAEFCD4071894F17A5CB015C7D60CBB7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>that includes demographic information of such individuals, including youth who are victims of trafficking; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HED733B478DE548E9A8324CE296854396"><enum>(4)</enum><text>that does not disclose the identity of any such individual.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4646E09624524ACEA42E460188587C68"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)—</text> <clause id="H8C8D97F2587D46F0977AA5ED61210CEA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>13</quote> and inserting <quote>12</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3A54E75420FE4993A4FA05B0625C2BEF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></clause> <clause id="HF696EF63B82A414BBF17D43C9D6B06E8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> 
<subclause id="HC0CF50F9A6E442C79D2EBD000551E7D5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting <quote>, including mental health services;</quote>;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HFB4B2B5914124388A3CFAA6573D34B60"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF819BE9D10884974B2F2D318EB8E7E8D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by adding at end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B5F04321F614051A92445244D28FF4E"> <clause id="H48F0B3D7F1244AD09338812C5E4AC0C1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">connections to caring adults; and </text></clause> 
<clause id="HDE7F3FB43EFD48559B6C58C10C24247B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>access to secondary education, higher education, and job training; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause> <clause id="HC8DFFFEDFA95422C9EA3360E4EAECAC4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (B) as subparagraph (E); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5E322F86A1F447189B9822196FD7A3C8"><enum>(v)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93D7C1B58C364A30A05A30B851E33123"> <subparagraph id="HBBE9301A5F7B475E918750419158D0FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incidences, if any, of such individuals who—</text> 
<clause id="H041EC28FF5FE49BFB4820260EE37C63A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are victims of trafficking;</text></clause> <clause id="H8E9550B595F348CB98EEC4499517986D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are victims of sexual exploitation; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H618402D42D6A42F8A3F82892F813A3E6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>were involved in the child welfare or foster care system;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7E96DB1CC97446C19059377B01849F1E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>demographic characteristics, including race, color, religion, national origin, sex, gender identity (as defined in section 249(c) of title 18, United States Code), sexual orientation, and disability; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAE3DC47C77B24AB4B778242BDE2A847C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>statistics on youth who are or were pregnant or parenting; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H2D808AED3749412FA47DDFB043A2CE60"><enum>7.</enum><header>Sexual abuse and trafficking prevention program; street outreach program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part E of the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/11261">34 U.S.C. 11261 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by striking section 351 and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD990DF453D6B44E68729D2C1538E8F9C"> 
<section id="H9F6A738F889240AE9A3F8E3A22FBE6D1"><enum>351.</enum><header>Authority to make grants</header> 
<subsection id="HCA807914D83A41BC9EF938B374E63C71"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall make 5-year grants to public and nonprofit private entities, and combinations of such entities, for the purpose of providing street-based services to runaway, homeless, and street youth who have been subjected to, or are at risk of being subjected to, sexual abuse or trafficking. The Secretary shall award such grants not later than 90 days before the start date of the grant and establish an appeal process for grantees.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA10DFBB6DA0A47BC9D72D31DCBB86CD9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In selecting applicants to receive grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to public and nonprofit private entities that have experience in providing services to runaway, homeless, and street youth.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6155AC5285684C4E8B6914E40FDC16D4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility requirements</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under subsection (a), an applicant shall certify to the Secretary that such applicant has expertise in serving runaway, homeless, and street youth and has systems in place to ensure that such applicant can provide services that consider the age, gender, and social and developmental background of youth described in subsection (a), and are culturally and linguistically appropriate.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H326E07D4A3D242B9922BE98BA888F82E"><enum>8.</enum><header>General provisions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part F of the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/11271">34 U.S.C. 11271 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H71CF2BEF7A2842CB8D70532A25D8C43B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="part" style="OLC">Part F</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="part" style="OLC">Part G</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53800D655B8A4D08A3E522B54AEBE10A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 381—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAE040E6862F34F3CA47640F8CB271DCC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(3), by striking <quote>facility</quote> and inserting <quote>center or project</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF57006EF98AA437882FC6B6A1CB94921"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), by striking <quote>facility</quote> both places it appears and inserting <quote>center or project</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD249587941A04FD99309FA13C8D6EECA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 382(a)—</text> <subparagraph id="HFD6344A68EE54D9783790690C02308AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>2000</quote> and inserting <quote>2026</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9FA2275A957547CC9D5610139F87CA91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the Workforce</quote> and inserting <quote>Workforce</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF09A0215FBAE4B66B679E9C8C6379199"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> 
<clause id="H213351C6766343B8BC97AE6EA00CDF74"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (B) through (D) as subparagraphs (C) through (E), respectively; and</text></clause> <clause id="H513CE7ECFB664ADBBEAE1F42885B119D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBF83DCFA85084ED68E84AD35C1B5C0A3"> 
<subparagraph id="H500C1EB6631C4351B7E5CD9D7A9D526C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifying youth who are victims of trafficking;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0F9E617803954B20879BCB871AA9B75C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> 
<clause id="H4633F71701074243A21FC59845D68777"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (A) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4AC4B14A48A0414C808D0E4F9B058B4B"> <subparagraph id="H1DFBA516D6414366A2813B9EB4FAC6C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number and characteristics of youth served by such projects, including such youth who—</text> 
<clause id="H224CB13B105140BDB52686A1B343FC4B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are victims of trafficking;</text></clause> <clause id="H0B2C2D246AE0424BAAD4A1AFCE944AF1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are pregnant or parenting;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6EAC9D28BD924101801C32FD41B7E612"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>have been involved in the child welfare system; or</text></clause> <clause id="HD95496722FDF4C149F7FD5FF1FA63305"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>have been involved in the juvenile or adult criminal justice system, the incarceration system, or legal proceedings related to such systems;</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> 
<clause id="HFDBEB28CA64546019AFA37FAABFE2FDA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (F) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9542482A8AD443419F0EAC950CAD5431"> <subparagraph id="H14863D4A4BF34BB4B134237640ADA574"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the ability of such projects to encourage the resolution of problems within the family, including with individuals identified by such youth as family, through counseling and development of self-sufficient living skills; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H88D425371011436DAB19A1DEC70324C6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 383(a) by striking <quote>facility’s budget</quote> and inserting <quote>budget of the center or project</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00162E63F7674065BC2FC14B8EA75C38"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 384, by adding at the end the following: <quote>Grantees are encouraged to share data with other programs and systems, without identifying individual youth in any shared records, to improve coordination and maximize the use of resources.</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9D1DC09CF3E04E4C855FFCFF73EB06CC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by inserting after section 384 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H96C32889969246C19168BA6EF4614A8F"> <section id="H45648D5989204E379E60A375530B83A4"><enum>384A.</enum><header>Administration and enforcement</header> <subsection id="H4C83DE1921314A508FA1DF00889714B4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Associate Commissioner of the Family and Youth Services Bureau, may waive any provision under this title for a period of not more than 3 years, unless an extension is granted under subsection (f), if—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC94AF88CE1854416BC7FCDDBD65D72D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a potential grantee requests a waiver that describes 1 or more conflicting or duplicative requirements or circumstances that prevent the effective delivery of services to runaway and homeless youth, such as an extraordinary circumstance, natural disaster, public health emergency, or financial crisis;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBCACA4B0B2514F228BF5947ADDF81067"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that the waiver will, by itself, contribute to or enhance the ability of the grantee to carry out the purposes of this title; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H45B4D4C93F474F5A84769F0C7E8DDC75"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that the waiver will not be inconsistent with the objectives of this title.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB869ED73FF2244C39D2AA766EF268B40"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A request made under subsection (a) shall be provided to the Secretary in writing and shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2023C01797DF4371851537AC3141C580"><enum>(1)</enum><text>detail each provision within this title for which the grantee seeks relief;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC5DCC6DB0474211AC132E25EAB18E28"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describe how a waiver from such provision will, by itself, improve delivery of services to runaway and homeless youth; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE08EB01F08B047899A2F198B3DFA5190"><enum>(3)</enum><text>certify that the health, safety, and well-being of runaway and homeless youth served through assistance received under this title will not be compromised as a result of the waiver.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H819D2E1ABEDC4EDFB25C39D41FDDF8F1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification of approval or disapproval</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2835ED3CAAED42E297645869BBA7B2F8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the receipt of a waiver request made under subsection (a), the Secretary shall inform the grantee of approval or disapproval of the request. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H857E358953C84DE49DF262935DCF8F1E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disapproval</header><text>If the request is disapproved, the Secretary shall inform the grantee, the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, and the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives of the reasons for the disapproval and give the grantee the opportunity to amend the request or appeal the decision. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H49232808E3764B8D9A3B5F7DAB6FA15E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Approval</header><text>If the request is approved, the Secretary shall grant a waiver and, not later than 30 days after granting such waiver, notify and submit a report to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, and the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives that describes— </text> 
<subparagraph id="H39BA5A6B17434A8585A0AE320A3E9D79"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each specific provision waived;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1906BC7E36F64EF89C82CCC5B90FC965"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the reason given by the grantee for the need for a waiver; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE814587FA48D4104BFA75C468D74D854"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the expected impact of the waiver on youth served under this program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD85AD55A14FF47F4B7798BAA6CC3B090"><enum>(d)</enum><header>External conditions</header><text>The Secretary shall not require or impose any new or additional requirements in exchange for receipt of a waiver if such requirements are not specified in this title.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCBAFA2B5955443DCAA3639661B9DB6C5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Secretary shall terminate approval of a request for a waiver authorized under this section if the Secretary determines, after notice and opportunity for a hearing, that the performance of a grantee who was granted relief under this section has been inadequate, or if such relief is no longer necessary to achieve its original purposes.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H221940E83E2F4433A27A5FE8A41A49C0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Waiver Extension</header> <paragraph id="H280EDF86245E424EABEC2F40A6C08B39"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may grant an extension to an existing waiver authorized under this section for a period of not more than 1 year upon a request for a waiver extension from the grantee. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C3B480AF9654164BB2FCCB26251FAEA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extension Request</header><text>A request for a waiver extension described under paragraph (1) shall be submitted to the Secretary not later than 30 days before the expiration date of the existing waiver, and shall re-certify the provisions in subsection (b) and explain the need for additional time of relief from such provisions provided in this title.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3BB364D6B436481AA978B69EA76C02BF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Restrictions</header><text>Nothing in this title shall be construed as authorizing the Secretary to permit a grantee to alter the eligibility requirements for eligible youth. Nothing in this section shall be construed as authorizing the Secretary to waive anything related to the Secretary's authority under this title.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE634B4334AB546548DB0F1DC03CCCBF0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in section 386(a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H3E07570FE7B5428FA4D085AE99BB3C59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>3 consecutive</quote> and inserting <quote>5 consecutive</quote> both places it appears;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H72D357D60C534E9D8BC78355959FE11E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, acting through the Associate Commissioner of the Family and Youth Services Bureau,</quote> after <quote>Secretary</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3ABE7B35FD3A48FFAB4F76EE36F5FB91"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting <quote> or virtually when appropriate,</quote> after <quote>on-site,</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H3F3B02C9EBC5419280D618FB62195BAD"><enum>(8)</enum><text>in section 386A—</text> <subparagraph id="H27C0B778AD3B411EA60821070CF14EC2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> 
<clause id="HA1F807CD6BBD498AB880DB9BFEBB7ED5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Reconnecting Homeless Youth Act of 2008</quote> and inserting <quote><short-title>Runaway and Homeless Youth and Trafficking Prevention Act of 2025</short-title></quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H79A2CBC0AB21444FBC3786B1D43E89A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>371,</quote> after <quote>sections</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFD4C0F98B03544E58658BDA44BCFB95B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c), by inserting <quote>371,</quote> after <quote>sections</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5B16144F39374EAEBC3A239A303EBE15"><enum>(9)</enum><text>by inserting after section 386A the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H177AE06E513D4DF7BB1F4ED23E48E743"> 
<section id="H90251D42EFE84AD9B430D28EEC447BFB"><enum>386B.</enum><header>Nondiscrimination</header> 
<subsection id="H55FE147675554974BE89BA808CB403CE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No person in the United States shall be excluded from participation in, be denied the benefits of, or be subjected to discrimination under this title on the basis of actual or perceived race, color, religion, national origin, sex, gender identity (as defined in section 249(c) of title 18, United States Code), sexual orientation, or disability.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H98086210E7C1409F98ABBB6E2240E332"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If sex-segregation or sex-specific programming is necessary to the essential operation of a program, nothing in this section shall prevent any such program or activity from considering the sex of an individual. In such circumstances, grantees may meet the requirements of this section by providing comparable services to individuals who cannot participate in the sex-segregated or sex-specific programming.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0120987F302A4599B1CABCBB5F60478A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disqualification</header><text>The Secretary shall enforce this section pursuant to section 654 of the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9849">42 U.S.C. 9849</external-xref>). The provisions of such section relating to the procedure for review of an action taken by the Secretary shall apply.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFF8A5C01D00647C0A77D745922F1D944"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as supplanting, displacing, preempting, or otherwise limiting the responsibilities and liabilities under other Federal or State civil rights laws with respect to discrimination on a basis described in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H347ACE79598245D5949B8A764FF3A882"><enum>(10)</enum><text>in section 387—</text> <subparagraph id="H3020F7BCE17B41308DAA3A3597B9655B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1), (4), (5), (6), (7), and (8), as paragraphs (9), (6), (7), (8), (11), and (13), respectively;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H86E591F1728E47E78FDDC07E93A59495"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (2) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB04C87F75E9140448404D6491B00D140"> <paragraph id="H52C733C508244B298E5E380EF4C060AC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Culturally and linguistically appropriate</header><text>The term <term>culturally and linguistically appropriate</term>, with respect to services, has the meaning given the term <quote>culturally and linguistically appropriate services</quote> in the <quote>National Standards for Culturally and Linguistically Appropriate Services in Health and Health Care</quote>, issued in April 2013, by the Office of Minority Health of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H406C28B9008B45B2AE3A8EA20F989AC2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(A)—</text> <clause id="H8F57215F576144418F212D27ED26CD36"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>21</quote> and inserting <quote>26</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC73FC2F4E4BA452B9B918F2BD43EA54A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking clause (ii) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H09BADAD6AA8349BD905CF34D2B62C583"> <clause id="H7A04476C54244252ABD0B1AC6F6972BE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the purposes of part B, not less than 15 years of age but less than 26 years of age, subject to section 322(d);</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H66B96870B89F4897885A254C82D786A3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE65B8CE8EBF54EE7BB59169419F736C2"> <paragraph id="H747C1009FF2444BDBEE1AE829A29DA80"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Mixed projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>mixed projects</term> means a building, structure, or campus that may house multiple programs serving youth under the age of 26. Any of these programs may be funded as authorized under this Act as well as funded by other entities, including private, public, and other government funding. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H656EBA567F7C4476A6AFAAFFCE7160CD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Prevention services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>prevention services</term> means services to prevent youth from becoming runaway, homeless, or street youth and may include—</text> <subparagraph id="H74CF25A98FF74DE4AFE587011606B9D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>individual, family, group, and peer counseling;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H147BBE92501F4354973A06AD40FCDF0C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>family mediation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8B9EB0C80C334D7EB90F33290EB8F48E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assessing the strengths, vulnerabilities, and needs of youth;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC2F93E34CB0D48CEBC2A08A70BEDBD3B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>connecting youth to public services and housing options;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF8A08D7E61894CF08BF1EDA9E120EFA7"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">emergency respite care for clients within the allowable age range of the underlying grant award, including care that provides parents and other caregivers with emergency services and temporary shelter that offer relief; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H217DDB54FDA9401A9C38A5228F5C1DB0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>connecting youth to education and employment programs; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFCAF21BB6A82425FA668B211C7E7DFF2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>case management and resource navigation; and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4FC4C5AC0D84B1F912FCD725C4BA191"><enum>(H)</enum><text>activities to improve access to local mental health and substance use treatment and prevention.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB80979CBD5E94DFCA97FA8584A5C4342"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in paragraph (7)(B), as redesignated by subparagraph (A)—</text> 
<clause id="H18D07939096C4D3A972D531B0BEF1DB8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i), by inserting <quote>, including the use of online methods of engagement, as appropriate, based on the needs of the community and population served</quote> after <quote>street youth</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H2D29A8F573574C9AA31A2F615C14BC43"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking clause (v) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F5084B340C94B26934D0A270E1D25A1"> 
<clause id="H357F050A2AAB46BDA5AC3276F5829649"><enum>(v)</enum><text>advocacy, education, and prevention services related to—</text> <subclause id="H768921D9711F45B7BFDA3B0C3A4B95DD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>substance use disorder;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HFCE54AC965A148C09A2026C249AB2AAA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>trafficking;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H65F4A1A30830448A9DACBAD5788941BD"><enum>(III)</enum><text>sexually transmitted infections, including human immunodeficiency virus;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF33B5D86CCBD4F1EAF64360904548019"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>violence, including physical assault, sexual assault, domestic violence, and gender-based violence; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HAAE0A24FC722444EB7B02710187A7AD8"><enum>(V)</enum><text>suicide.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7EC94A824FC42BAB1A6BA4FBA563EDD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in paragraph (8)(B), as redesignated by subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>prostitution, or drug abuse</quote> and inserting <quote>trafficking, or substance use disorder</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB741FD3637504B13BE0ECD8E88880875"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (9), as redesignated by subparagraph (A), by striking the paragraph (9) enumerator and all that follows through <quote>services’—</quote>, and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F04FC9B34374ADD91EFC7813B0E7E03"> 
<paragraph id="H8A4765C0193A4B27BA50B684DF1C9F38"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Substance use disorder education and prevention services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>substance use disorder education and prevention services</term>—</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE43204E0C3E241D48A905BE7DFE759D8"><enum>(H)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (9), as redesignated by subparagraph (A), the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAFB4B0E943964688B43130F50C9F310C"> 
<paragraph id="HC9C02512B91F44449BDFC67935E8E63C"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Trafficking</header><text>The term <term>trafficking</term> has the meaning given the terms <quote>severe forms of trafficking in persons</quote> and <quote>sex trafficking</quote> in section 103 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE956F44E70F942AB967E63B48A3396E0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in paragraph (11), as redesignated by subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>, to establish family or community supports,</quote> after <quote>self-sufficient living</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A3AAA78445945C99FFAAE797A7F6A23"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after paragraph (11), as redesignated by subparagraph (A), the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDFB72FA4A64A4846BC405863C8CAB45C"> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E0813A666064CEAAE27BB221F96BB6E"><enum>(12)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Trauma-informed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>trauma-informed</term> has the meaning given the term in section 103 of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/11103">34 U.S.C. 11103</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H199D09A7E8EA4E3999DA78B4EEB1BD0F"><enum>(K)</enum><text>in paragraph (13)(B), as redesignated by subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="H08D5C42B994D435B9446B7F82747AF9C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text> 
<subclause id="H05DC42F841D84C159E4008CDA081F344"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or able</quote> after <quote>willing</quote>; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE2D22079CD3D4F1B987AAC4408990895"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H8D05CBAA645C4925A5941B3F3E30550E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H6A0A14B7153F47D1A04BC49BB3B9F935"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H61BC79E859B44CFDA18152ADFA459FA7"> 
<clause id="H22E95EBDD39641CDA8D51E8453257AC4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>who is involved in the child welfare system, juvenile justice system, or criminal justice system, but who is not being housed by any such system.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H2ED4EDFB2FD64391906FD02EFC166D7F"><enum>9.</enum><header>Prevention services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Runaway and Homeless Youth Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/11201">34 U.S.C. 11201 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after part E the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H25A385EAED6642D58B4E895603E52CFB"> 
<part id="HE7556AE72EB04D76BCA8BBA3086194D0"><enum>F</enum><header>Prevention Services</header> 
<section id="HF92EF83718614E47AD8D6B5E10AB90AC"><enum>371.</enum><header>Authority to make grants</header> 
<subsection id="H836EED53773E43A9B007D096C043A046"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to make 5-year grants to an eligible entity, as described under subsection (c), that applies for an optional, additional prevention services grant. Any funds provided under this part are in addition to other funds grantees receive under other parts in this title.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF724C8864CFF47E0B4AE2C85F34EF05C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In selecting grantees to receive grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that are—</text> 
<paragraph id="H83F52D1FF967476CAA695F708E24B708"><enum>(1)</enum><text>public entities and nonprofit, private entities that have experience in providing services to runaway, homeless, and street youth, and youth at risk of separation from the family; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD61A987B1C4C4735AEC52AB10033EBA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>public entities and nonprofit, private entities that request prevention services grants of not more than $75,000 per year.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE9E4EBBC8BD546478729A2C78F5C9E9B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility requirements</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="HE88BC139020A4850842981C4D84304C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the potential grantee shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCD96307C5F9E4B0E945B7F5175711759"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be a successful basic center program or transitional living program, which may include a program that operates a maternity group home, that wants to establish, strengthen, or provide prevention services for youth at risk of homelessness and youth at risk of running away; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDAE53691B3EA4DC48E9AEEC2287069A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit to the Secretary a plan agreeing, as part of such program, to provide prevention services; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H200281D91F8E40019AA72D2C5AF1F084"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the potential grantee shall certify to the Secretary that such grantee has systems in place to provide services to youth described in subsection (a) that consider the age, gender, and social and developmental background of such youth, and are culturally and linguistically appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H89189044AC5943E898DF4F68514D34AE"><enum>10.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 388(a) of the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/11280">34 U.S.C. 11280(a)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H15B636BF978E4FE39704458062635404"> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9F8C9C6442A4ED09DA370FBC8CBA88D"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB31C4B8CCB674524867C71D1A1DE3A70"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this title (other than parts E and F) $200,000,000 for fiscal year 2026, and such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC3FDD730531247C19EC83433826F7BA9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allocation</header> <subparagraph id="H45375872624D4E46A139356E7039BF0E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Parts a and b</header><text>From the amount appropriated under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall reserve not less than 90 percent to carry out parts A and B.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H45D176E25DA94CE2BE5BF2DA06437C7C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Part b</header><text>Of the amount reserved under subparagraph (A), 45 percent and, in those fiscal years in which continuation grant obligations and the quality and number of applicants for parts A and B warrant not more than 55 percent, shall be reserved to carry out part B.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3643402548DA439C96E71EB68E7864D2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Parts c and d</header> <subparagraph id="H3EAEA719572D4F659713F1A13E978904"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In each fiscal year, after reserving the amounts required by paragraph (2), the Secretary shall use the remaining amount (if any) to carry out parts C and D (other than section 345).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC0EEDE4247184794BD5DBA583CE8225E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Periodic estimate</header><text>Of the amount authorized to be appropriated under paragraph (1), $2,000,000 shall be made available to carry out section 345 for each of fiscal years 2025, 2028, and 2030.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H52B6F11D31184CEDA3FD548A366910CD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Part e</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out part E $50,000,000 for fiscal year 2026, and such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F59F59C4E62419F95CABA1021DEAE81"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Part F</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out part F $67,500,000 for fiscal year 2026, and such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H024FA5DCEB9C4A5BBA9F377AAEDB80DD"><enum>11.</enum><header>Approval of application</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Runaway and Homeless Youth Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/11201">34 U.S.C. 11201 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6831F301CB1548DEA110B0AD4F74E797"> 
<section id="HDA4331F538624553964E5642E4A53D21"><enum>390.</enum><header>Approval of applications</header> 
<subsection id="H9D4A19B459624798B1540040EF7B6DFF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An application by a public or private nonprofit entity for a grant under section 311, 321, or 351, may be approved by the Secretary for an amount for a fiscal year that is—</text> <paragraph id="H40B14BFFAF5248839A17F86931D99A28"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not less than $225,000 and not more than $275,000 if the amount appropriated to carry out this title (other than parts E and F) for the fiscal year is equal to or greater than $200,000,000; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5306E9E7DAA64289B89CB8A5851EF629"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not less than $200,000 and not more than $250,000 if the amount appropriated to carry out this title (other than parts E and F) for the fiscal year is less than $200,000,000.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H700D0B767C0442CF8D2A9B2462245D0F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In selecting applications for grants under sections 311, 321, and 351, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible grantees who have demonstrated experience in providing services to runaway and homeless youth.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


