<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25114-GDL-5X-957"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S330 IS: Combatting China’s Pilfering of Intellectual Property Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 330</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250130">January 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To impose sanctions with respect to persons that operate in a sector of the economy of the People’s Republic of China in which the person has engaged in a pattern of significant theft of the intellectual property of a United States person, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H91B038A19EE04834A9C258A28B92E03C"><section section-type="section-one" id="HF2BC4EAD6CCE414FBCB515F089969661"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Combatting China’s Pilfering of Intellectual Property Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CCP IP Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB0D0E3EFA54A4763A553AB4EAB493737"><enum>2.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions related to the theft of intellectual property</header><subsection id="H93C87D9E4C8A4359A9DC7D2624648C86"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to each person described in subsection (c) that the President determines, on or after the date of enactment of this Act, operates in a sector of the economy of the People’s Republic of China in which the person—</text><paragraph id="H372255D2A5B046279B1A51E4E5FD47EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has engaged in a pattern of significant theft of the intellectual property of a United States person; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE9304D55DEE4BEBBD4CD09112513365"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has received the intellectual property of a United States person through a pattern of significant theft engaged in by other persons.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3CFF055601874253A8AED9E062D46560"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions imposed</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="H260B367E8AEB48BDBE97846ACBF48AF5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Asset blocking</header><text>The exercise of all powers granted to the President by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of a person described in subsection (a) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6646D20F75C42108A2A1C5393FF1BDA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aliens ineligible for visas, admission, or parole</header><subparagraph id="HCADDB49C4907464D9FD34F8ED00D3FBD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien described in subsection (a) is—</text><clause id="HA899C010ACFD464FA7A5716C5FE871C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States; </text></clause><clause id="HB8B3A7F7BA9D4EA18D6B50136FB7A2AE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and </text></clause><clause id="H723D11FE3B7641FCB96EFA180F73AD4A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>). </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0624094C45414362B7C2E1241A882657"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><clause id="HA095199EAB8642568B98588167E9F211"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The issuing consular officer, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) shall, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>), revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to an alien who the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) determines is described in subsection (a), regardless of when the visa or other documentation is issued. </text></clause><clause id="HF26E254F75724704BD1DC0F52B5C6844"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A revocation under clause (i) shall take effect immediately and shall automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H276BAB93801B43EFA9DE3D9994DF2303"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Persons described</header><text>A person described in this subsection is one of the following:</text><paragraph id="HF65F748CF1134C27A227F6EBD019650D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An individual who—</text><subparagraph id="H817D2A97F2834E6AB52233AEDC0446B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a national of the People’s Republic of China or acting at the direction of a national of the People’s Republic of China or an entity described in paragraph (2); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA114CFED20584B8EA60ED18984B9092E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not a United States person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD911F1EA1D484DFDAECD1856AF3B4970"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An entity that is—</text><subparagraph id="HB6707233720F497281121FB9803D3688"><enum>(A)</enum><text>organized under the laws of the People’s Republic of China or of any jurisdiction within the People’s Republic of China; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H597961578FF647A1822BAEA0074A828F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>owned or controlled by individuals who are nationals of the People’s Republic of China; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9874BC4F48B04660A37BE32CC6EB09D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>owned or controlled by an entity described in subparagraph (A) that is not a United States person. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1E0BD370E7E04E638207D04E380F1DC1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Penalties; implementation</header><paragraph id="H0C92FAFC961F4C129174FC2FB2105AA5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of subsection (b)(1) or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out that subsection shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H159EB045E67B4828A4B5B9141FDBF115"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) for purposes of carrying out this section. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H935A63553B8D401BA14117D2B86AC7F6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the imposition of sanctions under subsection (a) on a case-by-case basis with respect to a person if the President—</text><paragraph id="HD38085F561824D6DB34CAEB0AD633ED2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>certifies to the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate that such waiver is in the national security interests of the United States; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEDE77A38AF14D0E8DEFEDC017A76770"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes a justification for such certification.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H71394530967C488096D2E7DD7309F168"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination of sanctions</header><text>The President may terminate sanctions imposed under subsection (a) with respect to a person if the President certifies to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate that such person is no longer engaging in efforts to steal intellectual property of United States persons. </text></subsection><subsection id="HACCB1145BC93458F81233D8AD68C0466"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report that specifies each person the President determines meets the criteria described in subsection (a) for the imposition of sanctions. </text></subsection><subsection id="H74BEFC2D39174721B780AD24A43C5047"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HAB4AD9BCC35B49B1969416012888519E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Admitted; alien</header><text>The terms <term>admitted</term> and <term>alien</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D950D88FE2B48169C84AE56CF6F9E82"><enum>(2)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H0D5407F44BD044C6B9A5EEC246AEFA03"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual who is a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C08FAB37E1B4D85BC58F6AF59951142"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3EC947873A404731A449C1FBFAAC00F4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Restriction on issuance of visas</header><subsection id="HCA0F14A1E0364D07A7B181362EA8FDF6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Restriction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State may not issue a visa to, and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall deny entry to the United States of, each of the following: </text><paragraph id="H109E08AD54BF454F984B963F9A1B9D10"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Senior officials in the Chinese Communist Party, including the Politburo, the Central Committee, and each delegate to the 20th National Congress of the Chinese Communist Party. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H886C9DBB5DAF4061B5A239D15E4D4BE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The spouses and children of the senior officials described in paragraph (1). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA707C6163A041789B5B21D420D281CF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Members of the cabinet of the Government of the People’s Republic of China. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC2483DA56CE4C338099E121607646FC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Active duty members of the People’s Liberation Army of China. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H65F67078F26D4457AC14D93CD73C4FF7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The restriction under subsection (a) shall not apply for any year in which the President certifies to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate that the Government of the People’s Republic of China has ceased sponsoring, funding, facilitating, and actively working to support efforts to infringe on the intellectual property rights of citizens and entities of the United States. </text></subsection><subsection id="HD4E77C6645984AF8BFC4142AA897B169"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to Congress a report that—</text><paragraph id="HF38F517B83BD4FB2B294F874C34C6ED1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>details the efficacy of visa screening mechanisms to mitigate intellectual property theft by the People’s Republic of China; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F25306C6EDA4282A2569DF5E4727501"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes a list of research institutions associated with the People’s Liberation Army and the Ministry of State Security of the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

