<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H130E0F92D96E4121973EC8B9E426A585" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3287 IH: Pregnancy.Gov Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3287</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250508">May 8, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000471">Mr. Fitzgerald</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a clearinghouse of ZIP-Code based information to expecting mothers, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HFDBF31AD45844CB183FA104E2AF1770F" style="OLC">
<section id="HF4F34D63C81840508993D59F71EEE7B4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pregnancy.Gov Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H40FF420DC92F40709E5F007E741F8F52"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pregnancy.gov</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Public Health Service Act is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H264FA3EB5F264E9390FB250BF4D6CC85" style="OLC">
<title id="H1B9DF57EA8EB4B3783AF813111DE9FAE"><enum>XXXIV</enum><header>Pregnancy.gov</header>
<section id="H3E57859472DA42D886B544CAB24553C8"><enum>3401.</enum><header>Website</header>
<subsection id="H9B452C17F57C4BA185E93B00FC063096"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Website</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall publish a public website entitled <quote>pregnancy.gov</quote>. The Secretary may not delegate implementation or administration of such website below the level of the Office of the Secretary. Such website shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HF9054777445B47398594DEEC1697925F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A clearinghouse of relevant resources available for pregnant women.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H735787DDFE1A4568AEED2D38BE935300"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A series of questions through which a user is able to generate a list of relevant resources of interest within the user’s ZIP Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCCEE02B19C1E450794C15629D5F66462"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A means to direct the user to identify whether to list the relevant resources of interest that are available online or within 1, 5, 10, 50, and 100 miles of the user.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H604F3E99D7F64FF4ABFF6058A3836B9E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A mechanism to provide for the submission of feedback on how user-friendly and helpful the website was in providing the tailored information the user was seeking.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6BBD302804024DD0B598E264179B6F7A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A mechanism for users to take an assessment through the portal and provide consent to use the user’s contact information which the Secretary may use to conduct outreach via phone or email to follow up with users on additional resources that would be helpful for the users to review.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HFD8CFCF733354D258CCEFF2E74523113"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Resource list aggregation</header>
<paragraph id="H6B6C44DEFD254C57A29AF6B840E2E30B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall invite States to provide recommendations of relevant resources referred to in subsection (a)(3).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6EE52D89D0444D7791FA59670A32D732"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria for making recommendations</header><text>The Secretary shall develop criteria to provide to the States to determine whether resources recommended as described in paragraph (1) should appear on the website. Such criteria shall include the requirement that the relevant resource is not a prohibited entity and the requirement that the relevant resource has been engaged in providing services for a minimum of 3 consecutive years.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H63A9B277E9F14FF3890B45535FC4F577"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grant program</header>
<subparagraph id="HEF024FB2E8784373A2DE2393541ED0BF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide grants to States to establish or support a system that—</text> <clause id="HF330D2A204E44807B7B06DF26982A419"><enum>(i)</enum><text>aggregates relevant resources referred to in subsection (a)(3), in accordance with the criteria developed under paragraph (2); and</text></clause>
<clause id="H0E212E1345FC4D288D81B7FC0C443F35"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may be coordinated, to the extent determined appropriate by the State, by a statewide, regionally based, or community-based public or private entity.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA01E69F419734135A8095149B41726A2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under subparagraph (A), a State shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including a plan for outreach and awareness activities, and a list of relevant resources that would be included in the State system supported by the grant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HBC08201E1AA14BCDAD9695EB146EF3AA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition regarding certain entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Relevant resources listed on the website established under this section, and any additional resources promoted by the Secretary, may not include any resource offered by a prohibited entity. No prohibited entity may receive a grant provided under subsection (b)(3).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAC85D195474A4581A2382CC3DE67C5B2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Services in different languages</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the website under this section provides the widest possible access to services for families who speak languages other than English.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H076FB5D863224C17B403DD2E16351C0A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header>
<paragraph id="HD83C769B1FFF464283DF5A1B838D44FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the website is established under this section, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on—</text> <subparagraph id="HE72869D7805C46859B942B3379E7ACEB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the traffic of the website;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8862D520FBD44A1DAF6432B44970BF91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>user feedback on the accessibility and helpfulness of the website in tailoring to the user’s needs;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H48A47CDFCEB34867881A4975CE51DC1A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">insights on gaps in relevant resources with respect to services for pregnant and postpartum women, or women parenting young children;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H49366EE4692847C8B1CB2ACB33B38B78"><enum>(D)</enum><text>suggestions on how to improve user experience and accessibility based on user feedback and missing resources that would be helpful to include in future updates; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H723C2033C0ED47F19B37CFFA31C90DD4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>certification that no prohibited entities are listed as a relevant resource or are in receipt of a grant under subsection (b)(3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7C5C344B731D4B7CB2CDE0E0B37F1C0B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text>The report under paragraph (1) shall not include any personal identifying information regarding individuals who have used the website.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD23E68F2B0F6411E8F2936B614C18BDD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding</header> <paragraph id="H9228E26C59F54D31B448A23F9561920B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Website</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), this section shall be carried out using amounts available under the heading <quote>General Departmental Management—Office of the Secretary—Department of Health and Human Services</quote> under the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H42CFE6C0C2D6482D85A1879233C83CA9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant program</header>
<subparagraph id="H964B659B289947FDA6963CA252F70DC6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (b)(3) shall be carried out using amounts available for—</text> <clause id="H88A37894C6A94ED38BFDD9CCE9456BCE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the State Personal Responsibility Education Program under section 513 of the Social Security Act;</text></clause>
<clause id="H6CB7692D661E4374BD8AB82300767522"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>title X of the Public Health Service Act; or</text></clause> <clause id="H844303B59FD145A1991081468D97A5C0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the provisions of law specified in clauses (i) and (ii).</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8595DD89481F4A5C8CFD077A2D62C86E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorized amount</header><text>Of the amounts specified in subparagraph (A), the Secretary may use not more than $50,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEADEFF53E4AA4ABEAC2A72E0907D2D25"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed as prohibiting the appropriation of funds to carry out this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H4F59FFE766804C24B6D56376B52CDEC0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H00DE8B92F4BF4C7CBA778ADE24624183"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Abortion</header><text>The term <term>abortion</term> means the use or prescription of any instrument, medicine, drug, or any other substance or device to intentionally—</text>
<subparagraph id="H253FD585628847489FD6DA7DAA33F365"><enum>(A)</enum><text>kill the unborn child of a woman known to be pregnant; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H95B91759F287487BA8502568A84EAD84"><enum>(B)</enum><text>terminate the pregnancy of a woman known to be pregnant, with an intention other than—</text>
<clause id="H3D9F364614F946A49D05EE5D572D5496"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">after viability, to produce a live birth and preserve the life and health of the child born alive;</text></clause> <clause id="H19273B62160C4ACD9AFA47977039BF2B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to remove a dead unborn child; or</text></clause>
<clause id="HEE60AB7896C34B46A854F1250024DCA0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to treat an ectopic pregnancy.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H979FEA3391774DE0BF2B7A2CEDDBD800"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Born alive</header><text>The term <term>born alive</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8(b) of title 1, United States Code.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4E6A7EDF9413467B935965ED902CCB93"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibited entity</header><text>The term <term>prohibited entity</term> means an entity, including its affiliates, subsidiaries, successors, and clinics that performs, induces, refers for, or counsels in favor of abortions, or provides financial support to any other organization that conducts such activities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H76B8118E601845CBB1075AF6B578E191"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Relevant resources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>relevant resources</term> means the Federal, State, local governmental, and private resources that serve pregnant and postpartum women, or women parenting young children, in the categories of the following topics:</text>
<subparagraph id="HFC7CE11D22BC42048516EB598D472D86"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mentorship opportunities, including pregnancy and parenting help and case management resources.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3B8BA219DAE14F4098FB974CFD5A89C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Health and well-being services, including women’s medical services such as obstetrical and gynecological support services for women, abortion pill reversal, breastfeeding, general health services, primary care, and dental care.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDE08D952BA954DC584094864D1F2EFD5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Financial assistance, work opportunities, nutrition assistance, childcare, and education opportunities for parents.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2908B659CBC6477D923F7338BADAE764"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Material or legal support, including transportation, food, nutrition, clothing, household goods, baby supplies, housing, shelters, maternity homes, tax preparation, legal support for child support, family leave, breastfeeding protections, and custody issues.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCE33D74275EA435FABA6F6D656AA71C0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Recovery and mental health services, including services with respect to addiction or suicide intervention, intimate partner violence, sexual assault, rape, sex trafficking, and counseling for women and families surrounding the unexpected loss of a child.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDE4A99F92550445691D2C4F06BA5D081"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Prenatal diagnostic services, including disability support organizations, medical interventions for a baby, perinatal hospice resources, pregnancy and infant loss support, and literature on pregnancy wellness.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBAFE196F988B4BD2AAEA0C2FD64F6C3E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Healing and support services for abortion survivors and their families.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE0B3E4880A6B41A1A2AF9B9A22EFCA84"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Services providing childcare, adoption, foster care, and short-term childcare services and resources.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H32BE78CBB2CC4CF9BBCA6EA73E11501A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Comprehensive information on alternatives to abortion.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H99831852ED354D2E865F708A7DCF4E41"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Information about abortion risks, including complications and failures.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFF69AC38046B43CA9DAF9352E883B066"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Links to information on child development from moment of conception.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6E0F1341BE6D4C778113F715E13CF92A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Unborn child</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>unborn child</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1841(d) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6C1A8F3C14384CF9AD183C06856BFB02"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Website</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>website</quote> means the public website entitled <quote>pregnancy.gov</quote> required to be established under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

