<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9645AFAB4DE44A29807EC52341F3FCB9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1489 IH: Reinforcing Sanctions on Iranian Terrorists Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1489</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250221">February 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001216">Mr. Mills</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the application of sanctions regarding Mahan Air.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7989502C932A4C50AF4EDFB98A20A7DF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0CAB0C20FB66479BA12F0165D883A208" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reinforcing Sanctions on Iranian Terrorists Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H017252C85B6440B7BD77BBED588A9E39" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Application of Sanctions Regarding Mahan Air</header> <subsection id="H733A516E0C16419A860766C1C7C59B50"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HD90B1C6EBEBE4AA798FAF6A569329ED0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Mahan Air was added on October 12, 2011, to the Specially Designated Nationals list maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury, freezing its assets under United States jurisdiction and prohibiting transactions with United States parties, pursuant to Executive Order 13224 (September 23, 2001; relating to blocking property and prohibiting transactions with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism), which targets terrorists and their supporters.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD1621E96A3042BC8A3117EEE75B5807"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In announcing additional sanctions against Mahan Air on March 24, 2016, the Department of the Treasury stated that <quote>Based in Tehran, Iran, Mahan Air has facilitated [Islamic Revolutionary Guards Corps—Qods Force] transportation and arms and funds shipments. Mahan Air also continues to support the Iranian government’s destabilizing actions in the region by conducting flights to Syria in order to transport fighters. Mahan Air regularly uses the same aircraft it flies to Syria to fly commercial passenger routes to international destinations in Europe, the Middle East, and Asia.</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H838F68A5FEA54AEFBA859AC5CAF59AFF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Mahan Air reportedly serves the following destinations in Iran: Abadan Airport, Ahvaz International Airport, Ardabil Airport, Persian Gulf Airport, Bandar Abbas International Airport, Birjand International Airport, Bojnord International Airport, Iranshahr Airport, Isfahan International Airport, Kalaleh Airport, Kerman Airport, Shahid Ashrafi Esffahani Airport, Khorramabad Airport, Kish Airport, Larestan International Airport, Mashhad International Airport, Queshm International Airport, Sahahdaj Airport, Dasht-e Naz Airport, Shiraz International Airport, Sirjan Airport, Tabriz International Airport, Tehran Imam Khomeini International Airport, Mehrabad International Airport, Zabol Airport, Zahedan International Airport, and Zanjan Airport.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H967076208B184B5E913058FD1405F441"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Iran Airports Company, a State-owned enterprise, is the holding and operating company for civilian airports in Iran that facilitates Mahan Air’s operations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H04973DB6D4E747968F08EA3889CE3574"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Foreign persons that assist in, sponsor, or provide financial, material, or technological support for, or financial or other services to or in support of Mahan Air should be subject to United States sanctions pursuant to Executive Order 13224.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H32A3E70FB01B46989AAA05CA1E014BB3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination</header> <paragraph id="H4D32843090644DCE80C78DD97CF06011"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a determination as to whether to apply sanctions, in whole or in part, with respect to the Iran Airports Company pursuant to Executive Order 13224.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF29160B7DE8B4EE8BE05270522632DE8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The determination required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

