<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H626DDA63676740D6B6EA7E9DCEC04166" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3871 IH: Apprenticeship Infrastructure Tax Credit Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3871</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250610">June 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a credit to employers who hire individuals through an apprenticeship program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H33464F177F124E41A861A1C34962CA56" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBF2BC312DCAF430FB09397C19F333B52" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Apprenticeship Infrastructure Tax Credit Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H5C9ED2344EBE4E41A7D31DD037977B62"><enum>2.</enum><header>Apprenticeship infrastructure tax credit for employers</header> 
<subsection id="H5588E9C7665B410A9A2D93AFC69F310B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H899D40F5B7A242AD9368D70A3A2B0B59" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H9BA5B656F1044082942833F5D81938C3"><enum>45BB.</enum><header>Apprenticeship infrastructure tax credit for employers</header> <subsection id="HD1D8BF5B9FE34CB0B58F93CF7FDBC41C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 38, the apprenticeship infrastructure tax credit determined under this section for the taxable year is an amount equal to the sum of the applicable credit amounts determined during the apprenticeship credit period with respect to each apprenticeship employee of the employer.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB5A76744F94448D3A6D4B95BEC981DFC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicable credit amount</header><text>For purposes of this section, the applicable credit amount with respect to an apprenticeship employee shall be an amount equal to—</text> <paragraph id="H1D6E7A832F6B4776ABFF39F3596C2462"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of an apprenticeship employee not described in paragraph (2), $3,000, and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H13FD57C592D6433EA6D35BF467D3DA77"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of a recently separated veteran, a member of the National Guard or reserve component of the Armed Forces, or a military spouse, $6,000.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">The applicable credit amount with respect to an apprenticeship employee for taxable years beginning after the end of the apprenticeship credit period (determined without regard to subsection (c)(2)) shall be zero.</continuation-text></subsection> <subsection id="H1C7E4315E630410E9C01E2564C72DFF2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Apprenticeship credit period</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE48A6F1D96D94B05B2809EA3738643CF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The apprenticeship credit period with respect to an apprenticeship employee shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="H8231CC7E7C7C42E7AC4D827ACAE29CF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the taxable year during which such employee first enrolls in the employer’s qualified registered apprenticeship program, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6284D2932867438D9661ED485E98C115"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the succeeding taxable year if the qualified registered apprenticeship program in which such employee is enrolled is—</text> <clause id="H1643377338C24AEB8037C9E9E0FA8C52"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a time-based or hybrid program that requires 3,000 or more on-the-job learning hours, or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1DDBA774C11843318281577C15CE6AED"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a competency-based program with 3,000 or more on-the-job learning hours.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H51975B1D7E7F4605AA4742F4540F44EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Carryforward year</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The apprenticeship credit period with respect to an apprenticeship employee shall include the taxable year succeeding the taxable year described in subparagraph (A) or (B), as the case may be, in the case a credit carryforward to such succeeding taxable year with respect to an apprentice employee under subsection (d)(7).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD63F5EE2BF67475C8D2746278FB6961E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions and special rules</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H6A93B784C89842F7B6F32B027716023C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Apprenticeship employee</header> <subparagraph id="H66B9AE52FD28494D963933DD8C26E8CF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>apprenticeship employee</term> means an individual who—</text> 
<clause id="H4E126B3728D04169B1769CDED819AAE2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a new hire employed by an apprenticeship employer, and</text></clause> <clause id="H705CEBFED60148888A69E3584261EC33"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>enrolled under a written agreement in a qualified registered apprenticeship program with respect to an infrastructure-related occupation.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB328BD1C500E44F0A2FAEACCB8801D36"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Infrastructure-related occupation</header> 
<clause id="HC50FC97AD3774EA4899B735EBF38B7AA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>infrastructure-related occupation</term> means an occupation identified by the Secretary of Labor as eligible for the credit determined under this section.</text></clause> <clause id="H56BC80D6C1CD4DC2AF6FA4204626FD77"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Initial list applicable to <enum-in-header>2026</enum-in-header></header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For taxable years beginning in 2026, such term shall include occupations within the following major groups as defined in the Occupational Information Network (ONET):</text> 
<subclause id="H7960788DA38F4C5B9FC107EAEC170E25"><enum>(I)</enum><text>47–0000 Construction and Extraction Occupations.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H932CD3EE3D624B539F3691286E299919"><enum>(II)</enum><text>49–0000 Installation, Maintenance, and Repair Occupations.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H45557AD3357E41F69E9DE94382C927ED"><enum>(III)</enum><text>51–0000 Production Occupations.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE2C1753B3D3B487C9624C27E906D3FE1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>15–1200 Computer, Information Technology, and Security Occupations.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H366C17C438A24EA0BD40ED7701252F23"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Subsequent years</header><text>Occupations shall be identified under this subparagraph by utilizing standardized and occupation specific descriptors listed in the Occupational Network (ONET), and such occupations shall be updated annually consistent with customary tax document deadlines.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3FEE1BEA152D4910A7C7D044C44727C6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The term <term>apprenticeship employee</term> shall not include any apprentice—</text> 
<clause id="HA17E6EBD69164ADA926A6CDA6005CC84"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">hired more than 90 days prior to enrollment into the qualified registered apprenticeship program, or</text></clause> <clause id="H6066B00E507F49748A6619047F851535"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reported via a 1099 contractor rather than Form W–2, based on Internal Revenue Service standards.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4DCB62D004E54E50BAB7B3F7867C7B67"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Apprenticeship employer</header> 
<subparagraph id="H600C1F3B055C4DAA8D89083DE5C86D4D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>apprenticeship employer</term> means an employer that has entered into an agreement with a qualified registered apprenticeship program for the placement of apprenticeship employees.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED9C4467C04544D1BBE639289E353826"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such term shall not include an employer—</text> 
<clause id="HF838353FCC0F468B8459E9B9537225DD"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which is exempt from income tax under this chapter, or</text></clause> <clause id="H435FD88E70354B6EA476CB991D1613DF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which is the sponsor of the registered apprenticeship program, or is related to the sponsor for which the apprenticeship employee is enrolled.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA04BC0E2D23447DB90B435762E86495D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified registered apprenticeship program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified registered apprenticeship program</term> means an apprenticeship registered under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>) that meets the standards of subpart A of part 29 and part 30 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF5B41D6923C4B40A969BBF5346F93C2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Recently separated veteran</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>recently separated veteran</term> means any veteran who is enrolled into the qualified registered apprenticeship program to which the credit relates not more than 4 years after having been discharged or released from active duty in the Armed Forces of the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H29C22DE883E54B108E765A618C0DB339"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Member of National Guard or reserve component of Armed Forces</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term member of the National Guard or reserve component of the Armed Forces means any member of a reserve component of the Armed Forces (as defined in section 10101 of title 10, United States Code).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1537788AD7B42FE8215FCC981382ABD"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Military spouse</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>military spouse</term> means an individual who is legally married to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H867D33A4BEA24CEABFFAFB8C4C51E549"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a member of the Armed Forces on active duty,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCF3244B9E9BA422EAB19BF58A2D9E813"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a member of the National Guard or reserve component, or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H150B6F6BC14E4EE8BA8A546F7229208B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a veteran who was discharged or released from active duty in the Armed Forces of the United States not before the 4-year period ending on the date the individual enrolls in the qualified registered apprenticeship program to which the credit relates.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC975A3E4E73E4ECDABC62DAB875AC5BA"><enum>(7)</enum><header>New hire</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>new hire</term> means an individual who first begins work as an employee for the employer not more than 90 days before such individual’s enrollment in qualified registered apprenticeship program to which the credit determined under this section with respect to the employee relates.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1D1BFAC897C14D17A5884117F9DEA8D8"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Reduced credit where apprentice employed for fewer than 180 days</header> 
<subparagraph id="H398A38521487495E96214DB0FCBC79D8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a taxable year during which the apprenticeship employee is employed under a qualified apprenticeship program of the employer for at least 90 days, but fewer than 180 days, the applicable credit amount with respect to such employee for such taxable year shall be reduced to the amount which bears the same ratio to the applicable credit amount with respect to such employee (determined without regard to this subparagraph) as—</text> <clause id="H2648424BE8FB48C8B2CD207F5F47FAC7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of calendar days during the taxable year that the apprenticeship employee is so employed, bears to</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF003E4E38F734EBE96204521B7CAC8B2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>180.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1601E2DD85404DB28682234169079728"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Fewer than 90 days</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a taxable year during which the apprenticeship employee is employed under a qualified apprenticeship program of the employer for fewer than 90 days, the applicable credit amount with respect to such employee for such taxable year shall be zero.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE3B97B3AD4B445B2AA7A2892723493F1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Carryforward</header><text>The amount by which the credit amount is reduced under subparagraph (A) or (B) with respect to an apprenticeship employee for any taxable year may be carried forward to increase the applicable credit amount otherwise determined with respect to the employee under this section for the succeeding taxable year (determined without regard to this subparagraph and subsection (c)(2)). Any amount carried forward under the preceding sentence shall be subject to any reduction applicable with respect to the employee under subparagraphs (A) and (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9F68D356A25F4CB58CE7BDF9E113AB6B"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Coordination with other credits</header><text>The amount of credit otherwise allowable under this chapter with respect to compensation paid to any apprenticeship employee shall be reduced by the credit determined under this section with respect to such employee.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H45B03B9FCA6C4D488872BF5AE43A1E98"><enum>(10)</enum><header>No credit allowed in case laid-off apprentice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No credit shall be allowed under this section with respect to an apprenticeship employee if during the taxable year such employee is involuntary terminated by reason of a reduction in workforce or job elimination, business closure, downsizing, or restructuring, or any other non­ disciplinary termination initiated by the employer.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C24A81C0B7A4FAF8DB1817FDBA3E225"><enum>(11)</enum><header>No credit allowed in case of remuneration from apprenticeship employee</header> <subparagraph id="H6930F6C4CD934919943A2F263F1B3968"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No credit shall be allowed under this section with respect to an apprenticeship employee if such apprenticeship employee provides any remuneration (including tuition, application fees, or other payments) to either the apprenticeship employer or the sponsor of the qualified registered apprenticeship program in connection with the apprenticeship employee’s participation in such program.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9A0D04649918481EA9C2B00BB0A11F2D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception for public or non-profit funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to remuneration provided by the apprenticeship employee if such remuneration is sourced from public funding or private non-profit or foundational organizations intended to serve or support apprenticeship employees, including funding from the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, Pell Grants, the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program, Temporary Assistance for Needy Families, or other similar public or private non-profit or foundational organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7C047FFB3A0E4F1783D6D884D7640602"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Apprenticeship tax credit eligibility certificate</header> <paragraph id="H6B92689B28104CF0A9EF8E4E281C3899"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No credit shall be allowed to an employer under this section with respect to an apprenticeship employee under an apprenticeship program, unless the employer has received an apprenticeship tax credit eligibility certificate with respect to such apprenticeship employee.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA8AB59EFBFC04EC592CEB328EED7642A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Issuance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor shall use data from the Registered Apprenticeship Partners Information Database System (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as <quote>RAPIDS</quote>) to issue an apprenticeship tax credit eligibility certificates to apprenticeship employers not later than 31 days after the end of each calendar quarter. Such certificate shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H90F37513095F407AA01AF8E800B970C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Information identifying to the sponsor of the qualified registered apprenticeship program, including—</text> 
<clause id="H699EF5D0995541E0BB385BD502780FAE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the name of the sponsor,</text></clause> <clause id="H111916BF59B84041A918E4D142B8368E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the registration agency responsible for monitoring the sponsor,</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2BCB632FD40F4E4D812FB66FB15D47C4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the registration number of the registered apprenticeship program,</text></clause> <clause id="H2C89FA57643540EAA817E810ADCC3C3A"> <enum>(iv)</enum> <text>the O–Net Code for occupation of training, and</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="HD4EF6E43B88843A0BB81B3FAA17D40A0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the RAPIDS Code for the apprenticeable occupation approved by the Department of Labor Office of Apprenticeship.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H29BA5A1285984448A08246821B829177"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Information identifying the apprenticeship employer, including—</text> 
<clause id="H912C0CCE09EF452BA45DC994181B8795"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the full legal name of the apprenticeship employer,</text></clause> <clause id="H0B4D5CBFBED94196965A42D07BF9761C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the mailing address of the apprenticeship employer,</text></clause> 
<clause id="H76287A0487EA4BE18F84599142AFA7FB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the employer registration number assigned in RAPIDS, and</text></clause> <clause id="H4ED8A31EEADD4443B8CC4736B270458D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the apprenticeship employer’s Federal Employer Identification Number.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1E7BC1D427874B06ABCC76EBB480A4EF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Information identifying the apprenticeship employee, including—</text> <clause id="HDE6E05F224164B9DA951F6AF94B7CEDE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the full legal name of such employee,</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7E651E66FAAF4D908F0FC21B1332CAFD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the social security number or taxpayer identification number of such employee,</text></clause> <clause id="HBE8B7A084A704BF9841E8D5EBD2784FB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the dates of apprenticeship, including the enrollment date, expected completion date, the actual completion date (if applicable), the date hired by the apprenticeship employer, the termination date (if any), and the reason for exit if such employee is not employed on the last day of the period to which such certificate relates, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H458F12C75E4E4AABA7673C444CEBFE5E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">confirmation that the apprenticeship employee is a new hire with respect to the employer and is reported via Form W–2.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB81B9F72E8FE4154B4FCF5CB0E813734"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Updating apprentice status rules</header> <subparagraph id="H615CCCFC6908416898371A2D248CBC17"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall update the reporting requirements set forth in part 29 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations, which otherwise require a sponsor to update the status of an apprentice within 45 days of any change in such status, to further require that the sponsor ensure all employment status updates are completed within 30 days after the close of a calendar quarter in order to facilitate the issuance of the apprenticeship tax credit eligibility certificate not later than 31 days after the end of the calendar quarter. The Secretary of Labor may prescribe regulations to ensure compliance with this reporting requirement.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC90ACC191518456CBF25B346FC6C9CE5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Apprenticeship agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor shall update apprenticeship agreement forms to include the following:</text> <clause id="H68FF19E589EA41DBB353928141F6FF4B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The date the apprenticeship employee was hired by the apprenticeship employer.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H01A697AD00E842FD9FC2BB75562038CC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The apprenticeship employer confirmation that the apprenticeship employee is reported via Form W–2.</text></clause> <clause id="H968947F050224B03936D0E6265951C89"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The assigned registration number of the apprenticeship employer verifying the apprenticeship employer has a formal agreement with the sponsor of the qualified registered apprenticeship program.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFD170AB28A3C47FA8518CEA50DF2C339"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination of credit based on volume cap</header> 
<paragraph id="HCDA0C0ADDA65471D8FE9690E196E1203"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall not apply for any taxable year beginning after the date on which the Secretary (in consultation with the Secretary of Labor) certifies that the amount of credit determined under this section has reached an amount equal to $5,000,000,000.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF181C8CFFD3D4365AACA0A621C1F261E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Tracking and reporting</header> <subparagraph id="H3299D06DA2894F8A8E1D56C681387C12"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Secretary of Treasury</header> <clause id="H4ED786C6A1DC496C9743D3F3A7870AB3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall for purposes of paragraph (1) monitor and regularly calculate the amount of credit determined under this section and publicly certify when the limitation under paragraph (1) has been reached.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFF149677FCE24DABA64EBE39F61EF82D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Annual reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall not later than March 31, 2027, and annually thereafter, publish an report that details the total amount of credits determined under this section for taxable years ending in the preceding calendar year, the amount of any under-allocated credits identified under paragraph (4)(A), the take-up rate of certificates issued under this section for the preceding calendar year, and the total number of certificates issued under this section for the preceding calendar year.</text></clause> <clause id="H95088D954F784C5DA4B2BC4C3C80A60A"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Take-up rate</header><text>For purposes of clause (ii), the term <term>take-up rate</term> means the percentage of apprenticeship tax credit eligibility certificates issued under subsection (e) that result in credits determined under this section, as determined by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2B641920F2DB44F6B7C113F7B0D08BB3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Secretary of Labor</header> 
<clause id="H4B81B0F917A54C44A9B5004CED44D066"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary, shall annually review the determinations made by the Secretary under subparagraph (A) and estimate the extent to which credit limitation under paragraph (1) remains available.</text></clause> <clause id="H774688AF204F48FBA756CE7BEF712E36"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Commensurate adjustment of qualifying infrastructure-related occupations</header><text>Based on such review and estimates, the Secretary of Labor may adjust the list of qualifying infrastructure-related occupations identified under section subsection (e) to limit the issuance of additional apprenticeship tax credit eligibility certificates if necessary to ensure, to the extent practicable, the limitation under paragraph (1) is not exceeded before December 31, 2035.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFCD86423DE1C4183830136A1AB2BAD96"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Annual reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For taxable years beginning after December 31, 2026, any adjustments to the list of qualifying infrastructure-related occupations for a year shall be published by the Secretary not later than September 30 of the preceding year.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA76BA445B5DF410B818C476D218F5707"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation or prioritization when remaining balance is low</header> <subparagraph id="H73A9582501C243E699B507129A3234EF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When the remaining balance of credits allowable under this section, as determined by the Secretary under paragraph (2)(A), is less than $1,000,000,000, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, may prescribe any of the following:</text> 
<clause id="H8E0B82E55A50481DA2675965D8F241DE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Limiting the qualifying infrastructure-related occupations identified under subsection (d)(1)(B) for which apprenticeship tax credit eligibility certificates may be issued.</text></clause> <clause id="H65D76E1926F54886AF9C985B30DAC8DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Directing the issuance of such certificates to focus on apprenticeship employees who are recently separated veterans, members of the National Guard or Reserve Component of the Armed Forces, or military spouses.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H23BEE66CF1F44FDF85367B03AD896AFC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determination of certificates issued</header> 
<clause id="HFF9F42E99F8C4E2CB71B1B30B2EB8887"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Use of take-up rate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the annual report under paragraph (2)(A)(ii) has been issued for the preceding calendar years, the number of certificates issued under this paragraph shall be determined by adjusting the proportional allocation under paragraph (4)(C)(ii)(I) based on the take-up rate reported under paragraph (2)(A)(ii) for such year, to ensure that the estimated credit amount resulting from such issuance does not exceed the remaining balance under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1ADE38F800704211AE69B7085D98E598"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reallocation of under-allocated credits</header> <subparagraph id="H14591BC114C741088458D7076B1F5EAB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may identify, as part of the annual report required under paragraph (2)(A), any under-allocated portion of any apprenticeship infrastructure tax credits or other <quote>labor related</quote> tax credits for a prior taxable year.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEC7D4B2EF26F42CA8F7D3FF776EEB0C3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Under-allocated credits</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>under-allocated credits</term> means the difference between the estimated credit amounts associated with credits determined under this section for the preceding calendar year (as reported under paragraph (2)(B)) and the actual amount of credits claimed by any taxable entity (as reported under paragraph (2)(A)), to the extent such difference reflects credits that remain available within the volume cap under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9B394D7F63484DDA9B1B68CEF80B4DBC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Additional allocation by Secretary of Labor</header> <clause id="H1E38BC2DB9EF4A049A31EAD751D27BA4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon notification from the Secretary of under-allocated credits identified under subparagraph (A), the Secretary of Labor may provide for additional allocation of such credits by issuing additional apprenticeship tax credit eligibility certificates for the succeeding calendar year, subject to the limitations of clause (ii).</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H31E813AA6F5D4156B0707A221B546671"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>The limitations of this clause are as follows:</text> <subclause id="H5A58A6CA68E4453BA663A108DD6BEC85"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the annual report under paragraph (2)(A)(ii) has been issued for the preceding calendar year, the number of certificates issued under this paragraph shall be equal to the total number of certificates issued in the preceding calendar year, as reported under paragraph (2)(A)(ii), adjusted by the take-up rate for such year, to ensure that the estimated credit amount resulting from such issuance does not exceed the remaining balance under this section.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H6C58C353079C49E093E12EF0E8C4BAB8"><enum>(II)</enum><header>No annual report</header><text>If the annual report under paragraph (2)(A)(ii) has not been issued for the preceding calendar year, the number of certificates issued under this paragraph shall be equal to the total number of certificates issued in the preceding calendar year increased by 30 percent.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H4DA1282BC21C48009A1D59038C60AC7C"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The issuance of additional certificates under this paragraph shall not cause the aggregate volume cap under paragraph (1) to be exceeded.</text></subclause></clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1FDB44479BFE48179C0C1C9CE545E2F3"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor shall include in the annual report required under paragraph (2)(B) a summary of any additional allocations made under this paragraph, including the number of additional certificates issued, the estimated amount of credits associated with such certificates, the actual amount of credits determined under this section for the preceding calendar year (as reported by the Secretary under paragraph (2)(A)), and the occupations targeted by the additional allocations.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1F1522FB4CC5435090AAA47F7FD0D37E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall prescribe such rules as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including guidance for verifying the status of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2BDE674472A64BBFAABECCC8547429D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>individuals as recently separated veterans, Members of the National Guard or Reserve Component of the Armed Forces, or military spouses,</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6EAE3E9E734E4D11B8FA9125D8BA811E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">qualified registered apprenticeship programs,</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFDF51DB588934715B3706D669D0B4E89"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">apprenticeship employers and apprenticeship employees, and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H177F33B2CB34437298382F6145070D98"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">apprenticeship employees, including that such employees are reported via Form W–2, not a 1099 contractor, based on Internal Revenue Service standards.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3C272D7BD355413C8A26F12BBA154E1E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text>Section 280C(a) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>45BB(a),</quote> after <quote>45S(a),</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD4C1115BC48F47F6BD158B6B2301780C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Credit made part of general business credit</header><text>Section 38(b) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (40), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (41) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4CF4CF72042A4994A16A4727384CB924" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H9558D413BF354BBCA0C8113C1ABF78DF"><enum>(42)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the apprenticeship tax credit determined under section 45BB(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HD332DAA83E2E471A96785A877D58304C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB478AE6B94474D3187754A5E2B301A9C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 45BB. Apprenticeship tax credit for employers.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H13FA2D083A4F4CD38983F0B6188045B4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

