<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H96B27AB382A3416A9A7BE75597EED07D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3507 IH: Legislative Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3507</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250520">May 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the chairs of committees of the House of Representatives and the Senate to submit certain information to the Clerk of the House of Representatives or the Secretary of the Senate with respect to reported bills and joint resolutions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H28E103D80C7140A9ACEE59CD5BA192EE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H42630BDB633946D0A58465C21A5E9F60" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Legislative Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H2E20F7A2E53F49649616ACB33495C076"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirements with respect to inclusion of certain information for bills and joint resolutions</header> 
<subsection id="HAE2F5EEBE3FA4565B69300ACCAAB6ADF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements with respect to certain amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="H2CD3F600E8CE40B0AA059472244AAD18"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to a bill or joint resolution reported by a committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate, the chair of such committee shall submit to the Clerk of the House of Representatives or the Secretary of the Senate (as the case may be), not later than 3 legislative days after the date that the bill or resolution is reported by the committee, the name of any Member of Congress who submitted an amendment to the bill or resolution which was adopted by the committee.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E03319620484889971E1204F0F94C42"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amendments adopted with respect to matters that pass either House</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a bill or joint resolution passed by the House of Representatives or the Senate, the chair of the Committee on Rules of the House or the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate shall submit to the Clerk of the House of Representatives or the Secretary of the Senate (as the case may be), not later than 3 legislative days after the date that the bill or resolution is passed by such House, the name of any Member of Congress who submitted an amendment to the bill or resolution which was adopted by such House.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H54135B87DBEE49E8B97CD36570162102"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special rule with respect to matters reported by certain committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a bill or joint resolution reported by the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives or the Senate, the Committee on Ways and Means of the House, or the Committee on Finance of the Senate, the chair of such committee shall submit to the Clerk of the House of Representatives or the Secretary of the Senate (as the case may be), not later than 3 legislative days after the date that the bill or resolution is reported by the committee, the name of each Member of Congress who is responsible for the inclusion of a provision in the bill or resolution as reported by the committee.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA99876E303F840EB8B3CA3662E0A3B79"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inclusion of certain information in bills or resolutions</header><text>The Clerk of the House of Representatives, the Secretary of the Senate (as the case may be), and the Director of the Government Publishing Office shall ensure that any name submitted under subsection (a) or (b) with respect to a bill or resolution is included in any reported, engrossed, enrolled or enacted version of the bill or resolution in the form of a footnote that indicates which adopted amendment or provision in the bill or resolution any such Member submitted for or is otherwise responsible for its inclusion in such version of the bill or resolution, as applicable.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB6D8074688244F7EBCB5B6468A248E60"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Member of Congress defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>Member of Congress</term> means a Senator or Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HA316E7987E0442798F972C66AE5B3488" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exercise of rulemaking powers</header><text>The provisions of this section are enacted by the Congress—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7A157DA143C14F5DB65178620D77646C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the House of Representatives and the Senate, respectively, and as such they shall be considered as part of the rules of each House, respectively, or of that House to which they specifically apply, and such rules shall supersede other rules only to the extent that they are inconsistent therewith; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD55A5AE6E7004F8AADEA853811263F28"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change such rules (so far as relating to such House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of such House.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

