<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public"
    dms-id="HB99D2D555DE34E78823A2E90D16881FE" key="H">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3508 IH: End Diaper Need Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
        <congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
        <legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3508</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
        <action display="yes">
            <action-date date="20250520">May 20, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor
                    name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor
                    name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which
                was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and
                    Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name
                    committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be
                subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
                provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title display="yes">To provide targeted funding for States and other eligible
            entities through the Social Services Block Grant program to address the increased burden
            that maintaining the health and hygiene of infants and toddlers, medically complex
            children, and low-income adults or adults with disabilities who rely on adult
            incontinence materials and supplies place on families in need, the resultant adverse
            health effects on children and families, and the limited child care options available
            for infants and toddlers who lack sufficient diapers and diapering supplies, and for
            other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"
        id="H3447BBA0F6754249A5E35CCA7094334A">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="H18718CD378A140B194F8A59AC8F018A2">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>End Diaper Need Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="H8CC793CD11BF4D2AB6742C5E88B08E14">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Targeted funding for diaper assistance (including diapering supplies and adult
                incontinence materials and supplies) through the Social Services Block Grant
                Program</header>
            <subsection id="HFA4D6B04A5184B79874C5C7FE347B984">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Increase in funding for Social Services Block Grant Program</header>
                <paragraph id="HAF0D2912E28D4A828F1CFF31B2596225">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount specified in subsection (c) of section 2003 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397b">42 U.S.C. 1397b</external-xref>) for purposes of subsections (a) and (b) of such section is deemed to be $1,900,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029. Each State shall use the increase in funding the State receives as a result of this section in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H7B7FBC188672404A8F72BFC74BFFAF85">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Appropriation</header>
                    <subparagraph id="HBF7D205FB1E3444592E4E151A30E49A2">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                        <header>In general</header>
 <text>Out of any money in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated, there is appropriated $200,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029, to carry out this section.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H25CAF6FF9D1A4B1C995B00CBB2E10EFE">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <header>Reservations</header>
                        <clause id="HF0ABAAE41A1F4293AC42EF6C59FF3B46">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
                            <header>Purposes</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall reserve, from the amount appropriated under subparagraph (A) to carry out this section—</text>
                            <subclause id="H1172C4FE361C48D39447BB17DB5A0610">
                                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029, not more than 2 percent of the amount appropriated for the fiscal year for purposes of entering into an agreement with a national entity described in subparagraph (C) to assist in providing technical assistance and training, to support effective policy, practice, research, and cross-system collaboration among grantees and subgrantees, and to assist in the administration of the program described in this section; and</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="HEFBB3050AB31440AB55B089D2A260302">
                                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>for fiscal year 2026, an amount, not to exceed $3,000,000, for purposes of conducting an evaluation under subsection (d).</text>
                            </subclause>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H864AF15CD31C4F85A331FA853FB108FF">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
                            <header>No State entitlement to reserved funds</header>
 <text>The State entitlement under section 2002(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397a">42 U.S.C. 1397a(a)</external-xref>) shall not apply to the amounts reserved under clause (i).</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HD8AA9DA6AEAC4F6BBFBB9577D19B7C2F">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
                        <header>National entity described</header>
 <text>A national entity described in this subparagraph is a nonprofit organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code, that—</text>
                        <clause id="HC50423B5921542DAA804F276424B51A0">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>has experience in more than 1 State in the area of—</text> <subclause id="H0A6A6B92DE994362A4222327A6D5F139"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>community distributions of basic need services, including experience collecting, warehousing, and distributing basic necessities such as diapers, food, or menstrual products;</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="H3DB3DA18B5554916B24DE42B903D7E0F">
                                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>child care;</text> </subclause> <subclause id="HAE45798FC596482CA71DF1077CE23A99"> <enum>(III)</enum> <text>child development activities in low-income communities; or</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="HD94CA94522B44111B7555AE9961DF9B4">
                                <enum>(IV)</enum>
 <text>motherhood, fatherhood, or parent education efforts serving low-income parents of young children;</text>
                            </subclause>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H923BF02B4D574FA48DC954FD4966889C">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>demonstrates competency to implement a project, provide fiscal accountability, collect data, and prepare reports and other necessary documentation; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HB64EB73EFEA24B3C895439483178261C">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>demonstrates a willingness to share information with researchers, practitioners, and other interested parties.</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" id="H69CBF4C802E948F9B7A8B0680E0B14AB">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Rules governing use of additional funds</header>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H32B9D74BBE754E2196F4D4458587CB00">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>Funds are used in accordance with this subsection if—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H969A144F90BD4343A2755A52B94D7FB0"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the State, in consultation with relevant stakeholders, including agencies, professional associations, and nonprofit organizations, distributes the funds to eligible entities to—</text>
                        <clause id="H2C17C1F4CFEF4F2692A5FF330534B012">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>decrease the need for diapers and diapering supplies and adult incontinence materials and supplies in low-income families and meet such unmet needs of infants and toddlers, medically complex children, and low-income adults and adults with disabilities in such families through—</text>
                            <subclause id="HDF0B6F0E389246339398D71820F2F374">
                                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>the distribution of free diapers and diapering supplies, medically necessary diapers, and adult incontinence materials and supplies; and</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="HCF64C92BA8F640569817CEA298934C8D">
                                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>improving access to diapers and diapering supplies, medically necessary diapers, and adult incontinence materials and supplies;</text>
                            </subclause>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HCAB645A5449E4F6581E8A1E9DF256F5E">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out community outreach to assist in participation in diaper distribution programs or programs that distribute medically necessary diapers or adult incontinence materials and supplies; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HB43182CA49EB40F7AD65A3B0072CB1AF">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>increase the ability of communities and low-income families in such communities to provide for the need for diapers and diapering supplies, medically necessary diapers, and adult continence materials and supplies, of infants and toddlers, medically complex children, and low-income adults and adults with disabilities;</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H07362D1F578B4634958E61FD0FD5BB5D">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the funds are used subject to the limitations in section 2005 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397d">42 U.S.C. 1397d</external-xref>); and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H21B3C0A19267429C9BE518ADD0FC8CC4">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the funds are used to supplement, not supplant, State general revenue funds provided for the purposes described in subparagraph (A).</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="HFFA860E2051F49FCAC282B3BC892400B">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Administrative costs</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State receiving funds made available under subsection (a) may use not more than 5 percent of the funds for State administrative costs, which may include costs of contracting, monitoring, and reporting.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H4FA9AF9E1D0249D09C3D9DF47AE09167">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Allowable uses by eligible entities</header>
 <text>An eligible entity receiving funds made available under subsection (a) shall use the funds for any of the following:</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H38F4A2A4EE604F01B5BD5A2F1CA88A72">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>To pay for the purchase and distribution of diapers and diapering supplies, medically necessary diapers, and funding diaper (including medically necessary diapers) distribution that serves low-income families with—</text>
                        <clause id="HE355D645453F41889FD341A477D00D95">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>1 or more children 3 years of age or younger; or</text> </clause> <clause id="H450C7E3C2DC44B5EBBCC557F64CCD3E2"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>1 or more medically complex children.</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H4366A571562242ADA9F348B1430AA1FA">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To pay for the purchase and distribution of adult incontinence materials and supplies and funding distribution of the materials and supplies for low-income families with 1 or more low-income adults, adults with disabilities, or children with a disability who have attained 3 years of age and have not attained 19 years of age, who rely on adult incontinence materials and supplies.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H6FB1DA84F332461B89C3C1CAD3788888">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>To integrate activities carried out under subparagraph (A) with other basic needs assistance programs serving eligible children and their families, including the following:</text>
                        <clause id="HA619624DBD664E5DAFAE9A1810221DE9">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>Programs funded by the temporary assistance for needy families program under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/601">42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>), including the State maintenance of effort provisions of such program.</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H50D991C7F01F41D9AB9158AD10358867">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>Programs designed to support the health of eligible children, such as the Children’s Health Insurance Program under title XXI of the Social Security Act, the Medicaid program under title XIX of such Act, or State funded health care programs.</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HCA245A6127AA4BF89EF373652DDF9D37">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>Programs funded through the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children under section 17 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966.</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H48AD453BAA094F919095CED6A1EEE452">
                            <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>Programs that offer early home visiting services, including the maternal, infant, and early childhood home visiting program (including the Tribal home visiting program) under section 511 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/711">42 U.S.C. 711</external-xref>).</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HD65A6F48813F4779B6C5F3A8755AD17D">
                            <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>Programs to provide improved and affordable access to child care, including programs funded through the Child Care and Development Fund, the temporary assistance for needy families program under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/601">42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>), or a State-funded program.</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H299B63C9F27B414FACC0AB20CE19ABF9">
                            <enum>(vi)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Programs funded under part C of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1431">20 U.S.C. 1431 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H7B36D2472EB843B2A4836EA89BD4E07A">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
                    <header>Availability of funds</header>
                    <subparagraph id="H80A64B8D8A4A4656A918AE5859691240">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                        <header>Funds distributed to eligible entities</header>
 <text>Funds made available under subsection (a) that are distributed to an eligible entity by a State for a fiscal year may be expended by the eligible entity only in such fiscal year or the succeeding fiscal year.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H9A45AC46F77E4E0780B89C677DB7D1C9">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <header>Evaluation</header>
 <text>Funds reserved under subsection (a)(2)(B)(i)(II) to carry out the evaluation under subsection (d) shall be available for expenditure during the 3-year period that begins on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HF596B00E44784CC18832ACB858372BA6">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
                    <header>No effect on other programs</header>
 <text>Any assistance or benefits received by a family through funds made available under subsection (a) shall be disregarded for purposes of determining the family’s eligibility for, or amount of, benefits under any other Federal needs-based programs.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HA99C4F8D014A4FF3AEF55241F66BE1C2">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Annual reports</header>
 <text>A State shall include in the annual report required under section 2006 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397e">42 U.S.C. 1397e</external-xref>) covering each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029, information detailing how eligible entities, including subgrantees, used funds made available under subsection (a) to distribute diapers and diapering supplies and adult incontinence materials and supplies to families in need. Each such report shall include the following:</text>
                <paragraph id="HA92B2CA443A749A29275D10BC1B280BC">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>The number and age of infants, toddlers, medically complex children, and low-income adults and adults with disabilities who received assistance or benefits through such funds.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HA1D4504FCEDE468587C0B1F360377B64">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>The number of families that have received assistance or benefits through such funds.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HF6B44B2ED6994652BC8367E33ADDEDCB">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>The number of diapers, medically necessary diapers, or adult incontinence materials and supplies (such as adult diapers, briefs, protective underwear, pull-ons, pull-ups, liners, shields, guards, pads, undergarments), and the number of each type of diapering or adult incontinence supply, distributed through the use of such funds.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H6C997BA18E1E41E2AF3477BB60BE6139">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>The ZIP Code or ZIP Codes where the eligible entity (or subgrantee) distributed diapers and diapering supplies and adult incontinence materials and supplies.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H02DDC5B7A3B74649891FAFD55EC8FA4F">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>The method or methods the eligible entity (or subgrantee) uses to distribute diapers and diapering supplies and, adult incontinence materials and supplies.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H890FA3B358A7457D9A48361774DFD6DF">
                    <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>Such other information as the Secretary may specify.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H729B0CAC0C8F4822849F20B36A123737"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Evaluation</header> <text>The Secretary, in consultation with States, the national entity described in subsection (a)(2)(C), and eligible entities receiving funds made available under this section, shall—</text>
                <paragraph id="H69F6472F308842FDBCB9094179B5C54A">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act—</text> <subparagraph id="HD2328F4244004D4EB3ACDD5787D8E3FA"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>complete an evaluation of the effectiveness of the assistance program carried out pursuant to this section, such as the effect of activities carried out under this Act on mitigating the health and developmental risks of unmet diaper need among infants, toddlers, medically complex children, and other family members in low-income families, including the risks of diaper dermatitis, urinary tract infections, and parental and child depression and anxiety;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H1751F5B8246F44A09DCCB545723A0F2B">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>submit to the relevant congressional committees a report on the results of such evaluation; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H82DDD8D3808C49128DCCA3C3651942EE">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>publish the results of the evaluation on the internet website of the Department of Health and Human Services;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H2A7FDC32992C4CC49DDCF34A1567BCC0">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, update the evaluation required by paragraph (1)(A); and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H2902A0C1120C4B8DBC9DA33E59EDA3E1">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>not later than 120 days after completion of the updated evaluation under paragraph (2)—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="HD37651D8EB114F1DB1931E6B046AF96C">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>submit to the relevant congressional committees a report describing the results of such updated evaluation; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HB6ADAEB4291141FDAA3FA2B0392B9590">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>publish the results of such evaluation on the internet website of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H22B2A64FE408434F805CBA69114D257C">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Guidance</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue guidance regarding how the provisions of this section should be carried out, including information regarding eligible entities, allowable use of funds, and reporting requirements.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HF9CD510E5C484CE2BEB6BC6D11DB1A4D">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Definitions</header>
 <text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H99D1C17FDB484BDA9103FF06E39DEE37"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Adult incontinence materials and supplies</header> <text>The term <term>adult incontinence materials and supplies</term> means those supplies that are used to assist adults or adults with disabilities and includes adult diapers, briefs, protective underwear, pull-ons, pull-ups, liners, shields, guards, pads, undergarments, disposable wipes, over-the-counter adult diaper rash cream products, intermittent catheterization, indwelling catheters, condom catheters, urinary drainage bags, external collection devices, wearable urinals, and penile clamps.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H4D2E280EFB364632A4C3C0E8D139C8BE">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Adults with disabilities</header>
 <text>The term <term>adults with disabilities</term> means individuals who—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="HFB10291DE5A54335A480B96EFE39E4CB">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>have attained 18 years of age; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F6EF077F4964791B7E99C8F76879808"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>have a disability (as such term is defined, with respect to an individual, in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</external-xref>)).</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H7FD9AF9CCC9A44D0B29B09106399EED6">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Diaper</header>
 <text>The term <term>diaper</term> means an absorbent garment that—</text> <subparagraph id="HCF71E3C7CAAE4D8288E9E8026065DF3D"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>is washable or disposable that may be worn by an infant or toddler who is not toilet-trained; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H7AEEE7B5171D4DF9A56CEC70D1E2896F">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>if disposable—</text> <clause id="H4BE372BFFCFD4960B533EF65F4CB7851"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>does not use any latex or common allergens; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H2F8CE68D734B4AB88A931816C35865F5">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>meets or exceeds the quality standards for diapers commercially available through retail sale in the following categories:</text>
                            <subclause id="HE027E94F76F841D09949681DB713D7BF">
                                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>Absorbency (with acceptable rates for first and second wetting).</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="HB044A122B8C6482A86B04C43727C8166">
                                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>Waterproof outer cover.</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H6F04C9D1EF044A609023D0A5D59CE6CA"> <enum>(III)</enum> <text>Flexible leg openings.</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="H99F9FD2419414AA4AFA80D01FF464EEA">
                                <enum>(IV)</enum>
 <text>Refastening closures.</text> </subclause> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H63F62654B94443B9996AF38172E45F49"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Diaper bank</header> <text>- The term <term>diaper bank</term> means a nonprofit organization that—</text>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                        id="H1DEB21E431404B3A9F94E2BD0B9B2E31">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H2EAFD13DA4694CE0A6B12058CCC45B69">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>is established and operating primarily for the purpose of collecting or purchasing diapers and diapering supplies; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HF82184E128974C1AA0C8B64E29C6694B">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>distributes diapers and diapering supplies either directly or through partnerships for eventual distribution to individuals free of charge.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HE8447836A2794E29B8F31B49949B4C63">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
                    <header>Diapering supplies</header>
 <text>The term <term>diapering supplies</term> means items, including diaper wipes and diaper cream, necessary to ensure that—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H3B8498D4ADD04A4BAA5700F09CC2DFF3">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>an eligible child using a diaper is properly cleaned and protected from diaper rash; or</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H965675F2B53349EC8249A45DBF337BF4">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>a medically complex child who uses a medically necessary diaper is properly cleaned and protected from diaper rash.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HBC5CB1D3484241A38C30ED83B7990571">
                    <enum>(6)</enum>
                    <header>Eligible child</header>
 <text>The term <term>eligible child</term> means a child who—</text> <subparagraph id="H4C65C0DF5F7549D48F41C6367E4108AE"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>has not attained 4 years of age; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H5C07244820F043C0AFA2F30B4AD66FAD">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>is a member of a low-income family.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HA44D6EA6B2334AE49436FBDABE67C986"> <enum>(7)</enum> <header>Eligible entities</header> <text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a State or local governmental entity, an Indian tribe or tribal organization (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act), or a diaper bank or other nonprofit organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code that—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H4A173DF4459F46EEB6E025E3B96D4DFA">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>has at least 1 year of demonstrated experience in the area of—</text> <clause id="H697285B490024CA1A3F4ACECC27882D0"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>community distributions of diapers and diapering supplies and other basic need services, such as food or menstrual products;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H2762813595174CCB8303DC8294F5B254">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>child care;</text> </clause> <clause id="HA39BA57199EB40E8B7B8375222A3153C"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <text>child development activities in low-income communities; or</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H09B036545B89427696AA086B232C678F">
                            <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>motherhood, fatherhood, or parent education efforts serving low-income parents of young children;</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H2AFCC27121D84AD99B15EB3678C145C0">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>demonstrates competency to implement a project, provide fiscal accountability, collect data, and prepare reports and other necessary documentation; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                        id="HF347AD6B1D1C45CAAF87B9AB952D1A4C">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>demonstrates a willingness to share information with researchers, practitioners, and other interested parties.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HA9086681E9404C7F96570C42BC0B38F5">
                    <enum>(8)</enum>
                    <header>Federal poverty line</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal poverty line</term> means the Federal poverty line as defined by the Office of Management and Budget and revised annually in accordance with section 673(2) of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1981 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9902">42 U.S.C. 9902(2)</external-xref>) applicable to a family of the size involved.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H95370B48B5D74BFF96BDC66E266A24CF">
                    <enum>(9)</enum>
                    <header>Low-income</header>
 <text>The term <term>low-income</term>, with respect to a family, means a family whose self-certified income is not more than 200 percent of the Federal poverty line.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H48019AE89BC54BA688931EB39A01146E">
                    <enum>(10)</enum>
                    <header>Medically complex child</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>medically complex child</term> means an individual who has attained 3 years of age and for whom a licensed health care provider has provided a diagnosis of 1 or more significant chronic conditions.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HA526565A3F0941B880DA72DAC3FC0A97">
                    <enum>(11)</enum>
                    <header>Medically necessary diaper</header>
 <text>The term <term>medically necessary diaper</term> means an absorbent garment that is—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H390E1D5946A9477AAF9E6465A992CC13">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>washable or disposable;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H53D1C77714FC4BF6A4EE56C08B2B82A7"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>worn by a medically complex child who has been diagnosed with bowel or bladder incontinence, a bowel or bladder condition that causes excess urine or stool (such as short gut syndrome or diabetes insipidus), or a severe skin condition that causes skin erosions (such as epidermolysis bullosa) and needs such garment to correct or ameliorate such condition; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H2DE2422CDC864592B4303C666082E195">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>if disposable—</text> <clause id="H73FF8C4CB14E4AC0A0DC3A3B085E4B40"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>does not use any latex or common allergens; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H265DE68DB39F41F5903B640CA47FD451">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>meets or exceeds the quality standards for diapers commercially available through retail sale in the following categories:</text>
                            <subclause id="H8BDCDCC751F14808AF4BF297757F0019">
                                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>Absorbency (with acceptable rates for first and second wetting).</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="HB1C2F18085244FF1A9BCC99B181D906A">
                                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>Waterproof outer cover.</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H8A8939B754E8490BB992F3D6236DBA4D"> <enum>(III)</enum> <text>Flexible leg openings.</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="H45186F2096184BECA2728DCD7ECCACFE">
                                <enum>(IV)</enum>
 <text>Refastening closures.</text> </subclause> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H125EF7F182C0442F9F5078D625524CF9"> <enum>(12)</enum> <header>State</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, American Samoa, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, and the Republic of Palau.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H438480FF0F7B416FBD47F1CDA88047C3">
                <enum>(g)</enum>
                <header>Exemption of program from sequestration</header>
                <paragraph id="HEBC6B1FF23EC4AD3A842517DE305294D">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>Section 255(h) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/905">2 U.S.C. 905(h)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after <quote>Supplemental Security Income Program (28–0406–0–1–609).</quote> the following:</text>
                    <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                        id="HBA162EDE906341A99AF5819CA1E56A58">
                        <paragraph id="H0C9B60D98082461997D2F887867DD817">
                            <enum/>
 <text>Targeted funding for States for diaper assistance (including diapering supplies and adult incontinence materials and supplies) through the Social Services Block Grant Program.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                    </quoted-block>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                    id="HB7D2112E41C34D10822890A89DFFD1F7">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Applicability</header>
 <text>The amendment made by this subsection shall apply to any sequestration order issued under the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/900">2 U.S.C. 900 et seq.</external-xref>) on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="H715AA7D4775841A68A331DA7B9826F33">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Inclusion of diapers and diapering supplies as qualified medical
                expenses</header>
            <subsection id="HA1CC0B15AA7A4C979818D7A1D18258AD">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Health savings accounts</header>
 <text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">Section 223(d)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H3DC4A941083342608D109645ED74DA67"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>by inserting <quote>, medically necessary diapers, and diapering supplies</quote> after <quote>menstrual care products</quote> in the last sentence of subparagraph (A); and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H5A932CEA6492404EA8A4B90FA459F75E">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H76D1C3989E164174A6CE4F3CC3107645"> <subparagraph id="HB127BA47BB184920835D02433149E8EE"> <enum>(E)</enum> <header>Medically necessary diapers and diapering supplies</header> <text>For purposes of this paragraph—</text>
                            <clause id="H20D5D46D615048268C1040C78E486F7B">
                                <enum>(i)</enum>
                                <header>Medically necessary diapers</header>
 <text>The term <term>medically necessary diaper</term> means an absorbent garment which is washable or disposable and which is worn by an individual who has attained 3 years of age because of medical necessity, such as someone who has been diagnosed with bowel or bladder incontinence, a bowel or bladder condition that causes excess urine or stool (such as short gut syndrome or diabetes insipidus), or a severe skin condition that causes skin erosions (such as epidermolysis bullosa) and needs such garment to correct or ameliorate such condition, to serve a preventative medical purpose, or to correct or ameliorate defects or physical or mental illnesses or conditions diagnosed by a licensed health care provider, and, if disposable—</text>
                                <subclause id="H6441E6C6E1AE467CB84D5224DA2E3058">
                                    <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>does not use any latex or common allergens; and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H7F76C83E74544EFCAC429EAC546B6889"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text>meets or exceeds the quality standards for diapers commercially available through retail sale in the following categories:</text>
                                    <item id="H0CF7871E77664DDC9D3455DC484334C8">
                                        <enum>(aa)</enum>
 <text>Absorbency (with acceptable rates for first and second wetting).</text>
                                    </item>
                                    <item id="HD473627AFE0D4B5AA60BC4912D9AEF28">
                                        <enum>(bb)</enum>
 <text>Waterproof outer cover.</text> </item> <item id="HD6E0C0736D194091B9502F6BADADA373"> <enum>(cc)</enum> <text>Flexible leg openings.</text>
                                    </item>
                                    <item id="HAC2DBC8C4FA1425299B2A9895ADDD6D5">
                                        <enum>(dd)</enum>
 <text>Refastening closures. </text> </item> </subclause> </clause> <clause id="HA1EA9D088EEF4483BFF9F55CCDE8FE35"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <header>Diapering supplies</header> <text>The term <term>diapering supplies</term> means items, including diaper wipes and diaper creams, necessary to ensure that an individual wearing medically necessary diapers is properly cleaned and protected from diaper rash.</text>
                            </clause>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                    </quoted-block>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HF926142645B043ECB480740524B5933C">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Archer MSAs</header>
 <text>The last sentence of section 220(d)(2)(A) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>, medically necessary diapers (as defined in section 223(d)(2)(E)), and diapering supplies (as defined in section 223(d)(2)(E))</quote> after <quote>menstrual care products (as defined in section 223(d)(2)(D))</quote>.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H8E3CDE524D404F398E1DB66591EE129E">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Health flexible spending arrangements and health reimbursement
                    arrangements</header>
 <text>Section 106(f) of such Code is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H87C268A44BA04766904510E78416911C"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>by inserting <quote>, medically necessary diapers (as defined in section 223(d)(2)(E)), and diapering supplies (as defined in section 223(d)(2)(E))</quote> after <quote>menstrual care products (as defined in section 223(d)(2)(D))</quote>; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H15DAB94B624D44DFA27AC08F54B6AFF5">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>in the heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">, medically necessary diapers, and diapering supplies</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">menstrual care products</header-in-text></quote>.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H17DD2C317E60428CBD01BD7194514474">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Effective dates</header>
                <paragraph id="H5AC14C8485564B289EC2416BA196D52D">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>Distributions from certain accounts</header>
 <text>The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) shall apply to amounts paid after December 31, 2025.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                    id="H048D34BF8CE4416D907DDCEB9721359F">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Reimbursements</header>
 <text>The amendment made by subsection (c) shall apply to expenses incurred after December 31, 2025.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>


