<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL25052-MLG-K1-VCS"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S130 IS: Competition and Antitrust Law Enforcement Reform Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 130</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250116">January 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To reform the antitrust laws to better protect competition in the American economy, to amend the Clayton Act to modify the standard for an unlawful acquisition, to deter anticompetitive exclusionary conduct that harms competition and consumers, to enhance the ability of the Department of Justice and the Federal Trade Commission to enforce the antitrust laws, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Competition and Antitrust Law Enforcement Reform Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id549ed039ac99417091fbdb9e1c049738"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purposes</header><subsection id="id13541f279908457c8bc071ab28d6524c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="ide26118506124411395935bf784baf26b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>competitive markets, in which multiple firms compete to buy and sell products and services, are critical to ensuring economic opportunity for all people in the United States and providing resilience to the economy during unpredictable times;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idccaed29fb3de4b9fa49da8f035d35be4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>when companies compete, businesses offer the highest quality and choice of goods and services for the lowest possible prices to consumers and other businesses;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaba1a45533a141afa9f33c5274133fdc"><enum>(3)</enum><text>competition fosters small business growth, reduces economic inequality, and spurs innovation and job creation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id872a49a4218846908d55611e72e30ba8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>competitive markets are crucial for the United States global economic competitiveness and national security;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddd1dc3a4bd8c41118ffba37a82a73e29"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in the United States economy today, the presence and exercise of market power is substantial and growing;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id21484807cf854bdabaf19bc947a3c7a9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the presence and exercise of market power makes it more difficult for people in the United States to start their own businesses, depresses wages, and increases economic inequality, with particularly damaging effects on historically disadvantaged communities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2f1f49c285044782bdf149370109a18a"><enum>(7)</enum><text>market power and undue market concentration contribute to the consolidation of political power, undermining the health of democracy in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida72c1447d5c84633b5e873732c502627"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the anticompetitive effects of monopoly power or buyer market power include higher prices, lower quality, lessened choice, reduced innovation, foreclosure of competitors, and increased entry barriers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id11dfeacc3ca44d7e8fda9561f419a1c7"><enum>(9)</enum><text>monopsony power or seller market power allows a firm to force suppliers of goods or services to accept below market prices or to force workers to accept below market wages, resulting in lower quality products and services, reduced opportunities for suppliers and workers, reduced availability of products and services for consumers, reduced innovation, foreclosure of competitors, and increased entry barriers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id33b411ec0cc74f84862f53eb7fba52f0"><enum>(10)</enum><text>horizontal consolidation, vertical consolidation, and conglomerate mergers all have the potential to increase market power and cause anticompetitive harm;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id16d8d794da39492c8a7cbb783b574898"><enum>(11)</enum><text>extensive consolidation is reducing competition and threatens to place the American dream further out of reach for many consumers in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb9d9412857eb44cea5343793ac97bf59"><enum>(12)</enum><text>since 2008, firms in the United States have engaged in over $10,000,000,000,000 in mergers and acquisitions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida655312ef91c4aa0bf9c08e991ec4778"><enum>(13)</enum><text>the acquisition of nascent or potential rivals by dominant firms can present significant long-term threats to competition and innovation and harm the global economic competitiveness of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id072c25032aab452a93adfd531584620a"><enum>(14)</enum><text>the acquisition, by one of its competitors, of a maverick firm that plays a disruptive role in the market, by using an innovative business model or technology, offering lower prices or new, different products or services, or by other means that benefit consumers, often presents a threat to competition;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id244e3efe272f4e28beed0efdf9da7aab"><enum>(15)</enum><text>section 7 of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/18">15 U.S.C. 18</external-xref>) is the primary line of defense against anticompetitive mergers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id538fa9c48dfb44c685aedb94aeb97f6d"><enum>(16)</enum><text>in recent years, some court decisions and enforcement policies have limited the vitality of the Clayton Act to prevent harmful consolidation by—</text><subparagraph id="id487cf6cac7774a05917c1483cd114ba2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>discounting previously accepted presumptions that certain acquisitions are anticompetitive;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf6804fbed4e8463d9723832a47977eea"><enum>(B)</enum><text>focusing inordinately on the effect of an acquisition on price in the short term, to the exclusion of other potential anticompetitive effects;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf2ee4c0cac4f42c19add4fa344a7c355"><enum>(C)</enum><text>underestimating the dangers that horizontal, vertical, and conglomerate mergers will lower quality, reduce choice, impede innovation, exclude competitors, increase entry barriers, or create buyer power, including monopsony power;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id776dae57fe804aee974bddce1b4c2528"><enum>(D)</enum><text>failing to properly account for direct evidence of competitive harm, including intent evidence; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3f2334fef418431085577d8cad22a106"><enum>(E)</enum><text>requiring the government to prove harmful effects of a proposed merger to a near certainty;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddf6aef28d8314f179ced65962c92b5aa"><enum>(17)</enum><text>anticompetitive exclusionary conduct constitutes a particularly harmful exercise of market power and a substantial threat to the United States economy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf83f30414aed43de9c90e14b0fcd7658"><enum>(18)</enum><text>when dominant sellers exercise market power, they harm buyers by overcharging them, reducing product or service quality, limiting their choices, and impairing innovation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id74b3ac7b7a844d029ac1dbb465628ee3"><enum>(19)</enum><text>when dominant buyers exercise market power, they harm suppliers by underpaying them, limiting their business opportunities, and impairing innovation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddbf73578c4714d088e7127b483455a10"><enum>(20)</enum><text>when dominant employers exercise market power, they harm workers by paying them low wages, reducing their benefits, and limiting their future employment opportunities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbe509334c44d41888b4d4ef9b6728e34"><enum>(21)</enum><text>nascent or potential rivals, even those that are unprofitable or inefficient, are an important source of competitive discipline for dominant firms;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5ec5327d94f54462815c6da1ea0579b6"><enum>(22)</enum><text>antitrust enforcement against anticompetitive exclusionary conduct has been impeded when courts have declined to rigorously examine the facts in favor of relying on inaccurate economic assumptions that are inconsistent with contemporary economic learning, such as presuming that market power is not durable and can be expected to self-correct, that monopolies can drive as much or more innovation than a competitive market, that above-cost pricing cannot harm competition, and other flawed assumptions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf187f61a94a544fa83354a6092128dbe"><enum>(23)</enum><text>the courts of the United States have improperly implied immunity from the antitrust laws based on Federal regulatory statutes, even limiting the application of statutory antitrust savings clauses passed by Congress;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddf8525a8f72e4a29940115c99ed440a2"><enum>(24)</enum><text>the civil remedies currently available to cure violations of the Sherman Antitrust Act, including injunctions, equitable monetary relief, and private damages, have not proven sufficient, on their own, to deter anticompetitive conduct;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id525c811ba4cc46419f042aae25c7f1ad"><enum>(25)</enum><text>in some cases, effective deterrence requires the imposition of civil penalties, alone or in combination with existing remedies, including structural relief, behavioral relief, private damages, and equitable monetary relief, including disgorgement and restitution; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1c12c0583ecd405a8574b77bcadfe6c2"><enum>(26)</enum><text>Federal antitrust enforcement budgets have failed to keep pace with the growth of the economy and increasing demands on agency resources, significantly undermining the ability of the Federal antitrust agencies to fulfill their law enforcement missions and contributing to the rise of market power in the American economy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4d0d0448ca2c410fbec23cd329cc13b1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are to—</text><paragraph id="idd5f237731e3240b5a123d56f3b52ef2e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enhance competition throughout the American economy by strengthening antitrust enforcement by the Department of Justice, the Federal Trade Commission, the State enforcement agencies, and private parties;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id15bf9a73c05444aeaa38f6ca95ab5500"><enum>(2)</enum><text>revise the legal standard under section 7 of the Clayton Act to better enable enforcers to arrest the likely anticompetitive effects of harmful mergers in their incipiency, as Congress intended, by clarifying that the potential effects that may justify prohibiting a merger under the Clayton Act include lower quality, reduced choice, reduced innovation, the exclusion of competitors, or increased entry barriers, in addition to increased price to buyers or reduced price to sellers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id43362e99cebe4c6099df3e2199e3d7e4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>amend the Clayton Act to clarify that an acquisition that tends to create a monopsony violates the Clayton Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfbaf150d391e4d2aaceef2652bc7e4bb"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establish simple, cost-effective decision rules that require the parties to certain acquisitions that either significantly increase concentration or are extremely large bear the burden of establishing that the acquisition will not materially harm competition;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8fdd8707041646e3ab4e89da83ccd3ea"><enum>(5)</enum><text>prohibit and deter exclusionary conduct that harms competition, particularly by dominant firms;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5f280326648f424296cb95c29eb6c8d3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>enable the Department of Justice and the Federal Trade Commission to seek civil monetary penalties, in addition to existing remedies, for violations of the Sherman Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1ed711e2c6b2481dba2eafe152fdfeb1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>give the Department of Justice and the Federal Trade Commission additional financial resources and enforcement tools to craft remedies for individual violations that are effective to deter future unlawful conduct and proportionate to the gravity of the violation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id74d26815547841e98a13e7b235ccbcde"><enum>(8)</enum><text>provide further protections for those who provide evidence of anticompetitive conduct to government enforcers and potential financial rewards for whistleblowers who provide information to the government that leads to a criminal fine; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddad2ada014174dbbbccaad88560207e6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>grant successful antitrust plaintiffs the right to obtain prejudgment interest on damages awards to further deter anticompetitive conduct and increase compensation to injured parties.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id5149c99e9fea48c5b709a5f687d596d1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act the term <term>antitrust laws</term>—</text><paragraph id="id29608b088fd74018bef34ce33761781b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has the meaning given the term in the first section of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id05ce1d07f7ca467595d9e1c22437889b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes—</text><subparagraph id="id292a7a81b212449fa4ffb36f3420d929"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>) to the extent that such section applies to unfair methods of competition; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc5909e674c974ba6839c47fd79ea3f04"><enum>(B)</enum><text>this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="idd53047991baa471bb953c676c86b02a8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Unlawful acquisitions</header><subsection id="idfbbb9f9917424c1da9c466d87d4790fc"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Market power</header><text>Subsection (a) of the first section of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc361e05e4ba24a45a6e9e214d52235b6"><subsection id="id83b48d8d36b344f5acdea1ab3942fd90" commented="no"><enum/><text>The term <term>market power</term> in this Act means the ability of a person, or a group of persons acting in concert, to profitably impose terms or conditions on counterparties, including terms regarding price, quantity, product or service quality, or other terms affecting the value of consideration exchanged in the transaction, that are more favorable to the person or group of persons imposing them than what the person or group of persons could obtain in a competitive market.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id90af6c43a1c245169db2844d6adfafb3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Unlawful acquisitions</header><text>Section 7 of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/18">15 U.S.C. 18</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id2cf1d754e75b43ccbe4b8faec7ccc1e0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the first and second undesignated paragraphs, by striking <quote>substantially to lessen</quote> each place that term appears and inserting <quote>to create an appreciable risk of materially lessening</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id850409229a0f4e02bff714c2d93d7d41"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or a monopsony</quote> after <quote>monopoly</quote> each place that term appears; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaa08490b5b894bd193d63f6d8f47fc46"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaef16f10d0e442fd9fd9d975c8f597cd"><subsection id="ided1b47ee91504d28b7ed01a418affa06"><enum/><text>In a case brought by the United States, the Federal Trade Commission, or a State attorney general, a court shall determine that the effect of an acquisition described in this section may be to create an appreciable risk of materially lessening competition or to tend to create a monopoly or a monopsony, in or affecting commerce, if—</text><paragraph id="id464494c599134a81ab97a5b88ebdb321"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the acquisition would lead to a significant increase in market concentration in any relevant market;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2f72984796904a1bb3a1f1c27363ce89"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the acquisition would increase the ability and incentive to engage in exclusionary conduct, as defined in section 26A of the Clayton Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8e0c2e4f8c1e4ba9bfd7b5a00ae2ca4e"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id02d74f2cbdd840c48e8a514a1ae3f478"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the acquiring person has a market share of greater than 50 percent or otherwise has significant market power, as a seller or a buyer, in any relevant market, and as a result of the acquisition, the acquiring person would obtain control over entities or assets that compete or have a reasonable probability of competing with the acquiring person in the same relevant market; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id359c95a460f04c97b31ad366a571ac59" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as a result of the acquisition, the acquiring person would obtain control over entities or assets that have a market share of greater than 50 percent or otherwise have significant market power, as a seller or a buyer, in any relevant market, and the acquiring person competes or has a reasonable probability of competing with the entities or assets over which it would obtain control, as a result of the acquisition, in the same relevant market;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id54c1067ab987476d9c6ca935d9564574"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the acquisition would lead to the combination of entities or assets that compete or have a reasonable probability of competing in a relevant market, and either the acquiring person or the entities or assets over which it would obtain control prevents, limits, or disrupts coordinated interaction among competitors in a relevant market or has a reasonable probability of doing so;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfedafc9ea89a4d96bce9d24592bb7913"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the acquisition—</text><subparagraph id="id471e025638754f6aa439da6a5f64efec"><enum>(A)</enum><text>would likely enable the acquiring person to unilaterally and profitably exercise market power or materially increase its ability to do so; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf5665e4d18b24fc48fe8f05e71eed4c7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>would materially increase the probability of coordinated interaction among competitors in any relevant market; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id44298cf180aa4e088770bc92d7492cdb"><enum>(6)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id617f5fbe8d8a4f63877477e8b61480b7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the acquisition is not a transaction that is described in section 7A(c); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0ea0b5eede074476a40c9cc3827b9c59" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id45e8116a8a674528909e024c91750ee5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as a result of such acquisition, the acquiring person would hold an aggregate total amount of the voting securities and assets of the acquired person in excess of $5,000,000,000 (as adjusted and published for each fiscal year beginning after September 30, 2025, in the same manner as provided in section 8(a)(5) to reflect the percentage change in the gross national product for such fiscal year compared to the gross national product for the year ending September 30, 2024; or</text></clause><clause id="id95dcb16b0d0c4dde9a41f6061fc0ff67" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id392256deccfb4cd4a3420fec5f493596"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the person acquiring or the person being acquired has assets, net annual sales, or a market capitalization greater than $100,000,000,000 (as so adjusted and published); and</text></subclause><subclause id="iddea6fbf1be9d401a9a94276c2471735f" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>as a result of such acquisition, the acquiring person would hold an aggregate total amount of the voting securities and assets of the acquired person in excess of $50,000,000 (as so adjusted and published),</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">unless the acquiring or acquired person establishes, by a preponderance of the evidence, that the effect of the acquisition will not be to create an appreciable risk of materially lessening competition or will not tend to create a monopoly or a monopsony. In this paragraph, the term <term>materially</term> means more than a de minimis amount</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id631e980bf08e470f99f8d099df303b17"><enum>5.</enum><header>Post-proceeding data</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7A of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/18a">15 U.S.C. 18a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id303703a783d14817a6594145340b0794"><subsection id="id504c6070501940b1af9219e6a40297e1"><enum>(l)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idcb251620178043b5a578ce24ff2a44fc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Each person who resolves a proceeding brought under the antitrust laws by the Federal Trade Commission or United States by entering into an agreement or by the final judgment in a Federal or administrative court regarding an acquisition with respect to which notification is required under this section shall, on an annual basis during the 5-year period beginning on the date on which the agreement is entered into, file with the Federal Trade Commission or the Assistant Attorney General, as applicable, and the Competition Advocate, information sufficient for the Federal Trade Commission or the United States, as applicable, to assess the competitive impact of the acquisition, including—</text><subparagraph id="id3751ad0b2e4941c5860fe24a6bbc0a31" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the pricing, availability, and quality of any product or service, or inputs thereto, in any market, that was covered by the agreement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id066d5c34bab247b79445af00801d18da" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the source, and the resulting magnitude and extent, of any cost-saving efficiencies or any benefits to consumers or trading partners that were claimed as a benefit of the acquisition and the extent to which any cost savings were passed on to consumers or trading partners; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5478f63d1e0549adb7fed70b09ddf71f" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the effectiveness of any divestitures or any conditions placed on the acquisition in fully restoring competition.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfbe1051d510c4c7893f60b7ad8a8dccd" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The requirement to provide the information described in paragraph (1) shall be included in an agreement described in that paragraph.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id54a138522b0948859e31c7351c339ed6" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Federal Trade Commission, with the concurrence of the Assistant Attorney General, by rule in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, and consistent with the purposes of this section—</text><subparagraph id="id0918373598504c4db826293faa027c7e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall require that the information described in paragraph (1) be in such form and contain such documentary material and information relevant to an acquisition as is necessary and appropriate to enable the Federal Trade Commission and the Assistant Attorney General to assess the competitive impact of the acquisition under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb2ca035e726a40d5a49d29935bec8dd1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may—</text><clause id="id1eaa467540bc4543ad2e40697762919c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>define the terms used in this subsection;</text></clause><clause id="id423d071941514fd5a8db45b09fd42257"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>exempt, from the requirements of this section, information not relevant in assessing the competitive impact of the acquisition under paragraph (1); and</text></clause><clause id="id803e5e80712741f7a9ac2303e63be40f"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prescribe such other rules as may be necessary and appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida09f4b63f3e947edbbd90417efc9d4af"><paragraph id="id84ca752450994c53b111bd02731026cf" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The chief executive officer, chief financial officer, general counsel, or a corporate officer of similar authority shall certify, under penalty of perjury, the accuracy of a report under this subsection.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="idd6f6a102eab64caf821d6da88d625978"><enum>6.</enum><header>Federal Trade Commission study</header><subsection id="id4b424fdc5e4d477e9443cae5d1a8fea7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Federal Trade Commission, in consultation with the Securities and Exchange Commission, shall conduct and publish a study, pursuant to section 6(b) of the Federal Trade Commission Act, relying on public data and information if available and sufficient, and incorporating public comment on—</text><paragraph id="id4234a6553e7e454a830ea1a4a4c15ec4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the extent to which an institutional investor or related institutional investors have ownership or control interests in competitors in moderately concentrated or concentrated markets;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida54a993ee7074f0daa02609ff27a1aaf"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the impacts of such overlapping ownership or control on competition; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0a50fed5458f4ba8930afa0dcf462a9b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the mechanisms by which an institutional investor could affect competition among the companies in which it invests and whether such mechanisms are prevalent.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id20d48f01fd074dfcbd11b84247d7fad7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemption from Paperwork Reduction Act</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">Chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, shall not apply to the collection of information under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="id22792a35b6ed48ebac7c3918436593b5"><enum>7.</enum><header>GAO studies</header><subsection id="idcb2b96301e80486f9f452e00d60e2f16"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text><paragraph id="idcb718a9d4708491b982b43bfc63d85bc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct and publish a study to assess the success of merger remedies required by the Department of Justice or the Federal Trade Commission in consent decrees entered into during the 8-year period ending on the date on which the study is conducted, including the impact on maintaining competition, a comparison of structural and conduct remedies, and the viability of divested assets; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfca8707dcd1b462e89480053f4e54a35"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conduct a study on the impact of mergers and acquisitions on wages, employment, innovation, and new business formation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8e00b62dc126425fba27afe2380e8fc2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Update</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text><paragraph id="idc14c17d4c96a4376999bce45a0a8d653"><enum>(1)</enum><text>update the study under subsection (a)(1) every 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act, as added by section 5 of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3f03accbbd4542f2a7aba3a8a131cb8f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify specific remedies or alleged merger benefits that require additional information or research.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idd0c57532c95744f0a769211dda3c1cb3"><enum>8.</enum><header>Office of Competition Advocate</header><subsection id="idf7d5965105b941c4ab2c8b410b8e24d1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="id2c64357ba7e54de6aa850d1159098782" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9b9e406369674fe5878fa9468d189860" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Chair</term> means the Chair of the Commission; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id134f620f34764a4282057772676201c8" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3bb1b8883a5f453aa9421c108e946083" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>covered company</term> means any company that has, at any time, been required to make a filing under section 7A of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/18a">15 U.S.C. 18a</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idec8b6b2b75034445965ab7c5f63b88fb" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>Office</term> means the Office of the Competition Advocate established under subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idaacba41a6357422f8fe75426308cd156"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established within the Federal Trade Commission the Office of the Competition Advocate.</text></subsection><subsection id="id27cde70adb294cb69f3a4416937e2100"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Competition Advocate</header><paragraph id="id66fca9b7f3e545a4a043976b14b637eb"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of the Office shall be the Competition Advocate, who shall—</text><subparagraph id="id666c88094b974dd782b387b4acf3a4b4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>report directly to, and be under the supervision of, the Chair, but the Chair shall not prevent or prohibit the Competition Advocate from initiating, carrying out, or completing any of its duties under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7fcb943bbf5448db84bfc8cbc2e50e28"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be appointed by the Chair with the approval of the Commission, including at least 1 Commissioner who is not a member of the same political party as the Chair, from among individuals having experience in advocating for the promotion of competition; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddda7b3e2d23d4c988840da1ea15de50b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>serve a term of 7 years and shall not be removable except upon a unanimous vote of the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7c48b9aa45f54c679ec27546e7ce80ea"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The annual rate of pay for the Competition Advocate shall be equal to the highest rate of annual pay for other senior executives who report to the Chair of the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcf637af164e6481ba2599c02bfd65dd6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on service</header><text>An individual who serves as the Competition Advocate may not be employed by the Commission—</text><subparagraph id="iddbbe1c8f8de84674b6a50892adb37fae"><enum>(A)</enum><text>during the 2-year period ending on the date of appointment as Competition Advocate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8f332c47ff144f0aae14181d23bb266f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>during the 5-year period beginning on the date on which the person ceases to serve as the Competition Advocate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id20e254d1a1a140b0a53dd4baae20ca4a"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Staff of Office</header><text>The Commission shall allocate funds from the Commission budget to the Office of the Competition Advocate sufficient for the Competition Advocate to retain or employ such counsel, research staff, and service staff necessary to carry out the functions, powers, and duties of the Office.</text></subsection><subsection id="id6e09c1a993a243d3aa5a28028e37288d"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duties and powers</header><text>The Competition Advocate shall—</text><paragraph id="ida091d33951284269b163903418a0adc0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recommend processes or procedures that will allow the Federal Trade Commission and the Antitrust Division of the Department of Justice to improve the ability of each agency to solicit reports from consumers, small businesses, and workers about possible anticompetitive practices or adverse effects of concentration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7c442a19e51b420e8619fd8ff5c0652f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide recommendations to other agencies about agency actions that may have anticompetitive effects and the potential harm to competition;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5c3b3893cd4043afbd10baa13460f8c2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide recommendations to other agencies about agency actions that may have procompetitive effects and the potential benefit to competition;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id47666e68611942f490ecea76b136cf90"><enum>(4)</enum><text>publish periodic reports on—</text><subparagraph id="idd14ad4b56b134ccca92db7085a468d82"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effects of remedies required by the Department of Justice or the Federal Trade Commission in consent decrees;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1bb72e28d6394b189c7af341ce824e0b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the effects of law enforcement actions, whether successful or not, including settlements, preliminary injunctions, court-mandated remedies, or any other remedy imposed by a court or agreed to by the Department of Justice or Federal Trade Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5d864740c66943339395dec7a1941089"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the effects of a decision by the Department of Justice or the Federal Trade Commission to allow any merger or transaction to move forward without a consent decree or bringing a law enforcement action;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1d572c93015f4d3fb1ba9a33475ccec0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the effects of decisions and opinions issues by State and Federal courts related to the antitrust laws on competition and the future enforcement of the antitrust laws; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc2c689e9173e42519f6ed4a75048bdf3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the effects of other agency actions, including rulemakings, on competition;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcbe8b964772d4c35bc1031d13ae8da0c"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide recommendations to the Federal Trade Commission and Department of Justice about the effectiveness of policy statements, guidelines, or practices to improve the enforcement of the antitrust laws;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id95bf441241004192bba4a41c821ac01a"><enum>(6)</enum><text>report any evidence the Competition Advocate obtains that any person, partnership, or corporation has engaged in transactions or conduct that may constitute of a violation of the antitrust laws, or any settlement, agreement, or consent decree related to a potential violation of the antitrust laws, to the Commission, which may institute further investigation, initiate enforcement proceedings, or refer such evidence to the Attorney General;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id066b0296147b4ba69236a51087783bf1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>request such information or assistance as may be necessary for carrying out the duties and powers described in this subsection from any agency or unit thereof, including the Commission. The head of any agency shall, insofar as is practicable and not in contravention of any existing statutory restriction or regulation of the agency from which the information is requested, furnish to the Competition Advocate such information or assistance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id18d6c8eb2fa444ddb721cf12518b7b78"><enum>(8)</enum><text>have discretion to decide whether to release the recommendations of the Competition Advocate publicly;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd9e33f2287ae44b09473747dca8997d4"><enum>(9)</enum><text>have access to all information and data collected and retained by the Office of Market Analysis and Data; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8ef7f4979fb844f282f8848ae4f6bf0e"><enum>(10)</enum><text>submit all recommendations or reports to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id814cafd647c64c20a18febc6f54a657b"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Subpoena authority</header><paragraph id="idd5ff04c0dd1d4d10a10d9d2611964630"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Competition Advocate may either accept voluntary submissions of periodic and other reports from any covered company, or compel the production of such a report by subpoena for the purpose of carrying out its duties and powers in subsection (e).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id52323c56cb6c41b8ae6b3c07b821a8a6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Independent subpoena authority</header><text>Upon a finding that a covered company will not submit, or has not submitted, a sufficient report voluntarily, the Competition Advocate may, under its own independent authority, and notwithstanding any jurisdictional limitations in the Federal Trade Commission Act applicable to the Commission’s investigative authority, compel the submission of a periodic or other reports from any covered company by issuing a subpoena.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9eea9f70faf141b9a28b021c17ccbfca"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>The Competition Advocate shall have independent authority to bring an action in any appropriate Federal court to enforce any subpoena issued under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id65bd1290312f4858912e16c498ffe764"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Written finding</header><text>Before issuing a subpoena to collect the information described in paragraph (1), the Competition Advocate shall make a written finding that—</text><subparagraph id="id801444716f4b440eb116f7999158a7d6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the data is required to carry out the functions of the Competition Advocate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd7a56c1879e24d57909ce5acb3cced39"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the information is not available from a public source, from the covered company on a voluntary basis, or another agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd4882ab99da24eeeadca48da1366927d"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Mitigation of report burden</header><text>Before requiring the submission of a report from any covered company, the Competition Advocate shall—</text><subparagraph id="idfaf56fb6e79648b1a96feed94cc44bb8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coordinate with other agencies or authority; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id781863a677e04c9bbb729909858b61de"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whenever possible, rely on information available from such agencies or authority.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide546bdd1eae84731b0b9b0aa45bc45e5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text>Information reported to or otherwise obtained by the Competition Advocate shall be subject to the same confidentiality requirements and protection applicable to information reported to or otherwise obtained by the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id93d43212671f42dbb5f058a9a41095f2"><enum>9.</enum><header>Office of Market Analysis and Data</header><subsection id="idf93c1cd46a4c42a8901c54604c9af627"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established, within the Federal Trade Commission, an Office of Market Analysis and Data.</text></subsection><subsection id="idd830dfe08500419a9ecdecba49fb6524"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Office of Market Analysis and Data shall, in consultation with the Bureau of Economics, assist the Federal Trade Commission in—</text><paragraph id="ida147d858938c481eb34dc219601ac225"><enum>(1)</enum><text>collecting, validating, and maintaining data obtained from agencies, as defined in section 551 of title 5, United States Code, commercial data providers, publicly available data sources, any covered company, and any data obtained by the Commission pursuant to its authority under section 6(b) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/46">15 U.S.C. 46(b)</external-xref>), for the purpose of carrying out the functions in paragraphs (2) through (6); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8b618deee7384afd98d9340bb55ada84"><enum>(2)</enum><text>preparing and publishing, in a manner that is easily accessible to the public—</text><subparagraph id="id6515bc63715648d6baa628646f58334f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a concentration database;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcf462fc3cced43f7aa9a4bf17815ac3d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a merger enforcement database; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id22b666e7285d4ef69408131f595005ee"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other database that the Commission determines is necessary to carry out the duties of the Office;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id55cd3dd2e60b45c8a6ff3c81ee8fc115"><enum>(3)</enum><text>collecting and publishing data regarding concentration levels across industries and the impact and degree of antitrust enforcement;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6ed0103baa1c456b96f2b84d5b2a7886"><enum>(4)</enum><text>standardizing the types and formats of data reported and collected, including standards for reporting financial transaction and position data; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide77423d35d6e4db987a41416cd1da6e9"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publishing reports regarding competitive conditions and dynamics affecting markets or industry sectors, in the United States, local geographic markets, different demographic and socioeconomic groups (including the effects that market concentration, mergers and acquisitions, certain types of agreements, and other forms of business conduct have on competition), consumers, workers, innovation, the economic competitiveness of the United States, economic resilience, and national security; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb549bcfe3fcb41cbaf02f969ecc0a383"><enum>(6)</enum><text>publishing reports concerning the competitive effects of acquisitions, which shall include recommendations concerning appropriate enforcement action to remedy any anticompetitive effects discovered, and may include assessments of—</text><subparagraph id="idc57739d9ebd94582bc70ebbdb31247dd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the conditions of the relevant markets affected by the acquisition, over the period since the acquisition was consummated, including, but not limited to, the potential impact that the acquisition has had on—</text><clause id="id4cbc05ea1ed046d48fd8466f8c9b97ba"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the prices of goods or services, including wages in any affected labor markets;</text></clause><clause id="id00bec05bd5dd42c1b86da3f1a5fa78ab"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the output and quality of goods and services;</text></clause><clause id="id22573f6381444698b08325d37b1786d7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the entry or exit of competitors;</text></clause><clause id="idf6ba219bfb9e4de19f19abd7f99b4347"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>innovation;</text></clause><clause id="id80ad3f3b799f4be4a7342c615ea04ee3"><enum>(v)</enum><text>consumer choice and product variety;</text></clause><clause id="iddd1698b1e69e4d8ba241a9be2cf08252"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the opportunity of suppliers and vendors to sell their products or services;</text></clause><clause id="id7075da9d39824485a31da95450d3614b"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>coordinated interaction between competitors; and</text></clause><clause id="id0034fd1879eb4d9a86de31036c48c1b1"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>subsequent mergers and acquisitions activity;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id38c70e6a09e24b1191e0a3b5b58a1273"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether the acquiring person or its successors in interest—</text><clause id="id47ae061ee9fd47fe99f719eb93d67b26"><enum>(i)</enum><text>complied with all obligations under any agreement with the Federal Trade Commission, the United States, or State law enforcement authorities to resolve a proceeding brought under the antitrust laws; and</text></clause><clause id="id187d3d6c18b44c41a9e88e44fa88540c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>achieved measurable, transaction-specific efficiencies, which did not arise from anticompetitive reductions of output, as a result of the acquisition; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6443c616b94f4b1f84ccff2cbf3b733c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether any agreements with the Federal Trade Commission or the United States or remedies imposed by a Federal court to resolve a proceeding brought under the antitrust laws regarding the acquisition was effective in mitigating the anticompetitive effects from the acquisition.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9fdd5a2c3d4749a4a48f9121c70051c2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Information security</header><text>The Commission shall ensure that data collected and maintained by the Office of Market Analysis and Data is kept secure and protected against unauthorized disclosure. </text></subsection><subsection id="id187499ec3ab94115aa98f8ae6e78cd9c"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Commission may, under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, promulgate regulations relating to the collection and standardizing of data under subsection (b).</text></subsection></section><section id="id7557afa3463a4174bbc173590a5bceb9"><enum>10.</enum><header>Exclusionary conduct</header><subsection id="id76234b49b47b439d929467b62c919507"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 26 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/26a">15 U.S.C. 26a</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBEEF03184DAD4D98A4026493F3000298"><section id="idbda6794b1d2c4aef940144753e528dc8"><enum>26A.</enum><header>Exclusionary conduct</header><subsection id="id97ef9d4e150e45e5a0d95685026a6d29"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="idc52e46570ed54e159c9f94ad102e3622"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exclusionary conduct</header><subparagraph id="id2c95226ba4ac427fa6b1124e8de265c4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>exclusionary conduct</term> means conduct that—</text><clause id="idc7b15e9428ca49708107a2c585c00a4e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>materially disadvantages 1 or more actual or potential competitors; or</text></clause><clause id="id1e63f501eb8d4bcc98eb428b3f4e0e04"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>tends to foreclose or limit the ability or incentive of 1 or more actual or potential competitors to compete.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id13f9beb6d9084bdc89a5e47002b85b5c"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitations</header><clause id="id995670037e43415e9ea14a479a288485"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Applying for or enforcing a patent, trademark, or copyright, unless such applications or enforcement actions are baseless or made in bad faith or in violation of a legal obligation, shall not alone constitute exclusionary conduct, but such actions may be considered as part of a course of conduct that constitutes exclusionary conduct.</text></clause><clause id="id7fc196839ce840aaa04707b105b1a105"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Conduct</header><text>Conduct that is necessary to comply with Federal or State law shall not alone constitute exclusionary conduct, but such actions may be considered as part of a course of conduct that constitutes exclusionary conduct.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9d364b6dcf2e4b2692e860e6778f6292"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Market power</header><text>The term <term>market power</term> means the ability of a person, or a group of persons acting in concert, to profitably impose terms or conditions on counterparties, including terms regarding price, quantity, product or service quality, or other terms affecting the value of consideration exchanged in the transaction, that are more favorable to the person or group of persons imposing them than what the person or group of persons could obtain in a competitive market.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf0c7814241fe4a12bbd181d28cb61874"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Violation</header><paragraph id="id9378c9324cf14bceb1e92732878b9fd4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a person, acting alone or in concert with other persons, to engage in exclusionary conduct that presents an appreciable risk of harming competition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id762ad687cd234b2f88dd6f9dc50cc1e1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unfair method of competition</header><text>A violation of paragraph (1) shall also constitute an unfair method of competition under section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id83d0ca3851f04e4d9a4e8f09d4e8f365"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Presumption</header><paragraph id="id4632500141b64287bc8bda0cb4619d96"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), exclusionary conduct shall be presumed to present an appreciable risk of harming competition and shall be a violation of subsection (b)(1) if the exclusionary conduct is undertaken, with respect to a relevant market, by a person or by a group of more than 1 person acting in concert that—</text><subparagraph id="idcbf9de0922e74f4b951ca84dd6bd2ab4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has a market share of greater than 50 percent as a seller or a buyer in the relevant market; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6460301964f34f4a849e676b0ee2a442"><enum>(B)</enum><text>otherwise has significant market power in the relevant market.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idae6d0a6ec71b4ce7af1530d8204e75c2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply if the defendant establishes, by a preponderance of the evidence, that—</text><subparagraph id="id9495b62336834609a68cbeadb2c215d4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>distinct procompetitive benefits of the exclusionary conduct in the relevant market eliminate the risk of harming competition presented by the exclusionary conduct;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9b1290d8e56c433eb4d8d93d0b01a196"><enum>(B)</enum><text>1 or more persons, not including any person participating in or facilitating the exclusionary conduct, have entered or expanded their presence in the market with the effect of eliminating the risk of harming competition posed by the exclusionary conduct; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcfa6adf66c46427b9a0c57fc72c67fc0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the exclusionary conduct does not present an appreciable risk of harming competition.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id47f0bd5c192a413b9fa8bb4adb14ef64"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>If the presumption in subsection (c) does not apply, the determination of whether exclusionary conduct presents an appreciable risk of harming competition shall be based on the totality of the circumstances, which may include consideration of—</text><paragraph id="id95cb4a33e61d45388d752c4fa53706ae"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the extent to which any distinct procompetitive benefits of the exclusionary conduct substantially eliminate the risk of harming competition presented by the exclusionary conduct; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf8728262fd214aaeb4fc62547ca10e6a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether 1 or more persons, not including any person participating in or facilitating the exclusionary conduct, have entered or expanded their presence in the market, substantially eliminating the risk of harming competition presented by the exclusionary conduct.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9fd837d5b14b4db094f77ef8f7b1d68d"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>Although the following circumstances may constitute evidence of a violation of subsection (b)(1), such violation does not require finding—</text><paragraph id="id4239fe49b9034dccae3118d10baf79a3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that the unilateral conduct of the defendant altered or terminated a prior course of dealing between the defendant and a person subject to the exclusionary conduct;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida978300bbb004d218f13e29bc9437737"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that the defendant treated persons subject to the exclusionary conduct differently than the defendant treated other persons;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id41620d1ad0374379afe011b2a9793fbf"><enum>(3)</enum><text>that any price of the defendant for a product or service was below any measure of the costs to the defendant of providing the product or service;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id48a5dca59ab04061a356fa8f95ebc203"><enum>(4)</enum><text>that a defendant with significant market power in a relevant market has recouped or is likely to recoup the losses it incurred or incurs from below-cost pricing for products or services in the relevant market;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ae1889a9e524c64a4848800a2dab3e8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>that the conduct of the defendant makes no economic sense apart from its tendency to harm competition;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5a4bdc0e296c4813a879986f00d9c7eb"><enum>(6)</enum><text>that the risk of harming competition presented by the conduct of the defendant or any resulting actual harm to competition have been quantified or proven with quantitative evidence; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbca34fb8fdf640dcb49ba0377b8948f3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>that when a defendant operates a multi-sided platform business, the conduct of the defendant presents an appreciable risk of harming competition on more than 1 side of the multi-sided platform.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd32de70fe4a04a3e9c2caac838296e9c"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Civil penalties</header><text>Any person who violates subsection (b)(1) shall be liable to the United States for a civil penalty, which may be recovered in a civil action brought by the Attorney General of the United States, of not more than the greater of—</text><paragraph id="id67b1f23f02b749919699fbfb16f43988"><enum>(1)</enum><text>15 percent of the total United States revenues of the person for the previous calendar year; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id56a8ed86362c4340b6f26104d1246e1e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>30 percent of the United States revenues of the person in any line of commerce affected or targeted by the unlawful conduct during the period of the unlawful conduct.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id34f0e60bed0a4fc0872c1f599357b0b2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal Trade Commission authority</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id13e1937f6e214b2c90e4b6fb17531022"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 26A, as added by subsection (a), the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id332dd9ab8c20430e831dce7995839d0d"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5cb4ac1bc65b469fbd8d19142c794a2d"><enum>26B.</enum><header>Civil penalties</header><subsection id="idc9de7ee66ada4ec18810dd9864a215fc" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Civil penalty for violation of section 26A of the Clayton Act</header><text>The Commission may commence a civil action in a district court of the United States against any person, partnership, or corporation who violates section 26A(b)(1) to recover a civil penalty, which shall accrue to the United States, in an amount not more than the greater of—</text><paragraph id="id446fc7559c444c078f4a4afe9659c914" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>15 percent of the total United States revenues of the person, partnership, or corporation for the previous calendar year; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id43e0c5d75cab43aba1824b0f9cffe3a1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>30 percent of the United States revenues of the person, partnership, or corporation in any line of commerce affected or targeted by the unlawful conduct during the period of the unlawful conduct.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idaad7ce040b1d48208fed0cf5d8ccb155"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Commission litigation authority</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in section 16(a)(3) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/56">15 U.S.C. 56(a)(3)</external-xref>), the Commission shall have exclusive authority to commence or defend, and supervise the litigation of, any civil action authorized under section 26A and any appeal of such action in its own name by any of its attorneys designated by it for such purpose, unless the Commission authorizes the Attorney General to do so. The Commission shall inform the Attorney General of the exercise of such authority, and such exercise shall not preclude the Attorney General from intervening on behalf of the United States in such action and any appeal of such action as may be otherwise provided by law.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8e1e326c7bd1497bbc44cdf89643f4fa"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement guidelines</header><paragraph id="ida796bc7fa5b443bba53a55109a2bc469"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General and the Federal Trade Commission shall issue joint guidelines outlining policies, practices, and analytical techniques relating to agency enforcement under section 26A of the Clayton Act, as added by subsection (a) of this section, with the goal of promoting transparency and deterring violations of such section 26A.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id906d66313f5b4c959960cc09909e803a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Attorney General and the Federal Trade Commission shall update the joint guidelines issued under subsection (a), as needed to reflect current agency policies and practices, but not less frequently than once every 5 years beginning on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb6af7d19824447df8df096383c064321"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public notice and comment</header><subparagraph id="id640656607e5a44f295b2521c48bfd5c2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text>Before issuing guidelines under paragraph (1) or (2), the Attorney General and the Federal Trade Commission shall publish proposed guidelines in draft form and provide public notice and opportunity for comment for not less than 60 days after the date on which the guidelines are published.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id398a8ccb2c844271ab1cd25d6fbd378c"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inapplicability of rulemaking provisions</header><text>The provisions of section 553 of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to the guidelines issued under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id229a1c228b394a7daf18b1382f9431ba"><enum>11.</enum><header>Penalties for Sherman Act violations</header><subsection id="id3fa2e04c6c9a415d8762c0169554eed8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Civil penalty amendments</header><paragraph id="id37ab13320bd8448e8cb145a6bcf99c77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Section 1 of the Sherman Act</header><text>Section 1 of the Sherman Antitrust Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1">15 U.S.C. 1</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="id54beec970e494bc39c65c51d73c869dc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Every</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) Every</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2ccca83eb1a74e0e9aa5e564088cb73e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7857f38710c04b2d9a9d4326bdf5d26c"><subsection id="idbf4b193e0095467398fefd29e4e03358"><enum>(b)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id00c43a1367d247fbb8a405b8cd48749a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Every person who violates this section shall be liable to the United States for a civil or criminal penalty of not more than the greater of—</text><subparagraph id="ida9dad78c66794c8dadd4e61a835b6671" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>15 percent of the total United States revenues of the person for the previous calendar year; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2f25bd8ec0fb479d9412de70ca9d4213" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>30 percent of the United States revenues of the person in any part of the trade or commerce related to or targeted by the unlawful conduct under this section during the period of the unlawful conduct.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idefc27b3be8bf49628d5d6049e5b60049" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A penalty under this section may be recovered in a civil or criminal action brought by the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9d06873f0dca49ca8586fea75a4056c7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Section 2 of the Sherman Act</header><text>Section 2 of the Sherman Antitrust Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2">15 U.S.C. 2</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="id909675864df14b0588d94c195d961eed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Every</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) Every</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf6ac2226152a42a7adb5382e7179ba25"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idff48c40f60e1402c8628272bb6ac1a56"><subsection id="idf787bf143f274c259be92de16aa9036d"><enum>(b)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id95ccdd2a7c6741058e757154e7a5b273"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Every person who violates this section shall be liable to the United States for a civil penalty of not more than the greater of—</text><subparagraph id="id8fdc97a62fba45068d932d406fb3196f" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>15 percent of the total United States revenues of the person for the previous calendar year; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id538b75ffb56e49769066a45b8ea41030" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>30 percent of the United States revenues of the person in any part of the trade or commerce related to or targeted by the unlawful conduct under this section during the period of the unlawful conduct.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id39c3fc1bce004a7cb8a088299b052d9d" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A civil penalty under this section may be recovered in a civil action brought by the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id304d2811a8ad4858a28dafdf5e6bda4e"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act</header><text>Section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d036a312bc64f6c9e9b4ec5b8cb4fe0"><subsection id="idfac9c5e9cf10413fb6aadcee1c061307"><enum>(o)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idfc4e6fddbbba43599ac063d37fb4b2a3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Commission may commence a civil action in a district court of the United States against any person, partnership, or corporation for a violation of subsection (a)(1) respecting an unfair method of competition that constitutes a violation of sections 1 or 2 of the Sherman Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1">15 U.S.C. 1</external-xref>, 2) and to recover a civil penalty for such violation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id597037a4f45a4c5f9f16b7d8d571ece5" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In an action under paragraph (1), any person, partnership, or corporation found to have violated subsection (a)(1) respecting an unfair method of competition that constitutes a violation of section 1 or 2 of the Sherman Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1">15 U.S.C. 1</external-xref>, 2) shall be liable for a civil penalty of not more than the greater of—</text><subparagraph id="idd59886230f2c4dafa8a89a76c21e76b5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>15 percent of the total United States revenues of the person, partnership, or corporation for the previous calendar year; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id98c8fc3c70544760a98e654e2ab37c7b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>30 percent of the United States revenues of the person, partnership, or corporation in any line of commerce related to or targeted by the unlawful conduct described in paragraph (1) during the period of the unlawful conduct.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id1a7c8b75a1ea441cb6534f0a9da56a0c"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Section 16 of the Federal Trade Commission Act</header><text>Section 16(a)(2) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/56">15 U.S.C. 56(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="ide1e923a54a794bb4a66eb020b6b8ef75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7d0fb583933340babb7f784abbb33db9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E)—</text><clause id="iddf7f7ae9531f450ebb3350af1c7d505d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by moving the margins 2 ems to the left; and</text></clause><clause id="idd2b3dbd8b7fe4b99b32ed0dc52889189"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking the semicolon and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc8e7a58c299e4a7992f03f193a43726a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (E) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id178919f801ef44c59e7864aa5fe58061"><subparagraph id="id0cbc77d746954f848335cbbc26d73615" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to recover civil penalties under section 5(o);</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3d3465e1510842e19b45e70d8d7d7aac"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>The civil penalties provided in subsection (b) of section 1 of the Sherman Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1">15 U.S.C. 1</external-xref>), subsection (b) of section 2 of the Sherman Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2">15 U.S.C. 2</external-xref>), and subsection (o) of section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a) of this section, are in addition to, and not in lieu of, any other remedy provided by Federal law, including under—</text><paragraph id="id55fe6dbc8b4b4f5c8b40f6af108c405b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 4 or 16 of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/15">15 U.S.C. 15</external-xref>, 26); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id76e3e8b218c64563a2132c7731bb4c14"><enum>(2)</enum><text>section 13(b) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/53">15 U.S.C. 53(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id8d7fa91c658946fe9fad1bab48cce8a0"><enum>12.</enum><header>Joint civil penalty guidelines</header><subsection id="ida86d0c7b9c11409ca56865920c8dbcad"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General and the Federal Trade Commission shall issue joint guidelines reflecting agency policies for determining the appropriate amount of a civil penalty to be sought under sections 1(b) and 2(b) of the Sherman Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1">15 U.S.C. 1</external-xref>, 2), section 26A(f) of the Clayton Act, as added by section 10(a) of this Act, and section 5(o) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>), as added by section 11(a) of this Act, with the goal of promoting transparency and seeking remedies for individual violations that are effective in deterring future unlawful conduct and proportionate to the gravity of the violation.</text></subsection><subsection id="id1a858b9cd0184c9f808a66cf522fa27f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In determining civil penalty amounts under sections 1(b) and 2(b) of the Sherman Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1">15 U.S.C. 1</external-xref>, 2), section 26A(f) of the Clayton Act, as added by section 10(a) of this Act, and section 5(o) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>), as added by section 11(a) of this Act, a district court of the United States shall consider—</text><paragraph id="id102519254a7041428fd4447cf9fe49d2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the volume of commerce affected;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2066cb0d62f0480289602500bbc0f732"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the duration and severity of the unlawful conduct;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfe281fe2ef0a4d5993c3a3af4fdf50ce"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the intent of the person undertaking the unlawful conduct;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3b71531cf08a45bdaf86b2cffa6e9893"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the extent to which the unlawful conduct was egregious or a clear violation of the law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id567461a8a06a4464956211fbee3034e5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>whether the civil penalty is to be applied in combination with other remedies, including—</text><subparagraph id="id565ed743e0ff458fb1cf8ef5e7ba0b55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>structural remedies, behavioral conditions, or equitable disgorgement; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5c077907c8324eaba83a8ebb25baef7a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other remedies available under section 4, 4A, 15, or 16 of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/15">15 U.S.C. 15</external-xref>, 15a, 25, 26) or section 13(b) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/53">15 U.S.C. 53(b)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida37aed848e9f43a8a78415530650a149"><enum>(6)</enum><text>whether the person has previously engaged in the same or similar anticompetitive conduct;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb3a545a9c3b8447f9f4451dd182d4081"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the extent to which the penalty will act to deter future violations of the antitrust laws; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id789f626843c4455fbe6cf0098314f6b7"><enum>(8)</enum><text>whether the person undertook the conduct in violation of a preexisting consent decree or court order.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3f4008af1fa74945b8a15af84553d680"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Attorney General and the Federal Trade Commission shall update the joint guidelines issued under subsection (a), as needed to reflect current agency policies and practices, but not less frequently than once every 5 years beginning on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="id27f2a01d3f5b4578b6c5e0dedbc303f5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public notice and comment</header><paragraph id="id1bc5f4a8958f49fe98d1825f1d5ce773"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text>Before issuing guidelines under subsection (a) or subsection (c), the Attorney General and the Federal Trade Commission shall publish proposed guidelines in draft form and provide public notice and opportunity for comment for not less than 60 days after the date on which the guidelines are published.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb6502acb4ebd4589911ff250f18c0dbe"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inapplicability of rulemaking provisions</header><text>The provisions of section 553 of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to the guidelines issued under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id7f72e70cbcdf430e8fa53d0891e45297"><enum>13.</enum><header>Market definition</header><subsection id="idedf728f0e54c48cc9c056ca9b4ad0f3e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Establishing liability under the antitrust laws does not require the definition of a relevant market, except when the definition of a relevant market is required, to establish a presumption or to resolve a claim, under a statutory provision that explicitly references the terms <term>relevant market</term>, <term>market concentration</term>, or <term>market share</term>. Statutory references to the term <term>line of commerce</term> shall not constitute an exception to the foregoing rule that establishing liability under the antitrust laws does not require the definition of a relevant market.</text></subsection><subsection id="id2160f2e4fb6a49cc996eb7d9279da0cb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Direct evidence</header><text>If direct evidence in the record is sufficient to prove actual or likely harm to competition, an appreciable risk to competition sufficient to satisfy the applicable statutory standard, or that the effect of an acquisition subject to section 7 of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/18">15 U.S.C. 18</external-xref>) may be to create an appreciable risk of materially lessening competition or to tend to create a monopoly or a monopsony, neither a court nor the Federal Trade Commission shall require definition of a relevant market in order to evaluate the evidence, to find liability, or to find that a claim has been stated under the antitrust laws.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida703054c358544ceb0d678a531baea25"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to prevent a court or the Federal Trade Commission from considering evidence relating to the definition of proposed relevant markets to evaluate the merits of a claim under the antitrust laws.</text></subsection></section><section id="id7d55e94732814eb7a55fabc09e43679d"><enum>14.</enum><header>Limitations on implied immunity from the antitrust laws</header><subsection id="id5653c16a84c749588f878623026bda5b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any action or proceeding to enforce the antitrust laws with respect to conduct that is regulated under Federal statute, no court or adjudicatory body may find that the Federal statute, or any rule or regulation promulgated in accordance with the Federal statute, implicitly precludes application of the antitrust laws to the conduct unless—</text><paragraph id="id32b47d6b3f97484f91fa2a81f7719988"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a Federal agency or department actively regulates the conduct under the Federal statute;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3bd23ac0bac74878ad3f956ca97c7a14"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Federal statute does not include any provision preserving the rights, claims, or remedies under the applicable antitrust laws or under any area of law that includes the antitrust laws; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3e0af6a113014828ba5456d164e9dc3e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Federal agency or department rules or regulations, adopted by rulemaking or adjudication, explicitly require or authorize the defendant to undertake the conduct.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf3defccca96746f8a91b173daf3f5909"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Existing Federal regulation</header><text>In any action or proceeding described in subsection (a), the antitrust laws shall be applied fully and without qualification or limitation, and the scope of the antitrust laws shall not be defined more narrowly on account of the existence of Federal rules, regulations, or regulatory agencies or departments, unless application of the antitrust laws is precluded or limited by—</text><paragraph id="id4ee65da41b8c42adb8020164cd54dded"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an explicit exemption from the antitrust laws under a Federal statute; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id512dfb8f9e374f2dae3f58c0c60ed160"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an implied immunity that satisfies the requirements under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id031446bb4f004b30ac83c63868874896"><enum>15.</enum><header>Whistleblower protections</header><subsection id="id54c56d71f0f642ca83324b36fb7d064e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Protections for civil whistleblowers</header><text>The Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 27 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/26b">15 U.S.C. 26b</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd6fb19fa0ce44c4ca38fe1712fe0372f"><section id="id71c58e8cd7be4380a43ae5515c29e8c6"><enum>27A.</enum><header>Anti-retaliation protection for civil whistleblowers</header><subsection id="id0e782f20880b470facd4b604f89fd4fe"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Whistleblower protections for employees, contractors, subcontractors, and agents</header><paragraph id="idaa373ddf0b7b4cf2a35cc602f0e185b9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No employer may discharge, demote, suspend, threaten, harass, or in any other manner discriminate against a covered individual in the terms and conditions of employment of the covered individual because of any lawful act done by the covered individual—</text><subparagraph id="id72bd5f29f63645d8a21c0bc8f8b540d3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to provide or cause to be provided to the Federal Government or a person with supervisory authority over the covered individual (or such other person working for the employer who has the authority to investigate, discover, or terminate misconduct) information relating to any violation of, or any act or omission the covered individual reasonably believes to be a violation of, the applicable antitrust laws; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfa11acea23a6402885c6ef663b5679fe"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to cause to be filed, testify in, participate in, or otherwise assist a Federal Government investigation or a Federal Government proceeding filed or about to be filed (with any knowledge of the employer) relating to any violation of, or any act or omission the covered individual reasonably believes to be a violation of, the applicable antitrust laws.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddc548c19af6e4d2f9baeec4ad18b03c3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on protections</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to any covered individual if—</text><subparagraph id="id0e6042e3601b4e6ca3a098e146258127"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the covered individual planned and initiated a violation or attempted violation of the applicable antitrust laws;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id68290c5b5e494b9aa09e81fff09aa0ea"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the covered individual planned and initiated a violation or attempted violation of a criminal law in conjunction with a violation or attempted violation of the applicable antitrust laws; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id24dd318011b84526932a31858c9440f1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the covered individual planned and initiated an obstruction or attempted obstruction of an investigation by the Federal Government of a violation of the applicable antitrust laws.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide5574c82f91b43df935deb87a1ba031c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><subparagraph id="idbeea9e339e3843be88d4f225414d711f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Applicable antitrust laws</header><text>The term <term>applicable antitrust laws</term> means section 1, 2, or 3 of the Sherman Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1">15 U.S.C. 1</external-xref>, 2, and 3) or section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>) to the extent that such section applies to unfair methods of competition.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id967089860dab4b769a6b90daf36eefb8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered individual</header><text>The term <term>covered individual</term> means an employee, contractor, subcontractor, or agent of an employer.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddf648ef1726b48119ee20751103e6113"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Employer</header><text>The term <term>employer</term> means a person, or any officer, employee, contractor, subcontractor, or agent of such person.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id61068bf8defd45589c50a803fa9b0035"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Federal Government</header><text>The term <term>Federal Government</term> means—</text><clause id="idec890f13b04746e1b152b3596e0eac18"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a Federal regulatory or law enforcement agency; or</text></clause><clause id="idbe244637a11f4bd39b503055191ac181"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any Member of Congress or committee of Congress.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id759a6c5d64e749e8bbffd2087462c216"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> has the same meaning as in subsection (a) of the first section of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12(a)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id787037409a9645d1a3561e963d2b5f6d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement action</header><paragraph id="id9b33979c69ea4318bb1e9adcd063a4de"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A covered individual who alleges discharge or other discrimination by any employer in violation of subsection (a) may seek relief under subsection (c) by—</text><subparagraph id="idf1139ec4394244d6a8286b3daba29e2c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>filing a complaint with the Secretary of Labor; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idce052d8813c1478c94a80c7b59cb1237"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the Secretary of Labor has not issued a final decision within 180 days of the filing of the complaint and there is no showing that such delay is due to the bad faith of the claimant, bringing an action at law or equity for de novo review in the appropriate district court of the United States, which shall have jurisdiction over such an action without regard to the amount in controversy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida867c0c4c03f464bb62789f4f452953b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedure</header><subparagraph id="idab567b7a58f6409cbd4a9da5926288c8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A complaint filed with the Secretary of Labor under paragraph (1)(A) shall be governed under the rules and procedures set forth in section 42121(b) of title 49, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id806a371fb4264d348a1bafac142d9a16"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Notification made under section 42121(b)(1) of title 49, United States Code, shall be made to any individual named in the complaint and to the employer.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id233a52e76eb8453c8dde06cbc8b39679"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Burdens of proof</header><text>An action brought under paragraph (1)(B) shall be governed by the legal burdens of proof set forth in section 42121(b) of title 49, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id80286088cc804346b73bf099527b3f45"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Statute of limitations</header><text>A complaint under paragraph (1)(A) shall be filed with the Secretary of Labor not later than 180 days after the date on which the violation of this section occurs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5c78a0013efa455892b457ca317cf778"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Civil actions to enforce</header><text>If a person fails to comply with an order or preliminary order issued by the Secretary of Labor pursuant to the procedures set forth in section 42121(b) of title 49, United States Code, the Secretary of Labor or the person on whose behalf the order was issued may bring a civil action to enforce the order in the district court of the United States for the judicial district in which the violation occurred.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id073706f0076b425fa10a589f31767ffb"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Remedies</header><paragraph id="id3e880fa38e314b1b8b8d1d876987f399"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A covered individual prevailing in any action under subsection (b)(1) shall be entitled to all relief necessary to make the covered individual whole.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcc647756ad094f68a752377fd13c8d3b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensatory damages</header><text>Relief for any action under paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="idbf88968178384707b8a193b06dda4700"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reinstatement with the same seniority status that the covered individual would have had, but for the discrimination;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd70df07038894dc89dc20ccb680d929d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount of back pay, with interest; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id704d05737c4e463a8e888f3375d6e17d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>compensation for any special damages sustained as a result of the discrimination including litigation costs, expert witness fees, and reasonable attorney’s fees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id09562725991545f19076dbf91c69292f"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rights retained by whistleblowers</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be deemed to diminish the rights, privileges, or remedies of any covered individual under any Federal or State law, or under any collective bargaining agreement.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id42e76f50f8a5442ebdff12834d2ef0a4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Whistleblower reward</header><text>The Antitrust Criminal Penalty Enhancement and Reform Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1">15 U.S.C. 1</external-xref> note) is amended by inserting after section 216 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/7a-3">15 U.S.C. 7a–3</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc4d1c8abd8bf471086cb565c3fc48ca6"><section id="id912d4b42fba540a7b17987bf3abf3a71"><enum>217.</enum><header>Criminal antitrust whistleblower incentives</header><subsection id="id4893880ef11340338a846bc8b0521a9f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section the following definitions shall apply:</text><paragraph id="id4f318e4cf5d44417a26742461d748110"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Antitrust laws</header><text>The term <term>antitrust laws</term> means section 1 or 3 of the Sherman Act (15 U.S.C. 1 and 3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ided4dfe50b59a407c8b2d442951cb7338" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Collected proceeds</header><text>The term <term>collected proceeds</term> means any sanctions, fines, penalties, or awards obtained in any covered enforcement action, whether by judgment, settlement, or a deferred prosecution agreement. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb58182f1169f40459b51ac9214323492"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered enforcement action</header><text>The term <term>covered enforcement action</term> means any criminal action brought by the Attorney General under the antitrust laws that results in collected proceeds exceeding $1,000,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfadbf733fcbf443092f89533673c30ca" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Original information</header><text>The term <term>original information</term> means information that—</text><subparagraph id="id2b95d50cadfa4fe6a3b0aa367fa48b14" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is derived from the personal knowledge of a whistleblower;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf355169d796b488eb30e757d7f122c2a" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not known to the Attorney General or the Department of Justice from any other source, unless the whistleblower is the original source of the information; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8eef9bbaa83d4f5e87bb4d40d324b573" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not exclusively derived from an allegation made in a judicial or administrative hearing, in a governmental report, hearing, audit, or investigation, or from the news media, unless the whistleblower is a source of the information; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5ea590edcaad4c2295b6aafb0164fc62" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is not already required to be disclosed to the Department of Justice or another Federal agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf4265c39f4084d3e85f71e4fa87da5fd"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Related action</header><text>The term <term>related action</term>, when used with respect to any covered enforcement action brought by the Attorney General, means any criminal action brought by another United States entity that is based upon the original information provided by a whistleblower that led to the successful enforcement action by the Attorney General.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id940b5783bbae4e00b26c489193a389e4"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Whistleblower</header><text>The term <term>whistleblower</term> means any individual who provides, information relating to a violation of the antitrust laws to the Department of Justice, in a manner established by the Department of Justice.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf4eaf6a0e5a64f27a752ac68b0ad892d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Awards</header><paragraph id="id109e187865214f5a9f3f23fd4d4714de"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In a covered enforcement action, or related action, the Attorney General, subject to subsection (c), may pay an award or awards to a whistleblower who voluntarily provided original information to the Department of Justice that led to the successful enforcement of the covered enforcement action, or related action, in an amount not less than 10 percent and not more than 30 percent, in total, of what has been collected of the criminal fine imposed in the covered enforcement action or related action under the antitrust laws;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide7c4cfadeed84adeaa68c8491de8dec2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payment</header><text>Any amount paid under paragraph (1) shall be paid from the criminal fine collected in the covered enforcement action.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id90c05db467ed402fbc5f86afe0d14f78"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determination of amount of award; denial of award</header><paragraph id="idfa18ab75a1ab4f80a849316f36e1e074"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination of amount of award</header><subparagraph id="idfda17d4e150e4ba1855992829027b7b5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Discretion</header><text>The determination of the amount of an award made under subsection (b) shall be at the discretion of the Attorney General.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id61e50fda60884c3fba7df53751fe4bd2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>In determining the amount of an award made under subsection (b), the Attorney General shall take into consideration—</text><clause id="ide21528c65a424313b0361c473da12d99"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the significance of the information provided by the whistleblower to the success of the covered enforcement action;</text></clause><clause id="idf9c1b7fc377446608d4571ffd98cec95"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the degree of assistance and cooperation provided by the whistleblower in a covered enforcement action;</text></clause><clause id="ida82683e79a2848be827708edbef1a9b5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the interest of the Department of Justice in deterring criminal violations of the antitrust laws by making awards to whistleblowers who provide information that lead to the successful covered enforcement actions; and</text></clause><clause id="idf4cac84b6b934684b5ea374743ea729c"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>such additional relevant factors as the Attorney General may establish.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5cdf51f1a79d4e838d93e47f290d28e4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Denial of award</header><text>No award under subsection (b) shall be made—</text><subparagraph id="id088633d9f84c4c219c221107c6267c9e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to any whistleblower who is, or was at the time the whistleblower acquired the original information submitted to the Commission, a member, officer, or employee of—</text><clause id="idc47cc779310a41a6b6cf9d09e7ee82c5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any branch, agency, or instrumentality of the Federal Government; or</text></clause><clause id="id34044bb789454e7881dfc4db808c7284"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any law enforcement organization;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2d62af1fbbe149f8889140a9153e1462"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to any whistleblower who is convicted of a criminal violation related to the covered enforcement action for which the whistleblower otherwise could receive an award under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec584a6e95964caf80d23c9bb1e160db"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to any whistleblower who was an originator or leader of or who coerced any other party to participate in the activity giving rise to liability under the antitrust laws in the covered enforcement action for which the whistleblower otherwise could receive an award under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide919c4b2293c435b980c9d7cd42b85b0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to any whistleblower who fails to respond provide timely, truthful, continuing, and complete cooperation to the Department of Justice relating to the original information or intentionally withholds information relating to the original information;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id609c911420994fab9ff3163111264f0b"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to any whistleblower who commits, participates in, or attempts to commit or participate in any crimes after disclosing the original information to the Department of Justice;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0f5801b992c3419d933be0747361c34a"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to any whistleblower who fails to submit information to the Department of Justice in such form as the Department may require, or failed to report relevant information to the Department known to the whistleblower when the whistleblower first reported the information to the Department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2969b37fdec3471184e949860916c65d"><enum>(G)</enum><text>to any whistleblower who fails to submit information to the Department of Justice in such form as the Department may require as prescribed by regulation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9059d3555bf54122a17f8eed37839669"><enum>(H)</enum><text>to any whistleblower who planned and initiated an obstruction or attempted obstruction of an investigation by the Department of Justice of a violation of the antitrust laws; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id89d16569c7ab460b8e077a7d9ef76cc9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to any whistleblower who engages in conduct that would disqualify the whistleblower if the whistleblower were a leniency applicant under the Leniency Program of the Antitrust Division.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7f5444fac1a747acb4bafa9e3da08022" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Representation</header><text>Any whistleblower who makes a claim for an award under subsection (b) may be represented by counsel.</text></subsection><subsection id="idaf781be3c6524bf58c4dc0216ecd6862"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appeals</header><text>Any determination made under this section, including whether, to whom, or in what amount to make awards, shall be in the discretion of the Attorney General. Any such determination, except the determination of the amount of an award if the award was made in accordance with subsection (b), may be appealed to the appropriate court of appeals of the United States not more than 30 days after the determination is issued by the Attorney General. The court shall review the determination made by the Attorney General in accordance with section 706 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="id547c11729e3247bdb2327660221cd065"><enum>16.</enum><header>Prejudgment interest</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 4 of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/15">15 U.S.C. 15</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idda9928d277804a6b91ae3c9c1fa83bdf"><subsection id="ide8b3bfc7936e45a9aa8dcd4be94586e6"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), any person who shall be injured in his business or property by reason of anything forbidden in the antitrust laws may sue therefor in any district court of the United States in the district in which the defendant resides or is found or has an agent, without respect to the amount in controversy, and shall recover threefold the damages by him sustained, the cost of suit, including a reasonable attorney’s fee, and simple interest on threefold the damages by him sustained for the period beginning on the date of service of such person’s pleading setting forth a claim under the antitrust laws and ending on the date of judgment.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id7dd1fbbeb0ed400986071ed0bbf258c1"><enum>17.</enum><header>No forced arbitration for antitrust disputes</header><subsection id="ida918fb1ebfc94406aab472b859abe260"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title 9, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf54676a24938487e957709f1fc172b89"><chapter id="id904da2ad694e4ceb8c36bd78a0c10c61"><enum>5</enum><header>Arbitration antitrust disputes</header><section id="idebeb7d322692400f9632d3c66c134a64"><enum>501.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this chapter—</text><paragraph id="idf8743df654d0409fa9ac514027314cf0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>antitrust dispute</term> means a dispute—</text><subparagraph id="id2d90c766375b4281a52bf4a1e8e09216"><enum>(A)</enum><text>arising from an alleged violation of the antitrust laws (as defined in subsection (a) of the first section of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12(a)</external-xref>) or State antitrust laws; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id11b31c1d26284af2a01ad9960adec508"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in which the plaintiffs seek certification as a class under rule 23 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure or a comparable rule or provision of State law;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide482b3d1d3d04c8db672df1f9159f180"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>predispute arbitration agreement</term> means an agreement to arbitrate a dispute that has not yet arisen at the time of the making of the agreement; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcda1d90a02a74c909d143679b5c5433d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>predispute joint-action waiver</term> means an agreement, whether or not part of a predispute arbitration agreement, that would prohibit, or waive the right of, one of the parties to the agreement to participate in a joint, class, or collective action in a judicial, arbitral, administrative, or other forum, concerning a dispute that has not yet arisen at the time of the making of the agreement.</text></paragraph></section><section id="ida0b11e4361674f0681c0ec8cd87b3e9a"><enum>502.</enum><header>No validity or enforceability</header><subsection id="id4ebc8caa37124a5a81e204cb7407ca4e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, no predispute arbitration agreement or predispute joint-action waiver shall be valid or enforceable with respect to an antitrust dispute.</text></subsection><subsection id="id848479496b52412a87e1f198ccd53cf9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>An issue as to whether this chapter applies with respect to a dispute shall be determined under Federal law. The applicability of this chapter to an agreement to arbitrate and the validity and enforceability of an agreement to which this chapter applies shall be determined by a court, rather than an arbitrator, irrespective of whether the party resisting arbitration challenges the arbitration agreement specifically or in conjunction with other terms of the contract containing such agreement, and irrespective of whether the agreement purports to delegate such determinations to an arbitrator.</text></subsection></section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id5176a841bb0843268508b708ec2b0e5b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="idc659ffe998fa42c985c688d32618a85f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title 9 of the United States Code is amended—</text><subparagraph id="id12101d991ee94f64b74f1cd7fd13e53e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 2, by inserting <quote>or 5</quote> before the period at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1e26841b77c642048fb6dbcda6652ca2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 208, by inserting <quote>or 5</quote> before the period at the end; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf33e2417fc81480da07202542a42dc31"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in section 307, by inserting <quote>or 5</quote> before the period at the end.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7db7324e247a42cda50d1689601a14bf"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of chapters</header><text>The table of chapters for title 9, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4BE19201C01444478AB8182F5944B5C3"><toc><multi-column-toc-entry level="chapter" bold="on"><toc-enum>5.</toc-enum><level-header level="chapter">Arbitration of antitrust disputes</level-header><target>501</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ida2b14000e4bd491297f84f7d2eb03ec7"><enum>18.</enum><header>Additional remedies; rules of construction</header><subsection id="id29ca84c60428464f9efaa2a6a77e2c1e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Additional remedies</header><text>The rights and remedies provided under this Act are in addition to, not in lieu of, any other rights and remedies provided by Federal law, including under section 4, 4A, 15, or 16 of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/15">15 U.S.C. 15</external-xref>, 15a, 25, 26) or section 13(b) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/53">15 U.S.C. 53(b)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="idff3f56138967442284f3ecafe4d6de10"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to—</text><paragraph id="id999fe819e22e4a9b9449ceb54992f1d2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>impair or limit the applicability of any of the antitrust laws; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7c9a06a6254e49d6b3f7b358c7b540d0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibit any other remedy provided by Federal law.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id9045856e843b4a2888fc2e714f937e07"><enum>19.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subsection id="id09fc009b0b5147da8e875604491403b7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Fiscal year <enum-in-header>2025</enum-in-header></header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2025—</text><paragraph id="idf0b8789e8e894dd1a827785c02ded1a7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$535,000,000 for the Antitrust Division of the Department of Justice; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9729375e846e4d819db9020a5ffa6d5d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$725,000,000 for the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id98ed14228e184d99a8ca1d452c1eb282" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Subsequent years</header><text>Beginning in fiscal year 2026, and each fiscal year thereafter, all premerger notification filing fees collected pursuant to section 7A of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/18a">15 U.S.C. 18a</external-xref>) shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id516d5c4a3ffc42c5a45885d8235bd11f"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be retained and used for expenses necessary for the enforcement of the antitrust and kindred laws by the Antitrust Division of the Department of Justice and the Federal Trade Commission, to remain available until expended; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbe757bfd65cc4c1b98bed51e9e8394fc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be treated as direct spending described in section 250(c)(8)(A) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/900">2 U.S.C. 900(c)(8)(A)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

