<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF33A951C0DCE4AF8BBE8C2FE23DB4EF1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3432 IH: Trump Derangement Syndrome Research Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3432</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250515">May 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000626">Mr. Davidson</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of the National Institutes of Health to conduct or support research to advance the understanding of Trump Derangement Syndrome, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H74A3B3CDCFC34135A4EAA98E8A07E00F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8B1F6A9DF9D244E2BC10B51E4146AEF1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Trump Derangement Syndrome Research Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TDS Research Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H60C71BD481E64DE8B97EE0C70B5F4369"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HD4BFE4604C6745C789E366ACE29F69EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Trump Derangement Syndrome has been described as a behavioral or psychological phenomenon involving intense emotional or cognitive reactions to Donald J. Trump, his actions, or his public presence, with early documented references emerging during his 2016 presidential campaign.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D883FD0B5784B9B83FC32CD83D2B5CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notable early instances of TDS include certain media coverage amplifying polarized responses to Donald J. Trump’s campaign rhetoric, which some observers cite as initial signs of TDS, though precise origins remain understudied.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H94595582C41F45EB96558C85DEC4713C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recurrent, selective reporting by media outlets, emphasizing aspects of Donald J. Trump’s actions or statements while omitting broader context, has been alleged to contribute to TDS by intensifying polarized public reactions and deepening societal division.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1325AF1C4DB74DD293E2D5B9F179C25D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Frequent amplification of unverified or anonymously sourced claims about Donald J. Trump’s conduct has further fueled TDS, driving significant public outrage and contributing to heightened emotional responses among individuals and groups.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBDF8EB4CE01A4F5AA1D5FA347BDDC1C8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The following two confirmed assassination attempts against Donald J. Trump occurred in 2024:</text> <subparagraph id="H6DD6A663A4464E5A93E4310C423E4497"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On July 13, 2024, at a campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, a shooter wounded Donald J. Trump’s ear, killed one attendee, and injured two others.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1D8F37EC806549B3BBB7E52A4EEDEA72"><enum>(B)</enum><text>On September 15, 2024, at the Trump International Golf Club in West Palm Beach, Florida, a suspect was apprehended with a rifle and the incident was investigated as an assassination attempt.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6A1D80C5C3F84708AE17F531C3578180"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Understanding TDS may contribute to broader insights into political polarization, media influence, and psychological responses to public figures, with implications for public health and social cohesion.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB72CEB220C5C4AB69FB5C978FB8F2F31"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The National Institutes of Health, through its existing programs, is well-positioned to study the psychological and social factors underlying TDS, including its origins, media influences, and potential links to extreme behaviors, to inform public health strategies.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HD71756109DB0432BB65D22563E5633E2"><enum>3.</enum><header>NIH research on Trump Derangement Syndrome within existing programs</header> <subsection id="H5C4DA329E05A452D8DD0DFA0C654B8B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the National Institutes of Health, through the existing programs and authorities of the National Institute of Mental Health and other relevant institutes and centers, shall conduct or support research to advance the understanding of Trump Derangement Syndrome, including its origins, manifestations, and long-term effects.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H6D98E0CB2D8C4947B45CA365019588FD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Research objectives</header><text>The research conducted under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HA185D71334C444109A43FA2F7849E3EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>efforts to identify the initial emergence or earliest documented cases (commonly referred to as <quote>patient zero</quote> or index cases) of TDS, including historical and social analyses to trace the onset of TDS;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF134D231910743A28E6CA756C77501BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>investigation of the long-term psychological, social, or behavioral impacts of TDS on affected individuals, communities, or public discourse;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9A15BA281C94867A137517B01C575F5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>analysis of contributing factors, such as media exposure, political polarization, or social dynamics, to the development or spread of TDS; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H17783269136A468CB13905BC493AD211"><enum>(4)</enum><text>exploration of potential interventions, coping mechanisms, or strategies to mitigate adverse effects of TDS, as applicable.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7E01090DBFBD418CA0D50272BAB1A1D5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>The Director shall collaborate with the heads of other Federal agencies, academic institutions, and relevant organizations, as appropriate, to achieve the objectives described in subsection (b).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H917442CE7E124B6CA54799E8AFD78B30"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Director shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report on—</text> <paragraph id="H1449064E23BB48E58D819C11F8B4B41B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the progress of research conducted under this section;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7EDF89C2013E46B38B37184756905179"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any findings related to the initial emergence or long-term effects of TDS; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H557D99F2B6F142C4A9BE0A768B7E0249"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations for further research or public health actions.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H14E865101877440C82A3ECA1410DC4EA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>Trump Derangement Syndrome</quote> or <quote>TDS</quote> refers to a behavioral or psychological phenomenon characterized by intense emotional or cognitive reactions to Donald J. Trump, his actions, or his public presence, as observed in individuals or groups.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

