<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7F270B871949439C80A5436AE1F32B81" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5416 IH: Contract Postal Unit Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5416</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250916">September 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 39, United States Code, to modify the procedures used by the United States Postal Service for the closure or consolidation of contract postal units, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H24458588108C42269329150E26C3BCA3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0505BD9081FE485890BB94F65E9A78EF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Contract Postal Unit Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HF5C6B4DCEAA041168EC86D559DEE5CFB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modification of procedures to close or consolidate contract postal units</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 404 of title 39, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HCBD8F75A42E145C7A34C85ED426A6657" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H1E1FAE667CA940CB9B3952CF7A9D2556"><enum>(f)</enum> <paragraph id="HDC8E7741FB964C37B2A02F838EE3640D" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the closure or consolidation of any contract postal unit on or after the date that is 6 months after the date of the enactment of the Contract Postal Unit Transparency Act, the Postal Service shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H07981C57F97F429591A5C374B03D2431" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publish, on the Postal Service’s public website, a report on expected impacts the closure or consolidation will have on customers and what steps the Postal Service will take to ensure continued access to postal services in affected areas;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC31526644032461A98F7EEC7C0D918DD" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit a report to Congress on the reasons for closing or consolidating the contract postal unit;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H211A712B7E0A4E61A4946393F5740EEE" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>hold a public hearing on the closure or consolidation, which may be attended in-person or virtually by any members of the public affected by the closure or consolidation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5D157369EF534787A02214521209C64D" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>not later than 7 days after the hearing under subparagraph (C), publish, on the Postal Service’s public website, a summary of the hearing and include in such summary a description of any comments made or otherwise submitted at such hearing and the percentage of such comments that were in support or against the closure or consolidation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE3A3A85FE4F24EBAB70A3014B82B566C" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, a contract postal unit may not be closed or consolidated until on or after the date that is 180 days after the date the summary is published under paragraph (1)(D).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> </legis-body></bill>

