<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H11A71ACFB6FB4F7C91B14D1593B51537" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2949 IH: Working Families Task Force Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2949</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250417">April 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a national task force to expand opportunities and improve the standard of living for working families in America.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4077608CBA884514B82A828F04E424D4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6F7B1FAC1E29409992B067F9C25E31CE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Working Families Task Force Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H70F42D868659441E90896C945882E29E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Interagency task force</header> <subsection id="HE6E2B5FF628948059135608308BBB6F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretaries of Health and Human Services, Education, Housing and Urban Development, Commerce, Treasury, Transportation, and Agriculture and the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, shall establish an Interagency National Task Force on Working Families. The task force shall be titled the <quote>Working Families Task Force</quote> and for purposes of this Act be referred to as the <quote>Task Force</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC3445D93DEE94A4B8A2B17700BBE43CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Task Force shall be composed of not fewer than 10 members and shall include representatives designated by the relevant Secretaries from each of the following Federal agencies:</text> <paragraph id="HF6D127A7C8AD405E87304E7DD17AB8C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Department of Labor.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF891B5A6187B422A9EB3F26D8AB299DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Department of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H50199311AEC8477A94AB6D5303754659"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Department of Education.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE90823E7F422428385BA2D10908216A4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFFF22F2BF47C49038E71574D04EA5CEA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Department of Commerce.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8332E63E1C5A46BFA967878442536C2B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Department of Treasury.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4FFCD9A8BC9A4E1AAC8466C638345841"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Department of Transportation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9620A19A2B76418683A62FA91A662B77"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Department of Agriculture.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3689F23A85354D1AA88E1C25709C7D8C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Small Business Administration.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB31DB5AED523488EAEEC6A8F5C3CEE42"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Meetings</header> 
<paragraph id="H18FA0EFF0DD8486CA7EBCE0BCF4162C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Task Force shall meet not less than 1 time per quarter per calendar year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7FF701A33CF04511BCD69ADA7A08630B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>Two-thirds of the members of the Task Force shall constitute a quorum.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1C40E39D92234EE68634B4A20FCF2CA0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Task Force shall be to—</text> <paragraph id="H715FA180D1814E279807F9C7217FB428"><enum>(1)</enum><text>examine the challenges facing working families; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H809911C3F30E4979A04884CBB15DD730"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop recommendations to improve the standard of living and quality of life for working families.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3F0BFA6A7AF34232AE91E89B53811955"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Task Force shall include the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H1DD65D63AF6D4F0BB3B4A17D78B9430B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Identifying and evaluating key factors that impact the standard of living for working families, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H05448B5BC7644702A5E1678BB1856923"><enum>(A)</enum><text>addressing affordability challenges related to various economic conditions, including inflation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEAEE80DD730643B088CC49273CF0AE12"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reducing barriers to economic mobility;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF3B0DF91D1894595905A3E77960E4E63"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improving access to quality jobs with livable wages and strong labor standards;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H31498CF0C6F24A829A596637EBF9C43E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>expanding affordable child care for all families;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCA2D946CB69B4064A0EADB1CBD03312C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>improving incentives, including tax policies such as the child tax credit, child and dependent care tax credit, and earned income tax credit, that assist children and families;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8E49A44397204C6E822386EBBFB4385D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>supporting home care and medical care for seniors and families that need assistance;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1CC063EEBF154B479EF1710B43F3B6EC"><enum>(G)</enum><text>mitigating barriers to more affordable and higher quality health care and services;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H40EDD8BDC33D43FB8515C295D1569534"><enum>(H)</enum><text>obtaining and building quality, affordable housing;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3300B61833EF4A92B85B02DD26D0EB8E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>expanding educational and workforce training opportunities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H32FB8340EF714CA78E05DA5953FA160A"><enum>(J)</enum><text>increasing financial literacy and access to financial services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H640B77D03DB84654AB7D8533D1AC22EF"><enum>(K)</enum><text>accessing affordable and nutritious food;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H108055F30F1D4548B0E03F07A78B121B"><enum>(L)</enum><text>reducing gaps in access to technology and the internet that impact educational and employment opportunities and health services; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC713D950968143A4B3DEE70C332933F9"><enum>(M)</enum><text>reducing environmental hazards and creating a healthier environment;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0D6B415184404509A8B2422295D531FB"><enum>(N)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accessing affordable and renewable energy sources;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9C04861F82E34F418A5DCA6A702652BF"><enum>(O)</enum><text>accessing affordable, reliant, and efficient transportation systems; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8B8A71AF8C1C45F3A80F2BFD6ADD79AB"><enum>(P)</enum><text>addressing the impacts of staffing and funding cuts at Federal agencies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA25FC7D73EA4192BCC856F137F8B707"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assessing or developing a methodology to assess how various macroeconomic conditions (which may include unemployment, inflation, gross domestic product, and monetary policy) affect quality of life and affordability for working families.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H905C28147D1A4FB8B26B8ABBA549B2D2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Assessing the effectiveness of current Federal policies and programs in helping working families achieve an improved standard of living.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D1E873BC3A74EA19E1089785FF52E8D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Developing legislative and regulatory policy recommendations to enhance the efforts of Federal agencies and Congress to empower working families to meet the challenges of current economic conditions, raise their standards of living, and access the benefits of economic growth.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5510C22877DE49DC92C45F5AEB67034C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Task Force shall consult with a wide-ranging group of external stakeholders and public experts in order to develop the recommendations referred to in paragraph (4). </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6CF80827B9FE4113AB748889F4372A1D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Task Force shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7496E26588A64CE382CEC6672F7A025B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on its most recent findings and recommendations, which shall include a list of stakeholders and public experts with which the Task Force consulted and the meeting minutes for each meeting of the Task Force; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC062F82E25646FCA9733285B8C621B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make such report publicly available on the website of the Task Force.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC7A5F2136F164957B425A071EBC7DEB0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the following:</text> <paragraph id="HA29E3552D6034D04A2707D203E305E44"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H810705D06B494A65977FBA24FD576AF2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA012EF8C72014EB38C3F4A2E6E310038"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1453C12F4C6642C38D36039F6C8F2F76"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6376E4338B85474C90ECE76AE41107D5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

