<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H183C222824364B7C9AAEF988AA6B7116" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 673 IH: Supporting the recognition of September 8 through 14, 2025, as “Interscholastic Athletic Administrators’ Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 673</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250903">September 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the recognition of September 8 through 14, 2025, as <quote>Interscholastic Athletic Administrators’ Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the House of Representatives recognizes September 8 through 14, 2025, as <quote>Interscholastic Athletic Administrators’ Week</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, each year, the House of Representatives recognizes the invaluable contributions of interscholastic athletic administrators to the physical, academic, and emotional development of students in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas interscholastic athletic programs play a critical role in forming a well-rounded educational experience for students;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas participation in sports is proven to improve concentration, memory, and academic behavior, such as school attendance;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas participation in sports results in higher levels of confidence and self-esteem, reducing the risk of suicidal thoughts and other mental health struggles in teenagers and young adults;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas research shows that participation in sports can reduce the rate of youth violence and crime by providing youth with access to personal and professional growth opportunities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas participation in sports plays a critical role in the development of leadership skills and resiliency in students;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas interscholastic athletic administrators—</text><paragraph id="id3acfca26b983415b88f0ecd77fccde4b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>work tirelessly every day to ensure the safety and well-being of all student athletes;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb6d15be95b7040adbb3b130f03d04c8e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>often work long and unpredictable hours to ensure that every student athlete has access to the training and assistance they need; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0014e89e5f64407883b3b2115889e963"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">tirelessly dedicate themselves to the athletic, academic, and personal development of their students and players, building mature and hardworking young men and women;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 8,000,000 student athletes in the United States rely on the hard work of interscholastic athletic administrators for guidance, coaching, and mentorship; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the athletic programs led by interscholastic athletic administrators promote values of leadership, service, hard work, and teamwork in schools and communities: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H19BC91E430EF4B5F8C93C5C6A1882FB3"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HD8A51D04F2D849C4990A5232A9FDB8B4"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H4ED855BD0D904A94BD756A69CC7A69ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commends interscholastic athletic administrators for their commitment and their leadership of student athletes at the secondary school level; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EE0AD86E72C45E4930C5B4B98F373C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the critical role school athletic programs play in student leadership development; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H891007A11B8F4BA9A1A24EC6FEF22603"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commends the National Interscholastic Athletic Administrators Association as the leading organization that prepares individuals who lead secondary school athletics throughout the United States, providing continuous learning, compassion, and preparation within the profession.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

