<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-BIN25149-4RK-35-XPG"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 320 IS: Designating July 2025 as “Plastic Pollution Action Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 320</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250714">July 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating July 2025 as <quote>Plastic Pollution Action Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas plastic pollution represents a global threat that will require individual and collective action, both nationally and internationally, to address;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas approximately 460,000,000 tons of plastic are produced each year, a number that is projected to triple by 2050;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the United States—</text><paragraph id="idbbe1b82428534ef49dac89ff28c1d52c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the rate of plastic waste recycling decreased in 2021 to between 4 and 6 percent; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1a7cff1b44a44d9bafd6b295d501b17f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>less than 3 percent of plastic waste is recycled into a similar quality product;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a study from the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development found that, in 2024, the United States—</text><paragraph id="id9101a84baebe4e25a282562979746ecd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>mismanaged 3 percent of plastic waste;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1967cc8754e94093a60a057f5c64d32c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>landfilled 73 percent of plastic waste;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide8d53ee96858455cbf5c6f1448710453"><enum>(3)</enum><text>incinerated 19 percent of plastic waste; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida47ab753e0f74645bcf40115f6e15452"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recycled 5 percent of plastic waste;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas single-use plastics account for not less than 40 percent of the plastic produced every year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 12,000,000 tons of plastic waste enter the ocean every year from land-based sources alone;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, if no action is taken, the flow of plastics into the ocean is expected to triple by 2040;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as of the date of adoption of this resolution, studies estimate that there are approximately 171,000,000,000,000 pieces of plastic in the oceans of the world;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, of those 171,000,000,000,000 pieces of plastic in the ocean, 1 percent floats, 5 percent washes up on beaches, and 94 percent sinks to the bottom;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 2,000 marine species have consumed plastics;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas plastics, and associated chemicals of plastics, are ingested by humans and are associated with well-established human health risks;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas studies show that scientists have found microplastic particles in the blood, lungs, colons, breastmilk, livers, feces, sputum, and placentas of humans;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas studies suggest that humans ingest up to 1,500,000 microplastic particles per day;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas taking action to reduce plastic production and use, to collect and clean up litter, and to reuse and recycle more plastics will lead to less plastic pollution;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, every July, individuals challenge themselves to reduce their plastic footprint through <quote>Plastics Free July</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during the 50-year period preceding the date of adoption of this resolution, more than 18,000,000 volunteers have joined the International Coastal Cleanup to collect more than 380,000,000 pounds of plastic and debris while simultaneously recording their findings to inform research and upstream action;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas switching to reusable items instead of single-use items can prevent waste, save water, and reduce litter; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas July 2025 is an appropriate month to designate as <quote>Plastic Pollution Action Month</quote> to recommit to taking action, individually and as a country, to reduce plastic pollution: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id7ab41882204e4cde9a6040259a0ec109"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates July 2025 as <quote>Plastic Pollution Action Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3d34f8233eda48a784a12dff9d705331"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the dangers to human health and the environment posed by plastic pollution; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfde657da5d5b4c72b4218107229d64bb"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages all individuals in the United States to protect, conserve, maintain, and rebuild public health and the environment by responsibly participating in activities to reduce plastic pollution in July 2025 and year-round.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

