<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2CA017E01CF84137BB7A265E5C145916" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2003 IH: Affordable Loans for Students Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2003</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250310">March 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to lower the interest rate on Federal student loans to 2 percent.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1EB7728E43BF4F1D9B26602C55902668" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H8AC5E2AE07EC40F6A6DDC1C96A033403"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Affordable Loans for Students Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HABC8FE042D49470781B63F51BD7BBCE6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Program authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 451(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087a">20 U.S.C. 1087a(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8628DE2D8B004104993CD3AEEE77438D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and (2)</quote> and inserting <quote>(2)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H81B385C712624AA0B29B0AFB3FFCE042"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>; and (3) to make loans under section 460A(b)</quote> after <quote>section 459A</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H39EB65CA43F842BD9EDDDD60AFA943B4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Program for the loan modification of eligible Federal loans held by the Secretary, and refinancing of other Federal student loans</header> 
<subsection id="HF3429DE9D0FB4093B80E6C80C3530C58"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Loan modification and refinancing</header><text>Part D of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087a">20 U.S.C. 1087a et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9C07ED7442E74BF183EBBC07037475C9"> <section id="HAC025611046F4375B9BFDFDA918301FD"><enum>460A.</enum><header>Program for the loan modification of eligible Federal loans held by the Secretary, and refinancing of other Federal student loans</header> <subsection id="H2DCF1397407A45C187F1C43F88F7EFEB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal Direct Loan Modification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish and implement, with respect to each borrower of an eligible Federal loans held by the Secretary, procedures to modify, without any action from the borrower, the terms of such loan so that beginning on the first July 1 after the date of enactment of the Affordable Loans for Students Act, the applicable rate of interest shall be 2.0 percent on the unpaid principal balance of the loan.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD24A175746D54CFCACD7F230973C741E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Refinancing eligible Federal loans not held by the Secretary as Federal Direct Consolidation Loans</header> 
<paragraph id="HBAFB8A5BD6454D80BE8223BCB3E52988"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish and implement, with respect to each borrower of an eligible Federal loan not held by the Secretary, procedures to refinance such loan in accordance with the requirements of paragraph (2) and without any action from the borrower, except that such borrower may opt out of such procedures with respect to such loan.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA2CDC9C45E934BB4B61A92998E009ADC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In refinancing an eligible Federal loan not held by the Secretary with respect to a borrower of such loan, the Secretary shall carry out the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H79C3C4070FA64396B5FBB7BBA40C471D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make a Federal Direct Consolidation Loan under this subsection, in an amount equal to the sum of the unpaid principal, accrued unpaid interest, and late charges of the eligible Federal loan not held by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDA4C4D281C8740C3831D1136DEC6A64F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall pay the proceeds of such Federal Direct Consolidation Loan to the holder of the eligible Federal non-direct loan, in order to discharge the borrower from any remaining obligation with respect to such eligible Federal loan not held by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H252A1F39CDF84AF3A87DA2CAADBC2ADF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Terms and conditions of refinanced loans</header> 
<subparagraph id="H396E0A7C16D14B469D8D9DDA67C6015E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal Direct Consolidation Loan made under this subsection shall have the same terms and conditions as a Federal Direct Consolidation Loan that was not made under this subsection, except—</text> <clause id="HE3C444889D3344969BCBA615799D07E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that the Secretary may adjust such terms and conditions as necessary to enable the borrower to access loan forgiveness or other benefits available to the borrower under the loan before refinancing under this subsection, in any case where such benefits are more generous than provided under a Federal Direct Consolidation Loan; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE425B13241034B8B9AA2308EC620037B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as otherwise provided in this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H8D98C0DA3CE540489503CD6A6275998E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No origination fees</header><text>Notwithstanding section 455(c), the Secretary may not charge a borrower of a loan made under this subsection an origination fee for such loan.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H3421261C3BB5465CA2E4ABF0206BE100"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Interest rate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The applicable rate of interest for a loan made under this subsection shall be 2.0 percent on the unpaid principal balance of the loan.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2F2527A49B4D43BF963D04354ACC2551"><enum>(D)</enum><header>No automatic extension of repayment period</header><text>A loan made under this subsection shall not result in the extension of the duration of the repayment period of the original loan, and the borrower shall retain the same repayment term that was in effect on the original loan. Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to prevent a borrower from electing a different repayment plan at any time in accordance with section 455(d)(3).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H4993D997EC6B4138A4996EB606537C55"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</text> <clause id="HB3AB038C953A416295597CF9452C8216" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibit a borrower of an eligible Federal loan not held by the Secretary from consolidating such a loan with any other loan eligible for consolidation under this section into a single consolidation loan under this section; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBD62ED7BC67E415FB8782F276C596A99" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>require such a borrower to consolidate any such loan with any other loan eligible for consolidation under this section into a single consolidation loan under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H4F3B1A6FCC54429594DD2BCA8454109A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the second July 1 after the date of enactment of the Affordable Loans for Students Act, and on an annual basis thereafter, the Secretary shall submit a report to the authorizing committees that includes—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HD49C9CCE38624A4BA33D5E97CD4A6008"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the total number of borrowers whose loans have been modified or refinanced under this section during the preceding year; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H64782D3B9AF54F869EC908930C09CE88"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of such borrowers who are delinquent in making payments on such a loan.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAC45651A97474EC9BAAC9EEBE37DB33B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H324CBC1445EF455CB3601B19B87F991D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible Federal loan held by the Secretary</header><text>The term <term>eligible Federal loan held by the Secretary</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCBCF4ADFCF0A496AACEDBB20A0A9749D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any loan made under this part, and first disbursed before the first July 1 after the date of enactment of the Affordable Loans for Students Act;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H50EEFC0F33A646F9A0354D0D46BDD0B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any loan made, insured, or guaranteed under part B, and which is held by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB3A1C169EAC343C3A3F98186A87A9678"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any loan made under part E, and which is held by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBBD0DFF490D94C76893ABCB2BB0510F1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any loan made under subpart I of part A of title VII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/292">42 U.S.C. 292 et seq.</external-xref>), and which is held by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H795954D8171B4232BE5CB4D4DFDD23C6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible Federal loan not held by the Secretary</header><text>The term <term>eligible Federal loan not held by the Secretary</term> means any loan—</text> <subparagraph id="HD9187E5640304B069A38D707064298DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>made, insured, or guaranteed under part B, and which is not held by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2C6B3FFE7C7F468EBDAE4EB8127D3381"><enum>(B)</enum><text>made under part E, and which is not held by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAC50A81D43FE448599E4FB91A5107C42"><enum>(C)</enum><text>made under—</text> 
<clause commented="no" id="HB8C403EC51B3498C83D5FA3865875F90"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subpart I of part A of title VII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/292">42 U.S.C. 292 et seq.</external-xref>), and which is not held by the Secretary;</text></clause> <clause id="H15038550466144189E694AB8D57A5909"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subpart II of part A of title VII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/292q">42 U.S.C. 292q et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H68450438E70B4B78B380ABF7ECD54341"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">part E of title VIII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/297a">42 U.S.C. 297a et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H749912C6BD7D43A9B898EAF3CD45C7C4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Original loan</header><text>The term <term>original loan</term>, used with respect to a Federal Direct Consolidation Loan made under subsection (b), means a loan for which a borrower’s liability is discharged by such Federal Direct Consolidation Loan.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2B3F86F7284D42599BA8016FDAA4A57D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>The Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H8A2E6EB08762406EB6356B24C9A279AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 428C(a)(3)(B)(i)(V) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1078-3">20 U.S.C. 1078–3(3)(B)(i)(V)</external-xref>)—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0478603914984FA68658658D668A5548"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of item (cc) and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2C122E6AA4B54A849600EF722C933965"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of item (dd) and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HF7848A56B9224BEC9910D6A2B3B015E9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9A19E2004D644925A6F5765672959F50"> <item commented="no" id="HB14B9E76E2E042A2BAB5381671C71A46"><enum>(ee)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the purpose of obtaining a Federal Direct Consolidation Loan under section 460A(b).</text></item><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H35409A5619E64E5AB5F06AB6898CA0F4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Applicable rates of interest for loans made on or after the first July 1 after the date of enactment of the Affordable Loans for Students Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 455(b)(8) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(b)(8)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDEB9D41ED8084C1CB7E8BDE0D6519A38"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="paragraph">and before the first July 1 after the date of enactment of the Affordable Loans for Students Act </header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="paragraph">July 1, 2013</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HA48BBEB9E5F147C6A4211AA740F82541"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>and before the first July 1 after the date of enactment of the Affordable Loans for Students Act</quote> after <quote>July 1, 2013</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F83191846514F0F9DC31ED07F2D1287"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>and before the first July 1 after the date of enactment of the Affordable Loans for Students Act</quote> after <quote>July 1, 2013</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF3AB8C03B18D4B37AE296419E69E0234"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by inserting <quote>and before the first July 1 after the date of enactment of the Affordable Loans for Students Act</quote> after <quote>July 1, 2013</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H988219C372D644AD8A3789E7BAF9C379"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by inserting <quote>and before the first July 1 after the date of enactment of the Affordable Loans for Students Act</quote> after <quote>July 1, 2013</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4DA3C788C161407BA7FBFCECB1554C1A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (F) as subparagraph (G); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8974A370A94C425FBEB6B7BF3132D0A3"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after subparagraph (E) the following: </text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D6B03D531AC4F62AE88051CCB7BB6B7"> 
<subparagraph id="H4F26CD3072674209A1AC216481259A98"><enum>(F)</enum><header>New loans on or after the first July 1 after the date of enactment of the Affordable Loans for Students Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the preceding subparagraphs of this paragraph, for Federal Direct Stafford Loans, Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loans, Federal Direct PLUS Loans, and Federal Direct Consolidation Loans for which the first disbursement is made, or the application is received, on or after the first July 1 after the date of enactment of the Affordable Loans for Students Act, the applicable rate of interest shall be 2.0 percent on the unpaid principal balance of the loan.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

