<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC227854E066C4689A0E479CE8D99CC24" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4482 IH: Stop NOAA Closures Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4482</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000635">Ms. Dexter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose a moratorium on closing, suspending, terminating leases of, ceasing construction of, consolidating, or otherwise imposing any new limitation on access to facilities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H43595FFE34D84CC299B55AFF7EA0D4D8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8019858B7A8D4F01BD7AB59D0230C459" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop NOAA Closures Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H213256AF436449EC91F9DB7B4193651C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Moratorium with respect to facilities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</header> 
<subsection id="H696F08BF7BA84F639D136C706153A8EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Moratorium</header> 
<paragraph id="HF7F7840444914D98A14283556CF10EA3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), the Secretary of Commerce, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, or the Administrator of General Services, as the case may be, may not close, suspend, terminate a lease of, cease construction of, consolidate, or otherwise impose any new limitation on access to a facility of the Administration.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H36DC3B1614BA41808B8E21165B00FB01"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for emergencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to any temporary action by the Secretary of Commerce, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, or the Administrator of General Services, as the case may be, to close, suspend, terminate a lease of, cease construction of, consolidate, or otherwise limit access to a facility of the Administration in response to an emergency that poses an immediate threat to the health or safety of personnel of the Administration.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE8BCEB7701D14D1F8B24D9834DD80FC3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cessation upon report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall cease to be effective on the date that is 180 days after the report described in paragraph (4) is submitted.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H592CADD6E6F84FE5841856D7E20807F9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not earlier than January 21, 2029, the Secretary of Commerce, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the Administrator of General Services shall jointly submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report outlining and justifying the process for selecting any facility of the Administration for closure, suspension, termination of a lease, cessation of construction, consolidation, or other limitation on access to such a facility. Such report shall include information relating to the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDC9E185FFF2E40C78F7A789A10AF9283"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of the criteria used for such selection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6216C4D95E8A4580BFE939104B21DAC5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of any method of cost-benefit analysis applied in connection with such closure, suspension, termination of lease, cessation of construction, consolidation, or other limitation, including any analysis that takes into account the following:</text> 
<clause id="HAF3A81AB5FA44ACBBAA69B90D2C16DC3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The anticipated savings resulting from such closure, suspension, termination of lease, cessation of construction, consolidation, or other limitation.</text></clause> <clause id="HBBD9AA695AF94CC9920D3F613A773A64"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The anticipated costs associated with replacing services lost as a result of such closure, suspension, termination of lease, cessation of construction, consolidation, or other limitation.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC2267C0855DB46F087106CB0C602E620"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The anticipated impact on services of the Administration.</text></clause> <clause id="H5E2B8985FCD04BE3B371A1117E8145FC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such other relevant factors as the Secretary, the Administrator of the Administration, and the Administrator of General Services may determine.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H06280F14B3F5412191BD31BEA8D4C6EF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Future closures, suspensions, terminations of leases, cessations of construction, consolidations, and other limitations on access</header> 
<paragraph id="H1696B3EEEB4941CEAC8694CC8067C260"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (3), the Secretary of Commerce, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, or the Administrator of General Services, as the case may be, may not close, suspend, terminate a lease of, cease construction of, consolidate, or otherwise impose any new limitation on access to a facility of the Administration unless the requirement of paragraph (2) is satisfied.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB35A6E9C123A49DD81F5527637EB3E19"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement of this paragraph is that not later than 30 days before a closure, suspension, termination of lease, cessation of construction, consolidation, or other limitation with respect to a facility referred to in paragraph (1), the Secretary of Commerce, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the Administrator of General Services jointly submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report outlining and justifying the process for selecting such facility for such closure, suspension, termination of lease, cessation of construction, consolidation, or other limitation. Such report shall include information in accordance with subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(4).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA5C50AF7107041BD98C257F682789006"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception for emergencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to any temporary action by the Secretary of Commerce, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, or the Administrator of General Services, as the case may be, to close, suspend, terminate a lease of, cease construction of, consolidate, or otherwise limit access to a facility of the Administration in response to an emergency that poses an immediate threat to the health or safety of personnel of the Administration.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HC01B26DD0B79417BB95E7CA565E0779A" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (b) shall apply with respect to a closure, suspension, termination of lease, cessation of construction, consolidation, or other limitation referred to in paragraph (1) of such subsection occurring after the cessation of the moratorium under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

