<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDCDCBBA3F197456494FF976B42BFF0A4" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-joint" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HJ 77 IH: Establishing that it shall be the policy of the Government of the United States to recognize the sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity of Ukraine within that nation’s internationally recognized borders as established in 1991.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 77</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250318">March 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>) submitted the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Establishing that it shall be the policy of the Government of the United States to recognize the sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity of Ukraine within that nation’s internationally recognized borders as established in 1991.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the United States reaffirms its unwavering commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity within its internationally recognized borders as established in 1991;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Russia has illegally and forcibly occupied and annexed Crimea, Donetsk, Luhansk, Zaporizhzhia, and Kherson;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since 2014, Russia has flagrantly violated the United Nations Charter and international law through its war of aggression and illegal occupation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States upholds the principle of ex injuria jus non oritur—illegal acts create no legal rights—and that no unlawful act can become legal through force, coercion, or passage of time;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Ukraine’s borders and lands remain Ukrainian regardless of any act of war, coercion, or political manipulation; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as with the Welles Declaration of 1940, the United States categorically rejects Russia’s territorial claims made through aggression and sham referenda: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HFC837DC0513B4156B6BFBE7F86E79B6F"><section id="H45C47F0A30B54AEC937E1261E92BABBD" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it shall be the exclusive policy of the Government of the United States to not recognize, nor commit any action that implies recognition of, claims made by the Russia Federation over the sovereign Ukrainian territories it occupies, including but not limited to Crimea, Donetsk, Luhansk, Zaporizhzhia, and Kherson.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

