<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEBA48D21BEEA496398E5D863AA42869C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 922 IH: Period PROUD (Providing Resources for Our Underserved and Disadvantaged) Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 922</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250204">February 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide targeted funding for States and other eligible entities through the Social Services Block Grant program to increase the availability of menstrual products for individuals with limited access to such products.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H902D4B2AC4E8468FA389CDEAF804E1ED" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H551A3D7016E64B009FAEE74C71B454B8"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Period PROUD (Providing Resources for Our Underserved and Disadvantaged) Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H60A1B4C0B8F040CDA88176F5F338962B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Targeted funding for menstrual products through the Social Services Block Grant Program</header><subsection id="HECFC82BC893D4A18AC55B45E60DA18B0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Increase in funding for Social Services Block Grant Program</header><paragraph id="H31C24FC1D5D64A6BB83B125C3307D3F6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount specified in subsection (c) of section 2003 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397b">42 U.S.C. 1397b</external-xref>) for purposes of subsections (a) and (b) of such section is deemed to be $1,900,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2028, of which the amount equal to $200,000,000, reduced by the amounts reserved under paragraph (2)(B) for each such fiscal year, shall be obligated by States in accordance with subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EAE1573F3794EB1BDBB3C9FBD03EA83"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><subparagraph id="H6613AF3437EF4644BC45072315452B12"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Out of any money in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated, there is appropriated $200,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029, to carry out this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9D9EB6D22D3477DAD7D89D383289CE1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reservations</header><clause id="H42305A9DA93A48498ABB0D6AF7B9049B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The Secretary shall reserve, from the amount appropriated under subparagraph (A) to carry out this section—</text><subclause id="H1ED5D061FEE3476B81B1A0C4C5F19740"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029, not more than 2 percent of the amount appropriated for the fiscal year for purposes of entering into an agreement with an eligible entity described in subparagraph (C) to assist in providing technical assistance and training, to support effective policy, practice, research, and cross-system collaboration among grantees and subgrantees, and to assist in the administration of the program described in this section; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H9381799224C14FC8A031D2EFFEAFC385"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2026, an amount, not to exceed $2,000,000, for purposes of conducting an evaluation under subsection (d).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HED303DF6BFB24B3AAD010231AE52A2BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>No State entitlement to reserved funds</header><text>The State entitlement under section 2002(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397a">42 U.S.C. 1397a(a)</external-xref>) shall not apply to the amounts reserved under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1DF3AFE82284B91B5AC865AC6E88BF7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Eligible entity described</header><text>An eligible entity described in this subparagraph is a nonprofit organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code, that—</text><clause id="HAC9AC410F8C64246B5B1C2F92BB41E6C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has experience in the area of community distributions of basic need services, including experience collecting, warehousing, and distributing basic necessities such as menstrual products;</text></clause><clause id="H781F1F04ECC3499A8E620ACE8A7A77C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>demonstrates competency to implement a project, provide fiscal accountability, collect data, and prepare reports and other necessary documentation; and</text></clause><clause id="H3870D36A7E624573A7C1E8D31B071A54"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>demonstrates a willingness to share information with researchers, practitioners, and other interested parties.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE19899309DEE44B7BB56ACD88C8D7F0B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rules governing use of additional funds</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H93B2542E63D9400A8E8ADF343BFCE24C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Funds are used in accordance with this subsection if—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H64A8BD42E7EA4C2FB431FCC5D0233CB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the State, in consultation with relevant stakeholders, including agencies, professional associations, and nonprofit organizations, distributes the funds to eligible entities to—</text><clause id="H6B33DF3DD2BE4F7B9F1603A1F67251A2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>decrease the unmet need for menstrual products by low-income menstruating individuals through—</text><subclause id="HCBAC988C29E0430EA81C8AB4A5DF62B7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the distribution of free menstrual products;</text></subclause><subclause id="HEEDB8E7B0C594F5182CBEF12A371A281"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">community outreach to assist in participation in existing menstrual product distribution programs; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H3D4AC0B942554D16B2142023B62DA664"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving access to menstrual products among low-income individuals; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H672CA4BD6738428ABA3A0F4828D31690"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase the ability of communities and low-income families in such communities to provide for the need for menstrual products of low-income adults;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB264B9201F9B48F18AA0F30115B63482"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the funds are used subject to the limitations in section 2005 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397d">42 U.S.C. 1397d</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41361D1638FB4FBB9FB8889BC2E33A69"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the funds are used to supplement, and not supplant funds that are or have been made available from Federal, State, local, or philanthropic sources to carry out subtitle A of title XX of such Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8B94B795646A4986B679BA47396F0872"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allowable uses by eligible entities</header><subparagraph id="H9390AB08811247FC9A78CD16581E2544"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity receiving funds made available under subsection (a) shall use the funds for any of the following:</text><clause id="HDB47698D58E044E0AD34DDFCD7573D08"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To pay for the purchase of menstrual products by, and the distribution of menstrual products among low-income individuals.</text></clause><clause id="H74272C05FFBB455AB8F8D49F476BC581"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>To integrate activities carried out under subparagraph (A) with other basic needs assistance programs serving low-income families, including the following:</text><subclause id="H5C6ABF5D9B7B41E4BD2DAF310BAFA6DC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Programs funded by the temporary assistance for needy families program under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/601">42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>), including the State maintenance of effort provisions of such program.</text></subclause><subclause id="H330A4D5FAC6547FABAEE12DA63D75AB0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Programs designed to support the health of eligible children, such as the Children’s Health Insurance Program under title XXI of the Social Security Act, the Medicaid program under title XIX of such Act, or State funded health care programs.</text></subclause><subclause id="H1077199FDE1B4A51BD178F8A4951E71F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Programs funded through the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children under section 17 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966.</text></subclause><subclause id="HF2657FB27F764CA082A3AA56315E4372"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Programs that offer early home visiting services, including the maternal, infant, and early childhood home visiting program (including the Tribal home visiting program) under section 511 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/711">42 U.S.C. 711</external-xref>).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H8674B584AD274E3090EC5B72934D3AD8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>To provide training or technical assistance in carrying out activities under this section.</text></clause><clause id="HF811A691A39343D1ACDCF975B24F060E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>To cover administrative costs.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E78CE31F55F4653BF0303C5AF5FE2D5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on use of funds for administrative costs</header><text>An eligible entity receiving funds made available under this section shall not use more than 9 percent of the funds for administrative costs incurred pursuant to this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB639D0B59F945039DF1DA119FB9EC90"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No limits on where menstrual products may be distributed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not limit the locations at which menstrual products may be distributed pursuant to this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A562C23E48E43FBB9F862164AD6F208"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><subparagraph id="HB0D118F664684FD38111FCE2B84AB2B4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Funds distributed to eligible entities</header><text>Funds made available under subsection (a) that are distributed to an eligible entity by a State for a fiscal year may be expended by the eligible entity only in such fiscal year or the succeeding fiscal year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CAB1A509D0B43739D9AA129B8FDC1E8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>Funds reserved under subsection (a)(2)(B)(i)(II) to carry out the evaluation under subsection (d) shall be available for expenditure through September 30, 2028.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H09854F94A17641CFA91AD9D5FA7B5D1D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>No effect on other programs</header><text>Any assistance or benefits received by a family through funds made available under subsection (a) shall be disregarded for purposes of determining the family’s eligibility for, or amount of, benefits under any other Federal needs-based programs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6EF984881C1B4AFCBF5A6FFA9B39ADDE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2004 of the Social Security Act shall apply with respect to payments made to a State under this section in the same way it applies with respect to payments made to a State under section 2002 of such Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5AB403463AED4622B6AC61EFBC27475B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with States and the eligible entities described in subsection (a)(2)(C) receiving funds made available under this section, shall—</text><paragraph id="HF209706B0FC54470BED37585D2A80F6B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than December 30, 2031, complete an evaluation of the effectiveness of the assistance program carried out pursuant to this section, such as the effect of activities carried out under this Act on mitigating the health risks of unmet menstrual products need among individuals in low-income families;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H845CB2089DE24291BBA8ADC3F7F23536"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than March 31, 2032, submit to the Committees on Energy and Commerce and on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report on the results of the evaluation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A33382AAEC64F8AA9CA6BDCBDF521CA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not later than April 30, 2032, publish the results of the evaluation on the internet website of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0B3503AD0DA74455ABEA426AE828676B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue guidance regarding how the provisions of this section should be carried out, including information regarding eligible entities, allowable use of funds, and reporting requirements.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEB5432DDC7504EA9AD8251EC7A127BFF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HCA9F569A287B4CEFBEA8C8E4AAE16D13"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Menstrual products</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>menstrual products</term> means menstrual cups, menstrual discs, menstrual underwear, and sanitary napkins and tampons, that conform to applicable industry standards.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB3013ECFEF84AD9843401364B13CBC4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a State or local governmental entity, an Indian tribe or tribal organization (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act), or a nonprofit organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code that—</text><subparagraph id="H48D85FB31EF845E8B3D90B8C156E2CFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has experience in the area of community distributions of basic need services, including experience collecting, warehousing, and distributing basic necessities such as diapers, food, or menstrual products;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B56E3C68D304A9E894717399B0F2659"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstrates competency to implement a project, provide fiscal accountability, collect data, and prepare reports and other necessary documentation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD481E0DA328843C3B0C7F58F0DAC305B" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>demonstrates a willingness to share information with researchers, practitioners, and other interested parties.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2837965E86B143C99C24E3B87A7ADD6F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8706867DA7D44CACAED980F4D98FA9F0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given in section 1101(a)(1) of the Social Security Act for purposes of title XX of such Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE3EE7EA90F5847D3B697A17384224D0D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Limitation on authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the administration of this section, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary not more than $6,000,000 for fiscal years 2026 through 2029.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDEA92AFCB09345EFBEEF739A44604711"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Exemption from sequestration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds made available to carry out this section shall be exempt from reduction under any order issued under the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

