<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H524BB24624B149DD8210E69C338D5FE8" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 535 IH: Recognizing June 24th as Public Safety Awareness Day to promote citizen empowerment, effective law enforcement, community-based crime prevention, and prudent public policy in support of safer neighborhoods nationwide.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 535</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250623">June 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing June 24th as Public Safety Awareness Day to promote citizen empowerment, effective law enforcement, community-based crime prevention, and prudent public policy in support of safer neighborhoods nationwide.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas public safety is a foundational responsibility of government and a prerequisite for a thriving society;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas empowering citizens through education, resources, and self-advocacy builds stronger, more resilient communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas individuals and families affected by violent crime deserve access to robust support systems, including mental health services and victim assistance programs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community-centric safety strategies encourage civic engagement, reduce reliance on centralized bureaucracies, and reinforce personal and local responsibility;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public safety is undermined by ideologically driven policies that defund or demoralize law enforcement and neglect the real consequences of unchecked criminal behavior;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas research has shown that the presence of well-trained and well-supported law enforcement officers reduces crime and enhances public trust in the justice system;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas effective safety strategies must focus on targeted, evidence-based interventions, such as <quote>focused deterrence</quote>, which identifies high-risk individuals and offers pathways to change while holding repeat offenders accountable;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas non-policing solutions—such as increased street lighting, revitalization of public spaces, and neighborhood-based initiatives—contribute meaningfully to reducing crime and improving quality of life;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas prosecutorial failure to address quality-of-life offenses has contributed to deteriorating property values, eroded trust in public institutions, and weakened the social fabric of communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas investing in mental health and substance abuse treatment alleviates unnecessary strain on police resources and allows law enforcement to focus on serious threats to public safety;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the prudent and transparent use of taxpayer resources in support of law enforcement, crime prevention, and victim support reflects a government that is both responsible and responsive to its citizens;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many of America’s inner cities continue to experience disproportionately high rates of violent crime, with homicides, shootings, and assaults often concentrated in underserved communities and driven by persistent cycles of poverty, underinvestment, and gang activity;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas residents of high-crime neighborhoods—often low-income and majority-minority communities—face daily threats to their safety and well-being, undermining economic opportunity, access to education, and overall quality of life while reinforcing systemic inequities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2024, cities such as Philadelphia, Baltimore, St. Louis, New Orleans, and Chicago ranked among those with the highest per capita homicide rates in the nation, highlighting a national crisis that demands targeted, data-driven solutions and community-based interventions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Chicago recorded 617 homicides in 2023, leading the nation in total murders for the 12th consecutive year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this figure remains approximately 24 percent higher than the pre-pandemic total of 500 homicides in 2019;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Chicago’s murder rate in 2023 was five times higher than that of New York City, despite New York having more than three times the population; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the concentration of violent crime in specific neighborhoods underscores the need for targeted, community-based interventions to address public safety effectively: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HA25E1DFD83B346BCA562ABE46824C2BB"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H11AC39F39D6E4283A928DAF4EC5DEDE8"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H5589C8375BF248799650B58AFA3D0873"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of <quote>Public Safety Awareness Day</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55B1D36E60364F999402401331925DEB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the empowerment of citizens and communities in shaping local public safety priorities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1804A55AC7D34EA4A265E7ECC85C97CC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commits to advancing policies that strengthen law enforcement, uphold the Constitution, and restore accountability in government;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BAE3BCB96DA44738FE5F56F3316A50E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages public engagement, education, and reform efforts that support a safer, more secure America; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5403BC0DAE584087A41FB8465B29CBFC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>affirms strong support for law enforcement officers across the nation, recognizing their essential role in maintaining public safety, and calls for robust resources, clear authority, and policy frameworks that empower them to carry out their duties effectively and lawfully in securing communities and upholding justice.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

