<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7EC534C1A5C3474992B96BDF96EB14A8" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 812 IH: Condemning the United Nations and International Maritime Organization for proposing a global tax on shipping emissions, threatening United States sovereignty, trade, and economic interests.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 812</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251017">October 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning the United Nations and International Maritime Organization for proposing a global tax on shipping emissions, threatening United States sovereignty, trade, and economic interests.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas the International Maritime Organization (IMO), a specialized agency of the United Nations, is expected to vote on a <quote>Net-Zero Framework</quote> proposal that would impose a global tax or levy on maritime shipping emissions;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the proposed scheme would require vessels to pay into a centralized international fund based on their carbon emissions, creating an unprecedented global taxation system on trade and transportation;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas such a tax constitutes an attempt by a global body to impose direct economic costs on private industry and sovereign nations without representation, violating the principle of <quote>no taxation without representation</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States, under the Trump Administration, firmly opposed similar international carbon tax schemes and reaffirmed that American energy and trade policy must be decided by elected officials accountable to the American people, not by unaccountable global bureaucrats;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the imposition of a global shipping tax would increase the cost of transporting goods worldwide, raise consumer prices, and reduce the competitiveness of American producers and exporters;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas such measures would undermine United States energy independence, hinder free and fair trade, and threaten the prosperity of American workers in the shipping, manufacturing, and energy sectors; and</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States retains full sovereignty over its own taxation, trade, and emissions policies and will not cede that authority to international organizations or foreign governments: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HDBD928612AD94388874B93C928D54A26"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HD0DDF975966144A0BF636184D7327125"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="HB5E6FE1FBDFB45D8996D64237566E90B">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">condemns the proposed United Nations and International Maritime Organization <quote>Net-Zero Framework</quote> as an illegitimate attempt to impose a global carbon tax that would erode national sovereignty and harm American economic interests;</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H30408B7F4F004ED18F64B0FB64848861"><enum>(2)</enum><text>opposes any attempt by international organizations to impose global taxes, tariffs, or levies on American companies, workers, or consumers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87E6E6DF9E034E1E93F6FA7B72CDE61B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls upon the President of the United States to instruct United States representatives at the International Maritime Organization to vote against any global emissions tax proposal and to oppose any related enforcement mechanisms;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCFA71254D6064E0DBE73349271079020"><enum>(4)</enum><text>affirms that no American-flagged vessel or United States shipping company shall be subject to taxation, fees, or penalties imposed by any international body without the consent of Congress;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H21DF2F2DF2AC40C6A2C03E79A527B98C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>urges the administration to consider reciprocal measures, including tariffs or restrictions, against nations or entities that attempt to enforce or benefit from such a global tax on American commerce;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2F5A8D320E8F46C2AA7C6B043E5D4D40">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>reaffirms the United States commitment to free enterprise, energy independence, and the protection of American jobs and industries from unfair global regulation; and</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H362E18CB09E943A39B5CD627A707826B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>directs the Clerk of the House to transmit a copy of this resolution to the President, the Secretary of State, Secretary of Energy, Secretary of Transportation, the United States Ambassador to the United Nations, and the United States delegation to the International Maritime Organization.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

