<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5BB4F8E03681447D8F0F3057C3B1C2B7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2152 IH: Artificial Intelligence Practices, Logistics, Actions, and Necessities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2152</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a strategy to defend against the economic and national security risks posed by the use of artificial intelligence in the commission of financial crimes, including fraud and the dissemination of misinformation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE4BCD82F6C3B4BBDA7220E9FAC6A0204" style="OLC"><section id="HD55CA0C996A942CC88365384284434CF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Artificial Intelligence Practices, Logistics, Actions, and Necessities Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>AI PLAN Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H1BE57FA055C94C69B3535BAD963F7F74"><enum>2.</enum><header>Strategy to defend against risks posed by the use of artificial intelligence</header><subsection id="H3750D998C9594F6BB7C7678778A7C5C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the development and use of artificial intelligence in the commission of financial crimes by adversarial actors poses a significant risk to the national and economic security of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="H75B7082BD71B471E90E59F14469D0249"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy To defend against risks posed by misinformation, fraud, and financial crime conducted with artificial intelligence</header><paragraph id="HB0E8DFF3125649599095DC949CFB2DA8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the officials specified in paragraph (3), shall jointly submit to Congress a report that includes the following:</text><subparagraph id="H9C9F977FABFE4B10BE78D1B51717B571"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of interagency policies and procedures to defend United States financial markets, United States persons, United States businesses, and global supply chains from the national and economic security risks posed by the use of artificial intelligence in the commission of financial crimes, including fraud and the dissemination of misinformation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73ADA629534B416AA47A743D253D33E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An itemized list of readily available resources, hardware, software, and technologies that can be immediately utilized to combat the use of artificial intelligence in the commission of financial crimes, including fraud and the dissemination of misinformation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H422D9FC151F749609FEA113C53934B6D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An itemized list of resources, hardware, software, technologies, people, and budgetary estimates needed to help Federal departments and agencies to combat the use of artificial intelligence in the commission of financial crimes, including fraud and the dissemination of misinformation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1102F2E9AC2549B084EDBFDC22010602"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>Reports required pursuant to paragraph (1) shall take the following risks into consideration:</text><subparagraph id="H5ED0EADFC16E4DBD98A6C6540D86EDF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Deepfakes.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEBD5A2686AF4153BC080A6930DAD5A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Voice cloning.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13F01C57220C4054B60A18CE309CC686"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Foreign election interference.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FCCF62A516B4C1396794135E27A65C2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Synthetic Identities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79060B8ACADB495688E79357622F5CF9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>False flags and false signals that disrupt market operations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1651833CC0AE4649A9E535488971236F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Overall digital fraud.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AD9191604F248F580E4BBEB13CB3C4B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Officials specified</header><text>The officials specified in this paragraph are the following:</text><subparagraph id="H8E387E4F0B844D06A132299D3EC0093B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The United States Trade Representative.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E13B44752894940A689EE82EAC3776E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Attorney General.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9919590D65214F5E8D1FAA11262C39A7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B49F03930F740D38774916641E497F5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCB9E6AFA0D14FF0ABA9598DBC229A10"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB6039BEC07241079F4AE58EB5C216EE"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairman of the Securities and Exchange Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE9C71C1A07354676BE0C8D0228BDE508"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>Not later than 90 days after each report under subsection (b) is submitted, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Commerce shall jointly submit to Congress a set of recommendations relating to each such respective report that contain the following:</text><paragraph id="H1CE09D51E2CB47BABDDCA0AB34484F4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Legislative recommendations to address the risks posed by the use of artificial intelligence in the commission of financial crimes, including fraud and the dissemination of misinformation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6CBEFA1609346229B1805D90EE91424"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Best practices to assist American businesses and government entities with risk mitigation and incident response to address the risks posed by the use of artificial intelligence in the commission of financial crimes, including fraud and the dissemination of misinformation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

