<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-PAT25608-KP4-9M-877"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2900 IS: Work Zone Weather Integration Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2900</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250918" legis-day="20250916">September 18 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Transportation to establish a pilot program to improve roadway safety through real-time integration of weather hazard alerts and active work zone data, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Work Zone Weather Integration Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8de45b08ff0545a7b710b031ed46fda7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program</header><subsection id="id4e69b56438c24b0baa4b6b781a5fb430"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the <term>Secretary</term>), in consultation with the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, shall establish a pilot program (referred to in this section as the <term>pilot program</term>) to improve roadway safety through the real-time integration of weather hazard alerts and active work zone data.</text></subsection><subsection id="id893ccbcc012b4fbda2d39f146eac1e4d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the pilot program shall be—</text><paragraph id="id4801f6899b894aeeb197ff16ae800455"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to develop technical protocols for integrating National Weather Service hazard alert systems with work zone location and status data feeds;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfeda29524fc04bd98b5779ffbd79c620"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to deploy and evaluate those integrated alert systems in coordination with participating State departments of transportation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb3c50dc658d54f25a0f219ac88b82616"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to assess the feasibility, costs, and safety impacts of nationwide deployment of those alert systems.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0520ed983c46453d9ce1486ff0edd838"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Participation</header><paragraph id="id21813c3d7e7043b3a9b6e76030adb968"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall solicit voluntary participation in the pilot program from not fewer than 5 States, including at least 1 rural State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id31b9470ca98947be97230c754a28d155"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of certain funds</header><text>A State participating in the pilot program may use funds apportioned under section 402 of title 23, United States Code, for eligible activities carried out under the pilot program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id767ff3088bb74b55b53aa7f733789f0e"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program, the Secretary shall coordinate with, or ensure coordination among—</text><paragraph id="ide66cb3a0fcb24a6ba3706662e89325ab"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Federal Highway Administration;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9285c52975114377b140fcfca1d75d51"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0cd688e2443842eeb39d3a68715b098a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the National Weather Service; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideba33ff13c984cf383e9d841b0fe7039"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other relevant offices of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd01446ad4fac45ca926e263756c89783"><enum>(5)</enum><text>private sector navigation, telematics, and traveler information service providers, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id75b260db4d5f4e48bb1e61b2130f9ba1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report on—</text><paragraph id="ide5e376356ca14be19257fca2eff76f88"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the activities carried out under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd283d824caed4144b16460a9276055cd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>lessons learned from the pilot program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1c560e9474a74be89378a545d2c7c75a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations on whether and how to expand the integration of weather hazard alerts and work zone safety data nationwide.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

