<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7C24E49994F74124B50BDCE325AA16DA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4041 IH: To exempt certain forest management activities in Yosemite National Park from requirements of section 102 of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4041</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250617">June 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To exempt certain forest management activities in Yosemite National Park from requirements of section 102 of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE8A871DEB91E462D9404C28ED82F2A64" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H360C39FE7BD444489C4E24177884F752" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Categorical exclusion for certain forest management activities in Yosemite National Park</header>
<subsection id="HB7AFD19DCD1C4612B35E4EFE54043090"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Categorical exclusion established</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The forest management activities described in subsection (b) are a category of activities hereby designated as being categorically excluded from the preparation of an environmental assessment or an environmental impact statement under section 102 of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H03AF5B1647F64EFFA15503E0004DA931"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Forest management activities designated for categorical exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The forest management activities designated under subsection (a) for a categorical exclusion are—</text>
<paragraph id="H0E639BA342B34FC5A52E9B1896C6B1FC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the planning, approval, and execution of fuels removal activities, including brush removal activities, in Yosemite National Park; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H24F50240A69D48DAB19F8764BDB70DC7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the planning, approval, and execution of reforestation activities in Yosemite National Park.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

