<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H50E63F35780C4AAEB447CF4989E9729F" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 387 IH: Expressing support for the designation of May 2025 as “National Asthma and Allergy Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 387</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250506">May 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of May 2025 as <quote>National Asthma and Allergy Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 4,900,000 children in the United States currently have asthma;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas nearly 28,000,000 people in the United States, have asthma and the numbers are increasing each year;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 2018, on average, children missed more than 7,900,000 days of school and adults missed 10,900,000 days of work because of asthma;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas asthma is one of the most common noncommunicable diseases among children;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 1,500,000 individuals per year visit emergency departments because of asthma’s effects;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas asthma is a leading cause of hospitalizations and school absences due to a chronic disease among children;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the total economic cost of asthma in the United States was $81,900,000,000 per year from 2008 to 2013;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas fewer than half of people with asthma report being given an asthma action plan, which is key to the prevention of asthma attacks;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Black, Hispanic, and Indigenous individuals in the United States face the highest burden of asthma;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas asthma is a manageable disease that claimed the lives of over 3,500 Americans in 2021;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 20,300,000 people in the United States have food allergies, including about 4,300,000 children;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas food allergy has increased among United States children over the past 20 years, with the greatest increase in Black children;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas children with food allergies are 2 to 4 times more likely to have asthma or other allergic diseases; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas May would be an appropriation month to designate as <quote>Asthma and Allergy Awareness Month</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H8EC384405CF64361A114B9EC2BA4DE3F"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H10F2367F09604920A8726FF50F9558FB"><text>That the House of Representatives recognizes <quote>National Asthma and Allergy Awareness Month</quote> and calls upon the American people to observe such month with appropriate ceremonies and activities. </text></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

