<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HA4E1ABE14CD74C4594CF5CEA1B5E98EC"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3112 IH: Better Collaboration, Accountability, and Regulatory Enforcement for Animals Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3112</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250430">April 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000610">Mr. Reschenthaler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Animal Welfare Act to expand and improve the enforcement capabilities of the Attorney General, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF4C7F85FBEEE4C7BBD782E862A288587"><section id="H7F4636EFE62A463AB2DC45FE0AD8B90F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Better Collaboration, Accountability, and Regulatory Enforcement for Animals Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Better CARE for Animals Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2AEE337BF93F4903906C901A503DB09D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Strengthening animal welfare enforcement</header><subsection id="H8FAFADEBA82E40A8932BD87ABC96226F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 2 of the Animal Welfare Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2132">7 U.S.C. 2132</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H948D0875CE3B4667ABDE90EE30FDBB5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>of the United States or his representative who shall be an employee of the United States</quote> and inserting <quote>or a representative of the Secretary of Agriculture, who shall be an employee of the</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29BB2904413D468CB81843E861C338A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1), by adding <quote>or</quote> at the end after the semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68A7E1009E244BC8916B9B0A8A988737"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in each of subsections (a) through (o)—</text><subparagraph id="H657FED63A2EA4EAE96BA0DC2122FB22E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting a subsection heading, the text of which comprises the term defined in the subsection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80CF67525943419CA7C0AF00B7445F66"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by reordering the subsections so as to appear in alphabetical order based on the subsection headings (as so added); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62FBBFFCB52A4582A7D9EAA4F07CB45A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating the subsections (as so reordered) appropriately.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD2FD999DCD04477599E0BCB3F5A2CFA4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sale or transportation without license</header><text>Section 4 of the Animal Welfare Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2134">7 U.S.C. 2134</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H09680A1A679149A09FC55BC8D00FEF00" style="OLC"><section id="H323189FCA59B4FC68DBD45CAA745B496"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sale or transportation without license</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No dealer or exhibitor shall do any of the following in commerce: exhibit, purchase, offer to purchase, sell, offer to sell, transport, or offer for transportation any animal, unless the dealer or exhibitor has a valid license from the Secretary that has not been suspended.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H09DDF08C7E2E4B5682341DF86B67A519"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Investigations and inspections</header><text>Section 16(c) of the Animal Welfare Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2146">7 U.S.C. 2146(c)</external-xref>) is amended in the fourth sentence by striking <quote>enforce, and to prevent and restrain violations of this Act,</quote> and inserting <quote>enforce, prevent, and restrain violations of this Act, or any rule, standard, or regulation promulgated pursuant to this Act,</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HABA008EC2F924882A5B006C511F0157E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><text>Section 19 of the Animal Welfare Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2149">7 U.S.C. 2149</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HAEE1F074D3F543AD9D606163393ADC64"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (d), in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>, or any rule, standard, or regulation promulgated thereunder,</quote> before <quote>shall</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H08DF9BDA0D0442D5B4CB2F000F47A847"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HEC8EF830C1E84679B385019E8100F9A3" style="OLC"><subsection id="H820A14F6F04D4659A88F19483C9685AB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rewards and certain incidental expenses</header><text>With respect to the sums received by the Secretary or the Attorney General as penalties or fines for any violation of this Act or any rule, standard, or regulation promulgated thereunder, the Secretary or the Attorney General, as applicable, shall use those sums to pay the reasonable and necessary costs incurred by any person in providing temporary care for any animal pending the disposition of any civil or criminal proceeding alleging a violation of this Act with respect to that animal.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0FB83692737F4CC1A203F5952B42ED45"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Enforcement by attorney general</header><text>The Animal Welfare Act is amended by inserting after section 19 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2149">7 U.S.C. 2149</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H1172A53F3C174799890559C9E70E594C" style="OLC"><section id="H58A5D958F6FD415F994FFFE1BF3D0D1A"><enum>20.</enum><header>Enforcement by attorney general</header><subsection id="H47F8845D2852422DBAC7FE5A3B294B0F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General may bring a civil action in the appropriate district court of the United States for appropriate relief, including a temporary restraining order, preliminary or permanent injunction (including for removal or relocation of animals), license revocation, and civil penalties of up to $10,000 for each violation for each day during which the violation continues, against any person who violates any provision of this Act or any rule, standard, or regulation promulgated thereunder.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE9F3845A85484681AC9CB54381EF1DD4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Seizure and forfeiture of animals</header><paragraph id="HA8B4584A82374901A635AFB36D614D75"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any animal that is subjected to conduct that constitutes a violation of this Act, or any rule, standard, or regulation promulgated thereunder, shall be subject to seizure and forfeiture to the United States in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/46">chapter 46</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C1AB2EAE8EC4B249C2E2F8D8EA7B50A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Costs</header><text>Any person whose act or omission is the basis for a seizure authorized by subparagraph (1) may be charged a reasonable fee for expenses to the United States relating to the transfer and care of the seized animal.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF4B6B18729B148F4B92B876F58087A96"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Warrants</header><text>The judges of the district courts of the United States and United States magistrate judges may, within their respective jurisdictions, on proper oath or affirmation showing probable cause, issue such warrants or other processes as may be required for enforcement of this Act and any rule, standard, or regulation promulgated thereunder.</text></subsection><subsection id="H20C452AF3C9746BFA831E44FA2E02D25"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><paragraph id="H1921BD713927475BA6BEC89551D6170C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Attorney general</header><text>No action taken by the Attorney General pursuant to this section shall affect or limit the authority of the Secretary to enforce any provision of this Act or any rule, standard, or regulation thereunder.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA46A6C564978435AA9242D7ACD2249AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>No action taken by the Secretary shall affect or limit the authority of the Attorney General under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H0099FFAB7E314C69AC9F12B7D418FCF2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authority To apply for injunctions</header><text>Section 29(b) of the Animal Welfare Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2159">7 U.S.C. 2159(b)</external-xref>) is amended by striking the second sentence.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCEAE088A661B48C7ADAC32EB03A91701"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>The Animal Welfare Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2131">7 U.S.C. 2131 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HF673B021ADE9456F8C365BDBED703230" style="OLC"><section id="H1478F9C6D84343EAB7EE2473426F2F0D"><enum>30.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or the application thereof, is held invalid, the validity of the remainder of this Act and the application of such provision to other persons and circumstances shall not be affected.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H5D9B811F96854D2D922DFAF0E1ADB4CB"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with the Attorney General to carry out the authorities granted by the amendments made by this section, including an agreement to provide the Attorney General with timely information about violators who have multiple citations that seriously or adversely affect the health or well-being of an animal.</text></subsection></section><section id="H452727A89BF9487ABEB12DCCD3E3C832"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HA216480257764FFBB019F97759A5DBB4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 16(c) of the Animal Welfare Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2146">7 U.S.C. 2146(c)</external-xref>) establishes the jurisdiction of Federal courts to address violations of, and cases arising from violations of, that Act and provides the Attorney General with the authority to bring such cases in Federal court; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01670A7492974704BF35C4F1F99D7041"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the enforcement jurisdiction of the Federal courts, and the corresponding enforcement authority of the Attorney General, include violations of the rules, standards, and regulations promulgated under that Act.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

