<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HCB5695062A8545838C5BBC06E6FE357B" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 44 EH: Electing Members to certain standing committees of the House of Representatives.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="no">119th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="no">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. RES. 44</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20250115">January 15, 2025</action-date>
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Electing Members to certain standing committees of the House of Representatives.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="H70AD4A2E93334B13986CD497764581BC"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H21EE757B6B5E4F0BAD9AD76678D10D19"><text>That the following named Members be, and are hereby, elected to the following standing committees of the House of Representatives:</text> <paragraph id="H409B01EA6983449580AAEAFEEFDEAE08"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Committee on Agriculture</header><text>Mr. David Scott of Georgia, Mr. Costa, Mr. McGovern, Ms. Adams, Mrs. Hayes, Ms. Brown, Ms. Davids of Kansas, Ms. Salinas, Mr. Davis of North Carolina, Ms. Tokuda, Ms. Budzinski, Mr. Sorensen, Mr. Vasquez, Mr. Jackson of Illinois, Mr. Thanedar, Mr. Gray, Ms. McDonald Rivet, Mr. Figures, Mr. Vindman, Mr. Riley of New York, Mr. Mannion, Mrs. McClain Delaney.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H11D0BAB4C04B4EC294C5AEF4E057583E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Committee on Foreign Affairs</header><text>Mr. Sherman, Mr. Connolly, Mr. Keating, Mr. Bera, Mr. Castro of Texas, Ms. Titus, Mr. Lieu, Ms. Jacobs, Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick, Mr. Stanton, Mr. Moskowitz, Mr. Jackson of Illinois, Ms. Kamlager-Dove, Mr. Costa, Mr. Amo, Mr. Mfume, Ms. Jayapal, Mr. Latimer, Mr. Olszewski, Ms. Johnson of Texas, Ms. McBride.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02663336171D46A29DE5F28783DFF642"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Committee on Natural Resources</header><text>Mr. Grijalva, Mr. Neguse, Ms. Leger Fernandez, Ms. Stansbury, Ms. Hoyle of Oregon, Mr. Magaziner, Mr. Golden of Maine, Mr. Min, Ms. Dexter, Mr. Hernández, Ms. Randall, Ms. Ansari, Ms. Elfreth, Mr. Gray, Ms. Rivas.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1E159603512243038A4AF5AE6C768D97"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</header><text>Ms. Bonamici, Ms. Stevens, Ms. Ross, Ms. Salinas, Mrs. Foushee, Mrs. Sykes, Mr. Frost, Mr. Amo, Mr. Subramanyam, Ms. Rivas, Mr. Turner of Texas, Ms. McBride, Ms. Gillen, Mr. Whitesides, Ms. Friedman, Mrs. McClain Delaney, Mr. Riley of New York.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </resolution> 

