<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6A4588EAB8044969BC5DE930B2EDDD07" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1834 IH: Breaking the Gridlock Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1834</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250304">March 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Small Business</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HSO00">Ethics</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAN00">Appropriations</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To advance policy priorities that will break the gridlock.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6A1B634D621744C48C466BBE99C2A173" style="OLC"><section id="HC08DC86E041A493E83AB831C68D9BFF8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Breaking the Gridlock Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><title id="H3CAA55881A9C49F1B7743DC5D4A6F968"><enum>I</enum><header>Congressional Time Capsule</header><section id="HDB3F5115698040A9BEF11919E7C16149"><enum>101.</enum><header>Semiquincentennial Congressional Time Capsule</header><subsection id="HF7EF17FCF2EC49CB871AA774CE8E710C" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Creation by Architect of the Capitol</header><text>The Architect of the Capitol shall create a congressional time capsule, to be known as the <quote>Semiquincentennial Congressional Time Capsule</quote> (in this title referred to as the <quote>Time Capsule</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H016E9469501249E9BA07564D61584103"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><paragraph id="H311EA8D3C88E467E92098D0630D81C99"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination by congressional leadership</header><text>The Office of the Speaker of the House of Representatives, Office of the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, Office of the Majority Leader of the Senate, and Office of the Minority Leader of the Senate shall jointly determine the contents of the Time Capsule, taking into account the requirements of paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91A264E6C5634F39952D2B29055AE506"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specifications</header><text>The contents of the Time Capsule shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HFE819F1A471C40C0B943C04D4C21A743"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a representative portion of all books, manuscripts, miscellaneous printed matter, memorabilia, relics, and other materials relating to the United States Semiquincentennial;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04013CD28893467FBD178CC3E82833D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>copies or representations of important legislative and institutional milestones of Congress during the time before the Time Capsule is buried;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B2CFA7BA037410CB3E1DA66AB95E9ED"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a message from Congress to the future Congress when the Time Capsule will be opened; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F0490EF17D343AB92B13B6B79AFB92F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such other content as the offices described in paragraph (1) consider appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C5C336F443B447AB86F7F1E367316BA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the offices described in paragraph (1) may consult with the Architect of the Capitol, the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution, and such other entities of the Federal Government as the offices consider appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3F48773727D44B16984152AF3F31A46D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties of architect</header><text>The Architect of the Capitol shall—</text><paragraph id="H3FAC8E08F4E44BA1A5C8DCBF37C0A5C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prepare the Time Capsule to be sealed and buried on the West Lawn of the Capitol, at a location specified by the Architect, on or before July 4, 2026, at a time which would permit individuals attending this event to also attend the burial of a time capsule in Independence Mall in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, under section 7(f)(1) of the United States Semiquincentennial Commission Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/36/101">36 U.S.C. 101</external-xref> note prec.); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H150A1C8968624852B0CA63C188E60729"><enum>(2)</enum><text>install a plaque to provide such information about the Time Capsule as the Architect considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H140004180DAD4DE69CE7DD587AF9E0C6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Unsealing</header><text>The Time Capsule shall be sealed until July 4, 2276, on which date the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall present the Time Capsule to the 244th Congress, and such Congress shall determine how the contents within should be preserved or used.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFA4D7B55E2694EECB700EFD33ABB70DD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this title, and any amounts so appropriated shall remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="H8FFFE6008B93461091899468598E2F32"><enum>II</enum><header>Fire Suppression Cost Share Agreements</header><section id="H0CDCA94649B44BAC8416C86CE9F94498"><enum>201.</enum><header>Requirements relating to certain fire suppression cost share agreements</header><subsection id="H543537BC31CF49A9BCA44A7988A8BDE8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of standard operating procedures</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretaries shall—</text><paragraph id="H180EBE45AC7E4703898395B335148A11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish standard operating procedures relating to payment timelines for fire suppression cost share agreements established under the Act of May 27, 1955 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1856a">42 U.S.C. 1856a</external-xref>) (commonly known as the <quote>Reciprocal Fire Protection Act</quote>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89B375A3AE1B4F19BF6A61E185A4049B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to each fire suppression cost share agreement in operation on such date—</text><subparagraph id="HFAC495E4CDB54D759C9336AF0DA7C2F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review each such agreement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30F6A72E65D44036A1EDB2AA45414958"><enum>(B)</enum><text>modify each agreement as necessary to comply with the standard operating procedures required under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D98DFACDFB04AE1B2B4B48E1B55AACE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Alignment of fire suppression cost share agreements with cooperative fire protection agreements</header><text>The standard operating procedures required under subsection (a)(1) shall include a requirement that each fire suppression cost share agreement be aligned with each of the cooperative fire protection agreements applicable to the entity subject to such fire suppression cost share agreement.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF4B882AE48594FAD9E278FA65A428F31"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Payments pursuant to cost share agreements</header><text>With respect to payments made pursuant to fire suppression cost share agreements, the standard operating procedures required under subsection (a)(1) shall require that the Federal paying entity reimburse a local fire department if such fire department submits an invoice in accordance with cost settlement procedures.</text></subsection><subsection id="H47E7C4BB6E9647B0B4E97683929A4CBF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Secretaries should carry out reciprocal fire suppression cost share agreement repayments to local fire suppression organizations as soon as practicable after fire suppression occurs but not later than 1 year after fire suppression occurs.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9B9B4E0EED6D48E19629CEBEF807E1C0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Secretaries defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Secretaries</term> means—</text><paragraph id="HCF0BF49EE7854731B506A69F93DB6302"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H745C5B07E83048E2849CC3F271803073"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F7603F50B754CBEA965A4E2985397D9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Secretary of Homeland Security; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86438949EC024FFDBBC331B938A45558"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H6149B2055DDD4CBB9FB723801ED05E0E"><enum>III</enum><header>Udall Foundation Funding</header><section id="H328EC5EE5A0B4950B185C9DED095B5A7"><enum>301.</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 13 of the Morris K. Udall and Stewart L. Udall Foundation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/5609">20 U.S.C. 5609</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H2E975191C0BA418DB33151B6548A8421"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>through 2023</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>through 2029</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D0E617918564970BAB22D37E4874138"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), by striking <quote>$1,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$5,000</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BDF1461AE524771A8532D30CC7EE062"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>the fiscal year in which this subsection is enacted</quote> and inserting <quote>fiscal year 2026</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></title><title id="HEDC36EAB460E404E8EFDC417EB3BACFB"><enum>IV</enum><header>Strategy on Boko Haram</header><section id="HEEB3C679667F4E98A86DE7BBC85D84B4"><enum>401.</enum><header>Regional strategy to address the threat posed by Boko Haram</header><subsection id="HA1BA570B10224789BB0800EDD58A042E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy required</header><paragraph id="HEE4B9A8F9408403EB5AF2429C7CCE887"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Defense shall jointly develop and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a five-year strategy to help enable the Government of Nigeria, members of the Multinational Joint Task Force to Combat Boko Haram (MNJTF) authorized by the African Union, and relevant partners to counter the regional threat of Boko Haram and assist the Government of Nigeria and its neighbors to accept and address legitimate grievances of vulnerable populations in areas affected by Boko Haram.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEB458390F544190A387315C2CE5366D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>At a minimum, the strategy must address the following elements:</text><subparagraph id="HB87780D94F4542439D88D4D594982940"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Enhance, pursuant to existing authorities and restrictions, the institutional capacity, including military capabilities, of the Government of Nigeria and partner nations in the region, as appropriate, to counter the threat posed by Boko Haram.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F4FE51155FF4F59BEC15513B1508D1F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Provide humanitarian support to civilian populations impacted by Boko Haram’s activity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H793B2102D11F4316B859BB6008626006"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Specific activities through which the United States Government intends to improve and enhance the capacity of Multinational Joint Task Force to Combat Boko Haram partner nations to investigate and prosecute human rights abuses by security forces and promote respect for the rule of law within the military.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H213E24770692416A9C8A68D101F86136"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A means for assisting Nigeria, and as appropriate, Multinational Joint Task Force to Combat Boko Haram nations, to counter violent extremism, including efforts to address underlying societal factors shown to contribute to the ability of Boko Haram to radicalize and recruit individuals.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4722B463D2804E37A7C0E79A6BAD7B67"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A plan to strengthen and promote the rule of law, including by improving the capacity of the civilian police and judicial system in Nigeria, enhancing public safety, and responding to crime (including gender-based violence), while respecting human rights and strengthening accountability measures, including measures to prevent corruption.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13F49C684F8C4020AD50891929345777"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Strengthen the long-term capacity of the Government of Nigeria to enhance security for schools such that children are safer and girls seeking an education are better protected, and to combat gender-based violence and gender inequality.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AF46330D9FF47FDB549F7F45EB2D624"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Identify and develop mechanisms for coordinating the implementation of the strategy across the inter-agency and with the Government of Nigeria, regional partners, and other relevant foreign partners.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EF92DAF34F84CD0ACCA5A756EC3DF7C"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Identify the resources required to achieve the strategy’s objectives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7ACA14FD7E884730B597560664DD648F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>The Director of National Intelligence shall submit, to the appropriate committees of Congress, an assessment regarding—</text><paragraph id="H2D0DA575C2EB4C439D3A167339A22C60"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the willingness and capability of the Government of Nigeria and regional partners to implement the strategy developed under subsection (a), including the capability gaps, if any, of the Government and military forces of Nigeria that would need to be addressed to enable the Government of Nigeria and the governments of its partner countries in the region—</text><subparagraph id="HA398687E5D174639803487A5D0E22413"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to counter the threat of Boko Haram; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC1A1CD7E1B5434F89EF25DB65198B62"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to address the legitimate grievances of vulnerable populations in areas affected by Boko Haram; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBE254E846AB4218A2806699BC20CFB5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>significant United States intelligence gaps concerning Boko Haram or on the willingness and capacity of the Government of Nigeria and regional partners to implement the strategy developed under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5BBB86BAF20D41A7B3E17465B402CE81"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that lack of economic opportunity and access to education, justice, and other social services contributes to the ability of Boko Haram to radicalize and recruit individuals.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1F161B3D68434018B3B2911B88B8B7BA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of congress defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><paragraph id="HB8EE90E3107341CDBDA10D7FDFADDDEB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1603BC851EC469D97E606443F21F7F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H2CDB499EB8C44A1B9DFE8EEA6FEE8E93"><enum>V</enum><header>Veterans Interagency Task Force</header><section id="H11F0F46D47564037A7DB2438547A5D32"><enum>501.</enum><header>Reporting requirement for veterans interagency task force</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 32(c) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657b">15 U.S.C. 657b(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H73F0250B6E834891B13FE57016FD8995" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H67A7B2AB41CB4E618A0D3F8DB96B07A5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Along with the budget justification documents for the Small Business Administration submitted to Congress in connection with the budget for a fiscal year submitted under section 1105 of title 31, United States Code, the Administrator shall submit a report—</text><subparagraph id="HE5777670094A4FEAACF67AD4886B4079"><enum>(A)</enum><text>discussing the appointments made to and activities of the task force; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90AB7AA32C824B5F9CCEB8C0D3ED8D20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifying and outlining a plan for outreach and promotion of the programs and services for veterans, including Veteran Business Outreach Centers, Boots to Business, Boots to Business Reboot, Service-Disabled Entrepreneurship Development Training Program, Veteran Institute for Procurement, Women Veteran Entrepreneurship Training Program, and Veteran Women Igniting the Spirit of Entrepreneurship.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></title><title id="H784BA8072D9B4909809D512695D709FA"><enum>VI</enum><header>Veterans Pilot Program</header><section id="HDD2369613DD640D892A340E4B7A0D4A5"><enum>601.</enum><header>Veterans pilot program on promising retention models</header><subsection id="H5FF2207788D4407DA89971301532F078"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance, shall carry out a pilot program to make grants to eligible units of local government to improve retention in veterans treatment court programs (as such term is defined in section 2991 of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10651">34 U.S.C. 10651</external-xref>)) and drug court programs.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB1F19E9D71F74CFC9B7C09C22792F6A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>In order to be eligible for a grant under subsection (a), a unit of local government shall operate a veterans treatment court program or a drug court.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCB30BD26CE06455EAA1229F35789D3BA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A unit of local government seeking a grant through the pilot program under subsection (a) shall submit to the Attorney General an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require, including—</text><paragraph id="H91354F6328A94F8B8AD50F58F831EF5B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the therapeutic or treatment modality that the unit of local government plans to implement and data to support the use of the therapeutic or treatment modality, including information showing how the therapeutic or treatment modality will promote retention in and completion of veterans treatment court programs and drug court programs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H226AE7E34E4D4883BB09E73C6DC6FF58"><enum>(2)</enum><text>detailed plans on how the applicant would test the efficacy of the therapeutic or treatment modality.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8C0CE995146A4D25A2B4F10F47FD22F5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting metrics</header><text>Not later than 180 days after receiving a grant under subsection (a), a unit of local government shall submit to the Attorney General a report, which includes demographic information of participants in the veterans treatment court program, and completion rates of such participants. The Attorney General shall develop guidelines for the report required under this subsection.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="HA5112955A89A48DA8C9D951D6A14AB09"><enum>VII</enum><header>TSA Commuting Benefits</header><section id="H552C9A0051654B1A86A8516FD780E043"><enum>701.</enum><header>Feasibility study on TSA commuting benefits</header><subsection id="H6C36024E0601480296CDC1CCA57A12BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a study on the feasibility of treating as on-duty hours the time Transportation Security Administration employees working at airport locations spend traveling between regular duty locations and airport parking lots and bus and transit stops.</text></subsection><subsection id="H41307C1E7EA74D4EA690021B59BF724A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In conducting the feasibility study required under subsection (a), the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall consider the following with respect to Transportation Security Administration employees:</text><paragraph id="H2AC5C756C6F947D1A5BB89412D8C7350"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The amount of time needed by such employees to travel between regular duty locations and airport parking lots and bus and transit stops at small hub airports, medium hub airports, and large hub airports (as such terms are defined in section 40102 of title 49, United States Code).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18C7A9F6C5464FE2853C98199A3970AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The amount of time such employees spend commuting, on average, exclusive of the time described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8AD1AB85F994475AF111BE007FFA08F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The potential benefits to such employees and the Administration of treating as on-duty hours the time described in such paragraph.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F8BFBAFEEC9412AA6171BCA74AE6854"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The feasibility of using mobile phones, location data, and any other means to allow such employees to report their arrival to and departure from the airport parking lots and bus and transit stops concerned.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE00AE92972F4A049557A85E87AEC3B8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The estimated costs of treating as on-duty hours the time described in such paragraph, including by considering such hours creditable as basic pay for retirement purposes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H26A6A461F85847E39C2DB679BCF57711"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Other considerations determined appropriate by the Administrator.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H16472A8432F8448F82172D0637EB1BF8"><enum>VIII</enum><header>China Financial Threat Mitigation</header><section id="H865F2E48866947F1BFBCFF015757C663"><enum>801.</enum><header>China financial threat mitigation</header><subsection id="H2C9EB2A012A247C2AC214CAD186493E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Chairman of the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Chairman of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, and the Secretary of State, shall conduct a study and issue a report on the exposure of the United States to the financial sector of the People’s Republic of China that includes—</text><paragraph id="HE7C8D73533D34D229B1D7068E89D70F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of the effects of reforms to the financial sector of the People’s Republic of China on the United States and global financial systems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B0585A668AB40739258936C61A6EA41"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the policies the United States Government is adopting to protect the interests of the United States while the financial sector of the People’s Republic of China undergoes such reforms;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H775575AC7B6A49E09008B440834D0030"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description and analysis of any risks to the financial stability of the United States and the global economy emanating from the People’s Republic of China; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69159FDF95814C7AA0724F04D2C717FC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations for additional actions the United States Government, including United States representatives at relevant international organizations, should take to strengthen international cooperation to monitor and mitigate such financial stability risks and protect United States interests.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4D89FC329434907B6435332CE0AFC67"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transmission of report</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall transmit the report required under subsection (a) not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act to the Committees on Financial Services and Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, the Committees on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and Foreign Relations of the Senate, and to the United States representatives at relevant international organizations, as appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF21CC672BEAF47989CE796BC8CD87D7A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Classification of report</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall be unclassified, but may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD828101BE48F4DCAAC7A996FF57452DA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Publication of report</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall publish the report required under subsection (a) (other than any classified annex) on the website of the Department of the Treasury not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="HC7442E6B16904C28AC3ACFDAD73C094E"><enum>IX</enum><header>Servicemembers’ and Veterans’ Group Life Insurance</header><section id="HFFC44FCDBF6940E8933C880D364FD36A"><enum>901.</enum><header>Periodic review of automatic maximum coverage under servicemembers’ group life insurance and veterans’ group life insurance</header><subsection id="HB2223A452D154A0FA1CBD4B6C56F1C8C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/19">chapter 19</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H4D1EC17D9DE24C3CAC860EF610BF08D9" style="USC"><section id="H5B20D211997345E2A667AA20B8CA60D3"><enum>1980B.</enum><header>Periodic review of automatic maximum coverage</header><subsection id="H17B8D2D95C354858926D793949B29DEB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On January 1, 2026, and every three years thereafter, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H74E8E022B95944AAA2B57BC1F72D10F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>complete a review of how the amount specified in section 1967(a)(3)(A)(i) compares to the amount described in subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64A7D0728C31432781BA8D08A6BE7B3A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate the results of the review.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H03E55A89A5E442E0AA06B2B5FE184A4B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amount described</header><text>The amount described in this subsection is the amount equal to—</text><paragraph id="H425AA683031B4CD09BE42ADEC8B5A141"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$400,000; multiplied by</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F889C57E80F4E3A9C7E7618A08F3482"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the percentage of the increase (if any) in the average of the Consumer Price Index for the fiscal year ending during the preceding calendar year compared to the average of the Consumer Price Index for fiscal year 2005.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H631A51B862D04899A9C9BB529F5CC55D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consumer price index defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Consumer Price Index</term> means the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HFB078739AC264729B47F1ED391D429B8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 19 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1980A the following new item:</text><quoted-block id="H2FEB515337BA48E19A5B0032CFD4CA6A" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">1980B. Periodic review of automatic maximum coverage.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></title><title id="H3856964770744EAA8C0A8613F419203B"><enum>X</enum><header>Restoration of Amounts to Veterans</header><section id="HD8A515A453E44CD78AC5407495EFC11E"><enum>1001.</enum><header>Restoration of amounts improperly withheld for tax purposes from severance payments to veterans with combat-related injuries</header><subsection id="HE005E97D8B534ED28C9A5679C9CDA414"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall—</text><paragraph id="HF711964123BA4B80ABECD102071C0DCD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify—</text><subparagraph id="HC4E21280EDBD4CC0B901402BB3EB00AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the severance payments—</text><clause id="H0DB41EE3D6B84A77819CD4856F909ACC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that the Secretary paid after January 17, 1991;</text></clause><clause id="H37131B2118A04A3AA9AD9F9D791200A4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that the Secretary computed under section 1212 of title 10, United States Code;</text></clause><clause id="H96253FB9828743CDA2F105EA2F0832DC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that were not considered gross income pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/104">section 104(a)(4)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; and</text></clause><clause id="H6DC8BF7795174587ACF3A92317DCF1AA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>from which the Secretary withheld amounts for tax purposes; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD45909681C34B40A5CA12C6E7D2CB76"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the individuals to whom such severance payments were made; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9C6F9FA424449F984853455FEB12472"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to each person identified under paragraph (1)(B), provide—</text><subparagraph id="H0B2A3DF8E8E040CB96538ACF72B40B48"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notice of—</text><clause id="HB1B3A0808E0745449F501FCCE24BF91E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of severance payments in paragraph (1)(A) which were improperly withheld for tax purposes; and</text></clause><clause id="HE5CA539289144732BDD11640135AE2B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such other information determined to be necessary by the Secretary of the Treasury to carry out the purposes of this section; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9894E916142F4FD1B7AE72FE69C5E952"><enum>(B)</enum><text>instructions for filing amended tax returns to recover the amounts improperly withheld for tax purposes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDF1926A394C240B9BC6D0C5B295FB515"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Extension of limitation on time for credit or refund</header><paragraph id="HCCF8222A6D5E4A0AAD155E7CFB03A276"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Period for filing claim</header><text>If a claim for credit or refund under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6511">section 6511(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 relates to a specified overpayment, the 3-year period of limitation prescribed by such subsection shall not expire before the date which is 1 year after the date the information return described in subsection (a)(2) is provided. The allowable amount of credit or refund of a specified overpayment shall be determined without regard to the amount of tax paid within the period provided in section 6511(b)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H662C7B2937444B11B7AB11B6E00C164F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specified overpayment</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the term <term>specified overpayment</term> means an overpayment attributable to a severance payment described in subsection (a)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="HA68CACFBBA324E379A3ABE8C16CB3B32"><enum>XI</enum><header>Hearings by House Committees</header><section id="H4873660E39534050A482BAD3F958C57D"><enum>1101.</enum><header>Hearings</header><subsection id="H32414E6DAD5C466A8A1E273BCACDF636"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each standing committee of the House of Representatives shall hold a hearing on the implementation of this Act within one year of enactment.</text></subsection><subsection id="H299AAB6060E04A1B82BFA139C40F7961"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exercise of rulemaking authority</header><text>Subsection (a) is enacted—</text><paragraph id="H8332CF4571A64BBC8A2176C726641B0D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as an exercise of rulemaking power of the House of Representatives, and, as such, shall be considered as part of the rules of the House, and such rules shall supersede any other rule of the House only to the extent that rule is inconsistent therewith; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11B4CBBC809544CAA0C0102145F4CE05"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change such rules (so far as relating to the procedure in such House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of the House.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="HF98E6218EF3B43E681B6ABF64E2A8C43"><enum>XII</enum><header>Code of Official Conduct</header><section id="H9435DDE8028448E5AFB8C8A69AF94D95" commented="no"><enum>1201.</enum><header>Code of official conduct</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In rule XXIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives, strike clause 20 and insert the following:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" id="H1D2AE2C615AC4D699894306C90FBD7C8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HFD7111978EDE426D93B8B71929CF54C9" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>20.</enum><text>A Member, Delegate, Resident Commissioner, officer, or employee of the House may not, directly or indirectly, take any actions to prevent any individual from or retaliate against any individual for providing truthful information to the Committee on Ethics, the Office of Congressional Conduct, the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights, or any law enforcement official, provided that the disclosure of such information is not otherwise prohibited by law or House rules.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></title><title id="HF1B8D0151B2E4BA38A15117E305D8DCC"><enum>XIII</enum><header>Prohibiting Transfer of Sensitive Data to Foreign Adversaries</header><section id="HA08044D3BA1242BBBB58B6C4F6E28839"><enum>1301.</enum><header>Prohibition on transfer of personally identifiable sensitive data of United States individuals to foreign adversaries</header><subsection id="H99978D6FD9C94A08973DDDF59DA60277"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a data broker to sell, license, rent, trade, transfer, release, disclose, provide access to, or otherwise make available personally identifiable sensitive data of a United States individual to—</text><paragraph id="HD04F9447A6CD4653A615BB86CE8A4AE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any foreign adversary country; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC15B491D4ED403AA68D98D08AE4BF17"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any entity that is controlled by a foreign adversary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H853E17161DF14BF19296322FB8ABE624"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by federal trade commission</header><paragraph id="H96FDB1FE368B4044952536DBA59C9630"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of this section shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or a deceptive act or practice under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H921A059A5D0B41FDA1A8A2404236A4A9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of commission</header><subparagraph id="H321D3D46DCA24447A7CB100F51ECAAF5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall enforce this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CE10E9A640A4BCCB98ABE8522B77D9C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text>Any person who violates this section shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD50FB48A3E4B457E95B5C4ED7D122D1C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H03F8949636FF4887B1B0ED034DB81F48"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H4E57E58F1D5840D0B511271F75818829"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC62157F2682448ED98EC5ECB88F763AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Controlled by a foreign adversary</header><text>The term <term>controlled by a foreign adversary</term> means, with respect to an individual or entity, that such individual or entity is—</text><subparagraph id="HCEF4318B09264813AA25CB78B5C37471"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a foreign person that is domiciled in, is headquartered in, has its principal place of business in, or is organized under the laws of a foreign adversary country;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D9E20A09C794EF8BCE14EF6C094540E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity with respect to which a foreign person or combination of foreign persons described in subparagraph (A) directly or indirectly own at least a 20 percent stake; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5074B770A3BA4579A583478A4CF18783"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a person subject to the direction or control of a foreign person or entity described in subparagraph (A) or (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H23A97345DF4B455D8A5DC87E3A563C4B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Data broker</header><subparagraph id="HB7AD8A419C004EACA68A5074A509C898"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>data broker</term> means an entity that, for valuable consideration, sells, licenses, rents, trades, transfers, releases, discloses, provides access to, or otherwise makes available data of United States individuals that the entity did not collect directly from such individuals to another entity that is not acting as a service provider.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4DC771E3DE747CCAB06FF079B5BCFD9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>data broker</term> does not include an entity to the extent such entity—</text><clause id="H9D8BF57C9594448CAE7B285F39A186EF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is transmitting data of a United States individual, including communications of such an individual, at the request or direction of such individual;</text></clause><clause id="H9069F7B59DB44646859F5AF9093AEABE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is providing, maintaining, or offering a product or service with respect to which personally identifiable sensitive data, or access to such data, is not the product or service;</text></clause><clause id="HE140D846F69D4F89AA53C8818D6BC605"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is reporting or publishing news or information that concerns local, national, or international events or other matters of public interest;</text></clause><clause id="H1E7A6E2A81994741A2E45965382B4AFC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is reporting, publishing, or otherwise making available news or information that is available to the general public—</text><subclause id="H581D752904C64077B51432608C77A585"><enum>(I)</enum><text>including information from—</text><item id="HB7DBC42E8E99437AB2A906925B1B292B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a book, magazine, telephone book, or online directory;</text></item><item id="H18090E3E49264C4EAD4C09F2E73EE5CB"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a motion picture;</text></item><item id="HBBFC47C8C52348079450186870E38171"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>a television, internet, or radio program;</text></item><item id="H9129409AAD6F4CB7BFE35D11E01FA953"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>the news media; or</text></item><item id="HE080FAB81C8D4F0BA6310C3E7F38347C"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>an internet site that is available to the general public on an unrestricted basis; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H8F52F6F3638F47EE9AC7E079FE97799A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not including an obscene visual depiction (as such term is used in section 1460 of title 18, United States Code); or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H4E14069AB04144DDA813E518836B4E25"><enum>(v)</enum><text>is acting as a service provider.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H595E062F16A64BBF8E39C341D27AA56B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foreign adversary country</header><text>The term <term>foreign adversary country</term> means a country specified in section 4872(d)(2) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FD95349920843088E4A5AC5A33AD45D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Personally identifiable sensitive data</header><text>The term <term>personally identifiable sensitive data</term> means any sensitive data that identifies or is linked or reasonably linkable, alone or in combination with other data, to an individual or a device that identifies or is linked or reasonably linkable to an individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB2706D775FB48EDB99F431F43CCCA2B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Precise geolocation information</header><text>The term <term>precise geolocation information</term> means information that—</text><subparagraph id="HB47D085E639E451DA937FE34FDA3246E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is derived from a device or technology of an individual; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01E884DBA960429DA71F0716C51F3771"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reveals the past or present physical location of an individual or device that identifies or is linked or reasonably linkable to 1 or more individuals, with sufficient precision to identify street level location information of an individual or device or the location of an individual or device within a range of 1,850 feet or less.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B23E56815934D8B979126BC3BD7853C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Sensitive data</header><text>The term <term>sensitive data</term> includes the following:</text><subparagraph id="HBC904DD1679946428893F153B40A9B37"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A government-issued identifier, such as a Social Security number, passport number, or driver’s license number.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEAF2EF593A04F71ACCDCB22FD527138" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any information that describes or reveals the past, present, or future physical health, mental health, disability, diagnosis, or health care condition or treatment of an individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF34442AF629449C4B7BCE9929A99A6EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A financial account number, debit card number, credit card number, or information that describes or reveals the income level or bank account balances of an individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CD36B2C6892403EA4101B31AF2DA75B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Biometric information.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8AACBE0769249798EF8FA6515D08ACE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Genetic information.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7825155220754B80A3A48925931FF6DC"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Precise geolocation information.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD77B41888E3A4A528F5678556E1D53D5"><enum>(G)</enum><text>An individual’s private communications such as voice mails, emails, texts, direct messages, mail, voice communications, and video communications, or information identifying the parties to such communications or pertaining to the transmission of such communications, including telephone numbers called, telephone numbers from which calls were placed, the time calls were made, call duration, and location information of the parties to the call.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE575EB691DEF4DCD99159C0E4A0C3A36"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Account or device log-in credentials, or security or access codes for an account or device.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB098FCDC434F4CDDBBB1CEFB567D5E7F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Information identifying the sexual behavior of an individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C15287FE8794D58AFFB065C3E82C146"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Calendar information, address book information, phone or text logs, photos, audio recordings, or videos, maintained for private use by an individual, regardless of whether such information is stored on the individual’s device or is accessible from that device and is backed up in a separate location.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCE27D6CEB3F4D8395427AFD6C75F8C4"><enum>(K)</enum><text>A photograph, film, video recording, or other similar medium that shows the naked or undergarment-clad private area of an individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50B0C1F95BDE44299F246B2165750A20"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Information revealing the video content requested or selected by an individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4A90E5EE16646D9AE2088971B251F07"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Information about an individual under the age of 17.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H107AFDD90B264233B1F9DA89D2E7ADF5"><enum>(N)</enum><text>An individual’s race, color, ethnicity, or religion.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB07D91597E0C4DE9A9E9A0A62688FE0C"><enum>(O)</enum><text>Information identifying an individual’s online activities over time and across websites or online services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB5F308066D74BA68BF5A891516057B9"><enum>(P)</enum><text>Information that reveals the status of an individual as a member of the Armed Forces.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55C64452DA584E59A3D2192650B8ECDC"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>Any other data that a data broker sells, licenses, rents, trades, transfers, releases, discloses, provides access to, or otherwise makes available to a foreign adversary country, or entity that is controlled by a foreign adversary, for the purpose of identifying the types of data listed in subparagraphs (A) through (P).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE8C2917360044D2AB2850B71A828808"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Service provider</header><text>The term <term>service provider</term> means an entity that—</text><subparagraph id="H5D52FA140C1541CBA98B1246DA8933B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collects, processes, or transfers data on behalf of, and at the direction of—</text><clause id="H3CD6F3BF21604FBDA1BE2E562390F5B3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an individual or entity that is not a foreign adversary country or controlled by a foreign adversary; or</text></clause><clause id="HA5DEE94702BC4099B8F760714CA4F3A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a Federal, State, Tribal, territorial, or local government entity; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98F197DFCF504F9BAD9118C48BBED80F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>receives data from or on behalf of an individual or entity described in subparagraph (A)(i) or a Federal, State, Tribal, territorial, or local government entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EA2D48FEEA94E949810B5AB25EA8B7A"><enum>(9)</enum><header>United states individual</header><text>The term <term>United States individual</term> means a natural person residing in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD1CF0C57B696471C8DC99E4D4FBE62BF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the date that is 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="H0601F0DB759F44D6A5451982DF4D8133"><enum>XIV</enum><header>Determination of Budgetary Effects</header><section id="H0598454531A542BD9D1B1F2B12A40B4D"><enum>1401.</enum><header>Determination of budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go-Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the House Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></section></title><title id="H42627BB673B141D7B4EAF78FAD762A0D"><enum>XV</enum><header>Domestically Made United States Flags</header><section id="H6156C4B559A54C73AFCC4F55ABD49EF0"><enum>1501.</enum><header>Requirement for agencies to buy domestically made United States flags</header><subsection id="HB2A8BB5E331A409ABA21646698D11717"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement for agencies To buy domestically made united states flags</header><paragraph id="HC2D6E7FDB458460E9619F57BCC26EA00"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/63">Chapter 63</external-xref> of title 41, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H6D1F2AA71AD84C6489C0BD417B60EF64" style="USC"><section id="H2A62051F60B14DBF91D211C38266F2AF"><enum>6310.</enum><header>Requirement for agencies to buy domestically made United States flags</header><subsection id="H5B55DF494C634F65ABD7873DF5D6F129"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Except as provided in subsections (b) through (d), funds appropriated or otherwise available to an agency may not be used for the procurement of any flag of the United States, unless such flag has been 100 percent manufactured in the United States from articles, materials, or supplies that have been grown or 100 percent produced or manufactured in the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="H87AAD3EA46AD47079C8D86E282B64134"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability exception</header><text>Subsection (a) does not apply to the extent that the head of the agency concerned determines that satisfactory quality and sufficient quantity of a flag described in such subsection cannot be procured as and when needed at United States market prices.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2BFF29261FE242D4BBCD2F7161516E11"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception for certain procurements</header><text>Subsection (a) does not apply to the following:</text><paragraph id="HDCD25AFF042F452E8688D41342FAB947"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Procurements by vessels in foreign waters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBAF584E06814950AB6004968850CE64"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Procurements for resale purposes in any military commissary, military exchange, or nonappropriated fund instrumentality operated by an agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H306CEA9C10BA4482B88E7E4BD6BF161C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Procurements for amounts less than the simplified acquisition threshold.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA0D7A1886694EE5B97980F708221E0B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Presidential waiver</header><paragraph id="H514C3AADB25D4254A72710EE48A75D1D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may waive the requirement in subsection (a) if the President determines a waiver is necessary to comply with any trade agreement to which the United States is a party.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F58B8B5F1D64AA9999C81FEBE718418"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice of waiver</header><text>Not later than 30 days after granting a waiver under paragraph (1), the President shall publish a notice of the waiver in the Federal Register.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDAF95908363A4A8EB056434B82434468"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H6AF0F10342164B349FFF5078778B0F6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term <term>executive agency</term> in section 102 of title 40.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB9917665BD8462EAAA37F949FD26AEA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Simplified acquisition threshold</header><text>The term <term>simplified acquisition threshold</term> has the meaning given that term in section 134.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E2FB156C05A4727B7977C711834AE16"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block id="H249FE998FE8B4A518711A16C234166C7" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">6310. Requirement for agencies to buy domestically made United States flags.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB60E3A969E144A95837EBE4D93463495"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Section 6310 of title 41, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)(1), shall apply with respect to any contract entered into on or after the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="H410FDC26363C48248C39B11FA19A7D34"><enum>XVI</enum><header>Appropriations</header><section id="HBC5763E522404A1490C2F4FFD217BAD9"><enum>1601.</enum><header>Appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The following sums are hereby appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2026, and for other purposes, namely:</text></section><appropriations-major id="HC82E0334D90244648A61581ECA31EC0C"><header>DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H8A7C70B136AE46F9B1F325BCD5CC2DFF"><header>HEALTH RESOURCES AND SERVICES ADMINISTRATION</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H3CD0677A9FF4456096E25C8FDB2232C7" commented="no"><header>RURAL HEALTH</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for the Telehealth Resource Center of the Federal Office of Rural Health Policy of the Office for the Advancement of Telehealth, to provide assistance with respect to technical, legal, regulatory service delivery or other related barriers to the development of telehealth technologies for skilled nursing facilities (as defined in section 1819 of the Social Security Act) and nursing facilities (as defined in section 1919 of such Act), $1,000,000 to remain available through September 30, 2026. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="H931BD187C5C94CE4BC3DEC1664A771A7"><header>DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H8A5C8D85D159483EA46BDCBF884D184C"><header>EXECUTIVE OPERATIONS</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HE2DC37D70282448395E46D04EB2AD865"><header>OFFICE OF BUDGET AND PROGRAM ANALYSIS</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for necessary expenses of the Office of Budget and Program Analysis, $1,000,000. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="HF5DB92C23EBD45C39AB3B07815077300"><header>DEPARTMENT OF STATE</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H15542FC14AF04C2883C3BA9C1FE3A505"><header>CAPITAL INVESTMENT FUND</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for necessary expenses of the Capital Investment Fund, as authorized, $1,000,000, to remain available until expended. </text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-major id="H670CF4CC91464263AC08368A9EEEF937"><header>DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H760C0B36944C475F9C1756D09D975D50"><header>OPERATION AND MAINTENANCE</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H64EF5E938FD147FFAD42E5B3128D831D"><header>OPERATION AND MAINTENANCE, ARMY</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for expenses, not otherwise provided for, necessary for the operation and maintenance of the Army, as authorized by law, $1,000,000. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="H6D9DB2E9EBC94C828BAD64FA21E80E01"><header>DEPARTMENT OF HOMELAND SECURITY</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H910D76BBA1A24351A90D2BDA49178AD4"><header>DEPARTMENTAL MANAGEMENT, INTELLIGENCE, SITUATIONAL AWARENESS, AND OVERSIGHT</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H6DBCD4D388184404834444387DF53C32"><header>MANAGEMENT DIRECTORATE</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H12BA6E6EB2CF453190A4063834F8593C"><header>OPERATIONS AND SUPPORT</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for necessary expenses of the Management Directorate for operations and support, $1,000,000. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="H8E9B5592B77F4344A143560D02A442C5"><header>DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="HCDA8E3A25AF54DD8A5F1CE5B0BD41476"><header>ENERGY PROGRAMS</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HFC8F80287B3D496A92651263CEB02C85"><header>ENERGY INFORMATION ADMINISTRATION</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for Department of Energy expenses necessary in carrying out the activities of the Energy Information Administration, $1,000,000, to remain available until expended. </text></appropriations-small></title></legis-body></bill> 

