<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCBE5697A174C43F58DAEF3CF91525065" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2200 IH: To amend title 14, United States Code, to require the retention of certain enlisted members of the Coast Guard who have completed 18 or more, but less than 20, years of service, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2200</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250318">March 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 14, United States Code, to require the retention of certain enlisted members of the Coast Guard who have completed 18 or more, but less than 20, years of service, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2A035B1A25D04CA684B10A7CE8659FB4" style="OLC"><section id="HB3BCF0FA57AA4F3F8268B0A577AD95B9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Retention of enlisted members after completion of 18 or more, but less than 20, years of service</header><subsection id="HBB262BF190FE45B89C4518D08C298513"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/14/25">chapter 25</external-xref> of title 14, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H85DF51A8E1744B0784CD79A01D1302B9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HAD15EC6680394BCBA89F9E691EAB7ACE"><enum>2517.</enum><header>Retention of enlisted members after completion of 18 or more, but less than 20, years of service</header><subsection id="H6FFC91805BEF4D38AF00DA10C143F88C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Regular members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An enlisted member of the Regular Coast Guard who is selected to be involuntarily separated, or whose term of enlistment expires and who is denied reenlistment, and who, on the date on which the member is to be discharged, is within two years of qualifying for retirement under section 2306 of this title shall be retained on active duty until the member is qualified for retirement, unless the member is sooner retired or discharged under any other provision of law.</text></subsection><subsection id="H248A770E0EF849F8AA8B3A0B47C8902C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reserve members in active status</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An enlisted member of the Coast Guard Reserve serving in an active status who is selected to be involuntarily separated (other than for physical disability or for cause), or whose term of enlistment expires and who is denied reenlistment (other than for physical disability or for cause), and who, on the date on which the member is to be discharged or transferred from an active status, is entitled to be credited with at least 18, but less than 20, years of service, may not be discharged, denied reenlistment, or transferred from an active status without the consent of the member before the earlier of the following:</text><paragraph id="HAEF11408777D4FBC9C073D77998E4CFE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If, as of the date on which the member is to be discharged or transferred from an active status, the member has at least 18, but less than 19, years of service—</text><subparagraph id="H89200F86E96B42608DFE8C84F92E36B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which the member is entitled to be credited with 20 years of service; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C5BBF2BB1264E3BA5451963CD45486F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the third anniversary of the date on which the member would otherwise be discharged or transferred from an active status.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EB25E0155584DB4947FCA0E26E09789"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, as of the date on which the member is to be discharged or transferred from an active status, the member has at least 19, but less than 20, years of service—</text><subparagraph id="HA629AA023D8B4F318D3033454F0D16A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which the member is entitled to be credited with 20 years of service; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE28695AF4E944066AD998362CF8F42DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the second anniversary of the date on which the member would otherwise be discharged or transferred from an active status.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H7FD2BC1F3D274576A1AE73B379FF6FA5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/14/25">chapter 25</external-xref> of title 14, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/14/2516">section 2516</external-xref> the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H2A39ED720C074D6D8AF2FFAFB1A5F87D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">2517. Retention of enlisted members after completion of 18 or more, but less than 20, years of service.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

