<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB2A63850B609403992674168423C217A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4981 IH: Stamp Out Lyme Disease Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4981</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250815">August 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the issuance of a Lyme Disease Research Semipostal Stamp.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H12B3C1DE04A94A87AF2A022CF2A5D36A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBB4C37170E424AFCA7D5BF0B0CAF2E3E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stamp Out Lyme Disease Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H374E9AD6A0604C72BEE3CD120576A4F9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H348BBDD9EEEB4DC1845B8B5D920C239B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H42584437641F47FE878E9999A3CE043E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) estimate that 476,000 Lyme disease cases are diagnosed and treated in the United States annually.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H822470A9AE354F3A807C42BFF0B1F738"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The CDC reports that Lyme disease is difficult to diagnose due to its diverse manifestations and a lack of reliable testing options.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD5C28DD2822847C780C896BDF2AD3AB3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The National Institutes of Health (NIH) reports that a significant number of later-stage or post-treatment Lyme disease patients are not cured.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE590CFE18E4241CFB55C5E5219FA5FCA"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Tick-Borne Disease Working Group reports that 10 to 20 percent of Lyme disease patients will suffer from persistent symptoms which can be chronic and disabling.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD12F1EE08AA6440488C88E28E443F284"><enum>(5)</enum><text>According to the Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health, Lyme disease costs the United States healthcare system up to $1,300,000,000 per year.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H27D16F9B427C4DC28128CDBEEA6B8627"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>To afford a convenient way for members of the public to contribute to funding for Lyme disease and related tick-borne illness research within the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, the United States Postal Service shall issue a semipostal stamp (hereinafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Lyme Disease Research Semipostal Stamp</quote>) in accordance with this section.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H594ACFB159DF4D57A6DAB8C68D6D3E8B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Lyme disease research semipostal stamp</header> 
<subsection id="H854A600B3DFF4839B0902072826EC653"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text>The issuance and sale of the Lyme Disease Research Semipostal Stamp shall be governed by the provisions of section 416 of title 39, United States Code, and regulations issued under such section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5EF61446E00E4731A99B646DF1A0FEC3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disposition of proceeds</header> <paragraph id="H77238A501DA34F0E9B8C9532FBF8F08B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All amounts becoming available from the sale of the Lyme Disease Research Semipostal Stamp (as determined under section 416(d) of such title 39) shall be transferred to the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, for the purpose described in subsection (a), through payments which shall be made at least twice a year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1A28C213CBA54ED0A383909ACA76A444"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Proceeds not to be offset</header><text>In accordance with section 416(d)(4) of such title 39, amounts becoming available from the sale of the Lyme Disease Research Semipostal Stamp (as so determined) shall not be taken into account in any decision relating to the level of appropriations or other Federal funding to be furnished in any year to the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE3D697C5E9954C098E0237BBCFE5102B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Lyme Disease Research Semipostal Stamp shall be made available to the public for a period of at least 6 years, beginning no later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC6BBC2BAFCD446668F9E7F33ACCB038C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of this Act, the term <term>semipostal stamp</term> refers to a stamp described in section 416(a)(1) of title 39, United States Code.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

