<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H4235943E60EB4ECDBC3727161B881F57" key="H">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3391 IH: End Price Gouging for Medications Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3391</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250514">May 14, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which
        was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and
          Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name
          committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00"
          >Armed Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans'
          Affairs</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government
          Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural
          Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in
        each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the
        committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish reference prices for prescription drugs for purposes of Federal health programs, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HA221742B011446B79E3FFC2E0DFFCE35"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H7E547A96B7C14685ADD05E5B9818E1F7"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>End Price Gouging for Medications Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HDFC68F9C55894EC68AE2D03195B228C1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reference prices for prescription drugs</header> <subsection id="HA0019807757D480AB7A27A6247444630"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reference prices</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), in accordance with subsection (b), shall establish annual reference prices for each prescription drug. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, with respect to enrollees or beneficiaries in any of the Federal health programs described in subsection (c), the retail list price for a drug shall not exceed the reference price for such drug.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3E8CA96B580347888AD8ABFDE4F5E60D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criteria</header> 
<paragraph id="H631CA77404CF401480F88A97E60D83DD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each year, the Secretary shall establish the reference price for each prescription drug under subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="HB0613CF4783149A5980AB36C6096FCA9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by determining the lowest retail list price for the drug among the reference countries in which the drug is available, if drug pricing information is available for at least 3 of such countries; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDBE5CA2FADCA465A8B3C0ECCBFB89168">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in the case of a drug for which drug pricing information or dosage equivalents are not available for at least 3 of the reference countries, by determining an appropriate price based on the Secretary's determination of—</text>
            <clause id="H6C84054144B444448A3E937F8D81E691">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>the added therapeutic effect of the drug;</text> </clause> <clause id="H942EA659011A4B89BA1B650CF6E1A8E1"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>the value of the drug;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H14298471C3814EC6B7CE3BEB45E89182">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>patient access to the drug;</text> </clause> <clause id="H59EC0BC873B74C78B85D5800E343D33F"> <enum>(iv)</enum> <text>the costs associated with researching and developing the drug; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H4BBF457654214B419798C21672D27269">
              <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>other factors, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text> </clause> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE081EA9CE1164480B55A88B6C564914D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reference countries</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the reference countries are Australia, Austria, Belgium, Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the Netherlands, Sweden, Switzerland, and the United Kingdom.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H140FFAF241F74AFDA236B4276E44D824"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal health programs</header><text>The reference prices established under subsection (a) shall apply with respect to covered inpatient and outpatient drugs under—</text> <paragraph id="H21AAD7BB63074DD8B379BF99AAC5387A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2788457175314A9BB426166E9C41EB72"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a State Medicaid plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H82DE13761DAF431E9D4FE9FFD58574A9"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>the State Children's Health Insurance Program under title XXI of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397aa">42 U.S.C. 1397aa et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD397CB89FE4746D5AD1544BF6A524876"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the TRICARE program under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/55">chapter 55</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C51ABD4188144E6A2104D802562E8A3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>hospital care and medical services furnished by the Department of Veterans Affairs under chapters 17 and 18 of title 38, United States Code;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE643CCBBBB7B4F2C841EB9265D80E732"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC7EDB748C084894A2B581B6187C4F72"><enum>(7)</enum><text>any health program, service, function, activity, or facility funded, in whole or part, under the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1601">25 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>), including through direct or contract care provided under such Act or through a contract or compact under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8C10F1771EBB4E808EACC199865DA87B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability to other purchasers of drugs</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a drug manufacturer shall offer prescription drugs at the reference price to all individuals, including individuals who are not insured and individuals who are covered under a group health plan or group or individual health insurance coverage. In the case of individuals covered by a group health plan or group or individual health insurance coverage, such requirement is met if the amount covered under such plan or coverage plus the cost-sharing amount does not exceed the reference price.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEE82B55BEADA4D03BFEC49AB10194148"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <paragraph id="H9B5D6FD4C722461D80102646166FD538"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><text>A drug manufacturer who does not comply with the requirements of subsection (a) shall be subject to a civil penalty, for each year in which the violation occurs and with respect to each drug for which the violation occurs, in an amount equal to 5 times the difference between—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H51914C47F987460BBF0D1CBC4ECF1807"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total amount received by the manufacturer for sales of the drug under the Federal health programs under subsection (c) for the year; less</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H877A23F08C3E4C89949C205272E6D874"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total amount the manufacturer would have received for sales of the drug under such programs for the year if the manufacturer had complied with subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB7FA07ABD004426088E69FF3B414C42B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amounts collected</header><text>Each year, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer to the Director of the National Institutes of Health an amount equal to the amount collected in civil penalties under subsection (e) for the previous year. The Director of the National Institutes of Health shall use amounts so transferred for purposes of conducting drug research and development.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H336573E753CF4C648BA64A6AE1D36F3D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Applicability to brand and generic drugs</header><text>The reference price established under subsection (a) shall apply to drugs approved under subsection (c) or (j) of section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>) or under subsection (a) or (k) of section 351 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill>

