<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25790-SV5-P6-SNG"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2264 IS: Advancing VA’s Emergency Response to (AVERT) Crises Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2264</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250714">July 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To improve the emergency management capabilities of the Department of
 Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id99938202f68f4b1e9c599a028df0d63b"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advancing VA’s Emergency Response to (AVERT) Crises Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idef0c80ec7bcf49a095cfb864e4fd18f9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on emergency management roles for Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id48304bda4cd14810864ba830d75bb9fa"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report outlining the roles and responsibilities of all offices of the Department of Veterans Affairs involved with emergency management.</text></subsection><subsection id="id01508eb1084549eab048ed5ff48ef755"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In preparing the report required by subsection (a), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall consult with the Comptroller General of the United States, the Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and such other Federal agencies as the Secretary of Veterans Affairs considers relevant, to obtain insights from their experience and trends that they have found, and such recommendations as they may have with respect to the management by the Department of Veterans Affairs of emergency management functions.</text></subsection><subsection id="id924d5458b727456a8b0aa5a64bbba4dc"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report submitted pursuant to subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="idd2ddbec5b2124d3fa6a410f62d34b6f5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the organizational structure of each office, both during normal operations and during emergency or disaster operations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida2fc33cfcdbc437598da186ddfff8e5e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The roles and responsibilities of each office.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id88cceba8f3ec40ad91fd8b6e422b745b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A detailed description of roles and responsibilities that are shared by both the Office of Emergency Management of the Department and the Office of Operations, Security, and Preparedness of the Department, including an analysis of how each office plays a part in emergency management functions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b13d3d611614c5098b69c079f34aac8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recommendations for improving the structure and alignment of relevant offices to better prepare the Department for emergencies, remove redundancies, and improve accountability.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id40ebc045b217496aad78e3ede15a69bb"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An analysis of the feasibility and advisability of consolidating relevant offices into one centralized emergency management office to improve communication and streamline emergency preparedness and response efforts of the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id24ecccef4afe460c9c594eec710b3f64"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on Regional Readiness Centers of Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id905c980183d041868eaff7e5dfc085d2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the Regional Readiness Centers of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideb0c85e556b14429993fb65689e9dbf5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report submitted pursuant to subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="iddeaa3f1f85a841ada2c4530ecfe37c20"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of requests made by facilities of the Department to obtain supplies from a Regional Readiness Center since the inception of the Regional Readiness Center program, disaggregated by Regional Readiness Center.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd8de4d37a0a84f3ebc72e22423038e92"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Information on types and amounts of material distributed since the inception of the Regional Readiness Center program, disaggregated by Regional Readiness Center.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id91665764ed0d478a8325039bf434677e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Current inventory, disaggregated by Regional Readiness Center.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id46d6d5dfaf0e45b7b9b47b81f2b1edca"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An overview of the change in inventory in each Regional Readiness Center during the two-year period ending on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc1826534e2014196a320690f9dc763fc"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The percentage of inventory that is expired or that will expire in the next month, disaggregated by Regional Readiness Center.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id234478f50ea440118038ebd454823ad5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Operational costs since the inception of the Regional Readiness Center program, disaggregated by Regional Readiness Center.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id21db1ade0b9b4a08b7d315366970ee6b"><enum>(7)</enum><text>An analysis of the types and sizes of emergencies, including natural disasters, public health emergencies, or Fourth Mission activations of the Department, with respect to which each Regional Readiness Center would be able to provide sufficient resources to respond to, based on the current capacity of the Regional Readiness Center.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida369fcbab33848c5a0314041829413a0"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Any plans of the Secretary to realign or change the number of Regional Readiness Centers.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="iddb13760cedf4416a8b16ead8a74d3077"><enum>4.</enum><header>Plan to allow fuel sharing and increased coordination between the Federal
 Emergency Management Agency and the Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall, after consulting with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Homeland Security and Government Affairs of the Senate, and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives a report regarding—</text><paragraph id="id97722debf99845c7a667f479096f7972"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the current limitations preventing the Federal Emergency Management Agency from providing fuel or other resources to the Department of Veterans Affairs during emergencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id839df5912be044699fb23d08012b5e2e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether the Department requires action by Congress to allow such resource provision to occur;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddda1fa30e39c4315ab78b37e044ce292"><enum>(3)</enum><text>whether the Secretary has been unable to coordinate with the Administrator during prior emergencies or Fourth Mission activations due to a lack of authority for such coordination; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id406ee5dd5dba46828900e7a435af77ea"><enum>(4)</enum><text>whether the Secretary requires action by Congress to address any of the issues mentioned under paragraph (3).</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

