<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0C305D1DDBFF4AEE9039E8D3322B9B2C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2654 IH: Lifesaving Gear for Police Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2654</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250403">April 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the enforcement of certain regulations relating to sale, donation, and transfer of Federal Government property, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6CC8CE0681BA436CAEFA9F51F9038812" style="OLC"><section id="HB3C3A75A40F441D4B717341C4211B570" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Lifesaving Gear for Police Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H4286E00F73E74BAA8F95020F00842F05"><enum>2.</enum><header>State and local law enforcement access to lifesaving Federal equipment</header><subsection id="HF972F51FB6704FD7A26667DB7419114B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Unenforceability of certain regulations unless enacted into law</header><paragraph id="HE71DD713DB0E449BBCB596A89028E707"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No regulation, rule, guidance, policy, or recommendation issued on or after May 15, 2015, that limits the sale, donation, or transfer of property of the Federal Government pursuant to Executive Order 13688 (entitled <quote>Federal Support for Local Law Enforcement Equipment Acquisition</quote>) or Executive Order 14074 (entitled <quote>Advancing Effective, Accountable Policing and Criminal Justice Practices To Enhance Public Trust and Public Safety</quote>), including excess property of the Department of Defense, to State and local agencies for law enforcement activities (whether pursuant to section 2576a of title 10, United States Code, or any other provision of law, or as a condition on the use of Federal funds) shall have any force or effect after the date of the enactment of this Act unless enacted into law by Congress.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94B5597E7E724F87871709ACEBFD56B3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds To enforce regulations</header><text>No agency or instrumentality of the Federal Government may use any Federal funds, fees, or resources to implement or carry out a regulation, rule, guidance, policy, or recommendation issued as described in paragraph (1) that is not enacted into law by Congress.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E90537D8ED24F03AFC6B4614F441AA6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations on subsequent executive orders</header><text>In accordance with this subsection, the President may not reinstate any section of the Executive orders listed in paragraph (1) nor establish any substantially similar Executive order regarding the transfer of equipment to law enforcement under section 2576a of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B6466C3C7704F1E85EA32119ED83F89"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Return or reissue of equipment recalled or seized pursuant to regulations</header><text>Any property recalled or seized on or after May 15, 2015, pursuant to a regulation, rule, guidance, policy, or recommendation issued as described in subsection (a)(1) shall be returned, replaced, or re-issued to the agency from which recalled or seized, at no cost to such agency, as soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, if—</text><paragraph id="HAB747B8A008E479CBF866B97840F4907"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such agency requests that the property be returned, replaced, or re-issued;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC540836E7E9A4D768797147ED96F318D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such agency satisfies the conditions set forth under 2576a of title 10, United States Code, authorizing transfer and use of such property, if applicable; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H309099831F3D4672A6B8F94E820B19BE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the property is in stock and available for transfer to the agency to be used for law enforcement activities at the time the agency submits a request referred to in paragraph (1). </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

