<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H95E0C911B4AD4E87A538770917F962D7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2234 IH: Ensuring Veterans Timely Access to Anesthesia Care Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2234</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250318">March 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to update certain standards regarding anesthesia and pain management services in the Veterans Health Administration.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8FAC365144CA400EBC0BE33A4E901310" style="OLC"><section id="H1870696D1CBC40D4967724C7D8B055D8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Veterans Timely Access to Anesthesia Care Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H469A3F332AF64E73A0CB80F7529B58FD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Alignment of standards regarding certified registered nurse anesthetists in the Veterans Health Administration with standards of the Defense Health Agency</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall update VHA Directive 1123 titled <quote>National Anesthesia Program, Department of Veterans Affairs Certified Registered Nurse Anesthetists Practice Guidelines</quote> (or any successor directive) to recognize, in the Veterans Health Administration, certified registered nurses anesthetists as licensed independent practitioners in a manner consistent with the practice standards described by section 3(f)(2) of Enclosure of Defense Health Agency Administrative Instruction 6025.07, dated November 8, 2023, as amended.</text></section><section id="H5366F9DB159342ECA694B5192B710831"><enum>3.</enum><header>Requirements of anesthesia providers in the Veterans Health Administration</header><subsection id="HBBD57C484C4C440B981D190034196582"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall require an anesthesia professional employed by the Secretary as—</text><paragraph id="H6AC022348C8245F98D1F1D2675D5BBA8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a physician anesthesiologist to be certified by the American Board of Anesthesiology or a similar body determined by the Secretary; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13BE907808914A1DA567483670CB90F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a certified registered nurse anesthetist to be certified by the Council on Certification of Nurse Anesthetists or the Council on Recertification of Nurse Anesthetists or a similar body determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0681FFC6D99A43F084FEDB7968C687E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Direct care</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require an anesthesia professional described in subsection (a) to have completed at least 25 hours of direct patient anesthesia care (not including supervision of other anesthesia professionals).</text></subsection><subsection id="H4BB131F4719440C0895073F87CC1C06E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall suspend from employment in the Department of Veterans Affairs an anesthesia professional described in subsection (a) who has not complied with the requirements of this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H2603B97E71574DAD82234155A0629358"><enum>4.</enum><header>GAO report on anesthesia delivery in the Veterans Health Administration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report that contains the following, and which shall be made publicly available:</text><paragraph id="HED2BE1E70886438C82553CE834177400"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Data regarding outcomes regarding the following anesthesia models used in the Veterans Health Administration:</text><subparagraph id="H22C9E9F692744C758D25FD5C97101F7B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Delivery by an anesthesiologist.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE10CA78DAD3A4CDAAB52A8D453F9C4A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Delivery by a certified registered nurse anesthetist under the supervision of a physician.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95D1F72635A0469FA9F7737954EF7CE4"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Delivery by a certified registered nurse anesthetist without supervision.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CE16EACFC1E497AB316D693A5585D05"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A comparison of the cost effectiveness of the models described in paragraph (1), including—</text><subparagraph id="H5336992FD6154924A7EE2C9EA6A649BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the estimated cost to medical facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs and taxpayers for each such model; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1615B151B124DD690BD8504DB82EF6C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a breakdown of costs and savings to taxpayers and to veterans’ households associated with each such model.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

