<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H64B1B63342F74EB3A020EA1F027F3AAC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1202 IH: Stop Human Trafficking of Unaccompanied Migrant Children Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1202</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250211">February 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000603">Mr. Luttrell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. Scott Franklin of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish vetting standards for the placement of unaccompanied alien children with sponsors, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H96C386DEAAA34989A0E9D8C3A7B633B1" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H16DB1180AE744914AB8F40330C3847F9"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Human Trafficking of Unaccompanied Migrant Children Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD31B6FC6B8854731B75A193D763F568B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Vetting standards for placement of unaccompanied alien children with sponsors</header> <subsection id="H9799AB139D5E4C5589FFEF71821A95BD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Vetting of prospective sponsors</header> <paragraph id="HCE9847799DD24E9A90998410C8AE7BAD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Before an unaccompanied alien child (as defined in section 462(g) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/279">6 U.S.C. 279(g)</external-xref>)) may be released from the custody of the Secretary of Health and Human Services to the custody of a sponsor, the sponsor shall undergo and complete, to the satisfaction of the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the head of the department of children and family services of the applicable State (or the equivalent State agency) and in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security, a fingerprint background check and vetting process that includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6AADE0DDCA7E4EBA92A6CE82B8D51B44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a public records check;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0DE899B21B6E423DA19866E45236EF1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a check of the National Sex Offender Registry of the Department of Justice, conducted through the public internet website for such registry;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA5EE3626E1C74D8CB88D1DB4D28F647F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a Federal Bureau of Investigation National Criminal History check based on digital fingerprints or digitized fingerprints submitted on paper;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBB39EFF909454E92B3D6521391095F60"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a Child Abuse and Neglect check, obtained on a State-by-State basis; and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HACEA4D96E2A2405B97BB3313A4E0EBA2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a check of the criminal history repository of the applicable 1 or more States and a police records check of the applicable localities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF69172D01A78402AA72F0288A402D6ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adults household members</header><text>As part of the vetting process under paragraph (1), each individual who is 18 years of age or older in the household of a prospective sponsor shall undergo and complete all vetting processes required by paragraph (1), to the satisfaction of the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the head of the department of children and family services of the applicable State (or the equivalent State agency) and in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security, before an unaccompanied alien child may be placed in such household.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6CB8E1A184B6479DB2C174634CA6332C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on placement with illegal aliens</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services may not release an unaccompanied alien child to the custody of a sponsor who is an alien unlawfully present in the United States, unless such alien is a biological parent, legal guardian, or relative of the child.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8D6FF76BC9A043D69BEA20D58693E5B7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Monitoring visits</header> <paragraph id="H10F2B50C56494C08B0703E7B692300B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Pre-release</header><text>Before an unaccompanied alien child may be released from the custody of the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary shall conduct a home visit to the household in which the child is proposed to be placed, regardless of the sponsor category of the prospective sponsor.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1BB68445B3194CEEAC862DD7BE0EB891"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Post-release</header><text>For each child released from the custody of the Secretary of Health and Human Services after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall conduct—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86C1295AF03048B2AF95DD5BC8A39F01"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">during the 1-year period beginning on the date on which the child is so released, not fewer than 5 unannounced in-person home visits; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H834DEB25C27246F098EEFB63E77385D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>during the subsequent 1-year period, 1 in-person home visit each quarter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE8D2A022A2754C50B5338E0CCBA64E94"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Retroactive vetting</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in collaboration with the head of the department of children and family services of each applicable State (or the equivalent State agency) and in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall immediately conduct the fingerprint background check and vetting process described in subsection (a) for each sponsor with whom a child released from the custody of the Secretary of Health and Human Services has been placed since January 20, 2021, until the sponsor of each such child has been vetted in accordance with this Act. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFF55A3792A7549DCB2DD47EEC752D4B2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Monthly reports</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H18B50C7828BB4285B8A4540BAFB7AE8C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Children in custody and released to sponsors</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 30 days thereafter, the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall jointly submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives a report that contains, for the preceding month—</text> <subparagraph id="H6588D7F2E71D44B1BCA93466AAA1BCD1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of unaccompanied alien children encountered by the Secretary of Homeland Security; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H79979BF675434D978FD12AE8ED708B78"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of unaccompanied alien children released by the Secretary of Homeland Security into the custody of the Secretary of Health and Human Services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD5BFAA05AF27484583E8DDA5AD06E7DA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of sponsor background checks completed under subsection (a);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE316A76FEBA741CA8CF8D532657E293C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of sponsor background checks in progress under such subsection;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2AD84710F2634FB0825A8CE547673145"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the number of pre-release home visits completed; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H827A4A31975B4487BC64D21BE75A3DEE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the number of post-release home visits completed; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE57E0ECE4E84893A1EEC15FBDA17AFE"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the number of unaccompanied alien children released to sponsors, disaggregated by sponsor category; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF6F222E3627E4BFEBE733ED56A5A69F3"><enum>(H)</enum><text>total number of unaccompanied alien children in the custody of the Secretary of Health and Human Services, disaggregated by State and Department of Health and Human Services facility; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1A9EE0DE327D4FF8835278669D8FF2CB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the rate at which the Secretary of Health and Human Services rejected sponsorship applications. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2639D7A5F39E4901A5CBB6E677BA4DA1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Missing children</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 30 days thereafter, the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall jointly submit to Congress a report on all efforts made, during the preceding month, by the Department of Health and Human Services and the Department of Homeland Security to account for all children—</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C4D3CF95BC14B67B8968D07941A662D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who were released from the custody of the Secretary of Health and Human Services to a sponsor on or after January 20, 2021; and </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H72B4A1A8A1514EEB8A3A36ACC7661DE1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>as of the date of the enactment of this Act—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF3332D8250EF4C2A95BE940FFD738042"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who have been reported missing; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62E7AE759F0C491B9A9643435AD2D1B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to whom the Secretary of Health and Human Services has no record since the date of release from custody.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

