<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7447C6D100C74DD884819D12D7EC06D3" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 272 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States seeks to restore peace in Ukraine.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 272</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250331">March 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000626">Mr. Davidson</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States seeks to restore peace in Ukraine.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States has defined its mission in Ukraine as restoring peace between Ukraine and Russia;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States seeks to contain the war rather escalate or expand the war; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the parties to the war have repeatedly rejected American efforts to restore peace: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas> </preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H57BCACFF84974414890D71A220F9F605"> <section id="H2867B71D9C184A2B837C1551A20FB0BC" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives expresses—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEAD6208E1DC34728A090B377C85B4BBA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support for the Trump administration’s efforts to restore peace between Ukraine and Russia without expanding or escalating the war; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1289F4E56E244F02B8BF0DAE9F375888"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC9A8068FEAEC4716BC8F3B9924877937"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the United States should not expend any more money, resources, or manpower participating in the Russia-Ukraine War;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1D90D230D7624EBFB3432BB9B9D7D682"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all military advisors, intelligence assets, and involved government personnel should withdraw from participation in the war;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB2B01DE44D5449AE9B9FDC935093F462"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the United States Government should put America first and secure our own borders instead of those of far-off countries; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4F61F6703064F87B563D83DADB02148"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the United States should cease all intelligence sharing with the Ukrainian Government, as well as all involved European intelligence agencies that leak shared United States intelligence in contravention of this resolution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>


