<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4F33AD45F19340B8A56D57550E868747" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5189 IH: To amend title 10, United States Code, to require biennial assessments on the nutrition standards of the military departments, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5189</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250908">September 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to require biennial assessments on the nutrition standards of the military departments, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8FA316092376453A803E53868EF66414" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDCE384294300449988AA520AA0E307F5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Assessments and plan for increasing access to nutritious food on military installations</header> 
<subsection id="HA23D85B1DD4B492192E23778C8124411"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessments</header> 
<paragraph id="H0881F9647B334BA8BDF188DC729EEFE0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/23">Chapter 23</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/488">section 488</external-xref> the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H3E999B8DE2524F798E8CC20238E60DAC" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="HC82ADC72C6B047EDB6D06AD4DB66FD82"><enum>489.</enum><header>Biennial assessments on nutrition standards of military departments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">On a biennial basis, the Secretary of Defense shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8D8C436F369842DB84A54B8964FE759A">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>conduct an assessment of the nutrition standards of each military department, including by reviewing any nutrition program or related policy of that military department, and the extent to which such standards are reflected in the food options accessible to members of the Armed Forces at the military installations of that military department;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEEF678F71FD141C5980E5BAB864721EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit a report containing the results of such assessment to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3270A3555CCE489FBD84DAB0E0CBF3D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publish such report on a publicly available website of the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE6C003EE77C4CCF88DBACD0BB854435"><enum>(2)</enum><header>First report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 1, 2026, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate, and publish on a publicly available website of the Department of Defense, the first report required under section 489 of title 10, United States Code, as added by paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAAA32640D0384F2BACB706BD1CEE2FC3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plan</header> <paragraph id="H42CD2AD75E7E421A93501F7F7C2ED6D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness and the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, in coordination with the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Manpower and Reserve Affairs and such other entities as the Secretary of Defense determines appropriate, shall jointly submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate and publish on a publicly available website of the Department of Defense a plan to increase access to nutritious food on military installations, consistent with recommendations included in the report of the Government Accountability Office titled <quote>DOD Food Program: Additional Actions Needed to Implement, Oversee, and Evaluate Nutrition Efforts for Service Members</quote>, and dated June 24, 2024 (GAO–24–106155).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBD0F04D1B5DE43C294B53F942CBB6F2D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The plan under paragraph (1) shall include a strategy developed by the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Manpower and Reserve Affairs for increasing nutritious menu options at venues that are located on military installations, offer food services to members of the Armed Forces, and are not funded with appropriated amounts (referred to in the report specified in such paragraph as <quote>nonappropriated fund food venues</quote>).</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

