<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HECDF92CAD87B47CCB415E5A870335BFA" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 776 IH: Expressing concerns regarding the urgent and escalating threats facing Coptic Christians.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 776</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250930">September 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill of Arkansas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing concerns regarding the urgent and escalating threats facing Coptic Christians.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas St. Mark brought Christianity to Egypt, where Coptic Christians have been an Indigenous people of Egypt for over 2,000 years, deeply rooted in ancient Egyptian traditions, from language and liturgical music to ritual symbolism, and have preserved a cultural identity that long predates the Islamic conquest of Egypt in the seventh century;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas there are over 10,000,000 Copts in Egypt, making them the largest Christian and the largest non-Muslim community in the Middle East;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, according to the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom 2025 Annual Report, freedom of religion for religious minority communities continues to be systemically restricted in Egypt;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Coptic Christians today live as second-class citizens in their ancestral homeland, marginalized institutionally and socially;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Egyptian Government continues to disproportionately arrest Coptic Christians and converts to Christianity for blasphemy charges;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas hundreds of Coptic Christian women and minor girls have been lured, abducted, forcibly converted, abused, and forcibly married, and the Egyptian authorities have failed to meaningfully or consistently intervene or act to prevent these crimes or to prosecute the perpetrators;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas violence against Coptic Christians is rarely punished, particularly in villages and rural areas, making them more susceptible to repeated attacks and extending impunity to their attackers;</text></whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas the United States diplomatic leadership contributes meaningfully and materially to the international protection of religious minorities and their faith-based practices and places of worship;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States has a strong interest in combating the threat of terrorism and ensuring the stability of the region; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas religious freedom and human rights are essential cornerstones of democracy that promote respect for individual liberty, contribute to greater stability, and are priority values for the United States in promoting its engagement with other countries: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HB882D17023CA4A70B878B45FC92E899C"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H980CF18194A8481ABD42BAF682595B87"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HCE157FD1A2404FD09CDB70C77081E915"><enum>(1)</enum><text>acknowledges the central and historic importance of the United States-Egypt partnership in advancing the common interests of both countries;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBD669DCA901743008473297E4FC4A1D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>appreciates Egypt’s regional role as a partner in combating terrorism and violent extremism;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4A6F2B60B2134802A76D0946190DE889"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the necessity of strengthening protection of internationally recognized human rights and the rule of law in Egypt;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81C6F21E904A48FBB418F508A8E4DE06"><enum>(4)</enum><text>urges the Government of Egypt to ensure Coptic Christians are afforded the same rights as all other Egyptian citizens; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H030BAB9F61244F06916AD17496F0D934"><enum>(5)</enum><text>urges the Government of Egypt to take additional steps to end the culture of impunity for attacks on Christians by pursuing the arrest, prosecution, and conviction of individuals who commit such crimes, and to hold accountable any Government officials who fail to enforce the law.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

