<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCG25410-HYH-T8-DL8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1323 IS: The Facilitating Increased Resilience, Environmental Weatherization And Lowered Liability (FIREWALL) Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1323</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a refundable credit against tax for disaster mitigation expenditures.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HA5EA2D3397D74C3DBABC95BB45AC2F35"><section id="id648ab4c534e741dd952f08b0af4efdf3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>The Facilitating Increased Resilience, Environmental Weatherization And Lowered Liability (FIREWALL) Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3BCD3B76206C4962B195C9567F0B1E57" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Refundable personal credit for disaster mitigation expenditures</header><subsection id="HB241454A8C4D46C4A3C63361754FB1EF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart C of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to refundable credits) is amended by inserting after section 36B the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id82a6bedc2faf491aba79840d0bbfc1d9"><section id="HF737D8DEC7E84D5B9A0F1A3606D51A26"><enum>36C.</enum><header>Disaster mitigation expenditures</header><subsection id="H023AE302FEEE496A961EE12757624F36"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><text>In the case of an individual, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year an amount equal to 50 percent of the qualified disaster mitigation expenditures made by the taxpayer during such taxable year.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF9C36CBE60D440C896DD5C8A994C85C5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Maximum credit</header><paragraph id="ide71d563dfec94e7f9f61d77f455b17fc"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), the credit allowed under subsection (a) to any taxpayer for any taxable year shall not exceed the excess of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1e7148313e674fdba525684dfd2d7d3e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$25,000 (or, in the case of a married individual filing a separate return, 50 percent of such amount), over</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida214706236ad45dc93fca0dba3cc9a5e"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of credit allowed to the taxpayer under this section for all preceding taxable years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H42A268CE76FE4AFEA2F430B136762864"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Phaseout</header><text>The amount under paragraph (1) for the taxable year shall be reduced (but not below zero) by an amount which bears the same ratio to the amount under such paragraph as—</text><subparagraph id="HFD7E885FA69647A7A379E68431CEFC69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the excess (if any) of—</text><clause id="H491703CB900E4093B6F0EBC555CEBA3D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the taxpayer’s adjusted gross income for such taxable year, over</text></clause><clause id="HFB180DBC026E4657AB3838E19F1109C2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$200,000, bears to</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF99FD4239C73434283A1021C9B9E097C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$100,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id122e9b15ab294a219be7e7a853c18252"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation in the case of joint occupancy</header><text>In the case of any dwelling unit with respect to which qualified disaster mitigation expenditures are made and which is jointly occupied and used during any calendar year as a residence by two or more individuals, the following rules shall apply:</text><subparagraph id="id77a0ea3863b14a5785f658119a1bc5f0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Maximum expenditures</header><text>The maximum amount of such expenditures which may be taken into account under subsection (a) by all such individuals with respect to such dwelling unit during such calendar year shall be $25,000.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id12768fc97755486884342d3ed04abae8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Allocation of expenditures</header><text>The expenditures allocated to any individual for the taxable year in which such calendar year ends shall be an amount equal to the lesser of—</text><clause id="id3c293fef946646e896b5977d239d351a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of expenditures made by such individual with respect to such dwelling during such calendar year, or</text></clause><clause id="id5c8b1a25455344fab0961cccdf443dd6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the maximum amount of such expenditures set forth in subparagraph (A) multiplied by a fraction—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idad49d23d086849029cb2f05547b328c0"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the numerator of which is the amount of such expenditures with respect to such dwelling made by such individual during such calendar year, and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd808b02b1b034f15a9cc5f7dea886688"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the denominator of which is the total expenditures made by all such individuals with respect to such dwelling during such calendar year.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9ad2a2cc10ec4aa698713d33cb01b0be"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><subparagraph id="H32F8FF50D34C480E8175EEB861F4615D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any taxable year after 2025, the $25,000 dollar amounts under paragraphs (1)(A) and (3), the $200,000 amount under paragraph (2)(A)(ii), and the $100,000 amount under paragraph (2) (B) shall each be increased by an amount equal to—</text><clause id="H934B8E52B79C4E229EC3C822BF06AB1C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></clause><clause id="H9DF227ECF89D410CB23A76310E65D6BF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2024</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE54A290D8E9849FABAB07551988DD7AC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>If any reduction determined under subparagraph (A) is not a multiple of $50, or any increase under subparagraph (B) is not a multiple of $50, such amount shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $50.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H231267A4E0974F9EB75DE5A4DCEA758C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="HCA7A4B7B2EDA493DAE9EA0BB6BFD9A30"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified disaster mitigation expenditure</header><subparagraph id="idC02E9CAC59884DCB9B22A13382DE4D87"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified disaster mitigation expenditure</term> means an expenditure relating to a qualified dwelling unit—</text><clause id="id4DCF78B897A54232B3B6FA896AB0458A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for property to—</text><subclause id="HC86A6585AEDC41DEBE91D4B27EBA366D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>improve the strength of a roof deck attachment,</text></subclause><subclause id="H33A74035519649D8978FAA4B84AD349A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>create a secondary water barrier to prevent water intrusion or mitigate against potential water intrusion from wind-driven rain,</text></subclause><subclause id="H21D212712CF7494A8296DD96C9B0BB8E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>improve the durability, impact resistance (not less than class 3 or 4 rating), or fire resistance (not less than class A rating) of a roof covering,</text></subclause><subclause id="H09E4361C0168453088FA3532BAE2CBFA"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>brace gable-end walls,</text></subclause><subclause id="HA877FA759397485796C03596E3FD1F02"><enum>(V)</enum><text>reinforce the connection between a roof and supporting wall,</text></subclause><subclause id="H2891DABF19B74999844C8767F0FF6710"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>protect openings from penetration by wind-borne debris,</text></subclause><subclause id="HDF7FFF3E2FBC4462919E7FA9BDFB8153"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>protect exterior doors and garages from natural hazards,</text></subclause><subclause id="idDFF24990073D4D02A9289708982BFBA2"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>complete measures contained in the publication of the Federal Emergency Management Agency entitled <quote>Wind Retrofit Guide for Residential Buildings</quote> (P–804),</text></subclause><subclause id="idDC2671051C464848948848FC781D405B"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>elevate the qualified dwelling unit, as well as utilities, machinery, or equipment, above the base flood elevation or other applicable minimum elevation requirement,</text></subclause><subclause id="idB41F0D526D41435AA904E0BF6EB3598B"><enum>(X)</enum><text>seal walls in the basement of the qualified dwelling unit using waterproofing compounds, or</text></subclause><subclause id="id24E997FAC6A94ED7BF75219C62F059A0"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>protect propane tanks or other external fuel sources,</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idED55622F12434220A0C19CDFA31CB0B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to install—</text><subclause id="idC70A23209C634D57B01C918258327595"><enum>(I)</enum><text>check valves to prevent flood water from backing up into drains,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="idB2EC87B177F7478DB04A931C3A933313"><enum>(II)</enum><text>flood vents, breakaway walls or open lattice for homes located in V zones,</text></subclause><subclause id="idFA335BBF74C540F29D4BB58B9D2E2071"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a stormwater drainage system or improve an existing system,</text></subclause><subclause id="idEF1412B764C34CA3956F888CFDEF5DD5"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>natural or nature-based features for flood control, including living shorelines,</text></subclause><subclause id="idC31763DD73BC4BD6A177C3C4ADD46A00"><enum>(V)</enum><text>roof coverings, sheathing, flashing, roof and attic vents, eaves, or gutters that conform to ignition-resistant construction standards,</text></subclause><subclause id="id1C547381A8C24DD480B94664F70975C3"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>wall components for wall assemblies that conform to ignition-resistant construction standards,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id8E1ED7F09E634203991BCBD3B3F92650"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>a wall-to-foundation anchor or connector, or a shear transfer anchor or connector,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id87DF06F840B8444F9CA5FD03C3DF2936"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>wood structural panel sheathing for strengthening cripple walls,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="idF8FE1779318B4794AD0E3F247D27CBE8"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>anchorage of the masonry chimney to the framing,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id36D64DC3815D4FA7A6041D8478044024"><enum>(X)</enum><text>prefabricated lateral resisting systems,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id2C65F74AFF5D4A75BDE50BCA6246FA15"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>a standby generator system consisting of a standby generator and an automatic transfer switch,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="idCFEA162CF4A346539D14961DAAFAE99E"><enum>(XII)</enum><text>a storm shelter that meets the design and construction standards established by the International Code Council and the National Storm Shelter Association (ICC–500), or a safe room that satisfies the criteria contained in—</text><item commented="no" id="idA60420148D44403CB0FC6D3C0B4422C3"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the publication of the Federal Emergency Management Agency entitled <quote>Safe Rooms for Tornadoes and Hurricanes</quote> (P–361), or</text></item><item commented="no" id="id0631BE3A343140C5AC805EBADDD6770E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the publication of the Federal Emergency Management Agency entitled <quote>Taking Shelter from the Storm</quote> (P–320),</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="idFDFF6410556346A78E8E74674A09A59D"><enum>(XIII)</enum><text>a lightning protection system,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id7A9D0D05B9494209B5BB893A63D23A1C"><enum>(XIV)</enum><text>exterior walls, doors, windows, or other exterior dwelling unit elements that conform to ignition-resistant construction standards,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id1F5449C15BFD44339D6CC252E3E576AA"><enum>(XV)</enum><text>exterior deck or fence components that conform to ignition-resistant construction standards,</text></subclause><subclause id="id688B2CC18B2B4B88A34856450368BB83"><enum>(XVI)</enum><text>structure-specific water hydration systems, including fire mitigation systems such as interior and exterior sprinkler systems,</text></subclause><subclause id="id63238A04C5FA465AB2490B365B5DED80"><enum>(XVII)</enum><text>water capture and delivery systems to accommodate drought events or to decrease water use, including the design of such systems,</text></subclause><subclause id="id7B63CD2134674EFDBE8A27CF53E8A6B6"><enum>(XVIII)</enum><text>flood openings for fully enclosed areas below the lowest floor of the dwelling unit,</text></subclause><subclause id="idEB91C67D6A8546C49F41928251E67416"><enum>(XIX)</enum><text>lateral bracing for wall elements, foundation elements, and garage doors or other large openings to resist seismic loads, or</text></subclause><subclause id="id25D2FB3279C64EF393B2FA93A0EF5ED0"><enum>(XX)</enum><text>automatic shutoff valves for water and gas lines, or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idFCD200F70CA644D3A380D1EA1BE59CF5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for services or equipment to—</text><subclause id="id6C0F899D536D4EF0B520DCB50652678C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>create buffers around the qualified dwelling unit through the removal or reduction of flammable vegetation, including vertical clearance of tree branches,</text></subclause><subclause id="id866095C2E88D4A9DB46BFA54A00FCF3C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>create buffers around the dwelling unit through—</text><item id="id881D7E1518A04DC3BE533E0E14DF6A40"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the removal of exterior deck or fence components or ignition-prone landscape features, or</text></item><item id="id7FDA27CC391B4146BDF4E508DB3C1573"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>replacement of the components or features described in item (aa) with components or features that conform to ignition-resistant construction standards,</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id0D88D6B6D7A440CC993063277A73AB8E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>perform fire maintenance procedures identified by the Federal Emergency Management Agency or the United States Forest Service, including fuel management techniques such as creating fuel and fire breaks,</text></subclause><subclause id="id50C79BA916544B258E51E13A554EE28E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>gather and analyze water and weather data to better understand the local climate and drought history,</text></subclause><subclause id="idf1bf4090415b48bd9d3c084f9e338c60"><enum>(V)</enum><text>remove flammable vegetation within 5 feet of a structure,</text></subclause><subclause id="id563EEC820E2B4574B0AD8F0365AA394A"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>determine the risk of natural disasters which may occur in the area in which the qualified dwelling unit is located, or</text></subclause><subclause id="id709E3BD0A01E4AEAA10E78CE310C4585"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>prevent smoke inhalation, such as air filters or other equipment designed to prevent smoke from entering the dwelling unit, </text></subclause></clause><clause id="id4472103E2160483CBC87FD146A2BE34B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>for property relating to satisfying the standards required for receipt of a FORTIFIED designation from the Insurance Institute for Business and Home Safety, provided that the qualified dwelling unit receives such designation following installation of such property, or</text></clause><clause id="id9A9F06BE24FE4760AA4E9A1E4AFA0B85"><enum>(v)</enum><text>for any other hazard mitigation activity which has been identified by the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, for mitigation of a natural hazard.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB6C91B9946E14A7CAE21A4706D005606"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The term <term>qualified disaster mitigation expenditure</term> shall not include any expenditure or portion thereof which is paid, funded, or reimbursed by a Federal, State, or local government entity, or any political subdivision, agency, or instrumentality thereof.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H27C69D4B3D8541BBAA660B415564D9B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified dwelling unit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified dwelling unit</term> means, with respect to any taxpayer, a dwelling unit which is—</text><subparagraph id="H7082B41603444944B1A2D046046285EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">located in any State or territory—</text><clause commented="no" id="H4D693DAC89A9496BA1568FBC70420890"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in which a Federal natural disaster declaration has been made within the preceding 10-year period with respect to a wildfire, hurricane, windstorm or flood,</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HBDFF4222E37E40C59CDCF49F5670E17A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which includes an area which, during the taxable year or the period of the 10 taxable years preceding such taxable year, has received hazard mitigation assistance through the Federal Emergency Management Agency in regard to any wildfire, hurricane, windstorm or flood which, with respect to the expenditure described in paragraph (1) which is made by the taxpayer, is applicable to such expenditure, or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H009F7DCF52D143349B09295087B0ACC0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>which includes an area which, with respect to any taxable year, has been designated as a community disaster resilience zone (as defined in section 206(a) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5136">42 U.S.C. 5136(a)</external-xref>)) as the result of a wildfire, hurricane, windstorm or flood, and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id31b121fad3ce4dda936c80a94cda7b91"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">used as the principal residence (within the meaning of section 121) of the taxpayer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA166CFC26A004BDBBCB8E372D6001AF6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Other rules</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id94a4193cf55e4844a85a6d413577a835"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Documentation</header><text>Any taxpayer claiming the credit under this section shall provide the Secretary with adequate documentation regarding the specific qualified disaster mitigation expenditures made by the taxpayer during the taxable year, as well as such other information or documentation as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5c7d967f5c654517afeabb15845cfcfc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No deduction or other credit shall be allowed for expenditures which have been taken into account under this section, and the basis of any property for which a credit is allowed under this section shall be reduced by the amount of credit allowed.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC0C680D8B3DD4CB2834381CDD7E57DED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="idc7cd65001f67409785889c4b77df67f1"><enum>(1)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6211">Section 6211(b)(4)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>, 36C</quote> after <quote>36B</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idffd9f6cf840144ed98985b161f9a316c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 1324(b)(2) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>, 36C</quote> after <quote>36B</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd6bcb623a2c4610b0299ba85925686c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The table of sections for subpart C of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 36B the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E7D86E4C0984A1F8841E38083324E60"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 36C. Disaster mitigation expenditures.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0BC3C662C2904F61878C5EF7CEA7FBF1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2024.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

