<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC7BA1229DCD546E5A8C7DCCDEC7781BB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1571 IH: Bureaucratic Labor Adjustment and Downsizing Effort Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1571</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250225">February 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000388">Mr. Kelly of Mississippi</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To eliminate nonessential civil service positions in the executive branch of the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1B3D7A00BFD74977A1D8BB87646B4D8A" style="OLC"><section id="HF2BC7EB412294F3E99D8EF660C4E8312" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bureaucratic Labor Adjustment and Downsizing Effort Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7E9E68B9065D40B8A513AB1AE7810D29"><enum>2.</enum><header>Elimination of nonessential civil service executive branch positions</header><subsection id="H04DDF2E268214209A667FF887C1F760B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law—</text><paragraph id="H335259F7E8564BAEB0A2E8A429C372B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on the date provided under subsection (c), any Federal position described in subsection (b) is abolished; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55F9F114743344349236C5252E7A4288"><enum>(2)</enum><text>no Federal funds may be obligated or expended for the salary or expenses of any such position on or after such date.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3EEF8B88D4BC4E28AB7FCAB94747EAFC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Positions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A position described in this subsection is any position in the civil service (as that term is defined in section 2101 of title 5, United States Code) in the executive branch of the Federal Government that is designated as not excepted from furlough with respect to any lapse in appropriations occurring before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA7E3231BC49C4CED80E42C298DC72B64"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><paragraph id="H548B22132B1E4248939536E209C4F53F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unoccupied and nonessential</header><text>Positions under subsection (b) that are unoccupied on the date of the enactment of this Act shall be abolished on such date.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44F80C4D492046D2B5BB4EE495D6AAE4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Occupied and nonessential</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Positions under subsection (b) that are occupied on the date of the enactment of this Act shall be abolished on the first day after such date when such position becomes vacant (including a vacancy resulting from retirement, voluntary separation, or disciplinary action).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3AA968F45F2B4AD0931DB53BEFE061D5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On and after the date of the enactment of this Act, no Federal position—</text><paragraph id="H5A08E3BD98034D07BB1D7888965AB409"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may be designated as excepted from furlough that was not designated as excepted from furlough during a lapse in appropriations occurring before such date; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9D0746526C044DE97527852550E008A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>established after the date of enactment of this Act may be designated as excepted from furlough. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

