<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H8FEBAC8010C641B396CE4ABCA8DA751A" key="H">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3205 IH: No Subsidies for Gender Transition Procedures Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3205</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250505">May 5, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To deny tax deductions and other Federal funding for the costs of gender transition procedures.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HDBF0B67E0C334367908D5F257A771522">
<section id="H896AC9CE58E14F63BD8677067E0CFA66" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Subsidies for Gender Transition Procedures Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H97E1C02782DD4E19A841AEFC45774308"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Denial of medical expense tax deduction</header> <subsection id="H636ADF56A6DF4D70908721338EE17512"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (d) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/213">section 213</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H728F6AD45A0A43EA8F15B241980D11D3">
<paragraph id="H5752FBA3D2124874AE3DD1C1256E5A1F"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Expenses relating to gender transition</header>
<subparagraph id="HE888B74086D6405294635949B083C884"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>medical care</term> does not include any gender transition procedure.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED2844E86A3C4D238EBEFC861F629CF6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph—</text>
<clause id="HEBAEBE783CD14746BD2F3407D6167E18"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Gender transition procedure</header>
<subclause id="HB7483489AE164871BB6DDE3343ED9C17"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>gender transition procedure</term> means any hormonal or surgical intervention for the purpose of gender transition, including—</text> <item id="H069035B84E4E49A9B891DF5183D3234E"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the provision of gonadotropin-releasing hormone agonists or other puberty-suppression drugs or puberty-blocking drugs to stop or delay normally-timed puberty in an individual who does not identify as his or her sex,</text></item>
<item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB49923B041B346698EDF7596E24E66F0"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the provision of testosterone, estrogen, progesterone, or other androgen blockers to an individual at doses which are supraphysiologic to what would normally be produced endogenously in a healthy individual of the same age and sex, with the intent to align an individual’s physical appearance with an identity that differs from his or her sex,</text></item> <item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9EB63F006BAE4CDD9C7772F6E3E9DC73"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>surgical procedures that attempt to transform an individual’s physical appearance to align with an identity that differs from his or her sex or that attempt to alter or remove an individual’s sexual organs to minimize or destroy their natural biological functions,</text></item>
<item id="H4DAA5FFAEF954F1C9878272C46393CAE"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>castration, vasectomy, penectomy, orchiectomy, vaginoplasty, clitoroplasty, vulvoplasty, mastectomy, hysterectomy, oophorectomy, ovariectomy, reconstruction of the fixed part of the urethra with or without metoidioplasty or phalloplasty, metoidioplasty, phalloplasty, vaginectomy, scrotoplasty, implantation of erection or testicular prostheses, reduction thyrochondroplasty, chondrolaryngoplasty, tubal ligation, sterilization, augmentation mammoplasty, placement of chest implants to create feminine breasts, placement of fat or artificial implants in the gluteal region, liposuction, lipofilling, voice surgery, hair reconstruction, pectoral implants, any plastic, cosmetic, or aesthetic surgery which feminizes or masculinizes the facial or other physiological features of an individual, and any removal of any otherwise healthy or non-diseased body part or tissue.</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H535209762BC44AF5AB8821AC916482E2"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <term>gender transition procedure</term> does not include, when furnished to an individual by a health care provider with the consent of such individual (or, if applicable, such individual’s parents or legal guardian)—</text>
<item id="H7AEFC79068C14B228A831258DB46A2E0"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>services to individuals born with a medically verifiable disorder of sex development, including an individual with external sex characteristics which are irresolvably ambiguous, such as an individual born with 46 XX chromosomes with virilization, an individual born with 46 XY chromosomes with undervirilization, or an individual born having both ovarian and testicular tissue,</text></item> <item id="H892ECDCDFAAA4058B448E6CE59E891D7"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>services relating to any other physician-diagnosed disorder of sexual development with respect to which the physician has determined through genetic or biochemical testing that the individual does not have normal sex chromosome structure, sex steroid hormone production, or sex steroid hormone action for a healthy male or female of the same age,</text></item>
<item id="HAB5B68F8468744839F17C3CD33364378" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the treatment of any infection, injury, disease, or disorder caused or exacerbated by the performance of gender transition procedures, without regard to whether the gender transition procedure was performed in accordance with State and Federal law or whether the gender transition procedure is treated as medical care under this section,</text></item> <item id="H02CF32C0D7804218943B8D5C6ABAB8DD"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>any procedure undertaken because the individual suffers from a physical disorder, physical injury, or physical illness (but not mental, behavioral, or emotional distress or a mental, behavioral, or emotional disorder) which would, as certified by a physician, place the individual in imminent danger of death or impairment of major bodily function unless the procedure is performed to alleviate said physical disorder, physical injury, or physical illness,</text></item>
<item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H872FA5C50D6E4204B78C95738B791279"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>procedures to restore or reconstruct the body of the individual in order to correspond to the individual’s sex after one or more previous gender transition procedures, which may include the removal of a pseudo phallus or breast augmentation,</text></item> <item id="HF498D020BDD34D7E89063F6190BFC879"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>puberty suppression or puberty-blocking prescription drugs for the purpose of normalizing puberty for a minor experiencing precocious puberty, or</text></item>
<item id="H9C8C1907B5AC4695BC53EEFBDB171650"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>male circumcision.</text></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="H9B7C3B46160E4B4A84F6CC5F2532B0B7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Gender transition</header><text>The term <term>gender transition</term> means the process by which an individual goes from identifying with or presenting as his or her sex to identifying with or presenting as a self-proclaimed identity which does not correspond with or is different from his or her sex, and may be accompanied by social, legal, or physical changes.</text></clause>
<clause id="H8A26BE7D30854989BCCB34EB2140CABD" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Sex</header><text>The term <term>sex</term>, when referring to an individual’s sex, means either male or female, as biologically determined.</text></clause> <clause id="HC48585D8C52A4AF1BAC431FA184182D5"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Female</header><text>The term <term>female</term>, when used to refer to a natural person, means a person belonging, at conception, to the sex characterized by a reproductive system with the biological function of producing eggs (ova).</text></clause>
<clause id="H102652BFB14B4A2B802DC18AADE299DB"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Male</header><text>The term <term>male</term>, when used to refer to a natural person, means a person belonging, at conception, to the biological sex characterized by a reproductive system with the biological function of producing sperm.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H3AEFD690675A4873A78223818F1A6810"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HFD0F5480788047F4BC33C1A624085C40"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibiting Federal medicaid funding for gender transition procedures</header>
<subsection id="HBED59436D7B64441AF82AE56A99466E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1903(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(i)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HDFA5DB08CCFA483FA36450C980D05DB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (26), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H73ED405E9B504D46891F4EDC06DE267F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (27), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E3453928BC84B899EFC3D8A423456A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (27) the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA441DDD465A74D1A8438FB42DBA063F9">
<paragraph id="HB042F431CB9342F99C9BB6FF435AD497"><enum>(28)</enum><text>with respect to any amounts expended for any specified gender transition procedure (as defined in section 1905(kk)) to an individual enrolled in a State plan under this title (or a waiver of such plan), including any amounts expended for the administration of a State program that furnishes any such procedure.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA65C6A3AD5B64B179D32F39CF1868B97"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in the flush left matter at the end, by striking <quote>and (18),</quote> and inserting <quote>(18), and (28)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H05B157BA0CD14F369DB0DB184455CE3B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibiting Federal medicaid funding for gender transition procedures</header><text>Section 1905 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCEA7D96A5173434C9988B45B6E2470A6"> <subsection id="H717678D254C04720AA3B2CD01B0C5DDF"><enum>(kk)</enum><header>Prohibiting Federal medicaid funding for specified gender transition procedures</header> <paragraph id="HD04E01E1AD474423AB2CCECADC58A830"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Specified gender transition procedures defined</header><text>For purposes of section 1903(i)(28), except as provided in paragraph (2), the term <term>specified gender transition procedure</term> means, with respect to an individual, any hormonal or surgical intervention for the purpose of gender transition, including—</text>
<subparagraph id="H89D0DD30FEB3478E9BA89F1A713A3DDF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the provision of gonadotropin-releasing hormone agonists or other puberty suppression drugs or puberty-blocking drugs to stop or delay normally timed puberty in an individual who does not identify as his or her sex;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCABD6EB3E373411F9D558289AF149ACA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the provision of testosterone, estrogen, progesterone, or other androgen blockers to an individual at doses which are supraphysiologic to what would normally be produced endogenously in a healthy individual of the same age and sex, with the intent to align an individual’s physical appearance with an identity that differs from his or her sex;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB86C683F993D4F33A90FD7A90E030286"><enum>(C)</enum><text>surgical procedures that attempt to transform an individual’s physical appearance to align with an identity that differs from his or her sex or that attempt to alter or remove an individual’s sexual organs to minimize or destroy their natural biological functions; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H59ED121800564F21B9247D572D67B5AD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>castration, vasectomy, penectomy, orchiectomy, vaginoplasty, clitoroplasty, vulvoplasty, mastectomy, hysterectomy, oophorectomy, ovariectomy, reconstruction of the fixed part of the urethra with or without metoidioplasty or phalloplasty, metoidioplasty, phalloplasty, vaginectomy, scrotoplasty, implantation of erection or testicular prostheses, reduction thyrochondroplasty, chondrolaryngoplasty, tubal ligation, sterilization, augmentation mammoplasty, placement of chest implants to create feminine breasts, placement of fat or artificial implants in the gluteal region, liposuction, lipofilling, voice surgery, hair reconstruction, pectoral implants, any plastic, cosmetic, or aesthetic surgery which feminizes or masculinizes the facial or other physiological features of an individual, and any removal of any otherwise healthy or non-diseased body part or tissue.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB9EE24DC8DF4441BBF68EE79E7252AB3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <term>specified gender transition procedure</term> shall not include, when furnished to an individual by a health care provider with the consent of such individual (or, if applicable, the parents or legal guardian of such individual)—</text> <subparagraph id="HB82B8671D17642358734D7139FB6795A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>services to individuals born with a medically verifiable disorder of sex development, including an individual with external sex characteristics which are irresolvably ambiguous, such as an individual born with 46 XX chromosomes with virilization, an individual born with 46 XY chromosomes with undervirilization, or an individual born having both ovarian and testicular tissue;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6DD3E31624C04E4F86FE167DC60CD4C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>services relating to any other physician-diagnosed disorder of sexual development with respect to which the physician has determined through genetic or biochemical testing that the individual does not have normal sex chromosome structure, sex steroid hormone production, or sex steroid hormone action for a healthy male or female of the same age;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBF2DDAAFA22E45A7B3BB4E20045F7B57"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the treatment of any infection, injury, disease, or disorder caused or exacerbated by the performance of gender transition procedures, without regard to whether the gender transition procedure was performed in accordance with State and Federal law or whether the gender transition procedure is treated as medical care under this section;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE22D03FD66C44D26AE5538670DD6F3DE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any procedure undertaken because the individual suffers from a physical disorder, physical injury, or physical illness (but not mental, behavioral, or emotional distress or a mental, behavioral, or emotional disorder) which would, as certified by a physician, place the individual in imminent danger of death or impairment of major bodily function unless the procedure is performed to alleviate said physical disorder, physical injury, or physical illness;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8A3DB42BB8E949CEBAC99CD0923AC424"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any procedure to restore or reconstruct the body of the individual in order to correspond to the individual’s sex after 1 or more previous gender transition procedures, which may include the removal of a pseudo phallus or breast augmentation;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H79F59D02DDB94EEF8580CDA0410110DB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>puberty suppression or puberty-blocking prescription drugs for the purpose of normalizing puberty for an individual experiencing precocious puberty; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3DF5ECD864544B7BBB8856EACEF83BEE"><enum>(G)</enum><text>male circumcision.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3A77E96226A8408CAE2FEBBC4C1CDCC4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H355DE4F524A742C598D19C59BE5355C9"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Gender transition</header><text>The term <term>gender transition</term> means the process by which an individual goes from identifying with or presenting as his or her sex to identifying with or presenting as a self-proclaimed identity which does not correspond with or is different from his or her sex, and may be accompanied by social, legal, or physical changes.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD22078AB3DB145659593DEFF0DD6AD95"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Sex</header><text>The term <term>sex</term>, when referring to an individual’s sex, means either male or female, as biologically determined, including as described in subparagraphs (C) and (D).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4EA1408DDF0D447B80060CD491489261"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Female</header><text>The term <term>female</term>, when used to refer to a natural person, means an individual belonging, at conception, to the sex characterized by a reproductive system with the biological function of producing eggs (ova).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAFFF3FE34BC4461192B15C490CCD6947"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Male</header><text>The term <term>male</term>, when used to refer to a natural person, means an individual belonging, at conception, to the biological sex characterized by a reproductive system with the biological function of producing sperm.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H17683CF770F9434784C64D7998CFACF8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to services furnished on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HA2B44DB5CAE24405AB96A3C05D71D5EE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibiting Federal children’s health insurance program funding for gender transition procedures on minors</header>
<subsection id="H47F544E310994CD480381FA34961D610"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 2105(c) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397ee">42 U.S.C. 1397ee(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H80136F0B54904E44A1FDA0F3D33D7A98"> <paragraph id="H9BC7292D70E84AEAAC4B1F8936FB90E9"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Limitation on payment for specified gender transition procedures for minors</header><text>Payment shall not be made to a State under this section for any amount expended under the State plan to pay for specified gender transition procedures (as defined in section 1905(kk)) or to assist in the purchase, in whole or in part, of health benefit coverage that includes coverage of any such procedure.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE560361149D64EAF97CF425D95552171"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2107(e)(1)(N) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397gg">42 U.S.C. 1397gg(e)(1)(N)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>and (17)</quote> and inserting <quote>(17), and (28)</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H422144FC0BA448CAA8229F16CF937E93"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to services furnished on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HC62B5B500E4D4F518BB398110AF35A4B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prohibiting Federal medicare funding for gender transition procedures</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE15A1476BD342E1B31DD50F1B714F40"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1862(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE871F85DEB442F0B904A9F0894F8B25"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (24), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE7968AAD14EB4E06BA2B786E8C4613EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (25), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H40D18DD56B844ADAB637D19D36EA0336"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (25) the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB1D11D59FB248FAABD2183DF27A2C14">
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H525D45EA4527461FA746F8EA15B24E94"><enum>(26)</enum><text>which are specified gender transition procedures (as defined in section 1905(kk)).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE1E04EC959A04472AA3131D17A9A0074"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply to items and services furnished on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H8A8ADE03037C48C69B7B2E2546AF2274"><enum>6.</enum><header>Exclusion of gender transition procedures from essential health benefits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1302(b)(2) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18022">42 U.S.C. 18022(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0CF1DAAD19754283B0325562C6ADC70E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="paragraph">Limitation</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="paragraph">Limitations</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H69C0CE0E89804AA981A0415363F50475"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (B) as subparagraph (C);</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H35022EBE20504F6AA301ECD32E2BB266"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE6D8F220AAC485EBDC1D96003FCB0ED">
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H98417366240E41CAB1E43A9EFC3665A9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In defining the essential health benefits under paragraph (1), or in revising essential health benefits under paragraph (4)(H), the Secretary shall not include the category of gender transition procedures (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/213">section 213(d)(12)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) or any items or services covered within such a category.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD80D42839B25446591CF7C98E5B007A6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C) (as so redesignated), by striking <quote>paragraph (2)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (A)</quote>.</text></paragraph></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


