<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-AEG25173-RRW-W2-GP5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1070 IS: National STEM Week Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1070</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a National STEM Week to promote American innovation and enhance STEM education pathways for all students, including those in rural, urban, and underserved communities.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HE256CD1431EE4393BD8B4C42BA9C0D76"><section section-type="section-one" id="H6D740F499AD34F03A0E96B075A9FDAE6"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National STEM Week Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC9B746068B6E402D9E693A8398E3A9DF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H6541B9AB957A4260A7321F349E5944FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) fields are crucial to the economic competitiveness and innovative capacity of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6A92A0E2DC24513A081AA1A22096057"><enum>(2)</enum><text>There exists a need to enhance access to quality STEM education across all demographics and regions to address disparities in STEM participation and to ensure a diverse and capable future workforce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8518E6CF53864610B01E173D7D51791A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Informal and formal learning environments, including afterschool programs and at-home activities, play significant roles in stimulating interest and proficiency in STEM subjects.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E5FE0EDD8D14D1F983C2260CAB75C3E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Collaborations between educational institutions, industry partners, and communities can effectively inspire and prepare students for careers in STEM.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="HD466A3737F9A42D287063AD987683F3A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Designation of National STEM Week</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The National Science and Technology Council Committee on Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics Education (CoSTEM), in consultation with other relevant stakeholders, shall designate a week each calendar year as <quote>National STEM Week</quote>.</text></section><section id="H1786ED135FF045F189A44823320BADD4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Purposes of National STEM Week</header><subsection id="H60681BDBD6B048EF86046063E7DC87DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of National STEM Week are, through the programs and activities described in subsection (b), to—</text><paragraph id="H1C3FDACA973949DAA1509D188FA36FEA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>highlight the importance of STEM education in educational institutions across the country;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H45EEAD6E41864792B23353A084EF2270"><enum>(2)</enum><text>showcase diverse career pathways within STEM fields in both classroom settings and informal learning environments;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DE4E51B27DD405998F87A301CAF434C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourage family engagement with STEM activities at home to foster a conducive learning environment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AF72945645B4EEDA439C93555BA5363"><enum>(4)</enum><text>facilitate partnerships between educational institutions and industry leaders to provide students with real-world applications and mentorship opportunities in STEM fields; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C8CBC1F8B884936AE32ABC3E2DAB5B5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>support States and local communities in developing and promoting their own STEM Week activities and resources, tailored to their unique educational and industrial landscapes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H04D2EAA704F64A459E9C33C418303888"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Programs and activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During National STEM Week, the National Science and Technology Council Committee on Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics Education (CoSTEM) shall carry out the following:</text><paragraph id="HF13B71649FA24D4C9A04C55015A20CE2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Educational activities</header><text>Encourage educational institutions to participate in National STEM Week.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1A4606BB47248EF8F0B14653D634808"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community and family engagement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Encourage families of students attending the educational institutions participating in National STEM Week to participate in STEM activities. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DAADF5926054DE68AD51225F17F68C6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Industry involvement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Encourage STEM industries to—</text><subparagraph id="H6FD1F28580604188B0E462AC0061EC21"><enum>(A)</enum><text>engage with students enrolled in educational institutions by providing mentorship programs, site visits, and guest lectures; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F1763BE763E44E181F01903BD0DC828"><enum>(B)</enum><text>support STEM education initiatives at such educational institutions through funding, resources, and expertise.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3CE3C92078C1441F9B0C814886CF9A3B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reporting and evaluation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and on an annual basis thereafter, the National Science and Technology Council Committee on Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics (CoSTEM) shall submit to Congress a report detailing the activities conducted under National STEM Week, including—</text><paragraph id="HA53B83C0B6834E72AC760DE1260C01DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of nationwide participation and activities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25EA3A1BA14F465390FBF925AB761167"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an analysis of the impact of these activities on improving STEM education and closing educational gaps; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BC456515A4640EFBDA48C2C9818E7AB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations for improving future STEM Weeks based on feedback from participants and stakeholders.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H9F06E55A54B441DEA923CF1B7D4FB526"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H1E71A03C9A21491DBED2787F433F2613"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Educational institution</header><text>The term <term>educational institution</term> means any elementary school, secondary school, and institution of higher education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA75214FEF7234CF2B4A9EF9A13B346D1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elementary school; secondary school</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term> and <term>secondary school</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H82A6B9CF9DF1421C9BA0CAC4B87DB5CD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Industry leader</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>industry leader</term> means an individual in a leadership position within an industry partner who has the authority to make strategic decisions and allocate resources to support the purposes of National STEM Week.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFD73FE052804D98945DE75D1979BD8A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Industry partner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>industry partner</term> means a for-profit or nonprofit entity seeking to support the purposes of National STEM Week.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D9F33388F324AFE84828B619F2FCC30"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F3615AB79514A469A58F4E8F9A51316"><enum>(6)</enum><header>STEM</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>STEM</term> means science, technology, engineering, and mathematics. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H977CEC80839848BDBF44885E97D047D2"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the United States Virgin Islands.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

