<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H03E0E69128F5474EA65B9DF69DFE84D8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1067 IH: Lowering Infant and Toddler Tuition for Learning and Education Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1067</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250206">February 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish the childcare provider startup credit, to increase the amount of and make refundable the expenses for household and dependent care credit, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFDDDAE73868D42A8AD23C9A6AAFA2952" style="OLC"><section id="H37FDFBFB08024F41A880EEC487BA4704" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Lowering Infant and Toddler Tuition for Learning and Education Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>LITTLE Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H47EC80B6F4444D6B924617B12A3AAB46"><enum>2.</enum><header>Childcare provider startup credit</header><subsection id="HECC6CC4718B84EA2A1CF02D250F3D07F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H15EF6797A2C44A7BA4D482BF7FB5EDA5" style="OLC"><section id="H17A3870883114718BB7C4A679EF9ADA2"><enum>45BB.</enum><header>Childcare provider startup credit</header><subsection id="HC8BD52879B98411B972D384A1BD66155"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a qualified taxpayer, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this subtitle an amount equal to 30 percent of the qualified childcare startup expenses of the taxpayer for the taxable year.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC9C2AB503FCB4ECF80FCA4970B8B7674"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified taxpayer</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>qualified taxpayer</quote> means, with respect to a taxable year, a taxpayer that—</text><paragraph id="H63A4027F3C774E1C94A67B61313B51C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provides childcare services in compliance with any applicable State or local requirements for such services, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63E7A63BCA814B539AB244BCE5F6F871"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provided such services to 2 or more children for a significant portion of the taxable year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HABCFDEBA8B3F42139A16497CADE01B62"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified childcare startup expenses</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>qualified childcare startup expenses</quote> means, with respect to a taxable year, a start-up expenditure (as defined in section 195(c)(1)) paid or incurred during the 2-year period ending on the last day of such taxable year to establish and operate a childcare service.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFEFE409832014B49B3B6B294B5C400D0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The aggregate amount of credits determined under subsection (a) for any taxpayer in all taxable years may not exceed $10,000.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBCA761A1552F42BBB477521F13443828"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under subsection (a) for any expense for which a deduction or credit is allowed under any other provision of this chapter.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HDFB4DBEECBD64342B3423FE24F04036B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit allowed s part of general business credit</header><text>Section 38(b) is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (40), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (41) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H348605A765C647F09D5CFC229D6C2B21" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H12675929A5214766A15AB6924A0493A8"><enum>(42)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the childcare provider startup credit determined under section 45BB(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H586BF63BB0C0497DBBD7D770B8617002"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart B of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 36B the following new item:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H36813A1FB07F48C79CE172D7E3DD69B2" style="OLC"><toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H15EF6797A2C44A7BA4D482BF7FB5EDA5" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H17A3870883114718BB7C4A679EF9ADA2" level="section">Sec. 45BB. Childcare provider startup credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA103CEC001D74B2295711229E0ADE9DD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to expenses paid or incurred after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H2019A8C6690E434B978516463CF7E268"><enum>3.</enum><header>Household and dependent care credit increased and made refundable</header><subsection id="H975802C9B72842CC87C1C3DCEAA4C562"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart C of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amending by inserting after section 36B the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H612F433A01C043BE8A960A0256677143" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HCBF13908490B4C26B118770014973189"><enum>36C.</enum><header>Expenses for household and dependent care services necessary for gainful employment</header><subsection id="H2FFC4B5E3AFE4E06B8E2CEEA886F4B32"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><paragraph id="HD56502B7F4F14C32BC267961484417AC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual for which there are 1 or more qualifying individuals with respect to such individual, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year an amount equal to the applicable percentage of the employment-related expenses paid by such individual during the taxable year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA37D070CD77145D7A3E2298D6A786EEC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable percentage defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1), the term <term>applicable percentage</term> means 50 percent reduced (but not below 35 percent) by 1 percentage point for each $2,000 (or fraction thereof) by which the taxpayer’s adjusted gross income for the taxable year exceeds $15,000.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2A4AFB0922DC4C99A62FFC9C09B99E00"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions of qualifying individual and employment-Related expenses</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H62E39AFDA327494D82A9BD99D487265C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualifying individual</header><text>The term <term>qualifying individual</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HBEBFBB4A80A54FE0B21C05905E3DF7F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a dependent of the taxpayer (as defined in section 152(a)(1)) who has not attained age 13,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31DAB03697374C729B1482C2567B9340"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a dependent of the taxpayer (as defined in section 152, determined without regard to subsections (b)(1), (b)(2), and (d)(1)(B)) who is physically or mentally incapable of caring for himself or herself and who has the same principal place of abode as the taxpayer for more than one-half of such taxable year, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H976F635139104A74B61E03C9EAFA3A6A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the spouse of the taxpayer, if the spouse is physically or mentally incapable of caring for himself or herself and who has the same principal place of abode as the taxpayer for more than one-half of such taxable year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H64318B24B98C403E9FB44E0066E130D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employment-related expenses</header><subparagraph id="HED04499BA01147B4A84BDA838F151B23"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>employment-related expenses</term> means amounts paid for the following expenses, but only if such expenses are incurred to enable the taxpayer to be gainfully employed for any period for which there are 1 or more qualifying individuals with respect to the taxpayer:</text><clause id="H0617C720BEED4BE6BFCEE6A94976CD96"><enum>(i)</enum><text>expenses for household services, and</text></clause><clause id="H9B78BD528C044594B851A8661CF46C81"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>expenses for the care of a qualifying individual.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">Such term shall not include any amount paid for services outside the taxpayer’s household at a camp where the qualifying individual stays overnight.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6659206E52545DFAF0E2FDFB17F4525"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Employment-related expenses described in subparagraph (A) which are incurred for services outside the taxpayer’s household shall be taken into account only if incurred for the care of—</text><clause id="HF26BD7ADADF04F22BFCF8B3BCA290255"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a qualifying individual described in paragraph (1)(A), or</text></clause><clause id="HCBBC7698FCFE48079C48BA1AFB544620"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a qualifying individual (not described in paragraph (1)(A)) who regularly spends at least 8 hours each day in the taxpayer’s household.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF76D306FDE484788BC6E7DE80E36FF57"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Dependent care centers</header><text>Employment-related expenses described in subparagraph (A) which are incurred for services provided outside the taxpayer’s household by a dependent care center (as defined in subparagraph (D)) shall be taken into account only if—</text><clause id="H3C365B324FE54642AB43FCD7E43C1AB8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such center complies with all applicable laws and regulations of a State or unit of local government, and</text></clause><clause id="HCE9C93F371AD4D86A307B711E87E055A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the requirements of subparagraph (B) are met.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD40BD6803B2A4D84BD4DCBD13B60B7DE"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Dependent care center defined</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>dependent care center</term> means any facility which—</text><clause id="HAD9405937E6E43D4AA3F49591955E0EF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides care for more than six individuals (other than individuals who reside at the facility), and</text></clause><clause id="HB33DDD0CE9F94618B7641CB00FAAE698"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>receives a fee, payment, or grant for providing services for any of the individuals (regardless of whether such facility is operated for profit).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H18AD2234284349E7B1C893D522872A5B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Dollar limit on amount creditable</header><text>The amount of the employment-related expenses incurred during any taxable year which may be taken into account under subsection (a) shall not exceed—</text><paragraph id="H566AFB0EF7C54D79A91404ED98E5D58B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$7,500 if there is 1 qualifying individual with respect to the taxpayer for such taxable year, or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69D8E0CFA91047E0A67B371BF35C4CED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$15,000 if there are 2 or more qualifying individuals with respect to the taxpayer for such taxable year.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">The amount determined under paragraph (1) or (2) (whichever is applicable) shall be reduced by the aggregate amount excludable from gross income under section 129 for the taxable year.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="HDBF948527AB840E3B75F5DCD2DAF3DB3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Earned income limitation</header><paragraph id="H6FC2A13D2D8D47C68E244179D0871733"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the amount of the employment-related expenses incurred during any taxable year which may be taken into account under subsection (a) shall not exceed—</text><subparagraph id="H2241F9CCFCC84D87A94847B9B14F251B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of an individual who is not married at the close of such year, such individual’s earned income for such year, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4752502329364FBFBD795CEFB661D8F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an individual who is married at the close of such year, the lesser of such individual’s earned income or the earned income of his spouse for such year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2F845FF8F6E4CB7B78812D7E2D466DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for spouse who is a student or incapable of caring for himself</header><text>In the case of a spouse who is a student or a qualifying individual described in subsection (b)(1)(C), for purposes of paragraph (1), such spouse shall be deemed for each month during which such spouse is a full-time student at an educational institution, or is such a qualifying individual, to be gainfully employed and to have earned income of not less than—</text><subparagraph id="H288793D514C5459D96EF176281799079"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$250 if subsection (c)(1) applies for the taxable year, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C9161314D934FA6A696540744DC2238"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$500 if subsection (c)(2) applies for the taxable year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA09D4E93D724471989AE634C706D5B3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><paragraph id="H7F3708EAE065432BB43885AB974D6945"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any taxable year beginning after 2024, the dollar amounts in this section shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text><subparagraph id="H3C126BE6A1574003AFB7FB441CFA9B5B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD69247BCDB104A94A1C77517D50DF7C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2023</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EDF76AAD5C947B6876D1BAC935E8619"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>If any increase under paragraph (1) is not a multiple of $10, such increase shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $10.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H85F8CE594BE44232AA94F34BC0BC0E4D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Special rules</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H6BEB4605AE3947D7A76EBF9D752D669B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Place of abode</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual shall not be treated as having the same principal place of abode of the taxpayer if at any time during the taxable year of the taxpayer the relationship between the individual and the taxpayer is in violation of local law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5448FAF04B034516A4CFDD7EF91CF797"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Married couples must file joint return</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the taxpayer is married at the close of the taxable year, the credit shall be allowed under subsection (a) only if the taxpayer and his spouse file a joint return for the taxable year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H764E4D88601544669D8BAEF7F4F5A608"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Marital status</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual legally separated from his spouse under a decree of divorce or of separate maintenance shall not be considered as married.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H23140225079649FDB79121FA053F64D0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Certain married individuals living apart</header><text>If—</text><subparagraph id="H77DCBD4FA0994BE8933F58F312C4D136"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual who is married and who files a separate return—</text><clause id="H38238E03171E4490802A0E53BD3430BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>maintains as his home a household which constitutes for more than one-half of the taxable year the principal place of abode of a qualifying individual, and</text></clause><clause id="HCEE7D5452BEA4F08A849F7EC13084DFC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>furnishes over half of the cost of maintaining such household during the taxable year, and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H214E65E4E46F4916AC91BB06AE2A1F26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>during the last 6 months of such taxable year such individual’s spouse is not a member of such household,</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">such individual shall not be considered as married.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD5BC2D8C77B49528796E0DD6310D0BA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Special dependency test in case of divorced parents, etc</header><text>If—</text><subparagraph id="H4905ED2F8A764C1AAFCD6A6C3D494FDB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 152(e) applies to any child with respect to any calendar year, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D5D54B8366F4369869D23DC44C2EE2D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such child is under the age of 13 or is physically or mentally incapable of caring for himself,</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">in the case of any taxable year beginning in such calendar year, such child shall be treated as a qualifying individual described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (b)(1) (whichever is appropriate) with respect to the custodial parent (as defined in section 152(e)(4)(A)), and shall not be treated as a qualifying individual with respect to the noncustodial parent.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A607143CCCB4476915BBB7DDAA87808"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Payments to related individuals</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under subsection (a) for any amount paid by the taxpayer to an individual—</text><subparagraph id="H7222DC37E1894D92AEAE0E38E9B3DC93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to whom, for the taxable year, a deduction under section 151(c) (relating to deduction for personal exemptions for dependents) is allowable either to the taxpayer or his spouse, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H808FCDB400D84DEB990687CC889B1131"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who is a child of the taxpayer (within the meaning of section 152(f)(1)) who has not attained the age of 19 at the close of the taxable year.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>taxable year</term> means the taxable year of the taxpayer in which the service is performed.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC4C59A5A14F47949C5F66AECCB1EC7A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Student</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>student</term> means an individual who during each of 5 calendar months during the taxable year is a full-time student at an educational organization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB1962553029445CB1EA4A0D011328E0"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Educational organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>educational organization</term> means an educational organization described in section 170(b)(1)(A)(ii).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H467E3706D74C436397B5D07240F8A654"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Identifying information required with respect to service provider</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under subsection (a) for any amount paid to any person unless—</text><subparagraph id="HBACA6431F31A45D39AAAE0D62CC7EE18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name, address, and taxpayer identification number of such person are included on the return claiming the credit, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA43FC49BC0514299900F7D4EAABCDDF1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if such person is an organization described in section 501(c)(3) and exempt from tax under section 501(a), the name and address of such person are included on the return claiming the credit.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">In the case of a failure to provide the information required under the preceding sentence, the preceding sentence shall not apply if it is shown that the taxpayer exercised due diligence in attempting to provide the information so required.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFB36658D2DF420EB196E71723DE14D0"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Identifying information required with respect to qualifying individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No credit shall be allowed under this section with respect to any qualifying individual unless the TIN of such individual is included on the return claiming the credit.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C509743F184448D8FC5E811A47853AF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H952011C0CF754FA1A0BD6D7E50134AD5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="H7A48C31F1B954B198776E1540B9DBB19"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1324(b) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>36C,</quote> after <quote>36B,</quote>. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A8E086026C1490AB522CBFB6DC04B49"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart A of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by repealing section 21 and by striking the item relating to such section in the table of sections for such subpart.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFE551DE1ED045B0B95E2B2E5027FC1E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 45F(C)(1)(A)(iv) of such Code, as added by this Act, is amended by striking <quote>section 21(b)(1)(A)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 36C(b)(1)(A)</quote>. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CC0F38C135345E1A20089F7B368CBCE"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for subpart A of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by striking the item relating to section 21.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98FB05B6919B48ADB3BCF1128EF47C1F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6211(b)(4)(A) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>21 by reason of subsection (g) thereof,</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H45009048E1254CB48B7C5A03AA4C92DF"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6213(g)(2) of such Code is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H8BC5D431084945AEB93B090D3D635FC3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H), by striking <quote>section 21</quote> and inserting <quote>section 36C</quote>, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D13034B01164F24B90EC694D06EABC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (L)—</text><clause id="HD3B817B712CE4684939A1325A0770617"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>21,</quote>, and</text></clause><clause id="H8F24BA6126E642D7B52697787D91D6C1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>36C,</quote> after <quote>32,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H272234405A1E41008F24101F3F0CE415"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following sections of such Code are each amended by striking <quote>section 21(e)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 36C(e)</quote>.</text><subparagraph id="HF42C1BE37D2C459D911F7A8EE3A825EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 23(f)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FA2D1494A304BE19609E069A4092193"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 35(g)(6).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA820F4565DA432CAA349944B5D6BEA3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 129(a)(2)(C), as amended by this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA96B68C625F46E0BF2A2FE857FFC461"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 129 of such Code is further amended—</text><subparagraph id="HF7E00291F1724D3D96C34C773BC7B794"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2), by striking <quote>section 21(d)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 36C(d)(2)</quote>, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E84C9D4ED64482E91B33519AC7E0FC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(1), by striking <quote>section 21(b)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 36C(b)(2)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H83372C4558F84F1DB03260D6D59A2ADC"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 213(e) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>section 21</quote> and inserting <quote>section 36C</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H17669764D4AB4BFA924841919DEE0D90"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for subpart C of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 36B the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7D0AEE74B81F4AF4AAA25A7BB5E1E5A6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 36C. Expenses for household and dependent care services necessary for gainful employment.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H32008AD273E24B9F96524C12EE45E004"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

