<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LYN25094-CVW-HC-NP4"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1092 IS: Wastewater Infrastructure Pollution Prevention and Environmental Safety Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1092</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250324">March 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require certain products to be labeled with ‘Do Not Flush’ labeling, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H10FA998BFA9A413784665DCC6A0D77F7"><section section-type="section-one" id="H3C9629B2CBB54DE980652C685DA62B8D"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wastewater Infrastructure Pollution Prevention and Environmental Safety Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>WIPPES Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE7E81EAC4E5E4849ACA7E2A7D1D5E63E"><enum>2.</enum><header><quote>Do not flush</quote> labeling</header><subsection id="H4B51B63073E748E8B708131114113C5F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A covered entity shall label a covered product clearly and conspicuously with the label notice and symbol, in accordance with subsections (b) and (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="H7A052EBE07F64909A792223A19413C2B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><paragraph id="H79AC414F8D974F78BBCAC8295ACC2EBA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cylindrical packaging</header><text>In the case of a covered product sold in cylindrical or near-cylindrical packaging, and intended to dispense individual wipes—</text><subparagraph id="H0815A111D4FF470AA2C369590849087B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the symbol and label notice shall be displayed on the principal display panel in a clear and conspicuous location reasonably visible to the user each time a wipe is dispensed; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9EBDEA41F2A84789894B4D43FA046E31"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the symbol shall be displayed on the principal display panel and the label notice, or a combination of the label notice and symbol, shall be displayed on a flip lid in a manner that covers at least 8 percent of the surface area of the flip lid.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9027A2AC3AA48769E198F38F782CBFA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Flexible film packaging</header><text>In the case of a covered product sold in flexible film packaging, and intended to dispense individual wipes—</text><subparagraph id="H0D3E8AB92D024E13966164D7996B1E3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the symbol shall be displayed on the principal display panel and, if the principal display panel is not on the dispensing side of the packaging, on the dispensing side panel; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6AFEE3FABAA4F3F91CC633F7CD742E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the label notice shall be displayed on either the principal display panel or the dispensing side panel, in a clear and conspicuous location reasonably visible to the user each time a wipe is dispensed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4646BB0B13B4465CA0ADF87C8A620868"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rigid packaging</header><text>In the case of a covered product sold in a refillable tub or other rigid packaging that may be reused by a customer, and that is intended to dispense individual wipes, the symbol and label notice shall be displayed on the principal display panel in a clear and conspicuous location reasonably visible to the user each time a wipe is dispensed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71ACA160A3A44E11A6EFD4C1CE8FAD9B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Packaging not intended to dispense individual wipes</header><text>In the case of a covered product sold in packaging that is not intended to dispense individual wipes, the symbol and label notice shall be displayed on the principal display panel in a clear and conspicuous location reasonably visible to the user of the covered product.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A650228A92D4D94BE41BF3BE90E874E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Bulk packaging</header><subparagraph id="H407010FA5CB143A596EF209059A610F5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a covered product sold in bulk at retail, the symbol and label notice shall be displayed on both the outer packaging visible at retail and the individual packaging contained within the outer packaging.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20B67E0EF12E4D8D996F3EAE2AC8DD36"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>The following shall be exempt from the requirements of subparagraph (A):</text><clause id="H793A5A15353947018E269D0CCC5A3DEE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Individually packaged covered products that are contained within outer packaging, are not intended to dispense individual wipes, and have no retail labeling.</text></clause><clause id="H39C89C5ABE4A46209A3D50CB0A573BA0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Outer packaging that does not obscure the symbol and label notice on individually packaged covered products contained within.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB85D344D56647F5B6AB071CCE06B8B5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Packaging of combined products</header><subparagraph id="H315F481F1A7A408E8CB5A94E6EA5CCAD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Outer packaging</header><text>The outer packaging of combined products shall be exempt from the symbol and label notice requirements of subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FF0E6C5A9DB4DBCA7C675AA7ED29EF5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Packages less than 3 by 3 inches</header><text>In the case of a covered product in packaging smaller than 3 inches by 3 inches (such as an individually packaged wipe in tear-top packaging) and sold as part of a combined product, if a symbol and label notice are placed in a prominent location reasonably visible to the user of the covered product, such covered product shall be considered to be labeled clearly and conspicuously.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF66B722E0C2D4825BB7C01FB2E180BBE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reasonable visibility of symbol and label notice</header><paragraph id="H0AAEFF89A7F34D73B3742F76E3345C49"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered entity shall ensure that—</text><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5215B613E7ED4C868D9B35E18E257015"><enum>(A)</enum><text>packaging seams or folds or other packaging design elements do not obscure the symbol or label notice;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H864905103C864CBCA513EF011FAA278E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the symbol and label notice are each equal in size to at least 2 percent of the surface area of the principal display panel; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EDCF69534FA457C852EC23B8620ED9A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the symbol and label notice have high contrast with the immediate background of the packaging so that such symbol and label notice may be seen and read by an ordinary individual under customary conditions of purchase and use.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H725D555C6B5D4C9D978250E66C4F7D17"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Proximity of symbol and label notice</header><text>A covered entity may display a symbol and label notice either adjacent to or on separate areas of the principal display panel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H195CD987C6714EAE8B59F56A64C72F66"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Paragraph (1)(C) does not apply to an embossed symbol or label notice on the flip lid of a covered product sold in cylindrical or near-cylindrical packaging.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H459E30B8E8C64C83BC802839CF6CE6FE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Representations of flushability</header><text>With respect to a covered product, a covered entity may not make any express or implied representation that such covered product can or should be flushed.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3F2F082C8CF7426FB8BA9EB0DF11D12D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header><paragraph id="HAB69707F506A4F9796D70BD90E6BD111"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of this section or any regulation promulgated under this section shall be treated as a violation of a regulation under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE8D07720B7A47E4A592EF2E18C161EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><text>The Commission shall enforce this section and any regulations promulgated under this section by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties, as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section, and any person who violates this section or any regulation promulgated under this section shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5EF3BB800144F0E9143A14900D8675C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Commission may promulgate regulations under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, to implement this section. In developing the regulations, the Commission may consult with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, the Consumer Product Safety Commission, or any other agency as appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F090055FC6A4E4DA3277DE9AA9FD883"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H16227F05F4FC48C99E2BCD9528ABA7FA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Preemption of State laws</header><text>No State or political subdivision of a State may directly or indirectly establish or continue in effect, under any authority, requirements with respect to the <quote>Do Not Flush</quote> labeling of covered products that are not identical to the requirements of this section and the regulations promulgated under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA8233C9C7F6B4C5DBF28DA44A95E96C7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HC3ECD7FEE0B24D2CBFB88208F8A9779F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Combined product</header><text>The term <quote>combined product</quote> means two or more products sold in shared retail packaging, of which—</text><subparagraph id="HE988C450B94542959DB68D18B1811D69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at least one of the products is a covered product; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFB4B4AA0BAC426CBCCBB49F975E1821"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at least one of the products is another consumer product intended to be used in combination with such covered product.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCBD4FA8B82B4C95A9415670937C86D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <quote>Commission</quote> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0518B186FB5341AE8C339243CBF24D19"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>The term <quote>covered entity</quote> means a manufacturer, wholesaler, supplier, individual or group of individuals, or retailer that is responsible for the labeling or retail packaging of a covered product that is sold or offered for retail sale in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H489F4E39D6834507843F7A3F11C1A100"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered product</header><subparagraph id="HAA974385453D45D2AE25FDC06D3445A7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>covered product</quote> means a premoistened, nonwoven disposable wipe sold or offered for retail sale—</text><clause id="H7F70D720AE8C431FBC961802A11AF981"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that is marketed as a baby wipe or diapering wipe; or</text></clause><clause id="H1C5D93B12E444F8681844093BC16165A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that is a household or personal care wipe (including a wipe described in subparagraph (B)) that—</text><subclause id="H49DB10D5BF274B84818C40E8F654C0F4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is composed entirely, or in part, of petrochemical-derived fibers; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H086DE3E1C62A48528F30E199DBC26436"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has significant potential to be flushed.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3B703F911194659B8E7181F4DCF6EA4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The wipes described in this subparagraph are—</text><clause id="HA72F2FEFE2BD48829EEE600DFA0EAC93"><enum>(i)</enum><text>antibacterial wipes and disinfecting wipes;</text></clause><clause id="H7BD735289DB547F5B8797A82BBE30087"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>wipes intended for general purpose cleaning or bathroom cleaning, including toilet cleaning and hard surface cleaning; and</text></clause><clause id="H5E761E4D20384D57B38900AFAF158D91"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>wipes intended for personal care use on the body, including hand sanitizing, makeup removal, feminine hygiene, adult hygiene (including incontinence hygiene), and body cleansing.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H371FE31485AE48DBAED548D879011EDE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>High contrast</header><text>The term <quote>high contrast</quote> means, with respect to the symbol or label notice, that such symbol or label notice—</text><subparagraph id="H17DC626AF8DD438E9557CED0A123CC75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is either light on a solid dark background or dark on a solid light background; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AA9C74EEBD54FF18A90C82F64F4DA0B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has a contrast percentage of at least 70 percent between such symbol or label notice and the background, using the formula (B1–B2)/B1 * 100 = contrast percentage, where B1 is the light reflectance value of the lighter area and B2 is the light reflectance value of the darker area.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8048EDF7B11E4670BF90CA484986A534"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Label notice</header><text>The term <quote>label notice</quote> means the written phrase <quote>Do Not Flush</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDA1A5D070BF45BAA0E906A4F06E914B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Principal display panel</header><text>The term <quote>principal display panel</quote> means the side of a product package that is most likely to be displayed, presented, or shown under customary conditions of display for retail sale, and—</text><subparagraph id="H44478B11C8BD4A30BCA7818000A66A6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a cylindrical or near-cylindrical package, the surface area of which constitutes at least 40 percent of the product package, as measured by multiplying the height by the circumference of the package; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B7CAD05A3FD4DBA999B55834E5FE590"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a flexible film package in which a rectangular prism or near-rectangular prism stack of wipes is housed within the film, the surface area of which is measured by multiplying the length by the width of the side of the package when the flexible packaging film is pressed flat against the stack of wipes on all sides of the stack.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2166E6DE872A47E3AD75CCD85004CEE4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>State</quote> means each State of the United States, the District of Columbia, and each commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB3C26B8E36C486D8B5E6ADACACE8C20"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Symbol</header><text>The term <quote>symbol</quote> means the <quote>Do Not Flush</quote> symbol, as depicted in the most recent edition of the Guidelines for Assessing the Flushability of Disposable Nonwoven Products published by the Association of the Nonwoven Fabrics Industry (INDA) and the European Disposables And Nonwovens Association (EDANA), or an otherwise equivalent symbol adopted by the Commission through rulemaking under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE771E476D94F417B8985E48842E2FDC8"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall apply to a covered entity beginning on the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

