<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25026-H4V-47-6XD"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S680 IS: Ending China's Unfair Advantage Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 680</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250220">February 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit funding for the Montreal Protocol on Substances that Deplete the Ozone Layer and the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change until China is no longer defined a developing country.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ending China's Unfair Advantage Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idE3A7F6B67FA6475EB624A48332C0713E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id5E9AE34DBF0746598881591D9047DCD6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idAD6ACF0CBEB34F7DA56884244ABF2CFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id72e6391ff66342078920780a234200e7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id58174A62C4B249BA869CE5552790EC6A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49f60d62e08c40719b3e127b0ac9b6d6"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idCF73C8FFCBB344A9BE3CD0F39928D09B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Montreal Protocol</header><text>The term <term>Montreal Protocol</term> means the Montreal Protocol on Substances that Deplete the Ozone Layer, done at Montreal September 16, 1987. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9631976f716449acb8292c32100f5447" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change</header><text>The term <term>United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change</term> means the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, adopted in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil in June 1992. </text></paragraph></section><section id="id228B24FEB0D243F6986FFDFEC0C1D924"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds for the Montreal Protocol on Substances that Deplete the Ozone Layer until China is no longer defined as a developing country</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no Federal funds may be obligated or expended to implement the Montreal Protocol, including its protocols and amendments, or any fund established under the Protocol, until the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the Parties to the Montreal Protocol have amended their Decision I/12E, <quote>Clarification of terms and definitions: developing countries,</quote> made at the First Meeting of the Parties to remove the People's Republic of China. </text></section><section id="id74E4261DF87E438EA97F5F9D3833BC57"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds for the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change until China is included among the countries listed in Annex I of the Convention</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no Federal funds may be obligated or expended to fund the operations and meetings of the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, including it protocols or agreements, or any fund established under the Convention or its agreements, until the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the Parties to the Framework Convention have included the People’s Republic of China in Annex I of the Convention. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

