<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H7354A7AE361B474F99FE9ACAB0279C4A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1450 RH: OFAC Licensure for Investigators Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 34</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1450</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–47, Part I]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250221">February 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Office of Foreign Assets Control to develop a program under which private sector firms may receive a license to conduct nominal financial transactions in furtherance of the firms’ investigations, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="HB53E268F02FA4505A490E1D9FFF9D31E" style="OLC"><section id="HDBFF13B4B82A4F8FA5440C2BFB2867BE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>OFAC Licensure for Investigators Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4FC847E0428D42BE94049A2C4113C729"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sending and receiving of nominal amounts</header><subsection id="HDD282A07396343B8BE6CD9DC797525FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Foreign Assets Control shall, not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, establish a pilot program under which a private sector firm may receive a license to conduct nominal financial transactions in furtherance of the firm’s investigations.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5350417BA53E4D0EB4EA385FC734C13A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When establishing and carrying out the pilot program required under subsection (a), the Director of the Office of Foreign Assets Control shall coordinate with the Director of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network for the purposes of supporting activities of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network Exchange, as described in section 310(d) of title 31 of the United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0A0D8A501756479F9FC8B3BE92532B7F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting on activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each private sector firm that receives a license described under subsection (a) shall submit a detailed monthly report to the Director of the Office of Foreign Assets Control on the activities of the firm conducted under such license.</text></subsection><subsection id="H164667E99CEA42D282FA2527FFD2986D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><paragraph id="HD9B3B1BFA81742ACB78ACB67C97ABB15"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the date that is 1 year after the date on which the pilot program is established under this section, and annually thereafter until the end of the 1-year period beginning on the date the pilot program is terminated, the Director of the Office of Foreign Assets Control shall submit a report to the Committees on Financial Services and Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and Foreign Relations of the Senate containing—</text><subparagraph id="H25C72EBC5B6948E399C6BDD202A4D5C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of licenses requested under the pilot program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC69B480090BD4A4CB5A79CB6F104D1D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of licenses granted under the pilot program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6116AE837D654C039B2049055EB1AD99"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a broad discussion of the utility of the pilot program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9099A6C3BAF4B7EA327C38B983A387C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Classified briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After submission of each report required under paragraph (1), the Director of the Office of Foreign Assets Control shall provide the Committees on Financial Services and Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and Foreign Relations of the Senate with a classified briefing containing—</text><subparagraph id="HD162CA9C87DC4BA8A1C9AEF8ACF9F9A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>additional detail on the applicants for a license under the pilot program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B6D1B0948434D028C716AF599E0FC64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identification of the firms granted a license;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35DD525328974A33A1FC3DBCADCD2C56"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information on the operation of the pilot program, including how long each license lasted and the personnel needed to manage the pilot program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A0D2238EF534F74B6B0B62B34E3E4FC"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information gleaned by the Office of Foreign Assets Control from running the pilot program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE10E02075BBA4483942595C14F4672FD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the utility of that information;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D84DA70B9EE41379553AB7E677FD388"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any obstacles to the operation or utility of the pilot program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC369D94CF23B4F8B9ACCAFD246323212"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any recommendations for improving or extending the pilot program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2F5307EDC8324A4F9FECF858C5A3FD9A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The pilot program established by the Director of the Office of Foreign Assets Control under subsection (a) shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date on which the Director of the Office of Foreign Assets Control establishes such program.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

