<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD8D27C3B2A8B4D4AABF495BCEA31F36D" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 303 IH: Recognizing that members and affiliates of Tren de Aragua are alien enemies perpetrating an invasion of the United States and affirming that the President is exercising his constitutional authority to repel that invasion.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 303</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001317">Mr. Brecheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing that members and affiliates of Tren de Aragua are alien enemies perpetrating an invasion of the United States and affirming that the President is exercising his constitutional authority to repel that invasion.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas article II of the United States Constitution vests Executive power to the President of the United States, and establishes the President as Commander in Chief of the Armed Forces;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Alien Enemies Act of 1798 was enacted by Congress and signed into law to give the President of the United States the authority to repel an alien invasion of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas invocation of the Alien Enemies Act of 1798 is an exercise of the President’s authorities as Commander in Chief;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Alien Enemies Act of 1798 states: <quote>Whenever there shall be a declared war between the United States and any foreign nation or government, or any invasion or predatory incursion shall be perpetrated, attempted, or threatened against the territory of the United States, by any foreign nation or government, and the President of the United States shall make public proclamation of the event, all natives, citizens, denizens, or subjects of the hostile nation or government, being males of the age of fourteen years and upwards, who shall be within the United States, and not actually naturalized, shall be liable to be apprehended, restrained, secured and removed, as alien enemies</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, at the time the Alien Enemies Act was enacted, the term <quote>invasion</quote> was understood to include actions by non-state actors, as confirmed by James Madison’s comments at the Virginia Ratifying Convention for the United States Constitution and definitions in Webster’s 1806 and 1828 dictionaries, and the term <quote>government</quote> was understood to include the institutions for governing non-state organizations, the Alien Enemies Act can be invoked in response to invasions by non-state actors;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on 20 January 2025, President Donald J. Trump issued <quote>Designating Cartels And Other Organizations As Foreign Terrorist Organizations And Specially Designated Global Terrorists,</quote> designating Tren De Aragua as a foreign terrorist organization;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Executive order further details Tren De Aragua’s <quote>campaigns of violence and terror in the United States and internationally are extraordinarily violent, vicious, and similarly threaten the stability of the international order in the Western Hemisphere;</quote></text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas 20-year-old nursing student Laken Hope Riley’s assailant, who was convicted of murdering and attempting to sexually assault her, was a confirmed Tren de Aragua member;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the 2 Venezuelan illegal aliens charged with murdering and sexually assaulting 12-year-old Jocelyn Nungaray on June 16, 2024, are believed to have ties to Tren de Aragua;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas law enforcement has confirmed Tren de Aragua taking over apartment complexes at gunpoint across the United States, including Aurora, Colorado and San Antonio, Texas;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, in March 2024, more than 100 suspected Tren de Aragua members were arrested for their involvement in charging at National Guardsmen and Department of Public Safety troopers at the El Paso border;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, in June 2024, a Tren de Aragua member was charged with shooting and injuring New York City Police Department officers Cristopher Abreu and Richard Yarusso after they tried to lawfully detain him;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, on July 30, 2024, United States Border Patrol issued a bulletin warning that Tren de Aragua gave the <quote>green light</quote> to its over 1,000 members to fire on and attack law enforcement;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, as of March 2025, Tren de Aragua is present in at least 19 States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on March 15, 2025, President Donald J. Trump issued <quote>Invocation of the Alien Enemies Act Regarding the Invasion of The United States by Tren de Aragua</quote>, a proclamation that finds and declares that Tren de Aragua is <quote>perpetrating, attempting, and threatening an invasion or predatory incursion against the territory of the United States</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the proclamation further details and declares that Tren de Aragua is <quote>undertaking hostile actions and conducting irregular warfare against the territory of the United States both directly and at the direction, clandestine or otherwise, of the Maduro regime in Venezuela</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the 118th Congress, more than 80 Members of Congress sponsored or cosponsored legislation stating that the mass illegal immigration brought on by the open-border policies of the Biden administration constituted an invasion of the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the removal of alien enemies engaged in an invasion of the United States is necessary for the safety of the American people, and is a proper exercise of the Executive power of the President of the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H8971E40910F44BD6B2EFFB032E1D77AD"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H6AFE6F48AF964811982CA37363463C57"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HF0DC667A60674236BC9E6DACEE23C586"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes that Tren de Aragua is a terrorist organization perpetrating an invasion of the United States directly and at the direction of a foreign government;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5342BEEF573E4604BD126A17005EE34D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes that members and affiliates of Tren de Aragua are alien enemies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC166A649115C43F5B8097BA71197FDBB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes and affirms that the President is exercising his Constitutional and legal authority to repel an invasion of alien enemies by apprehending, restraining, securing, and removing members and affiliates of Tren de Aragua from the United States of America.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

