<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6AC1EAC319B544268AADAA492645EA54" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 41 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the month of January, as “Tamil Language and Heritage Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 41</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250114">January 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the month of January, as <quote>Tamil Language and Heritage Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Tamil is one of the longest-surviving classical languages in the world, with a traceable history exceeding 2,600 years;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the recent archaeological excavations at Keeladi in Tamil Nadu, India, have uncovered evidence of a well-developed urban civilization dating back to the 3d century BCE;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tamil is an official language in 3 countries and spoken by over 80,000,000 people worldwide, with approximately 360,000 Tamil speakers in the United States as of 2023;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Tamil community celebrates the Pongal Festival each year in mid-January, marking the Tamil month of <quote>Thai</quote> and celebrating the harvest, cattle, and Tamil arts, contributing to the vibrant cultural diversity of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tamil people, culture, tradition, and language have impacted many aspects of the economic, social, and cultural history of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas esteemed Tamil literary works, including the <quote>Thirukkural</quote>, <quote>Tholkappiyam</quote>, <quote>Aganaanuru</quote>, <quote>Puranaanuru</quote>, <quote>Silappatikaram</quote>, and <quote>Manimegalai</quote>, embody enduring values that inspire Tamil culture and enrich global heritage;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these literary works can be read and interpreted by modern-day Tamil people, have been translated into more than 100 languages, and their values remain relevant to contemporary life;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas recognizing January as <quote>Tamil Language and Heritage Month</quote> allows the people of the United States to celebrate the rich history, language, and culture of the Tamil people and encourages all Americans to learn about the contributions of Tamil Americans to the cultural fabric of the Nation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas States such as Michigan, Georgia, and Massachusetts have made proclamations to celebrate the cultural contributions of the Tamil people; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas States such as North Carolina, Wisconsin, Virginia, and Minnesota have recognized January as Tamil Heritage Month, reflecting the growing appreciation of Tamil culture across the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HD7781FBF540E4D2880983A73BAB3CB8A"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H9657C37482514742BF6FFD8CE8AD7257"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HA3E130D1F7C54E5D9B2B77C223C4F11E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>Tamil Language and Heritage Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72F2B307F27E4753A4FEFF2108AD0A49"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes that Tamil Americans enhance the rich diversity of and strengthens the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF923C30748E24499964695B9BC4B55B6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>acknowledges the significance of Pongal, a festive celebration of harvest, for the Tamil people.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

