<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H47DB0A3358FE48588F2639B108395E30" public-private="public" resolution-type="constitutional-amendment" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HJ 5 IH: Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to limit the number of terms an individual may serve as a Member of Congress.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 5</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250103">January 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>) submitted the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to limit the number of terms an individual may serve as a Member of Congress.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="constitutional-amendment" id="HA1D3192C542B4ACD8F452F8C2EDA3D79"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H9A0D6D55144040B0A2E48D8968AB2EA2"><text>That the following article is proposed as an amendment to the Constitution of the United States, which shall be valid to all intents and purposes as part of the Constitution when ratified by the legislatures of three-fourths of the several States within seven years after the date of its submission for ratification: </text><quoted-block style="traditional" id="H26F47BE4B7BE425FA5651A72B34085A3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><constitution-article id="H0B4B8016D15F4410BBE9B4A1160DF04D"><enum> —</enum><section id="H3C95B035B4B446C08CC1B8FAA6E69BA4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person shall serve as a Representative for more than six two-year terms. Service as a Representative for more than one year of any two-year term shall be treated as a complete term for purposes of this section, without regard to whether the service was completed by the individual originally elected to the term.</text></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A95E2F75E254CC7B4A98DF274B57A05" section-type="section-one"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person shall serve as a Senator for more than two six-year terms. Service as a Senator for more than three years of any six-year term shall be treated as a complete term for purposes of this section, without regard to whether the service was completed by the individual originally elected to the term.</text></section><section id="HAEAD0742235444DAB11863BD32ABB829" section-type="section-one"><enum>3.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This article shall not apply to any person who served as a Representative or as a Senator during any Congress occurring before the One Hundred Eighteenth Congress.</text></section></constitution-article><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

