<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL25A09-SMM-F4-R6X"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2441 IS: Build Now Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2441</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250724">July 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S389">Mr. Kennedy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on
                    Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for adjustments to community development block grant allocations
 based on improvements in housing growth rates.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Build Now Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idb6595fbc62e04d50bf37b3926b21bf76"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id1557c043d1bc4dfcb88fe5d96224b46e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered recipient</header><text>The term <term>covered recipient</term> means a metropolitan city or urban county, as those terms are defined in section 102 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5302">42 U.S.C. 5302</external-xref>), that receives funds under section 106.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide68b2e6f83ec41c58443e697443ccdc0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Current annual growth rate</header><text>The term <term>current annual growth rate</term>, with respect to an eligible recipient and a fiscal year, means the average annual percentage increase in the number of housing units in the jurisdiction of the eligible recipient, as calculated by the Secretary, during the period—</text><subparagraph id="ida5ce27883e11465695cd1039c84c8dc4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>beginning with the third quarter of the sixth preceding fiscal year; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc00255d3801c4e2ba7d8245ea6c59800"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ending with the third quarter of the preceding fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2368589a5f4042a098c1dc8fa892847a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible recipient</header><text>The term <term>eligible recipient</term> means any covered recipient unless—</text><subparagraph id="id490e3a1f9ae547c8be29b2094b1175d9"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idc5b7683680514c73ba1f3c728c7b5a83"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the median Small Area Fair Market Rent in the jurisdiction of the covered recipient is at or below the 60th percentile of median Small Area Fair Market Rents in the jurisdictions of all covered recipients; and</text></clause><clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7acefa63d6ce413e859fdd31757182a7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the median home value in the jurisdiction of the covered recipient is below the median home value for the United States;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec25fe59e2fa49bca7fa5a25af3e68f0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the annual natural rental vacancy rate in the jurisdiction of the covered recipient is greater than the national annual natural rental vacancy rate for the most recent year available, as published by the Bureau of the Census;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7acb6772e6984c42976e24b815b085e5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>during the 1-year period preceding the date on which the Secretary allocates funds under section 106, the jurisdiction of the covered recipient has been the subject of a major disaster or emergency declaration under section 401 or 501, respectively, of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>, 5191); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb818089388384866aa1526b9e6ceb859"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the covered recipient lacks the legal authority to enact or update zoning and permitting ordinances.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8d5ec59b94034f7baab3c3a5d2c60d3d" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Extremely high-growth recipient</header><text>The term <term>extremely high-growth recipient</term> means an eligible recipient for which the current annual growth rate is at or above 4 percent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idef1981c66611426fba98db7ed11aadc4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Housing growth improvement rate</header><text>The term <term>housing growth improvement rate</term>, with respect to an eligible recipient and a fiscal year, means the quotient of—</text><subparagraph id="ide02ca532600d4d209ed5e1640aba4444"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the current annual growth rate of the eligible recipient; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id90319d4529b842889c6bbf6a375e38cc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the prior annual growth rate of the eligible recipient.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5a2e3efc24a64a2fa18e15ed9f0f0c9b"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Prior annual growth rate</header><text>The term <term>prior annual growth rate</term>, with respect to an eligible recipient and a fiscal year, means the average annual percentage increase in the number of housing units in the jurisdiction of the eligible recipient, as calculated by the Secretary, during the period—</text><subparagraph id="id75a34365aa394f64aa6ce9c2711f1ced"><enum>(A)</enum><text>beginning with the third quarter of the 11th preceding fiscal year; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4249df17c82d41c1b9499cbff2292750"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ending with the third quarter of the sixth preceding fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id794fa55403574b86929b1ce5a408c39a"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3639a2997dcf4d679991caa601348918"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Section 106</header><text>The term <term>section 106</term> means section 106 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5306">42 U.S.C. 5306</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="id62a4a0ac2fca4b728be6c9051ce23334"><enum>3.</enum><header>Adjustments to community development block grant allocations</header><subsection id="id5f567364a6be4a608fa1e28ff6e645a8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In allocating amounts to an eligible recipient under section 106 for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall adjust the allocation based on the housing growth improvement rate of the eligible recipient, in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7472e6be4dd748dfa7445e1360b8b20d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adjustments</header><paragraph id="idb3a2252e72ea4b53bc0c37616fc8af19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Housing growth improvement rate at or above median; extremely
 high-growth recipients</header><subparagraph id="id07d1537bd9ce4cf48aa1feed855734fa"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If, with respect to a fiscal year for which the allocation under section 106 is being determined, the housing growth improvement rate for an eligible recipient is at or above the median housing growth improvement rate for all eligible recipients other than extremely high-growth recipients, or if an eligible recipient is an extremely high-growth recipient, the Secretary shall allocate to the eligible recipient for that fiscal year, in addition to the amount that would otherwise be allocated to the eligible recipient under section 106, a bonus amount, as determined under subparagraph (B) of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id01f4c066d7244363b151eb1a3a390d20"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Bonus amount</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the bonus amount for an eligible recipient for a fiscal year shall be equal to the product of—</text><clause id="id3bf7980c6cce40db961e2dae33f3386f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the aggregate amount by which allocations to eligible recipients are decreased under paragraph (2) for that fiscal year; and</text></clause><clause id="id1145f6329f1c4f598ade4bfb0ae8d58c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the quotient of—</text><subclause id="id9cf4e4c0a648451da39e1913fe0e4ced"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of housing units, as of the third quarter of the preceding fiscal year, in the jurisdiction of the eligible recipient, as calculated by the Secretary; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idf13afefb07cb4eec8e2c73626870813a"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of housing units, as of the third quarter of the preceding fiscal year, in the jurisdictions of all eligible recipients that receive a bonus amount under this paragraph, as calculated by the Secretary.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idaf2662ef9171498db3af5195c4f777b8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Housing growth improvement rate below median</header><text>If, with respect to a fiscal year for which the allocation under section 106 is being determined, the housing growth improvement rate for an eligible recipient is below the median housing growth improvement rate for all eligible recipients other than high-growth outliers, the Secretary shall decrease the amount that would otherwise be allocated to the eligible recipient under section 106 for that fiscal year by 10 percent.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id57d341e552d24adfb272811f82731607"><enum>4.</enum><header>Calculation of housing units</header><subsection id="id8bb11aefef334573b16c608eaadafd21"><enum>(a)</enum><header>H<enum-in-header>UD</enum-in-header> requirements</header><text>In calculating the number of housing units in the jurisdiction of an eligible recipient under any provision of this Act, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="id63bd7d8ffb644f83b7c4ca76c30a48ca"><enum>(1)</enum><text>use the Current Address Count Listing Files and other data products, as needed, of the Bureau of the Census tabulated from the Master Address File; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1c6b05d928514cbb8bf35b7646c3e42b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make calculations at the block level, using boundaries that reflect the most current boundaries.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5c65979259fd4a5ea3175fc41c89860a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Census Bureau and Postal Service Requirements</header><text>The Bureau of the Census and the United States Postal Service shall provide any relevant data to the Secretary upon request to assist the Secretary in making a calculation described in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="idf321395d4b75412797d735d11675124a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Adjustment of calculation periods</header><text>The Secretary may adjust the calculation periods under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 2(2), subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 2(6), and subclauses (I) and (II) of section 3(b)(1)(B)(ii) by not more than 2 months to achieve alignment with the data provided by the Bureau of the Census.</text></subsection></section><section id="idd1aa2f9f25e44cfa9046c76c45f93126"><enum>5.</enum><header>Annual report on housing growth improvement rate</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Before allocating funds under section 106 for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall publish a report that—</text><paragraph id="ida0ef19adb3ac4f0291620651ee309d62"><enum>(1)</enum><text>includes the housing growth improvement rate for each eligible recipient; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id83577125a13344e9819bf47b8f0ab771"><enum>(2)</enum><text>lists, for the most recent fiscal year for which allocations were made under section 106—</text><subparagraph id="id3f1ee664872d42fd825ef5c0a347874c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the eligible recipients that received a bonus amount under section 3(b)(1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id04e5046123d543b1b001f620f4d588cb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the eligible recipients for which the allocation under section 106 was decreased under section 3(b)(2) of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id9395f1fa17ad466f8d0b1cd64d83f076"><enum>6.</enum><header>Notification; implementation dates</header><subsection id="id56da7b656d7a436db433d60c6b5b2039"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notification</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id873e143b18c24872b8c73db5a34a9433"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall notify each eligible recipient of the recipient's housing growth improvement rate and whether that housing growth improvement rate is above, at, or below the median housing growth improvement rate for all eligible recipients other than extremely high-growth recipients.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4e142acaf59149098988a44263e45479" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>As part of the notification under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall share guidance, including resources developed by the Department of Housing and Urban Development, on best practices and recommendations on policies to reduce regulatory barriers to housing and increase housing supply.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5a17e86d51434ef197d07d90c307191f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation dates</header><text>Section 3 shall take effect beginning with the second full fiscal year after the date of enactment of this Act and remain in effect through fiscal year 2042.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


