<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-NEW25828-S15-GC-5C1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 414 ATS: Designating September 2025 as “National Child Awareness Month” to promote awareness of charities that benefit children as well as youth-serving organizations throughout the United States and recognizing the efforts made by those charities and organizations on behalf of children and youth as critical contributions to the future of the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 414</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250919" legis-day="20250916">September 19 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating September 2025 as <quote>National Child Awareness Month</quote> to promote awareness of charities that benefit children as well as youth-serving organizations throughout the United States and recognizing the efforts made by those charities and organizations on behalf of children and youth as critical contributions to the future of the United States.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the millions of children and youth in the United States represent the hopes and the future of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas numerous individuals, charities benefitting children, and youth-serving organizations that work with children and youth collaborate to provide invaluable services to enrich and better the lives of children and youth throughout the United States; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas raising awareness of and increasing support for organizations that provide access to health care, social services, education, the arts, sports, and other services will result in the development of character in, and the future success of, the children and youth of the United States; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the month of September, as the school year begins, is a time when parents, families, teachers, school administrators, and communities increase the focus on children and youth throughout the United States; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the month of September is a time for the people of the United States to highlight and be mindful of the needs of children and youth; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas private corporations and businesses have joined with hundreds of national and local charitable organizations throughout the United States in support of a month-long focus on children and youth; and </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas a long-term commitment to children and youth is in the public interest and will encourage widespread support for charities and organizations that seek to provide a better future for the children and youth of the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate designates September 2025 as <quote>National Child Awareness Month</quote>—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id970e29fac4e24b0d9780d7408edd3fb4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to promote awareness of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6cc25b7895024c4c89fe8b450581c4f5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">charities that benefit children; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5bda466d413c4539a10f756a021f39cf"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">youth-serving organizations throughout the United States; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4458564c612c49ec844b840b3186cc45"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to recognize the efforts made by the charities and organizations described in paragraph (1) on behalf of children and youth as critical contributions to the future of the United States; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07965f6999024f378acee8f9932c655b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to recognize the importance of meeting the needs of children and youth, including children and youth who—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id518f4aae12ac45909bc167343e5c55cd"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have experienced homelessness; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id256b267600ea49a9b65a9e981b71f30d"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are in the foster care system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1f0495a422bf4acebd7129c682ac642a"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have been victims, or are at risk of becoming victims, of child sex trafficking;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idde26b0758ec74608a71bccb6f0e5a8fe"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have been impacted by violence; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9b58341aaa9d470d8e9fef921b2a7302"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have experienced trauma; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddd0b3cd603264b8fa7bde6452b93cfde"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have serious physical and mental health needs. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

