<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR25548-F2V-1S-7XJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1701 IS: Strategic Teams for Organized Response Mobilization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1701</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250508">May 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To permit the use of health care workforce platforms during declared emergencies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strategic Teams for Organized Response Mobilization Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STORM Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7b79ca9e194d4962912f1aab7296faed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Use of health care workforce platforms during state of emergency</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title V of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5191">42 U.S.C. 5191 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD6F818C83E6D46698622E5D6A09E4912"><section id="idd05f101114284b948369f24e3013d3b7"><enum>504.</enum><header>Health care workforce platforms</header><subsection id="id9b99597405364829b6d07c3d0e843390"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="idC9D59371BA1E48428A4D86675B1EBD56"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Emergency</header><text>The term <term>emergency</term> means an emergency declared under section 501.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id419DCE4654444180A7979DBDBF931817"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Health care workforce platform</header><text>The term <term>health care workforce platform</term> means a private entity technology platform that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf4d70e64926747ca8101aa69c81268a6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>partners with credentialed independent contractor health care workers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id549a4b9fb1f1406db4eba59c43acf0c5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has the capability to facilitate health care workforce surge capacity during an emergency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7c27dd27ddbd463cae9fcaf2ad080cba"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is self-sustaining during times other than those in which an emergency is declared.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB3C2BB397CAB43DD8C2C4DE34EAB368F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Independent contractor health care worker</header><text>The term <term>independent contractor health care worker</term> means a health care professional who—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23DD986475884838A9B831377AC7FB0F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>holds a valid license to practice as a health care professional in not less than 1 State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBE0F805FBABE47B79D5245D37DE0F31E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides health care services on a contractual basis, rather than as an employee of a health care facility or organization;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3B10985C24C3478E89BA72AEB0D90B6E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is credentialed and verified by a health care workforce platform; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9981FD6BEA4C4684917B668C8F8A8DA6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is engaged to respond to health care needs during an emergency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ideba41b46f18f4fa39ea96d991a7cd1d5"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Public-Private partnership</header> <paragraph id="idA0A5FB524AC24E6AA48236EEACCAC23D"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Certification</header> <text>The President may certify health care workforce platforms as eligible to enter into an agreement under paragraph (2).</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id477B9F0E923B46FA9583932A44925A4D">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Voluntary agreements</header>
              <subparagraph id="id76F0B4E3356A42568CFCAC96A1A5C4FB">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>The President may enter into an agreement with a health care workforce platform certified under paragraph (1) under which the President may use the health care workforce platform for the duration of any emergency declared during the term of the agreement.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="id544D8AD3A3DE4AF089341325DDE99F9E">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <header>Term</header>
 <text>The duration of the term of an agreement entered into under subparagraph (A) shall be not less than 1 year.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="id96c0674ae92348fdbfa204e35dd03885"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Facilitation of State licensure waivers</header><paragraph id="idA0FC67D6D30A4E4887104D2C9118FF1D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During any emergency, the President may coordinate with States to facilitate a waiver of licensure requirements of the State for out-of-state independent contractor health care workers responding to an emergency through a health care workforce platform with which the President has entered into an agreement under subsection (b)(2) if—</text><subparagraph id="ida8e292d1635140008542c1f7f0f4940d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the services of the independent contractor health care worker are being used by the President or the State or a local government affected by the emergency for the purpose of responding to the emergency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id444ec9658d194549b34f5feb7b20d049"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the independent contractor health care worker holds a valid license to practice as a health care worker in not less than 1 State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide832e8594b784cb4b88f6db621e744b0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedures and criteria</header><text>The President shall establish model procedures and criteria for the waiver of State licensure requirements under paragraph (1) that a State affected by an emergency may adopt at the time of the emergency that—</text><subparagraph id="id810C2021A00347DFA343AE6217E8DB6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include requirements that independent contractor health care workers demonstrate qualifications and undergo background checks;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFF74F6CE29004669A35535774FEA64CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prioritize the expedited deployment of qualified independent contractor health care workers to areas affected by an emergency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id49F486F2A89F467180950B8C7E5A3ABB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may rely on vetting of independent contractor health care workers by a health care workforce platform with which the President has entered into an agreement under subsection (b)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1596f373b86d4cd5a08c711d64b6a08f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination with State authorities</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the President shall—</text><subparagraph id="idA0816AD4F475498381D5FD9785F42290"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coordinate with relevant State authorities to ensure the efficient implementation of licensure waivers or temporary licenses; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD47229E8758D40AF9D3571D57B75683B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consider State-specific regulations and requirements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbeb3ac5aa1434be48ff8f42f44be71db"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Strategic Teams for Organized Response Mobilization Act</short-title>, and annually thereafter, the President shall submit to Congress a report on the use of State licensure waivers during emergencies under this section, including—</text><paragraph id="idCF978D379C1143C5BC715762AF8976D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information on the number of independent contractor health care workers for whom a State waives a licensure requirement under subsection (c)(1) to facilitate deployment during an emergency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idEBC73BBF8B574E24A29B3229DBF94734"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the duration of the deployment of independent contractor health care workers described in paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id585BCF057F044740BAF3D9A3C89581FD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any challenges encountered in the process of carrying out subsection (c)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide27d3b00e2344336bdb64d56e90c8bb2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Liability protections</header><paragraph commented="no" id="id6bbd792cfc4c43269dcf43a9a8c19538"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), an independent contractor health care worker or health care workforce platform that engages in activities authorized under this title and complies with or reasonably attempt to comply with this title shall not be liable for any injury or damage sustained to a person or property as a result of such activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc5af95a2eb214f8aa0ff8d37a50d30d6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply in a case of willful misconduct, gross negligence, or bad faith.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id6f94ec3b2e304cbea9eeeb5c274c4231"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal Tort Claims Act</header><text>Any private entity, including an independent contractor health care worker and a health care workforce platform, that enters into a contract or agreement with the Federal Government or acts at the direction of a Federal agency to respond to an emergency during an emergency the primary responsibility for the response to which the President determines rests with the United States under section 501(b), shall be deemed an employee of the government for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">chapter 171</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, with respect to claims arising from acts or omissions within the scope of such contract or agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idf2d866384748479ca517c85b1c812226"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This subsection shall apply only to activities—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f50bd202a59468d934ffa3177dd4e97"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conducted in response to an emergency the primary responsibility for the response to which the President determines rests with the United States under section 501(b); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6bd3b17789a94a0e9a008854455e7a38"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that are within the scope of the duties authorized by this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id993b3e576b614ca280d60b57178d412c"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall issue such regulations as are necessary to implement this section, including regulations to determine the applicability of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">chapter 171</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, to independent contractor health care workers and health care workforce platforms under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

