<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA759CC18423643469EBDE0ADEDD35771" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2339 IH: Children’s Health Protection Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2339</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250325">March 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000635">Ms. Dexter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Office of Children’s Health Protection to be maintained within the Environmental Protection Agency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE6DB29FEBD5045B8933BCB6CDB7CE6B4" style="OLC"><section id="HD6833E5236554532955D608DE29F0180" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Children’s Health Protection Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H307EDB43361E45FB8EF1B21C15FFF39A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Office of Children’s Health Protection</header><subsection id="H8CCC9CE4B5824FAD96E1B39FB6316CFB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall maintain, within the Agency, the Office of Children’s Health Protection.</text></subsection><subsection id="H65C111A7C7EC4D09BF681BACFB1A5519"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Director</header><paragraph id="H06EE3363553C4F2C901AD7BCBA1435C9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Office shall be headed by a Director.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H296EB61178F74B12BA90B35D4A31E417"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The Director of the Office shall be appointed by, and report to, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency. In making such appointment, the Administrator shall take into consideration the recommendations of the Children’s Health Protection Advisory Committee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81448F8607D0415EB5243E355AF31831"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Co-Chair of President’s Task Force</header><text>The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall delegate to the Director of the Office responsibility to serve as Co-Chair, on behalf of the Administrator, of the President’s Task Force on Environmental Health Risks and Safety Risks to Children established by Executive Order 13045.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC832AA989EB044C5914AB1DD3AA1C845"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Director of the Office shall—</text><paragraph id="H0285D72C9B2E43A1AEA0306310A46A51"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify and assess environmental health risks and safety risks that may disproportionately affect infants, children, and adolescents;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E6A9F378E374195AE063E964D004DE7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">work to ensure that Federal policies, programs, activities, and standards address disproportionate risks to infants, children, and adolescents that result from environmental health risks or safety risks, including consideration of the unique environmental justice concerns affecting infants, children, and adolescents;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA9F4855FF6D4742A1EC3681B05A21F1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>coordinate Federal research and programs, including grant programs, to advance the activities described in paragraphs (1) and (2);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF92B6250EB114A88A582BEB5D22F9C18" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advise other offices of the Environmental Protection Agency and other Federal agencies on all matters related to and concerning environmental health risks to infants, children, and adolescents; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2098C879713F4EEC8610F09A165100D6" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out other duties as the Administrator determines appropriate, including any responsibilities of the Administrator under Executive Order 13045; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C3152BB38B84488A2ADF19B7CA8C8EE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>carry out national activities to—</text><subparagraph id="H61124B4490034877A685A18D2EBF82E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reduce negative environmental impacts on infants, children, and adolescents through involvement in rulemaking, policy, enforcement actions, research, and applications of science that focuses on prenatal and childhood vulnerabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26A4D1E0E674424AB9649E92AC3B5CE4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">help protect infants, children, and adolescents through promoting and issuing guidance for safe chemicals management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9C2C670F6ED449F93C9DED518517448"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate community-based programs to eliminate threats to infants’, children’s, and adolescents’ health;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38B9F040C98043D3834DF69091EFCB30"><enum>(D)</enum><text>increase the environmental health literacy of health care providers through support of pediatric environmental health specialty units;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40E49D46F0684FF3AF9E17FAC964F24A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>evaluate and communicate trends in environmental contaminants that may contribute to childhood disease; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19F5C59D092943C0A2231A7C01886F11"><enum>(F)</enum><text>develop and publish resources for local educational agencies to establish, maintain, or enhance a school environmental health program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD55EF5E33083487F86FC32D8CCF38223"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">otherwise protect infants, children, and adolescents from environmental health risks or safety risks.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE8ACBF3A8DB44ADF91BD66F225FF6076"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Transition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall make such changes to the Office of Children’s Health Protection of the Environmental Protection Agency, as in existence on the day before the date of enactment of this Act, as may be necessary for such Office to become the Office required by subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H618415BB18D5434CAA86E7FA0B3B5659"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $7,842,000 for fiscal year 2026 and each subsequent fiscal year.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD6F7C13BDB9B499ABFDF03636DB0BB47"><enum>3.</enum><header>Children’s Health Protection Advisory Committee</header><subsection id="HF04C55C7A6CD4E239654ED863BE79BD3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall maintain an advisory committee, to be known as the Children’s Health Protection Advisory Committee, to—</text><paragraph id="HDFB7E12A94CE429086DE9234769663B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide advice and recommendations to the Administrator and other officials of the Environmental Protection Agency regarding the programs and activities of the Office;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB560C46F7EF34518B29E3421AC0E97D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advise the Administrator and other officials of the Environmental Protection Agency on regulations, research, and communications related to infant’s, children’s and adolescent’s health; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2B8F2B9AC9C412EAAFA8962B0E91DE4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support the Environmental Protection Agency, including the Office, in implementing Executive Order 13045 and other issues related to infants’, children’s, and adolescents’ health protection as deemed appropriate by the Administrator.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H203FEEE845C34D65A21D9C8CA5248D2D" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability of FACA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Children’s Health Protection Advisory Committee shall be subject to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, except that the Children’s Health Protection Advisory Committee shall be a permanent advisory committee and shall not terminate under section 1013 of such title.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1FF7DD3265D848AB87835DD7B39ED5BF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President, acting through the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall make such changes to the Children’s Health Protection Advisory Committee established pursuant to Executive Order 13045 as may be necessary for such Advisory Committee to become the advisory committee required by this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H51A35B9E9AD84A38AFCDB3662BC6538E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H47A7350093C24407BD0A990530D8D367"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Children’s Health Protection Advisory Committee</header><text>The term <term>Children’s Health Protection Advisory Committee</term> means the advisory committee maintained pursuant to section 3.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16EBFCDAD7D241398F4B6BD4F3E9B09A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Executive Order 13045</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Executive Order 13045</term> means Executive Order 10345 (relating to protection of children from environmental health risks and safety risks) published in the Federal Register on April 23, 1997 (62 Fed. Reg. 19885).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94FF5C0EF27C4189AD94D4637D09EF86"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Local educational agency</header><text>The term <term>local educational agency</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F3D349A53F946A286CF5A58ED39842F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Office</header><text>The term <term>Office</term> means the Office of Children’s Health Protection maintained pursuant to section 2.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H53A33C2888AE495F8D27F7B3A6D48BF0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To carry out this Act, there is authorized to be appropriated $13,200,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

