<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9B9024075AAD47FD9A47B7474DCF2CD7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HR 872 IH: Federal Contractor Cybersecurity Vulnerability Reduction Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 872</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250131">January 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require covered contractors implement a vulnerability disclosure policy consistent with NIST guidelines, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDA36B9CBCA2D46EC8EFCCD7C89E0CF6F" style="OLC"><section id="H52457544E6A14E8082362D31B231C868" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Contractor Cybersecurity Vulnerability Reduction Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H15C35B087F644EA1B5625C5A6CEB883D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal contractor vulnerability disclosure policy</header><subsection id="H932C94AB927D4452885A2964D162ADB1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><paragraph id="HBC0F2FAD640F461E915FDCD67069F2D3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, the National Cyber Director, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and any other appropriate head of an Executive department, shall—</text><subparagraph id="H0E4EA123E29B42EBADA642345FC78445"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review the Federal Acquisition Regulation contract requirements and language for contractor vulnerability disclosure programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB37D83E887E49408BADED43D16D5389"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommend updates to such requirements and language to the Federal Acquisition Regulation Council.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H09FF890268724B55BC58C372CAE738B3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The recommendations required by paragraph (1) shall include updates to such requirements designed to ensure that covered contractors implement a vulnerability disclosure policy consistent with NIST guidelines for contractors as required under section 5 of the IoT Cybersecurity Improvement Act of 2020 (15 U.S.C. 278g–3c; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/207">Public Law 116–207</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H52D2F8DD56E14054883C1E6AEDFAE9D8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procurement requirements</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the recommended contract language developed pursuant to subsection (a) is received, the Federal Acquisition Regulation Council shall review the recommended contract language and update the FAR as necessary to incorporate requirements for covered contractors to receive information about a potential security vulnerability relating to an information system owned or controlled by a contractor, in performance of the contract.</text></subsection><subsection id="H94D8522DF2BB4D9E99EE6EC55BC1ADFB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The update to the FAR pursuant to subsection (b) shall—</text><paragraph id="HAF3ABB508DBF4DDA9C5CD885640C4FC4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, align with the security vulnerability disclosure process and coordinated disclosure requirements relating to Federal information systems under sections 5 and 6 of the IoT Cybersecurity Improvement Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/207">Public Law 116–207</external-xref>; 15 U.S.C. 278g–3c and 278g–3d); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0A42CBB6D824A449C52BEF11BA16841"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, be aligned with industry best practices and Standards 29147 and 30111 of the International Standards Organization (or any successor standard) or any other appropriate, relevant, and widely used standard.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC71E4A4CFC4B45CCB504300E1AAF1110"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The head of an agency may waive the security vulnerability disclosure policy requirement under subsection (b) if—</text><paragraph id="HA497303CBEBD4E5E93988A921EE89C9B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the agency Chief Information Officer determines that the waiver is necessary in the interest of national security or research purposes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC898497E519A4F74ADD7A35C4AFDF304"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if, not later than 30 days after granting a waiver, such head submits a notification and justification (including information about the duration of the waiver) to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H30A04AEA7C764F49B407F7D75D6FF55C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Department of defense supplement to the federal acquisition regulation</header><paragraph id="H8E8B5B80EA30405696AA878D0C7B1F1C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Review</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall review the Department of Defense Supplement to the Federal Acquisition Regulation contract requirements and language for contractor vulnerability disclosure programs and develop updates to such requirements designed to ensure that covered contractors implement a vulnerability disclosure policy consistent with NIST guidelines for contractors as required under section 5 of the IoT Cybersecurity Improvement Act of 2020 (15 U.S.C. 278g–3c; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/207">Public Law 116–207</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H595DD5A986ED4578AF9F9AAF72B2E380"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Revisions</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the review required under subsection (a) is completed, the Secretary shall revise the DFARS as necessary to incorporate requirements for covered contractors to receive information about a potential security vulnerability relating to an information system owned or controlled by a contractor, in performance of the contract.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01A7C23D2809461E948093F2944FC20C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the revision to the DFARS described in this subsection is carried out in accordance with the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7AFE86C75B934BDBA89CAE7E37166840"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Chief Information Officer of the Department of Defense may waive the security vulnerability disclosure policy requirements under paragraph (2) if the Chief Information Officer—</text><subparagraph id="H8FEE1C216CDA4C648B310D1E30F4FCFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determines that the waiver is necessary in the interest of national security or research purposes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5116EFE384C840D6A947AC40B9486D2E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after granting a waiver, submits a notification and justification (including information about the duration of the waiver) to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H687E73ECA03E479195BA500309F235BD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H26D5A5CB60CA47618833D302A5E0A6EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>agency</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 3502 of title 44, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF37081C8445478E8351B1C40E3911D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered contractor</quote> means a contractor (as defined in section 7101 of title 41, United States Code)—</text><subparagraph id="H9FA4B664B3674526A98340432AB67800"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whose contract is in an amount the same as or greater than the simplified acquisition threshold; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7176D916442745DAAEB661CC57EDEDD8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that uses, operates, manages, or maintains a Federal information system (as defined by section 11331 of title 40, United Stated Code) on behalf of an agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF2C979736BD44F586FAFD8494B82B12"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>DFARS</quote> means the Department of Defense Supplement to the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16EEC9C0C19E4CBBB646E5737841EAD9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <quote>Executive department</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA80EB593706245A6A9EF12A4DE21BB77"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <quote>FAR</quote> means the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H174F26EFF0E345D8B8166E73DADDD005"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <quote>NIST</quote> means the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09D810E2EB6E47FCA102E91795A3EBA9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The term <quote>OMB</quote> means the Office of Management and Budget.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4447766DEC2E404DABADC1E96553619D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The term <quote>security vulnerability</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 2200 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/650">6 U.S.C. 650</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DAEEB138FD74216B3F40ACB44230F50"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The term <quote>simplified acquisition threshold</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 134 of title 41, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

