<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF32E656E74C6419CAFB464051A6B0015" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2122 IH: IMPACT Act 2.0</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2122</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001222">Mr. Miller of Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To strengthen and enhance the competitiveness of cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixture production in the United States through the research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of technologies to reduce emissions from cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixture production, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H29715454FD27424B8C8FDAFC3B1925E1" style="OLC"><section id="HDD433FB9D851452984B49AD8D7ADBC83" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>IMPACT Act 2.0</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HAD3C989974D24EE2AF9DD14A34630C3A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal highway administration</header><subsection id="HE791746C12D34EF5B2A06C39B57724A2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Performance-Based low-Emissions transportation materials grants</header><paragraph id="H6359355EFCB04430829D8F5F12700E04"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this subsection is to encourage States to improve State-level cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixture specifications and standards to facilitate the purchase of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H989E611E48574A12A1124932ABEDB867"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration (referred to in this section as the <quote>Administrator</quote>) shall provide to States—</text><subparagraph id="H5AEA4EC664E145E18DF5593163188B16"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reimbursement for the additional cost of using low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures used in highway projects of the State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4752962C02C4B34B8D6D28263F3369D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incentives for the acquisition of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures for use in highway projects of the State; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1F03366C2D04708B86B50EACDB4330C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>technical assistance to update the specifications and standards of the State to be performance-based specifications and standards; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63C7C65E791B4665885B2AB8ED8BD689"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">technical assistance to benchmark and quantify embodied greenhouse gas emissions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BD3672F45AE4354872A5F8035483855"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reimbursement and incentive amounts</header><subparagraph id="H416BFD0136624CE9A9C3D5909F7662FD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reimbursement amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of reimbursement under paragraph (2)(A) shall be equal to the incrementally higher cost of using such materials relative to the cost of using traditional materials, as determined by the State and verified by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98CEC3C6083C450881EF0A309000D4EE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Incentive amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of an incentive under paragraph (2)(B) shall be equal to 2 percent of the cost of using low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures on a highway project of the State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11DC1003BF4F42A0917BBD9DEB884ACD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts provided for reimbursement and incentives under this subsection may not exceed the amount authorized to be appropriated under paragraph (6).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H84C9C0A8B75F4879BCA17E07EBA11647"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive reimbursement or incentives under this subsection, a State shall have in effect, as appropriate, special provisions, specifications, or standards, such as engineering performance standards, or a collection of embodied greenhouse gas emissions reporting tools, such as environmental product declarations, that facilitate the purchase of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4F144783F6A4DA7ABDA79D99F16EFF3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Administrator shall leverage the Every Day Counts Initiative of the Department of Transportation to promote the commercialization of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FEC150777524DE6A3B766C7A6F54B62"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this subsection $15,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2025 through 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H12F121EF92304A2181CF908B99604325"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Directory of low-Emission cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures</header><paragraph id="H41B697AD5A524AEEADB2181DBCCA8AA8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall establish and maintain a publicly available directory of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures submitted by States that the Administrator determines to be eligible for reimbursement or incentives under subsection (a). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36EF6250E6314A5AB5BCAA0FADADDB5F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission and approval</header><subparagraph id="HD7BC5B3E315843F390AB471E0519DE68"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall establish a procedure under which States may submit new low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures to be included in the directory under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F5533AB14A0477D9B687296F6E06BEA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>To be considered for inclusion in the directory under paragraph (1), a State shall submit an application relating to the low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixture to the Administrator at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Administrator determines to be necessary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EE5C7ECD2F84B68A1245EDFB25B079D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Decision deadline</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Administrator receives an application under subparagraph (B), the Administrator shall—</text><clause id="H7208063C3FE3412FB44B34E0D65AF973"><enum>(i)</enum><text>approve the application and include the low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixture in the directory under paragraph (1); or </text></clause><clause id="H643F5D3D59A74D0C95832812C534C602"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>deny the application.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FE591BECFA2451DA8C2178FEB94887F"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Written reasons for denial</header><text>If the Administrator denies an application under paragraph (C)(ii), the Administrator shall provide the State a written explanation for the denial.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA415EC84DC2C4C9C9A2BDBBBE4A2768E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Project selection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures approved under paragraph (2)(C)(i) and included in the directory under paragraph (1) may be used in any highway project.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFDF8CFD7D78F4A35BD9E73BC35E93FF5" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Advance purchase commitment program</header><subsection id="HE0DF72EA56414E6785532AE53831A90D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of this section are—</text><paragraph id="HC854B30ECA084797894C7CA7DABE3F7E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to allow States to purchase or contractually guarantee the direct purchase of conforming low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9329F5D0D7847609C7D79278BEE9ED1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to encourage continuous innovation and long-term emissions reductions in the production of concrete, cement, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD5341DC66F6A450193BE80390AC0BA99"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 133 of title 23, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H2381A8B6A01942C2837D6EC2D98ACE11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b) by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H464234B2C9A94556AAF8755226F6327B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HB26E0BD724A943A4A60D4C6A52D22495"><enum>(25)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A project that includes the use of innovative, domestically produced cement, concrete, asphalt mixture, or asphalt binder manufactured using a process described in subsection (l).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCFCB0702C4A4A63A520F92E45E979E1"><enum>(26)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (m), a project that is carried out through an advance multiyear contract with a producer for a specified quantity and specified price of innovative, domestically produced cement, concrete, asphalt mixture, or asphalt binder manufactured using a process described in subsection (l). </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0BB4F6AA53E466A89EA7E2865CBA72C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H25B63346FE3540AC9B3DF5D3CD66E916" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H28A7CE46A4DC49CAA3EF98B29C0E09FA"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Requirements for certain projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The process referred to in paragraphs (25) and (26) of subsection (b) is a manufacturing process that—</text><paragraph id="HB32B7FC1B5F24E9E96C0769AC87FD1DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">produces materials with—</text><subparagraph id="H8CB3112A3A88438CA6DC25D21B33EECB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>superior durability to conventional materials; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE9E642101B944168C4F3AE6000B9CC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>superior performance with respect to—</text><clause id="H91538DAE43E84F35BFFE38124F99C857"><enum>(i)</enum><text>compressive strength;</text></clause><clause id="HDB1A4A5BFFDC41C69FCFE3BD2E7184A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>tensile strength; or</text></clause><clause id="HB62F123187E3470CB2DD9707D0F0AF25"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>workability; or</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H542AF55BF36A419DA682444B3B68C47E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>produces materials that meet the engineering specifications of the State and achieve superior performance with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="HFF0D93BAD56145E98B6477550F140EF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>environmental performance; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D11F398EBC04447AB0AA14A05CC275B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>energy efficiency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H14B7FC86F2014F05BCEA65B8B3714034"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State flexibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 133(h)(6) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H0CEBED6150C948878F9A8E4753F1E9FE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H0A5EE8C783B7419EA7915A0CE322250A"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Procurement for innovative building materials</header><clause id="HB83CA1A7DEF841069596E8CA989ED0E0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State may use the funds set aside under this subsection to enter into an advance multi-year contract described in subsection (m) for a specified quantity and specified price of innovative, domestically produced cement, concrete, asphalt mixture, or asphalt binder.</text></clause><clause id="HAD4A8DF4E87A49D5BD6ADD432B9AD3E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>States may not provide payments to the producer as part of the advance procurement under clause (i) unless materials have been delivered according to contract terms and conditions. </text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H03C44845F7814B9C8BF73E58EF106BB3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Section 133 of title 23, United States Code, is further amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H67EB78ADBDA149A6A494E3D90CB860B3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H609AE63D4E744046B06A8E723FEBB24F"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Advance multi-Year contracts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in this section, none of the funds made available under this section may be used for a multi-year contract unless—</text><paragraph id="H1C4904C76BE84ABD972561D4D236051D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cancellation provisions in the contract do not include consideration of recurring manufacturing costs of the producer associated with the production of unfunded units to be delivered under the contract;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11159371B42948DE98CA0E9701880E5F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the contract provides that payments to the producer under the contract shall not be made in advance of incurred costs on funded units;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H83F886B2BC914A1BA8B4BA5206F81AFD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the contract does not provide for a price adjustment based on a failure to award a follow-on contract;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H933F7BEB9FBC48799FDEBFFE47860872"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the producer submits a statement describing the quantity and cost of the cement, concrete, asphalt mixture, and asphalt binder;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A87A0B2597E4CBEB8E37006252A4E7B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the producer demonstrates material steps towards commercial production and operational capacity of cement, concrete, asphalt mixture, or asphalt binder production with respect to logistics, planned material storage, handling capacities, and delivery mechanisms, of which failure to demonstrate material progress towards commercial production and operational capacity may result in termination of a portion or all of the advance procurement at the sole discretion of the State; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69C8316C95034E28B862DA5C39A30F2E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the contract fulfills, to the maximum extent possible, preference criteria set by the State.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H62B91FBC27CE457EAAE497B9930163FD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Low-Emissions cement, concrete, and asphalt defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>low-emissions cement, concrete, and asphalt</quote> means cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixture that reduces, to the maximum extent practicable, greenhouse gas or directly related pollutant emissions to levels below commercially available cement, concrete, or asphalt. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

