<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8C0FE09498C84EB0A425E537FD44C879" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1539 IH: Medical Device Electronic Labeling Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1539</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250224">February 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to expand the types of devices for which required labeling may be made available solely by electronic means, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0D611833508444F099C0B5FA6303831A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H140140234187488097AF2711E09AA45E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medical Device Electronic Labeling Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE1DA4BF05D984AF883267E474BC59EE4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Allowing required labeling of devices to be made available solely by electronic means</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 502(f) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/352">21 U.S.C. 352(f)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H82F0E28B4B22423DBAB93F681C88EF37" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HB563AB546B16491F86830AA3CCBA2876"><enum>(f)</enum> 
<paragraph id="HBC771D5310F9408AA7F8505D4ADE8FD8" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Unless its labeling bears (A) adequate directions for use; and (B) such adequate warnings against use in those pathological conditions or by children where its use may be dangerous to health, or against unsafe dosage or methods or duration of administration or application, in such manner and form, as are necessary for the protection of users, except that where any requirement of clause (A) of this subparagraph, as applied to any drug or device, is not necessary for the protection of the public health, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations exempting such drug or device from such requirement.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF62C6307AB9647A49F0EB24C148C0F52" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Subject to subparagraph (3), required labeling for devices (including in vitro diagnostic devices) may be made available solely by electronic means, provided that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H976EDE4D45D7422289D5DA18EC46EC21" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such required labeling is readily accessible to intended users of such devices;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H58415D060B8B46829F92AACCC4F4629C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the manufacturer affords intended users of such devices the opportunity to request the required labeling in paper form, and upon such request, promptly provides the requested information in paper form without additional cost; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HADDF4118BEFB4134B6EA748F7EFD66A0" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the label affixed to the device or its immediate container includes all information in compliance with this Act and the regulations thereunder or any applicable order of the Secretary under subparagraph (3)(A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC960D88858964A3D990483DA21C2D70E" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum> <subparagraph id="H48B3E7F0F06E4B0DB6AC1120F2984945" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>With respect to devices for which labeling is made available solely by electronic means, the Secretary may issue an order establishing requirements in addition to, or exceptions from, the requirements under subparagraph (2) for the label affixed to a device type.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB0C5A1CBF08E4FC0BFCCAC9043C5E782" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, such order shall be published in the Federal Register, following publication of a proposed order in the Federal Register and consideration of comments to a public docket.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDF1E6E1C11F440A49BD09614AEE6E280" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such order may require the label of a device to contain certain information or comply with certain conditions only if the Secretary determines such requirement is necessary to provide a reasonable assurance of the safety and effectiveness of the device.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

