<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCD6F2DD958C24675AE88236B7190FB57" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 454 IH: Raising concern about the constitutional reforms in Mexico.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 454</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250529">May 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Raising concern about the constitutional reforms in Mexico.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas the United States and Mexico are committed to strengthening bilateral and regional cooperation that benefits the people of the United States and Mexico;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States and Mexico are top trade partners, trading more than $896,000,000,000 worth of goods in 2023;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas United States companies directly invested $130,300,000,000 into Mexico in 2022, and nearly 5,000,000 United States jobs depend on trade with Mexico;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States, Mexico, and Canada will participate in the first review of the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement (USMCA) in 2026;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Government of Mexico has actively taken steps to expropriate assets owned by American companies;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas former Mexican President López Obrador proposed constitutional reforms on February 5, 2024, including specific proposals to modify the structure of the Mexican judiciary, including popular election of judges and justices;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Mexican President Claudia Sheinbaum has continued to advance these constitutional reforms;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas reforms regarding the judicial system became law on September 15, 2024;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Mexican judicial branch employees, including judges, magistrates, and others at the Federal, State, and local levels, initiated a widespread and indefinite strike on August 21, 2024, in response to judicial reforms;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Mexico’s National Association of Circuit and District Judges, the Mexican Bar Association, the United Nations Special Rapporteur on the Independence of Judges and Lawyers, the United States Chamber of Commerce, and thousands of striking Mexican Federal court employees and magistrates have voiced concerns with the reforms;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, under judicial reforms, all Federal judges, including Supreme Court Justices, would be directly elected, independent oversight of the judiciary would end, and judicial qualification standards would be reduced;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas broader constitutional reforms to—</text> <paragraph id="H363BAC8A06274214952B357AC33271A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">eliminate autonomous institutions overseeing social development policy and education; the energy, hydrocarbon, and telecommunications industries; and enforcement of antitrust and transparency laws became law on December 20, 2024;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H99233E41B83A4051977642BE896DC9EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">impose a prohibition on genetically modified corn became law on March 17, 2025; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA78F216922B842EF87D1CBB99483C190"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reduce the size, oversight capacity, and sanctions authority of Mexico’s National Electoral Institute will be considered in 2025; and</text>
            </paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas secondary legislation to enact such constitutional changes presents an ongoing opportunity for change: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas> </preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H56EF12C4C2F3418B84FC42BF994609F7"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HB0EFE93DA0EB47049E9EDA8EFB68348B"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA44AF63803AF4E32B8E220CA81B098B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">raises concern that the constitutional reforms and secondary legislation would have a long-term negative impact on Mexico’s democratic institutions, separation of powers, judicial independence and transparency, and security, while undermining its electoral system, National Guard, and independent oversight agencies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3C0C0A6A93A42BEAB4897FABEF7F9C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses deep concern that the constitutional reforms and secondary legislation may contradict commitments made in the United States-Mexico-Canada Trade Agreement, jeopardizing critical economic and security interests shared by the United States and Mexico and weakening North American economic integration;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H926FBBAC9B3147E083F50A5EB5D49662"><enum>(3)</enum><text>underscores that several aspects of the reform package undermine United States-Mexico joint efforts to strengthen the rule of law, counter organized crime, and address the scourge of fentanyl and human and arms trafficking among broader bilateral priorities; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBCBC72A6D4A14817B7F29BC920BD0459"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reaffirms its commitment to a robust, mutually respectful relationship between the sovereign countries of the United States and Mexico.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

