<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1F70E78D8A3C4D7D8D8DA87595801E42" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5406 IH: Opportunities to Support Mothers and Deliver Children Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5406</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250916">September 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide grants for the conduct of demonstration projects designed to provide education and training for eligible individuals to enter and follow a career pathway in the field of pregnancy, childbirth, or postpartum, under the Health Profession Opportunity Grant Program under section 2008 of the Social Security Act.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H48DBEDFDEAEC4E82B09AAE13156090AB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC72DB7236BA545AFB017960A23537E1F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Opportunities to Support Mothers and Deliver Children Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H68B72C1FDEA642468E158E62FCDCE65D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants for demonstration projects to provide career pathways in the field of pregnancy, childbirth, or post-partum</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2008 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397g">42 U.S.C. 1397g</external-xref>) is amended by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (e) and inserting after subsection (c) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16FDC74148064519B5439AB7EE1B2C0C" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HEACD6F8996E447AC9E132A41E0476571">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Demonstration projects To provide career pathways in the field of pregnancy,
            childbirth, or postpartum</header>
          <paragraph id="H557E24827DED4A9EB4A114F6D2FFE666">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Grant authority</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Education, shall award grants in accordance with this subsection to eligible entities to conduct demonstration projects for the purpose of providing education and training for eligible individuals to enter and follow a career pathway in the field of pregnancy, childbirth, or postpartum, in a State that recognizes doulas or midwives and that provides payment for services provided by doulas or midwives, as the case may be, under private or public health insurance plans.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HC27BD44728F948DD91F3C1500726A9AE">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Duration</header>
 <text>A demonstration project shall be conducted under this subsection for not less than 3 years.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H60798B1EEBAB407A93AB93E94B754338">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Application requirements</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An applicant seeking a grant under this subsection for a demonstration project shall submit to the Secretary an application for the grant, that includes the following:</text>
            <subparagraph id="H09F8E91B210E4C47A88E145F5E01AFAA">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>A description of the partnerships, strategic staff hiring decisions, tailored program activities, or other programmatic elements of the project that are designed to support a strong career pathway in pregnancy, birth, or postpartum services.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HD51CB72FE627483A869A9CD166B93949">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A demonstration that the State in which the project is to be conducted recognizes and permits doulas and midwives to practice in the State.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HEE30E56C670644E0BF6F2893B0895DB7">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>A demonstration that the applicant has experience working with low-income populations, or a description of the plan of the applicant to work with a partner that has the experience.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEF3180AE1A994DB58A33FD415DE795CB">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Evaluations</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, by grant, contract, or interagency agreement, conduct rigorous and well-designed evaluations of the demonstration projects for which a grant is made under this section, which shall include identification of successful activities for creating opportunities for developing and sustaining, particularly with respect to low-income individuals and other entry-level workers, a doula, midwife, or other pregnancy or postpartum workforce career pathway that has accessible entry points, that meets high standards for education, training, certification, and professional development, and that provides increased wages and affordable benefits, including health care coverage, that are responsive to the needs of the workforce.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H52A603DFF2A74C339DE80BF06CB26622">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H40E9E3C11D614352AE8917346C094573"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>Eligible entity</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means any of the following entities that demonstrates in an application submitted under this subsection that the entity has the capacity to fully develop and administer the demonstration project described in the application:</text>
              <clause id="H039A15FA36C94056A7FBA99F4150746B">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>A local workforce development board established under section 107 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H46E793E9AA0D4E0E8AB1CF9373FD618F">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or territory, a political subdivision of a State or territory, or an agency of a State, territory, or such a political subdivision.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H3F07F95160704825BD20A9AE51AFDD67">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An Indian tribe, a tribal organization, or a tribal college or university.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H537C14FE5E7C4F18B0A71C50FC241D72">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>An institution of higher education (as defined in the Higher Education Act of 1965).</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H5B99E2173C4A41748E96909A226F79F4">
                <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>A hospital (as defined in section 1861(e)).</text> </clause> <clause id="HCE37F922F8EC477D996AFDD1EDC18BB9"> <enum>(vi)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A skilled nursing facility (as defined in section 1819(h)(1)(A)).</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H4EA9DC8178824B318A8B4390B2BB828D">
                <enum>(vii)</enum>
 <text>A Federally qualified health center (as defined in section 1861(aa)(4)).</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HC7FF3CC07EB343B68ADAB9426DCDB1B5">
                <enum>(viii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A nonprofit organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, a labor organization, or an entity with shared labor-management oversight, that has a demonstrated history of providing health profession training to eligible individuals.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H3576FF80DF6F4C9DA49A23B3A0EEDC0A">
                <enum>(ix)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity recognized by a State, Indian tribe, or tribal organization as qualified to train doulas or midwives, if midwives or doulas, as the case may be, are permitted to provide services in the State involved.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H4C4A9FAA4C1C497C89EA770BCC32DB11">
                <enum>(x)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An opioid treatment program (as defined in section 1861(iii)(2)) and other high quality comprehensive addiction care providers.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HA0D757D6F23F432B9667714D80A41B75">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Eligible individual</header>
 <text>The term <term>eligible individual</term> means an individual whose income does not exceed 138 percent of the Federal poverty level.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H88106F54107A42F08479FF111D43E488">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <header>Midwife</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>midwife</term> means a midwife who meets, at a minimum, the international definition of the midwife and global standards for midwifery education as established by the International Confederation of Midwives.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H9C0BA749BD48481689E53C1979CADAAD">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <header>Tribally-recognized midwife</header>
 <text>The term <term>tribally-recognized midwife</term> means an individual who is recognized by an Indian tribe (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act) to practice midwifery for the tribe.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HB16E460182734557BA2FB57DCDA7BC27">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <header>Doula</header>
 <text>The term <quote>doula</quote> means, with respect to an application to conduct a demonstration project under this subsection, an individual who—</text>
              <clause id="H476B9442048945E69ADDB576CD95E9AC">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <subclause id="H446F74A8A5324C19828ED45394F31BFC"
                  display-inline="yes-display-inline">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has completed 60 hours of training in providing non-medical information, emotional support, and physical support to clients during pregnancy, childbirth, and the postpartum period;</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="HD956728A72C14A3BBDDCAF20733DD5B8" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>is certified by an organization, that has been established for not less than 5 years and requires the completion of continuing education to maintain the certification, to provide the information and support referred to in subclause (I); and</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="H1B1FDFC2E52C49889F328B7BAAB694B8" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text>maintains the certification by completing the required continuing education; or</text>
                </subclause>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H7298BD805EBD4ABBAF53D1BE13239955">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the permission of the local government in the State in which the applicant intends to conduct the demonstration project, to provide the information and support referred to in clause (i)(I).</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HC990A01F814E4F60BD25F3B55F0E9DBC">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <header>Appropriation</header>
 <text>Out of any funds in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this subsection $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2026.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H67430862470B4C2D91AC550378E65F52"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendment made by this Act shall take effect on October 1, 2025.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

