<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3E135FE3927C41C9AF199A255DDC4D06" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2307 IH: To establish the Commission on National Agricultural Statistics Service Modernization to modernize the data collection and reporting processes of the National Agricultural Statistics Service, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2307</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250324">March 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Commission on National Agricultural Statistics Service Modernization to modernize the data collection and reporting processes of the National Agricultural Statistics Service, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB84E20B84E3B45A9873BF280304B0780" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC1C66BDAC5DE478D9F3E203C3CC84648" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Commission on National Agricultural Statistics Service Modernization</header> 
<subsection id="H6A75D4DD330149258596498A5E940F50"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established a commission to be known as the Commission on National Agricultural Statistics Service Modernization (referred to in this section as the <quote>Commission</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEFFCA3F3BE584E5683F6A89220B3D028"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Commission shall conduct a study of the National Agricultural Statistics Service and provide recommendations on—</text> 
<paragraph id="H66FB64ABD9254006BCD5B30CC562DABB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>how data collection can be modernized and streamlined to—</text> <subparagraph id="H225ACF374B1C456EBDD4B8E44CF7A956"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improve the quality of statistics reported;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2BEBBEAED08B4CF0A1E0389D0A70D1FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">account for differences of national, regional, and local production;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5D6DD910C70C4541B1A7ED98C5B93897"><enum>(C)</enum><text>accelerate adoption of new and innovative technologies to reduce the number of surveys needed;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA3BF6A56EBFB4D8791B8627EA6434DB1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>improve producer response rates in statistical surveys and identifying ways to reduce survey fatigue;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF04642E64FBE4B04AF80CF7E12D51C2B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>increase transparency and confidence in statistical reports through improved collaboration with agricultural stakeholders; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBFB8B2767EFB4E269E30218A1CD6ED96"><enum>(F)</enum><text>use more real-time statistical and environmental data to complement existing survey-based data and reporting; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H47ABFA17C71F454E9151FD4FD083DBC3"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve collection and generation of timely data on the specialty crop industry; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9DA89C7D4A3E41FD8BF86AD3362573B4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>how the modernization and streamlining determined under paragraph (1) can be implemented and the estimated costs of such implementation. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE500CB98E5094C8EA8AA664D194900DF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header> <paragraph id="HF56645B6DFA84965A8FFDF479A2C53A1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Commission shall consist of the following 11 members:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC083F1DACB354128B6308C916089AFD5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Administrator of the National Agricultural Statistics Service of the Department of Agriculture.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5DEB3C9C9E8246B5ADA8DAC5897D854E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Economic Research Service of the Department of Agriculture.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0033374700834D27A510DF75D340B552"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Chief Economist of the Department of Agriculture.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HABB1FD81C33B48B797B499FE5BD67DFE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Chair of the World Agricultural Outlook Board of the Department of Agriculture.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2C3E36228B244E9D81D16E4A975AC7B1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A representative from the Bureau of Labor Statistics.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B0527CDACA94BEFBE5F30782C8E1D45"><enum>(F)</enum><text>3 members appointed by the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate, of which—</text> 
<clause id="H128BC789CE29432B8BF948BBB703F2BB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>1 shall be appointed by the Chairman of the Committee;</text></clause> <clause id="HA0155DAED68F4884927346F3DD9E8E15"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>1 shall be appointed by the Ranking Member of the Committee; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HED8F9FC2A43943E993A3C8A18B9AA329"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>1 shall be appointed jointly by the Chairman and Ranking Member of the Committee. </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7B16E398C592428587B6742F5E78EA16"><enum>(G)</enum><text>3 members appointed by the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives, of which—</text> 
<clause id="H9E2AE844FC5B4A2D80C2BF0085FCC2F6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>1 shall be appointed by the Chairman of the Committee;</text></clause> <clause id="HB96C06EF606D4C51A0D0B75F8795CD16"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>1 shall be appointed by the Ranking Member of the Committee; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEFA6F2B3ACA84EC0B7CA846B9B74ADCC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>1 shall be appointed jointly by the Chairman and Ranking Member of the Committee. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2DE368FB086D47DDBF96F868953E4B37"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Date of appointments</header><text>The appointment of all members of the Commission shall be made not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC2620BD177934BBCB907EBE278EF9F1D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Term; vacancies</header> 
<subparagraph id="H7A94AB3227FF4B0DBFA1B7774605173A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Term</header><text>A member shall be appointed for the duration of the Commission.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF6DA3E9E634B48E9872ADB1F1E30D12D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>A vacancy on the Commission—</text> 
<clause id="HCAB3734960E54F3E9A43C11BBA06F29E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall not affect the powers of the Commission; and</text></clause> <clause id="H751F4A02AC9B4597B3D7B6AB0F01BA60"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment was made.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFBF1B4F0CA9D4B859F39C5C328DA2CE5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which all members of the Commission have been first appointed, the Commission shall hold the initial meeting of the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H45B5944922F64B31886FBE9568111A3F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, but a lesser number of members may hold hearings.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD9BE8E3E6ABA4D9FBC1750D9138FE2A8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Chairperson of the Commission shall be selected by a majority of the Members of the Commission.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H31BEDD73DEFD440EBFDC34E07CD147B0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit to the President, the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report containing the results of the study required by subsection (b), including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H794972E683034834934BAFB3C280CCF5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an inventory of surveys conducted by the National Agricultural Statistics Service and the frequency with which they are conducted; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF0AAD5C5C9654AC4AEB58E3242345EC8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such recommendations for administrative, regulatory, and legislative changes as the Commission considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC2680BB89D464CC08FA7C2E853E2B1DE"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Hearings</header><text>The Commission shall hold such hearings, meet and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as the Commission considers appropriate to carry out this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9F158E92B23B48E3AE5AE56362598399"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Stakeholder engagement</header><text>The Commission shall establish a process to collect feedback from agricultural stakeholders to inform the results of the study required under subsection (b) and the report required under subsection (f).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBAD88949EBC24A1882E2C4E8FC028C22"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Information from Federal agencies</header> 
<paragraph id="HC29A1D3A97A74718B361AE78800DD17C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission may secure directly from a Federal agency such information as the Commission considers necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE7A654619CA46B3950C5EB79ACBE84E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority to request information</header><text>At the request of the Chairperson of the Commission for information described in paragraph (1), the head of a Federal agency shall provide such information to the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFF40F9AD5E8A4BB893E21F4691F7363B"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Postal services</header><text>The Commission may use the United States mail in the same manner and under the same conditions as other agencies of the Federal Government.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7B6E39CFAB424D159685AF418F77BB15"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Assistance from the Secretary</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall provide to the Commission appropriate office space and such reasonable administrative and support services as the Commission may request.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2A5553BFD8AC4D2FBCFE3FDA47FEF569"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Compensation of members</header> 
<paragraph id="HA4D1FC42DE0B49FC856283B006D2B822"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Non-Federal employees</header><text>A member of the Commission who is not an officer or employee of the Federal Government shall be compensated at a rate equal to the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5, United States Code, for each day (including travel time) during which the member is engaged in the performance of the duties of the Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D277AC20CEA45F885C7F01E9FC67032"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal employees</header><text>A member of the Commission who is an officer or employee of the Federal Government shall serve without compensation in addition to the compensation received for the services of the member as an officer or employee of the Federal Government.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE4DAB13B0AA24E389DE751C94147F703"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>A member of the Commission shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for an employee of an agency under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from the home or regular place of business of the member in the performance of the duties of the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4D45764A92134A90926F6880B2D60CE9"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Federal Advisory Committee Act</header><text>Sections 1008 and 1013 of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to the Commission or any proceeding of the Commission.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H785D90F0297C4B91B5DB3517BF2B213F"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Commission shall terminate on September 30, 2030.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF5CC1B9282D34110984C84C58F46B816"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $1,000,000 for fiscal year 2026, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

