<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25F56-3TM-92-TFD"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2667 IS: West Bank Violence Prevention Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2667</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250801">August 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prevent violence in the West Bank and authorize the imposition of sanctions with respect to any foreign person endangering United States national security and undermining prospects for a two-state solution by committing illegal violent acts.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H348FB17FD7AD4513945B5D064CED9B31"><section section-type="section-one" id="H1A21097E4A1D45D78A40F0BF47A67393"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>West Bank Violence Prevention Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H32AB7558C7924B69A6CA8BB9FADE7E56"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sanctions with respect to actions threatening peace, security, or stability of the West Bank</header><subsection id="H10C3C24465AF4B00AAB5F2C2072A66D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall impose sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any foreign person determined by the President to meet any of the following:</text><paragraph id="id2e66ac2325f543409d2a38c17a595eb3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To be responsible for or complicit in, or to have directly or indirectly engaged or attempted to engage in directing, enacting, implementing, planning, ordering, participating in, enforcing, or failing to enforce policies that would prevent, actions that threaten the peace, security, or stability of the West Bank, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="idbc08249d3b34400692b5139aa76bbf1f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An act of violence targeting civilians.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcd816de5830e47238fe23daccfcd3124"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A threat of violence targeting civilians with the intent to coerce or intimidate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5775090698984613a8e3193b2605e703"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Efforts to place civilians in reasonable fear of violence with the purpose or effect of necessitating a change of residence to avoid such violence.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id08c69f0388cb42c1a4450779489912bc"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Destruction by private persons of physical property, without the consent of the owner, that renders the property unusable, a residence uninhabitable, or agricultural land unworkable.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id27a4cd77d1d541d4aeb9c648a64bb09a"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Seizure or dispossession of property by private persons.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBF09629956A401BB4251B5F839771FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To be or have been a leader or official of—</text><subparagraph id="H7D54655C5C1049398979E3AB8763456E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an entity, including any government entity, that has engaged in, or members of which have engaged in, any of the activities described in paragraph (1) or (5) related to the leader’s or official’s tenure; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFF57DCB2D3F46D2AC01FB59566B0C80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity the property and interests in property of which are blocked under this section as a result of activities relating to the leader’s or official’s tenure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D297E95E1DA4A1D91BD1596FA93B035"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To have materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to or in support of, any person the property and interests in property of which are blocked under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA9C572BD6CA647EEB77B354B1F80BE34"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To be owned or controlled by, or to have acted or purported to act for or on behalf of, directly or indirectly, any person the property and interests in property of which are blocked under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C92050EB7034D4597E8187A54AE5996"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To have committed or have attempted to commit, or to have participated in training to commit, acts of terrorism targeting the West Bank.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3BFF49E0658415EB23AA51A7DC0B21C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To be a leader or official of an entity subject to sanctions under paragraph (5).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8241D9B4873E498188F3192B9108463A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="H3FABCB9A7574495FB1F8EF5816955411"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Asset blocking</header><subparagraph id="H7A0A89DCE53643B9842D648C5A5EB036"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the requirements of section 202 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>), the President shall exercise all powers granted to the President by that Act to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of any foreign person described in subsection (a), if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H25929CF18CA34175AE33A0C4FB4AE348"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Matters to be included</header><text>A prohibition on transactions under subparagraph (A) includes—</text><clause commented="no" id="HCC8C3D2E19AE422DA028677C26B11189"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the making of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services by, to, or for the benefit of any person the property and interests in property of which are blocked pursuant to subparagraph (A); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HDBDABBBA39624AAA835301F623236CC9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the receipt of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services from any such person.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2c774e217b0c44418968b4c6a6514ecd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ineligibility for visas, admission, or parole</header><subparagraph id="id9256adc19f9048228674bc8e69564342"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien described in subsection (a) shall be—</text><clause id="id877eefa528644ac3a56978dda1b35057"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause><clause id="id4248faa502364dddb344e0bbc0f5393f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="ide80b756442e24f2d80ee659b23cd5687"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaed04143f0604f10bbd98979cf40eb77"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><clause id="id3991c36bc6984830b45acc21e80bccee"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The visa or other entry documentation of an alien described in subsection (a) shall be revoked, regardless of when such visa or other entry documentation is or was issued.</text></clause><clause id="id706203460b1444abb2997e9eeb0b894d"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Immediate effect</header><text>A revocation under clause (i) shall—</text><subclause id="idbd7dbe2fb7c4470a83879e7a414fd7be"><enum>(I)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id16e32f86a6234d36a536f0b10216fb95"><enum>(II)</enum><text>automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the possession of the alien.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H08B1B582C86E4BB0BBF4052EBC156BE0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="id1a07d418e16441e6a7a9643035424f26"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorized intelligence activities</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply with respect to any activity subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091 et seq.</external-xref>) or any authorized intelligence activities of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb26f9c77152e4b7b9c66b751b9223bf0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Humanitarian assistance</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply to—</text><subparagraph id="id98fc1f1b29ec4ba99a32d9b6c054d6ab"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the conduct or facilitation of a transaction for the provision of agricultural commodities, food, medicine, medical devices, or humanitarian assistance, or for humanitarian purposes; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3a3a74f1d93c4ce5bb98394e67d37c63"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transactions that are necessary for or related to the activities described in clause (i).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id32b39f65a14643ccab6dbc041794f6a3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception to comply with international obligations and for law enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sanctions under subsection (b)(2) shall not apply with respect to the admission of an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide23aa3a31a234f81871a73ce1459533a"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb92ed9b15418473c8ab32cb77922c540"><enum>(B)</enum><text>would further important United States law enforcement objectives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H09B71B4B95664E519ED6C7FD74B2F518"><enum>(d)</enum><header>National security waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may waive the imposition of sanctions under this section with respect to a foreign person if the President determines that the waiver is in the national security interests of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="idf252219c08724aa59848af15d89c7a0e"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination of sanctions</header><text>The President may terminate the application of sanctions under this section with respect to a foreign person if the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that—</text><paragraph id="id83769a51b1c44229b96fb6c44fa8d86d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the person—</text><subparagraph id="id0e547a5637394dc0a4e0421dad986c8f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not engaging in the activity that was the basis for such sanctions; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8a2465c0a7e540918b9deeb37e7cd2d7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has taken significant, verifiable steps toward stopping the activity that was the basis for such sanctions; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc30accde63914c44953c2a898a72ca50"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the President has received reliable assurances that the person will not knowingly engage in any activity subject to sanctions in the future.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id598eb92ab4f3459286e1d82c58080f4a"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Implementation; penalties</header><paragraph id="ide8e8e27d6201482d817cf053c8897079"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida2433f8c03d14372a35ea9e96f838c45"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of this section or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out this section shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D834419F0294AE3BAF4474B0CEE19A6"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2cfa04cbdea84337a1892ad33f51fd15"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the implementation of this section, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb0de91e37721446cbaa05616cfed14e5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the names of any persons that have been designated for the imposition of sanctions under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id78b3c726690443e5a07e0e17ca6d1fac"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the sanctions considered and imposed with respect to each such person; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f53ff2551764e08a8c3159a7bc2dcdd"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the activity each such person engaged in that was the basis for the sanctions;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id73cf7ca7963e4e67b11b587dfb9d29ec"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a list of persons for which the imposition of sanctions was waived under subsection (d) and a detailed, specific description of the activity each such person engaged in that would have been the basis for imposing sanctions but for the waiver;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf5e01c5a468c4d959fdc3b5ea7c02d20"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of the circumstances in the West Bank relating to acts of violence against civilians and private property and an assessment of whether any of such acts of violence were against United States persons or property owned by United States persons; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf9fd64e013ea474496e7d5a1c24b51f5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of the actions the United States Government and regional partners are taking to reduce violence against civilians and the destruction of private property in the West Bank.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3F41CDB147454400909AB8F0CE6667C0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="idb2373fbefbf3448d8642e68da34ac04b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Admission; admitted; alien; etc</header><text>The terms <quote>admission</quote>, <quote>admitted</quote>, <quote>alien</quote>, and <quote>lawfully admitted for permanent residence</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id69ac60f32067496395044eeb58ec8f87"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agricultural commodity</header><text>The term <term>agricultural commodity</term> has the meaning given that term in section 102 of the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/5602">7 U.S.C. 5602</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E3DD25CC93947DE9145159AE7C2620D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H717983C8A6A54AB6B1D422705007E6F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H172BF0ACB3C042358168F3D3A6C26518"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB0B6EF8DDD74F23A12CA25D720131BE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Entity</header><text>The term <term>entity</term> means a partnership, association, trust, joint venture, corporation, group, subgroup, or other organization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id21270987c5c64e6492928af4f49cb814" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Medical device</header><text>The term <term>medical device</term> has the meaning given the term <term>device</term> in section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id428962db0bfd43148423486f4d5c26d4"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Medicine</header><text>The term <term>medicine</term> has the meaning given the term <term>drug</term> in section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DF5C4677A114E208D294DDF88BC1A80"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means an individual or entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddbb4a2ea9e8746878f5aae69e4401bb4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idd2c33bd0217547bb9aaf30b611c8fc67"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id364e6f85d09d471da7dfb005e55fe57f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide90487807e0d48b8990554daeead1a9f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any person in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B12E3A4487B42BA9F69901E9CED115A"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Terrorism</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>terrorism</term> means an activity that—</text><subparagraph id="H4642F34BA27A494CB5EB027A0D46F2C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>involves a violent act or an act dangerous to human life, property, or infrastructure; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84BC0A05CAE64C3AAEE1C2860835479A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>appears to be intended—</text><clause id="H7E2AE84F91994E3A85DEE59409283CFF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to intimidate or coerce a civilian population;</text></clause><clause id="H4D877629CEE6472C8BE7FA9BEECBEFF1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to influence the policy of a government by intimidation or coercion; or</text></clause><clause id="HBF388990E5E34EAE9013620EC91C73DA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to affect the conduct of a government by mass destruction, assassination, kidnapping, or hostage-taking.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

