<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H045D95B9875F47EDAB7A69BB776B419C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4156 IH: SOIL Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4156</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250626">June 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a pilot program to establish a pre-approval or pre-qualification process for direct farm ownership loans under subtitle A of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act in order to streamline the application process and provide greater certainty to borrowers.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2008B802E38E4EF4B0790B3BEF1934DE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4AC4EBE69A4747CD9AE32FEFFC004411" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Support for Ownership and Investment in Land Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>SOIL Act</quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBA4EAD52FC6B4F9DB67B07AB3752E43E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Farmer loan pilot projects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subtitle D of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act is amended by inserting after section 333D (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1983d">7 U.S.C. 1983d</external-xref>) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H481DA84434FE4F328783E587E0F4A06A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1A58A82CA0CD44409DD03204550DFC32"><enum>333E.</enum><header>Prior approval or qualification authorization pilot program</header> 
<subsection id="HBF8ECD638C714648B9FBCEC0CA1B516E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall carry out a pilot program to establish a pre-approval or pre-qualification process for direct farm ownership loans made under subtitle A in order to streamline the application process and provide greater certainty to borrowers.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCB8CCDA36CCE459C8B092DE93358554F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility requirements</header> <paragraph id="H2C84BF29926940DE82D0332308BD5554"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the Secretary may establish alternative eligibility requirements for direct farm ownership loans under subtitle A that are processed through the pilot program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6DC9411C659343718F4598CC2F922964"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Applicants satisfying the alternative eligibility requirements shall remain subject to all other provisions of subtitle A.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HACE57B156C2243518F227F42ED15BA91"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Loan assessments</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program, the Secretary shall consider streamlining the determinations under section 360(b).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCDEAF8871CD94A57A07F68F615A8A055"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report examining the actions undertaken under, and the results of, the pilot program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2F9436C0216746E7AD9575C3F14FE4CB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination of effectiveness</header><text>The authority provided by this section shall terminate effective September 30, 2030.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

