<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5168EF00F2EA41DB86B63D68CF8B9E41" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 636 IH: Pregnancy Resource Center Defense Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 636</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250122">January 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend section 248 of title 18, United States Code, to provide adequate penalties and remedies for attacks on facilities providing counseling about abortion alternatives and attacks on places of religious worship.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFE0E9C2123364C4097FB0AD479D9FB78" style="OLC"><section id="H7BA50FD58E4042C79AF4C3740EF34BF7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pregnancy Resource Center Defense Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="HFC4241E3D00D4E01A194BF19B9D71DE8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Attacks on facilities providing counseling about abortion alternatives and places of religious worship</header><subsection id="H6A8FB1743DF64D38A105962550DCD312"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Criminal penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 248(b)(1) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>, except that for a first offense, if the conduct involved a facility described in subsection (a)(3) that exclusively provides abortion-alternative services or involved a place of religious worship and did not involve exclusively a nonviolent physical obstruction, the length of imprisonment shall be not more than 3 years</quote> after <quote>or both</quote>. </text></subsection><subsection id="HC505B67FE44A4CDEA61360D93B338CD1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil remedies</header><text>Section 248(c) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H7A72162962E740DF9D4728655536CAF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(B), in the second sentence, by inserting <quote>, or $20,000 per violation for conduct involving a facility described in subsection (a)(3) that exclusively provides abortion-alternative services or involving a place of religious worship</quote> after <quote>per violation</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7DDDB037C3242F994041C5F25D49254"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(B)(i), by inserting <quote>, $25,000 for a first violation, if the violation involved a facility described in subsection (a)(3) that exclusively provides abortion-alternative services or involved a place of religious worship and did not involve exclusively a nonviolent physical obstruction,</quote> after <quote>physical obstruction</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAAF560B2018942A8901BF1136C0CD360"><enum>3.</enum><header>Destruction of buildings, vehicles, and property</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 844(i) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>or if the building is a facility described in section 248(a)(3) that exclusively provides abortion-alternative services or is a place of religious worship,</quote> before <quote>shall be imprisoned for not less than 7 years</quote>.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

