<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H26A4516690C04126B7B0F7472AF398C4" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HRES 691 IH: Expressing the sense of Congress that August 30, 2025, be observed as the 135th anniversary of the 1890 Institutions.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 691</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of Congress that August 30, 2025, be observed as the 135th anniversary of the 1890 Institutions.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas former Senator Justin Morrill helped lead the passage of the Second Morrill Act of 1890 on August 30, 1890 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/321">7 U.S.C. 321 et seq.</external-xref>), to establish and support land-grant institutions for African Americans to attend;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the mission of the 1890 Institutions (as defined in section 2 of the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7601">7 U.S.C. 7601</external-xref>)) is educational instruction, agricultural research, and statewide extension efforts;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the universities that were founded and form the 1890 Institutions include—</text><paragraph id="H5CCA768589CF49E89BB4BB6CF963E814"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> Lincoln University, in Missouri, in 1866;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FC8F4B758E144A39D27443C9F42BBF5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Alcorn State University, in Mississippi, in 1871;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9993ABD30DB846538E6281F1CA83BF9F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The University of Arkansas, Pine Bluff, in Arkansas, in 1873;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9A3C21C8B5A441987B64343952D403F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Alabama Agricultural and Mechanical University, in Alabama, in 1875;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H608621FCCB5544749275AE6AC12DED0E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Prairie View Agricultural and Mechanical University, in Texas, in 1876;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CB4D0F9798B40FDA38D4D380EEF51A2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Southern University and Agricultural and Mechanical College, in Louisiana, in 1880;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01508E7A8FA643249D1D2BA065A93FD7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Tuskegee University, in Alabama, in 1881;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B9B232A8774453A91A2510F4EBB165B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Virginia State University, in Virginia, in 1882;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H789C736FD0254BB297C0ABA476B97F73"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Kentucky State University, in Kentucky, in 1886;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72F97F161E4A4ECC89D73F64BE8F90F3"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The University of Maryland Eastern Shore, in Maryland, in 1886;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H808F71E716E54BF7899E88B2B9C3B16D"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Florida Agricultural and Mechanical University, in Florida, in 1887;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5DDFB8A7E6F4F10907A1F9B0944E608"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Central State University, in Ohio, in 1887;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E5BCD5885404A88AD64519A368B5D79"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Delaware State University, in Delaware, in 1891;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6929957A63E145FBA6A686289B89B1EA"><enum>(14)</enum><text>North Carolina Agricultural and Technical State University, in North Carolina, in 1891;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D93D7AF250D4117A36052571EEF990B"><enum>(15)</enum><text>West Virginia State University, in West Virginia, in 1891;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC82D14DA51A84EF0A36D347BABE0F1A9"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Fort Valley State University, in Georgia, in 1895;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6565D26DD0454B8ABC53B8D718A6F4E3"><enum>(17)</enum><text>South Carolina State University, in South Carolina, in 1896;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97C1515299B44540877097A63B31D0E0"><enum>(18)</enum><text>Langston University, in Oklahoma, in 1897; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC0F9462A25A48FCB019F7C8964A09FB"><enum>(19)</enum><text>Tennessee State University, in Tennessee, in 1912;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Council of 1890 Universities is comprised of the 19 presidents and chancellors of such universities and provides leadership to advance the interests of the 1890 Institutions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, collectively, such universities have over 88,000 undergraduate and graduate students in disciplines including—</text><paragraph id="H478E4D0A1A76482A806A80B156E85FDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">agriculture and related sciences;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E17C3665D784A4092C3307DB6D8053D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>computer and information sciences;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A1EF1D18EAD4C6A9A8913BB24C4AC22"><enum>(3)</enum><text>biological and biomedical sciences;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FAB58268F854CE697D38F19017FF7DC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>physical and social sciences; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AB0103ACA1B4469AF618A42E4476B65"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) areas; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF296807010B488F9AA155809D77043E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>other majors and degrees;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Association of 1890 Research Directors helps lead research activities at the 1890 Institutions, and the Association of Extension Administrators serves the extension needs of individuals, families, and communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 1890 Universities Foundation was established in December 2016 to help facilitate strategic initiatives across the 1890 Institutions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in successive farm bills, including the Agriculture Improvement Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/334">Public Law 115–334</external-xref>), Congress made new Federal investments in the 1890 Institutions, such as—</text><paragraph id="H2D3B32BC4B744CB59B14C0C57E60CFB3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> the program providing scholarships for students at 1890 Institutions under section 1446 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3222a">7 U.S.C. 3222a</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FE04D6F1A7D4774A27864E46C80A34E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the recognition of at least 3 centers of excellence at 1890 Institutions under section 1673(d) of the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/5926">7 U.S.C. 5926(d)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA1A00FEA32B454385A6C900F746E268"><enum>(3)</enum><text>allowing for the carryover of funds for extension at 1890 Institutions under section 7114 of the Agriculture Improvement Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/334">Public Law 115–334</external-xref>);</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the ongoing Federal-State partnership to provide support for the 19 historically Black 1890 Institutions, sections 1444 and 1445 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3221">7 U.S.C. 3221</external-xref>, 3222), the Smith-Lever Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/341">7 U.S.C. 341 et seq.</external-xref>), and the Hatch Act of 1887 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/361a">7 U.S.C. 361a et seq.</external-xref>) require the States to fully match the Federal funding provided under such provisions of law;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in Executive Order 14283 (90 Fed. Reg. 17543; relating to the White House Initiative to Promote Excellence and Innovation at Historically Black Colleges and Universities), section 3(b)(ii)(C) of such Executive order encourages fostering private-sector initiatives and philanthropic partnerships to promote centers of academic research and program excellence at historically Black colleges and universities, and section 3(b)(ii)(H) of such Executive order encourages States to provide the required State matching funds for 1890 Institutions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress has provided significant Federal funding and resources to support and supplement agricultural research, education, extension, farmer and rancher assistance, and facility improvements, as well as scholarships and programs that provide internships and pathways to agricultural sector or Federal employment for 1890 Institutions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2025, Congress provided $60,000,000 in scholarship support for students at 1890 Institutions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Department of Agriculture has worked collaboratively with the 1890 Institutions through the USDA–1890 Task Force established in 1988, enabling such Institutions to work across the Department of Agriculture, and through a June 2022 memorandum of understanding, has reaffirmed and strengthened the ongoing relationship between the 1890 Institutions community and the Department of Agriculture; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Department of Agriculture, in partnership with Congress, has worked with 1890 Institutions and other organizations to ensure that disadvantaged farmers and ranchers receive the assistance they need to better serve their communities: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H20B944263F5B4A3E81454240E679ED0A"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HDD39D677B2AC47E5A7F1A1573B6CCF9B"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That Congress—</text><paragraph id="H731ABF0D27FB4FE9B1B003F0E79B9F1C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the 135 years of significant and meaningful contributions the 1890 Institutions have made to the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FCAD0C3E885482998E2B96423944ADC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages that the 135th anniversary of the 1890 Institutions should be observed with Federal and State ceremonies and other appropriate events around the country;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB8CAA14DD04479D959C04CA591A44F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>celebrates the collaborative work the 19 historically Black 1890 Institutions have undertaken to address the agricultural research and extension needs of the country;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H056EE6F20AD047D090F7F5B6B66FAFD1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports the efforts of the Department of Agriculture and other Federal agencies to build stronger partnerships with the 1890 Institutions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11165D68FAC040B9A90CA0100BD5B441"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages the creation of task forces similar to the USDA–1890 Task Force across other Federal agencies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B3D2A084FFD41129B5499B8C09C0CCF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>commits to working in a bipartisan way to address the past funding and program inequities of the 1890 Institutions.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

