<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H0B82EEF922E2452F90AEF847201A8828" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1701 : Strategic Ports Reporting Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1701</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date>May 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State to monitor efforts by the People’s Republic of China to build or buy strategic foreign ports, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCFDC11838B5E41FA81EEF4F86FD1210B" style="OLC"><pagebreak></pagebreak><section id="HE10C68E6B54B4681A39312FC91C142F5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strategic Ports Reporting Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HAFCB3285D5AB4C2399F814AC6C8F2049"><enum>2.</enum><header>Mapping and strategy required</header><subsection id="H9F6700860A9044678A077F9C735BDB03"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mapping of global ports</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall—</text><paragraph id="HFAB2E8B0A0A04FFA9D0777BE1ACE6D0B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop an updated, global mapping of foreign and domestic ports identified to be of importance to the United States, because of a capability to provide military, diplomatic, economic, or resource exploration superiority; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA39AE8EFE65B4EFCBE79E51D09D5BDC8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify any efforts by the Government of the People’s Republic of China (PRC) or other PRC entities to build, buy, or otherwise control, directly or indirectly, such ports.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1E99DFA0CA7A4720A872D95750299A42"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission of map</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall submit the mapping developed pursuant to subsection (a) to the appropriate congressional committees. Such submission shall be in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE221CD384971485A8CC2BF11A8F0FE4F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Department of state and department of defense study and report on strategic ports</header><subsection id="HAC96044498F8407592A30E4861E7FEE4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study required</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall conduct a study of—</text><paragraph id="H6FF5ABB0EBEE498E9DE7629480B92051"><enum>(1)</enum><text>strategic ports;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD22C8B5178A4A29BA35B9FCFD1E1D03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the reasons such ports are of interest to the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABBFC081C03045C8808EEEE726AF7B21"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the activities and plans of the Government of the People’s Republic of China (PRC) to expand its control over strategic ports outside of the People’s Republic of China;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9188A7DA137461E8FA40BEBF0C642FB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the public and private actors, such as China Ocean Shipping Company, that are executing and supporting the activities and plans of the Government of the PRC to expand its control over strategic ports outside of the PRC;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H431B76ECC5D24933A1E616A6F3A7DEDF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the activities and plans of the Government of the PRC to expand its control over maritime logistics by promoting products, such as LOGINK, and setting industry standards outside the PRC;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D4403DD940E4E6681692CA495CD40C5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>how the control by the Government of the PRC over strategic ports outside of the PRC could harm the national security or economic interests of the United States and allies and partners of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28D0FA1D7D0C4AE5BAD8D648785FB61B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>measures the United States Government could take to ensure open access and security for strategic ports and offer alternatives to PRC investments or stakes in strategic ports.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HADEB45B9A2E6422980E0131ADB9132F5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conduct of study</header><text>The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Defense may enter into an arrangement with a federally funded research and development center under which the center shall conduct the study required under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H4FD73C8855EA4CDA876E803218595636"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="HFAE05E8FC9004F87B423EA3CAEE9CF72"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the findings of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF22E315685D341AE950B1E641F11A287"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HCFC781DDBDF54F38BDBA3B38F2D4C941"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a detailed list of all known strategic ports operated, controlled, or owned, directly or indirectly, by the PRC or by a foreign person of the PRC, and an assessment of the national security and economic interests relevant to each such port;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C6D55926E614261A4906920396F5D95"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a detailed list of all known strategic ports operated, controlled, or owned, directly or indirectly, by the United States or United States persons and an assessment of the national security and economic interests relevant to each such port;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABBA81D8315F44A38318BE2978441919"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an assessment of vulnerabilities of—</text><clause id="H266D9100E00E4CAAB12A9C3E9BF94AF2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ports operated, controlled, or owned, directly or indirectly, by the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="HA33790D6333A4840BE8CBE9742760F73"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>strategic ports;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39531FCA51D842F6AA2AA9042487BC33"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an analysis of the activities and actions of the Government of the PRC to gain control or ownership over strategic ports, including promoting products, such as LOGINK, and setting industry standards;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6B3A3DCDDF84C76ABB8C16DCBC4EC44"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an assessment of how the Government of the PRC plans to expand its control over strategic ports outside of the PRC;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73A37F0F58454C2CB80010906D200E5A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a suggested strategy, developed in consultation with the heads of the relevant United States Government offices, that suggests courses of action to secure trusted investment and ownership of strategic ports and maritime infrastructure, protect such ports and infrastructure from PRC control, and ensure open access and security for such ports, that includes—</text><clause id="HF53AB6BCF73D40768F29AB2C3026F834"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a list of relevant existing authorities that can be used to carry out the strategy;</text></clause><clause id="HCC1D17FAF36146238D0609B10450A28B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a list of any additional authorities necessary to carry out the strategy;</text></clause><clause id="HD0DBD8A1BB5F49CCB5FBF4A70DA95E24"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an assessment of products owned by the Government of the PRC or by an entity headquartered in the PRC that are used in connection with strategic ports or maritime infrastructure;</text></clause><clause id="HDD4F98E48750420DBC88B1CF9D8B2206"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an assessment of the costs to—</text><subclause id="HD1FF1E6909A4439DAA27EC10E4D149CE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>secure such trusted investment and ownership;</text></subclause><subclause id="H97B0DE88D7714EFEAE89644DD490380B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>replace products owned by the Government of the PRC or an entity headquartered in the PRC that are used in connection with such ports; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HBFFF6E8689854DAD829887D139FB62E2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>enhance transparency around the negative impacts of PRC control over strategic ports; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6C25E0ADF0C848EABC0AC2069514874C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a list of funding sources to secure trusted investment and ownership of strategic ports, which shall include—</text><subclause id="HAD79DA52CB6647D2A25952D20FE68107"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an identification of private funding sources; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HAF12EEBCD3F9413CBB1289FC359C4B94"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an identification of public funding sources, including loans, loan guarantees, and tax incentives; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H567224D9A9B641828323854E2BB95990"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a suggested strategy for Federal agencies to maintain an up-to-date list of strategic ports.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5F6636B8BF746B7B63BD52E00F8BABA" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of any national security threat posed by such investments or activities to United States diplomatic and defense personnel and facilities in the vicinity of such ports, including through cyber threats, electronically enabled espionage, or other means.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85F07AD1A1B54C63A945D523216412B8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD13C2DA398924EB5A2ECD635B44F9E36"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HB09AC94FA4E04AD1BB8943DB9D7296CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H193E06F4B99C441DBABFBA2DF7369AEE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEE39176C7A24C0B90B84F680F6784AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D6A083912B746FAA286B0999A12144E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>relevant United States Government offices</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H2FF2C30D1E7B461E9C26E983B30B1605"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Unified Combatant Commands;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29616F5D5AE44F98AB8A49196C0715AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Office of the Secretary of Defense;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40D9D01DD2BE44699991B1C57A03C937"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Office of the Secretary of State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A0E810065314B38AE719B7A65FE5B6E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the United States International Development Finance Corporation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4143415C9174C64B2B71BDDF23C463B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Office of the Director of National Intelligence; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AA066C3ABC945BFAFD4A68DFD814279"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Maritime Administration of the Department of Transportation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H65D7BA637D7B4BB4A6FD7656AEF339D6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>strategic port</quote> means an international port or waterway that the heads of the relevant United States Government offices determine is critical to the national security or economic prosperity of the United States.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250522" legis-day="20250521" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives May 22 (legislative day May 21), 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

