<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MUR25514-V9Y-KP-62D"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>111 S2073 IS: State Public Option Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2073</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a State public option through Medicaid to provide Americans with the choice of a high-quality, low-cost health insurance plan.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HF54BF53110D1490498F005DFA547FC0A"><section section-type="section-one" id="H79874BC6A8694366BDA46FEEA33DAC12"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>State Public Option Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1B9D3630FBEA4A9199369B41C69E94DA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Medicaid buy-in option</header><subsection id="H41B19C1F81E346998A94C05397C71413"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1902 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H86FE4FB367AB4053AB9D52673541AB82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(10)—</text><subparagraph id="H300DE77342AF42EC933E003FB7BF02D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(ii)—</text><clause id="H4C98151103934F74B462F630484A68E0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subclause (XXII), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></clause><clause id="HC0963E99FBC34B0F94913461A1E853B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subclause (XXIII), by adding <quote>or</quote> at the end; and</text></clause><clause id="H2E0EAE24B2D14200B135DB1A7FC994C1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" act-name="" id="HF9719BAB58A5421D965B45606E9F9156"><subclause id="HF25BF227C04A4D52B674A153499B45E7"><enum>(XXIV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beginning January 1, 2026, who are residents of the State and are not concurrently enrolled in another health insurance coverage plan, subject, in the case of individuals described in subsection (uu) and notwithstanding section 1916 (except for subsection (k) of such section), to payment of premiums or other cost-sharing charges;</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H586A558D470F42E0AB0685F59F5A710D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the matter following subparagraph (G), by inserting <quote>or subparagraph (A)(ii)(XXIV)</quote> after <quote>described in subparagraph (A)(i)(VIII)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9ABC377C73F54F2C952288A689FB9E4B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" act-name="" id="H73422553F2AC48578D75B98E46EA8DBC"><subsection id="H56B65569611841FF88EA39782FD9EEF9"><enum>(uu)</enum><header>Previously undescribed individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Individuals described in this subsection are individuals who are—</text><paragraph id="H72E3D8F6F5AE44B9AF6B86B44A7EE02E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">described in subclause (XXIV) of subsection (a)(10)(A)(ii); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEBE4344C989443FDB5E8A229B9CFC55F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are not described in any other subclause of such subsection or any other provision in this Act which provides for eligibility for medical assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H6551FC9F7BF04EBDB2D930F9B544345E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Provision of at least minimum coverage</header><paragraph commented="no" id="HA312087766B849E68BCAE5D5FFFDC731"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1902(k)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(k)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or an individual described in subclause (XXIV) of subsection (a)(10)(A)(ii)</quote> after <quote>an individual described in subclause (VIII) of subsection (a)(10)(A)(i)</quote> each place it appears.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H039D87EA39F64930AABDAB147AAD173A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 1903(i)(26) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(i)(26)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>individuals described in subclause (VIII) of subsection (a)(10)(A)(i)</quote> and inserting <quote>individuals described in subsections (a)(10)(A)(i)(VIII) or (a)(10)(A)(ii)(XXIV) of section 1902</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H48E1CB372533403DB6E314CB88E94E18"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal financial participation in buy-In program</header><paragraph id="H69A11E95928D4764BB35FAD1B80125FA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Enhanced match for administrative expenses</header><text>Section 1903(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H1184B30FF833425D87D60DF83D26B4E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (7) as paragraph (8); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H010B9B202521488889550C4524C36EBB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (6) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" act-name="" id="HE1030ACC944B42E0A26B4C21092817CB"><paragraph id="HD258775BEE304B2DA7B71ABFE91BA2A9"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amount equal to 90 percent of the sums expended during such quarter which are attributable to reasonable administrative expenses related to the administration of a Medicaid buy-in program for individuals described in section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii)(XXIV) (as found necessary by the Secretary for the proper and efficient administration of such a program); plus</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C1C4EEDB6334D25B357736D0FACAF9B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of premium and cost-sharing revenues from Medicaid buy-in program</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD1EF34D045CB408083173A6788C1F1C0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 1903(a)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(a)(1)</external-xref>), for any fiscal quarter during which a State collects premiums, cost-sharing, or similar charges under subsection (k) of section 1916 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396o">42 U.S.C. 1396o</external-xref>) (as added by this Act), including any advance payments of premium tax credits under section 1412 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act or payments for cost-sharing reductions under section 1402 of such Act that are received by the State, the total amount expended during such quarter as medical assistance for individuals who buy into Medicaid coverage under subclause (XXIV) of section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii) of the Social Security Act (as added by this Act) shall be reduced by the amount of such premiums or charges.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5549263447174E54A62A1050E21469E4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of excess premiums</header><text>Each State that collects premiums or similar charges under subsection (k) of section 1916 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396o">42 U.S.C. 1396o</external-xref>) (as added by this Act) in a fiscal year shall pay to the Secretary of Health and Human Services, at such time and in such form and manner as the Secretary shall specify, an amount equal to 50 percent of the amount, if any, by which—</text><clause id="HCE41ACEAC8004F9BB3A285EDDF858AFE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total amount of such premiums and charges collected by the State for such year; exceeds</text></clause><clause id="H91D5B83B1E1B4F0CB265E3C68AB1A736"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the total amount expended by the State during such year as medical assistance for individuals who buy into Medicaid coverage under subclause (XXIV) of section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii) of such Act (as added by this Act).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF6DC789F09F14555A9011C9CC407011D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cost-Sharing requirement</header><text>Section 1916 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396o">42 U.S.C. 1396o</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C0E9AFC7EF941AFB2D34B8CC3D2F98A"><subsection id="H7A807E5F779B4132A16323C90ECCEE2F"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Premiums and cost-Sharing for individuals participating in Medicaid buy-In program</header><paragraph id="HEC217294A3B341BEB4B30B2CF19FF788"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), with respect to individuals who are eligible for medical assistance under subsection (a)(10)(A)(ii)(XXIV) of section 1902 and are described in subsection (uu) of such section, a State may—</text><subparagraph id="H823D0B7893654A01A0DDF200ECB5FAE9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>impose premiums, deductibles, cost-sharing, or other similar charges that are determined on an actuarially sound basis; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDCD6B0ABECD4DC5B7B5368BA41D946B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>vary the premium rate imposed on an individual based only on the factors described in section 2701(a)(1)(A) of the Public Health Service Act and subject to the same limitations on the weight which may be given to such factors under such section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H05CEB217B5D04A0C91E8D3C6E25A4338"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations</header><subparagraph id="H403D33CF91A742E39A24C96E368F3215"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Premiums</header><text>The total amount of premiums imposed for a year under this subsection with respect to all individuals described in paragraph (1) in a family shall not exceed an amount equal to 8.5 percent of the family’s household income (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B(d)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) for the year involved.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1128929F81C4C88A905BE94E82CB3DE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other cost-sharing</header><clause id="H86CB12F48230404FA57FE7A84C68A2F7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The cost-sharing limitations described in section 1302(c) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act shall apply to cost-sharing (as defined in such section) for medical assistance provided under section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii)(XXIV) in the same manner as such limitations apply to cost-sharing under qualified health plans under title I of such Act.</text></clause><clause id="HAA8A652AFA76416EA161F40D18334389"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Availability of cost-sharing reductions</header><text>Individuals provided medical assistance under section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii)(XXIV) and subject to cost-sharing under this subsection are eligible for cost-sharing reductions under section 1402 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (subject to the income eligibility threshold in subsection (b)(2) of such section), and in applying such section—</text><subclause id="HF4A3C1221BD14FFC9D1A47DB3593D79A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>enrollment in a State plan under section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii)(XXIV) shall be treated as coverage under a qualified health plan in the silver level of coverage in the individual market offered through an Exchange established for or by the State under title I of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H91D45ECEA1A64DDF9A47A8E42741DC61"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the State agency administering such plan shall be treated as the issuer of such plan.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8671C396A81B49848001A466238072CD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Premiums and cost-sharing for certain other individuals</header><text>If an individual is eligible for medical assistance under subsection (a)(10)(A)(ii)(XXIV) of section 1902 and is not described in subsection (uu) of such section, a State—</text><subparagraph id="H520258A9575140E59D402676062EE1E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall not impose premiums and cost-sharing on the individual under this subsection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE608A9806EF64BF3BA0ADAFA866EBBBA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may impose premiums and cost-sharing on the individual to the extent allowed by another provision of this Act (other than section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii)(XXIV)) which provides for eligibility for medical assistance, but only if the individual is described in such other provision.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA28F6FEDB99E47889410620AA18D29A8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Application of premium assistance tax credits</header><text>An individual who is required to pay premiums under this subsection for a year for medical assistance shall be eligible for a premium assistance credit under section 36B of the Internal Revenue Code to the same extent that such individual would be eligible for a premium assistance credit under such section if such individual had paid the same amount in premiums for coverage under a qualified health plan for such year.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H608A68F9D73C49A9A2F7692A0815FBA2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Managed care</header><text>Section 1932(a)(1)(A)(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396u-2">42 U.S.C. 1396u–2(a)(1)(A)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, including an individual who is eligible for such assistance after buying into such coverage under section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii)(XXIV),</quote> after <quote>the State plan under this title</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H29D4825E2B4B45BD86C885091C68EA9F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Offering buy-In program on State exchange; enrollment periods</header><paragraph commented="no" id="HA7FDF174F59940779ED10C1773546895"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State that has elected to allow individuals to buy into Medicaid coverage under section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii)(XXIV) of the Social Security Act (as added by this Act) shall allow individuals to enroll in such coverage through an Exchange established by or for the State under title I of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBDD4E4EBCDC24797A817B465B3D65E3A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enrollment periods</header><text>A State may limit the enrollment of individuals into Medicaid coverage under section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii)(XXIV) of the Social Security Act (as added by this Act) to the enrollment periods provided for under section 1311(c)(6) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H797F724D72B440B4BFFA7C0F06DCB460"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Application of advanced premium tax credits to Medicaid buy-In plans</header><paragraph commented="no" id="HA8757C851177463EB46982D19F255280"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">Section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H26058571622A464CACBF6DEE58CD6D24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(3)(B), by adding at the end the following new sentence:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF41723B8B19440EC9DF64FF17CAA6827"><quoted-block-continuation-text commented="no" quoted-block-continuation-text-level="subparagraph">If an applicable taxpayer resides in a rating area in which no silver plan is offered on the individual market but the taxpayer buys into Medicaid coverage under section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii)(XXIV) of the Social Security Act, such Medicaid coverage shall be deemed to be the applicable second lowest cost silver plan with respect to such taxpayer.</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8E26DC6663C44DB7BAF995E75AFA0400"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (h) as subsection (i); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida1c5fa4f62aa45f2a51d493263bdbf9e"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after subsection (g) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H90D72A75A167495A8CBCD6AF318BB215"><subsection commented="no" id="H5E27FC6564A344DF8E3B20029C21E52F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Application to individuals purchasing Medicaid coverage</header><text>In the case of any individual who buys into Medicaid coverage under section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii)(XXIV) of the Social Security Act, this section shall be applied with the following modifications:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HFFCBF303820B4529812AD706136E8FF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The amount determined under subsection (b)(2)(A) shall be increased by the amount of the monthly premiums paid for such coverage.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5186E7518F0444EBB12932AF35448226"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Subsection (c)(2)(A)(i) shall be applied by treating coverage under the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act in the same manner as a qualified health plan that was enrolled in through an Exchange.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA34D14F2F6E343B8BECEE75C391E53E3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In applying subsection (c)(2)(B)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H36A8813B8ED14978857B4DF92A1A059E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual shall not be considered to be eligible for minimum essential coverage described in section 5000A(f)(1)(A)(ii) by reason of eligibility for medical assistance under a State Medicaid program under section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii)(XXIV); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7D45DA47490A4A1D87712B476C39AD27"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an individual who is not covered by minimum essential coverage described in section 5000A(f)(1)(B) shall not be considered to be eligible for such coverage.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBB897DEA90A74174921B6417125295B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advanced payment of credit</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6178B13C30B648049E746C6383F918F6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall establish a program under which—</text><clause commented="no" id="HDBE0491404954CE58E778316FAA11478"><enum>(i)</enum><text>upon request of a State agency administering a State Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act, advance determinations are made in a manner similar to advanced determinations under section 1412 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act with respect to the income eligibility of individuals enrolling in such program for the premium tax credit allowable under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the cost-sharing reductions under section 1402 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HE4CCF93CD34549EEB0893138DE7EC20C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Secretary notifies—</text><subclause commented="no" id="H400E433469BF42DDBBD3E6D588E2F267"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the State agency administering the program and the Secretary of the Treasury of the advance determinations; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H95BE92435BCF425DA353F34880D45B87"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Treasury of the name and employer identification number of each employer with respect to whom 1 or more employees of the employer were determined to be eligible for the premium tax credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the cost-sharing reductions under section 1402 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act because—</text><item commented="no" id="HD280054AEF784D6C8966E4D485C73581"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the employer did not provide minimum essential coverage; or</text></item><item commented="no" id="H5A06A297E3D7452399EC1E45BDDA21C4"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the employer provided such minimum essential coverage but it was determined under section 36B(c)(2)(C) of such Code to either be unaffordable to the employee or not provide the required minimum actuarial value; and</text></item></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HBEDADCA5A52C4C58AADD55C09511BAF5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Treasury makes advance payments of such credit or reductions to the State agency administering the program in order to reduce the premiums payable by individuals eligible for such credit.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF56BAC5795544B958F8AF38B719A8E75"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determinations and payments</header><text>Rules similar to subsections (b) and (c) of section 1412 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act shall apply for purposes of this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3FD33F948B00491FAAE408AD4C1B4025"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Coordination with credit</header><clause commented="no" id="H1F156441A7D4426888C6593D07FD85E0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">Section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>and under section 2(g)(2) of the <short-title>State Public Option Act</short-title></quote> after <quote>section 1412 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act</quote> each place it appears in subsections (f)(1), (f)(2), and (g)(1).</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HD7276DBFBB2E43238A78ED7D3D6AF0B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Information reporting</header><text>Section 36B(f)(3) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following flush sentence: <quote>In the case of any coverage under the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act for which a credit under this section is allowable by reason of subsection (h), the State agency administering the Medicaid program shall be treated as an Exchange for purposes of this paragraph and subparagraph (A) shall not apply.</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE1C125B810AA4DE9B9FB5EF831931CDE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conforming amendment relating to employer responsibility</header><text>Paragraph (6) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4980H">section 4980H(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>, except that for purposes of subsections (a)(2) and (b)(2), the term <term>qualified health plan</term> shall include any plan described in section 36B(h)</quote> after <quote>such Act</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD19928264A094302A3FF867449722C10"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H17A99851751543B9B4F40EA221EFCEDF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 1902(a)(10) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(10)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a), is further amended, in the matter following subparagraph (G)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H11C09DCF1DBF4EFEB2DEBC833DCF57BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and (XVIII)</quote> and inserting <quote>, (XVIII)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H08D486DCE32D460D8FC0CB49BCD019B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, and (XIX) the medical assistance made available to an individual described in subparagraph (A)(ii)(XXIV) shall be limited to medical assistance described in subsection (k)(1)</quote> before the semicolon.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H28D9728FEC2643C18ED572811E7AD5BF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 1903(f)(4) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(f)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>1902(a)(10)(A)(ii)(XXIV),</quote> after <quote>1902(a)(10)(A)(ii)(XXII),</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8664102C63964D77913DB348EE623344"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 1905(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(a)</external-xref>) is amended, in the matter preceding paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H78DCDA6E5C24468A920DC52DF2E05CF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of clause (xvi);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFCBBCC6599054265B78F37D6302D5390"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or</quote> at the end of clause (xvii); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6DEBA7E750AE46AC98FC81D90027DFC0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (xvii) the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" act-name="" id="H16CD3DC1722E494B971E00CC616C5FA2"><clause commented="no" id="H53B4C99C0E4C4C7694DF56F28C6B48B3" indent="up2"><enum>(xviii)</enum><text>individuals described in section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii)(XXIV),</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2AC728F307524F15ADC4B95C8E0F93A8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Section 1916A(a)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396o-1">42 U.S.C. 1396o–1(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>or (j)</quote> and inserting <quote>(j), or (k)</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD73DB6A6DE7D4838B84B5006D4A07A83"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Section 1937(a)(1)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396u-7">42 U.S.C. 1396u–7(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, subclause (XXIV) of section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii),</quote> after <quote>1902(a)(10)(A)(i)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H88D57CC80B8C42BAA94799995128C337"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reviewing and updating Medicaid quality measures</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62a325d3d88846e4b4b4340515b4acee"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the <term>Secretary</term>) shall review quality measures that are in use under the Medicaid program and, not later than January 1, 2030, shall update such measures to the extent necessary to ensure that such quality measures are appropriate for the population of individuals who are eligible to buy into Medicaid coverage under subclause (XXIV) of section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(10)(A)(ii)</external-xref>), as added by section 2. </text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idea1e2ad368d847e18821139aeef707e3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>The Secretary shall review, and, not later than January 1, 2032, update any corresponding State reporting requirements to include the quality measures under subsection (a). </text></subsection><subsection id="id49afc445d88a482eb11e49564a3e5a97"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State implementation funding</header><text>The Secretary may award funds, from the amount appropriated under subsection (d), to States for the purpose of updating and implementing the metrics developed under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="idd06f4104bf4d4172943b960c2a51612b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text>There is appropriated to the Secretary, out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $50,000,000 for fiscal year 2026, to remain available until expended, for the purpose of carrying out this section. </text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id41fec8bc878042e083982505f9187086"><enum>4.</enum><header>Renewal of application of Medicare payment rate floor to primary care services furnished under Medicaid and inclusion of additional providers</header><subsection commented="no" id="H14054939279D4EB0B434B4145D37B178"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Renewal of payment floor; additional providers</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H1FA5AFE61FE34641B56F29073AFD339C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1902(a)(13) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(13)</external-xref>) is amended by striking subparagraph (C) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB95EDB2ECC4E4EE68918FC52E867B8B0"><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H925F8691ABE1468586435857694BA3FF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>payment for primary care services (as defined in subsection (jj)) at a rate that is not less than 100 percent of the payment rate that applies to such services and physician under part B of title XVIII (or, if greater, the payment rate that would be applicable under such part if the conversion factor under section 1848(d) for the year involved were the conversion factor under such section for 2009), and that is not less than the rate that would otherwise apply to such services under this title if the rate were determined without regard to this subparagraph, and that are—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H795841C54324447FBDAEAA5290B7F289"><enum>(i)</enum><text>furnished in 2013 and 2014, by a physician with a primary specialty designation of family medicine, general internal medicine, or pediatric medicine; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD7E022B56C5411FABA8C5D203ED0089"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>furnished in the period that begins on the first day of the first month that begins after the date of enactment of the <short-title>State Public Option Act</short-title>—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB4AC2B5951D4E9C819DFD6C33DA7080"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by a physician with a primary specialty designation of family medicine, general internal medicine, or pediatric medicine, but only if the physician self-attests that the physician is Board certified in family medicine, general internal medicine, or pediatric medicine;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6EDF9DC3E91344B4BC755A2BC9CC633E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by a physician with a primary specialty designation of obstetrics and gynecology, but only if the physician self-attests that the physician is Board certified in obstetrics and gynecology;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC14183121724978A809A7281B324B90"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by an advanced practice clinician, as defined by the Secretary, that works under the supervision of—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C52B7DEA9284EEDB1118F5C72CEF44E"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a physician that satisfies the criteria specified in subclause (I) or (II); or</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC50FB4E7AFF64048BADA7F9724B20EF8"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a nurse practitioner or a physician assistant (as such terms are defined in section 1861(aa)(5)(A)) who is working in accordance with State law, or a certified nurse-midwife (as defined in section 1861(gg)) who is working in accordance with State law;</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HF16CD0C0A2A044419918597D2B57B366"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>by a rural health clinic, federally qualified health center, or other health clinic that receives reimbursement on a fee schedule applicable to a physician, a nurse practitioner or a physician assistant (as such terms are defined in section 1861(aa)(5)(A)) who is working in accordance with State law, or a certified nurse-midwife (as defined in section 1861(gg)) who is working in accordance with State law, for services furnished by a physician, nurse practitioner, physician assistant, or certified nurse-midwife, or services furnished by an advanced practice clinician supervised by a physician described in subclause (I)(aa) or (II)(aa), another advanced practice clinician, or a certified nurse-midwife; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF79B9550B3284FB58F1BA9AB11D6182A"><enum>(V)</enum><text>by a nurse practitioner or a physician assistant (as such terms are defined in section 1861(aa)(5)(A)) who is working in accordance with State law, or a certified nurse-midwife (as defined in section 1861(gg)) who is working in accordance with State law, in accordance with procedures that ensure that the portion of the payment for such services that the nurse practitioner, physician assistant, or certified nurse-midwife is paid is not less than the amount that the nurse practitioner, physician assistant, or certified nurse-midwife would be paid if the services were provided under part B of title XVIII;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1127B79A8DF64C269D94CE66266C457D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 1905(dd) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(dd)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H65F44260C31B47D3B73D6EFBC7E26A2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Notwithstanding</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H76491ECAB16143C5B6E06A611F6967DC"><paragraph commented="no" id="H65A4840C8D8647D5AABEC0369C703FDA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4C25DED2961943EF89BBAF3EB9BAB905"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or furnished during the additional period specified in paragraph (2),</quote> after <quote>2015,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0EF9A7CAA2FC4F50AC639385492C1A38"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H35C69217EA5849EA923C997C971CA711"><paragraph commented="no" id="HBAC0FF43D4D34940B7E00047FF89E942"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional period</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the additional period specified in this paragraph is the period that begins on the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>State Public Option Act</short-title>.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HAA501E19848D4D049F172B571A38D345"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Improved targeting of primary care</header><text>Section 1902(jj) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(jj)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HE753264F29654D58A4B858F0C0C86DD9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) and (2) as subparagraphs (A) and (B), respectively and realigning the left margins accordingly;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA5C6F308DED94974902F8EED7230003E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>For purposes of</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1E55BDE6F38402686B45E059C6C7378"><paragraph commented="no" id="H0BF5AB911F8E44BAAC1EA74738986BF7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDDE8169E7D464286AA296C14C22374FA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE75FFC19030B4D61990F6C69986EB9EA"><paragraph commented="no" id="H2D6E6AE96F2A4E8EA1BDE689837F31F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>Such term does not include any services described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1) if such services are provided in an emergency department of a hospital.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H87845B4C6ACB42EC854BBA76858DB036"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ensuring payment by managed care entities</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H37676D465B424808BE543DCC03DAE04E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1903(m)(2)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(m)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB785733BEABD4A7C8E0C3A2ABAAFA354"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (xii), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0F61734FCE5843E09E707F3048053C99"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (xiii)—</text><clause commented="no" id="idDB5CC174947E4E888786F3D432AA166C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by realigning the left margin so as to align with the left margin of clause (xii); and </text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idAACB9C105BF8406F884D35C9C05C87B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of clause (xiii) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7676594ACB0B44B19054D538A8DBC8EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (xiii) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAC4EB340914049C68D6C0A33725609A5"><clause commented="no" id="HEFBD53766A674A18BA51FA686BA27813" indent="up2"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>such contract provides that (I) payments to providers specified in section 1902(a)(13)(C) for primary care services defined in section 1902(jj) that are furnished during a year or period specified in section 1902(a)(13)(C) and section 1905(dd) are at least equal to the amounts set forth and required by the Secretary by regulation, (II) the entity shall, upon request, provide documentation to the State, sufficient to enable the State and the Secretary to ensure compliance with subclause (I), and (III) the Secretary shall approve payments described in subclause (I) that are furnished through an agreed upon capitation, partial capitation, or other value-based payment arrangement if the capitation, partial capitation, or other value-based payment arrangement is based on a reasonable methodology and the entity provides documentation to the State sufficient to enable the State and the Secretary to ensure compliance with subclause (I).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H12B253E56AD445EC9C5AB849CFB65AF8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 1932(f) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396u-2">42 U.S.C. 1396u–2(f)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>and clause (xiv) of section 1903(m)(2)(A)</quote> before the period.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HCFB09376F99C429A868AC56D8BA3837E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Increased FMAP for medical assistance to newly eligible individuals</header><subsection commented="no" id="H2D21189CD31745B696A733134E8C6876"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1905(y)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(y)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H93CE24059A124A00970DB4B26DECA363"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>2014, 2015, and 2016</quote> and inserting <quote>each of the first 3 consecutive 12-month periods in which the State provides medical assistance to newly eligible individuals</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3861439C774D48B289A34FC7889AA6BF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>2017</quote> and inserting <quote>the fourth consecutive 12-month period in which the State provides medical assistance to newly eligible individuals</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H207264D22843438BB83583C3DF2F153A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>2018</quote> and inserting <quote>the fifth consecutive 12-month period in which the State provides medical assistance to newly eligible individuals</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H84A1F93ED9724060A5DF197A9339C566"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>2019</quote> and inserting <quote>the sixth consecutive 12-month period in which the State provides medical assistance to newly eligible individuals</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAA111F893B6A4E44B9943E11FC3204D3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>2020 and each year thereafter</quote> and inserting <quote>the seventh consecutive 12-month period in which the State provides medical assistance to newly eligible individuals and each such period thereafter</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0A336411C8E348E6A571B8EB143EC15E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect as if included in the enactment of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H50AA94FD49B14C0BB5C218861FD4BFCD"><enum>6.</enum><header>Medicaid coverage of comprehensive sexual and reproductive health care services</header><subsection id="H3CB77B5A0A8A40C48DBD784D2697B81B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Inclusion of comprehensive sexual and reproductive health care services as medical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1905(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(a)</external-xref>), as amended by section 2(h) and section 209(a) of title I of division G of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2024, is further amended—</text><paragraph id="H1B99E234BB1845B087F79704616E5067"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (31), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA97DF4F396A94E7D9738E9A08F13BFD7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (32) as paragraph (33); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H802229A6E2F9472B92F87A0CD41B17C7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (31) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA86CC7CB564B4230BB54FE9A7F471049"><paragraph id="H18B8A37CBF284B0C8710EE7B6997B946"><enum>(32)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">comprehensive sexual and reproductive health care services, including abortion services and abortion-related services; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD152B69D793E490F98950FF83B8AC361"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requiring coverage of comprehensive sexual and reproductive health care services as condition of State plan approval</header><text>Section 1902(a)(10)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(10)(A)</external-xref>), as amended by subsections (a) and (h) of section 2, is further amended, in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>and (30)</quote> and inserting <quote>(30), and (32)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEA175DA932DD42B58CC3A4A5F4508802"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85532602946f4b1e8f19a0554f2a35af"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1932(e)(1)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396u-2">42 U.S.C. 1396u–2(e)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>Clause (i)</quote> and inserting <quote>With respect to the period beginning before January 1, 2023, clause (i)</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42984d0c15904239aa150a7202b7ae94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 1937(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396u-7">42 U.S.C. 1396u–7(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="id9AEED9772B664735BFDC68F05AFC48F9" act-name=""><paragraph id="IDD70890BDA7374DFBB560B053D25A8811"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Coverage of comprehensive sexual and reproductive health services</header><text>Notwithstanding the previous provisions of this section, a State may not provide for medical assistance through enrollment of an individual with benchmark coverage or benchmark-equivalent coverage under this section unless such coverage includes medical assistance for comprehensive sexual and reproductive health care services, including abortion services and abortion-related services.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H81B88244C101406596E8DC1E1FFC3438"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to medical assistance furnished on or after January 1, 2026.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

