<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE44EA7B323314F59A68A5B276B649C5C" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 687 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that China should no longer be labeled as a “Developing Nation” by the United Nations.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 687</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250909">September 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that China should no longer be labeled as a <quote>Developing Nation</quote> by the United Nations.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas the World Bank classifies the People’s Republic of China as a country with an upper-middle-income economy; </text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Office of the United States Trade Representative, China was the largest goods exporter in the world and the third largest purchaser of United States goods exports in 2022;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, according to the United States Government Accountability Office, China invested $679,000,000,000 on infrastructure projects in nearly 150 countries between 2013 and 2022;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, according to the United States Government Accountability Office, China is the top investor in global energy, financing 226 power plants in 64 countries between 2013 and 2022; and</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the People’s Republic of China is still classified as a developing nation under multiple treaties and international organization structures, even though China has grown to be the second largest economy in the world: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H4B5A60182E42415DB5F53369DFC93544"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H35543DE5B76D4A1CBAF0954924A252CB"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that China should no longer be labeled as a <quote>Developing Nation</quote> by the United Nations.</text></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

