<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MUR25057-Y9C-GK-RM9"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S626 IS: Stopping Online Confusion for Investigative Agencies and Law-enforcement by Maintaining Evidence Determined Interparty Arrangements Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 626</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250219">February 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To improve the communications between social media platforms and law enforcement agencies, to establish the Federal Trade Commission Platform Safety Advisory Committee, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stopping Online Confusion for Investigative Agencies and Law-enforcement by Maintaining Evidence Determined Interparty Arrangements Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SOCIAL MEDIA Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idB86230F5A95946358DCF6EBC63F9CEDD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Better Investigation Communications</header><subsection id="idAC94C4E5E8574B828FCBB7E01AC1EC2D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Law enforcement portal</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, each social media platform shall—</text><paragraph id="idEF30178E5A2C45C387387E306E9C26F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>create a law enforcement portal that meets the requirements described in subsection (b) to provide—</text><subparagraph id="idBE00BD3F195F43B38D05D3F2F0A1FD10"><enum>(A)</enum><text>clear information to law enforcement on who in the company to contact regarding any law enforcement matter; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB0189D0263E849BF838999EF41A84422"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the company has outsourced their law enforcement compliance work to a third party, the contact information of the third party; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idE3EE5BDCFEE6432382A5816E0D32AF2D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publish on the homepage of the social media platform a link to such law enforcement portal.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7D9E08A9064149D592932FCB46A896D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The law enforcement portal created under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="idA448A6A6925C4E55BB338926BF2BA5CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the name of and contact information for the lead point of contact for law enforcement for the social media platform;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3F4DB383D5E649FA8E4D6AAE01ADDB35"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the phone number (which shall connect to a United States-based call center that is staffed on a 24/7 basis) and email address a law enforcement agency may use to contact the social media platform; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idC61D8E073182495ABA220F0F19CEF6C8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>clear policy information related to law enforcement investigations, such as what, if any, notice is provided to the users of such platform in connection with any law enforcement investigation and when such notice is provided.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id975789D59D8B480C875B2E7079F90625"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improving Data Collection and Reporting</header><subsection id="id8BBF7EEDECC4426E919A01C0115B3023"><enum>(a)</enum><header>FTC Platform Safety Advisory Committee</header><paragraph id="id16B3224A4D244F68A95B1ACAC88C7696"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><subparagraph id="id14C33D77DB384C6C883E9883EFE4E022"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established the Federal Trade Commission Platform Safety Advisory Committee (in this section referred to as the <quote>Advisory Committee</quote>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE3EBF357F0BF4B529FE21791A9ACE6B0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Advisory Committee is to provide recommendations to the Commission for the development of uniform reporting metrics on—</text><clause id="id83216531BE754F39941909E7089757E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>social media platforms'—</text><subclause id="id03E0DFCAA8D241468EBF9BCAC6C30DE7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>monitoring or removal of illegal or illicit content on their platforms; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id50A301CDF3EC4D498AD1420166D5FFCC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>collaboration with or referral to law enforcement regarding such content; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idCD4EEE22AB034509BC5E5C32D701B75C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the responsiveness of such social media platforms to law enforcement inquiries and other relevant metrics as determined by the Commission. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id09BEBF0E081B4164809080544308F92C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><subparagraph id="id98065006EA884AA5AE6B9EBA0B03DE90"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall be composed of 11 members, each appointed by the Chair, to serve 3-year terms—</text><clause id="id9E6C992ACFFA45ADB11974C90DC7D60A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>1 of whom shall be a representative from the Commission;</text></clause><clause id="idB245B590E91B4147B66429BE914B342E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>1 of whom shall be a representative from the Drug Enforcement Administration;</text></clause><clause id="id467BF4234A1043849CC310A6010B38C7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>1 of whom shall be a representative from U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, Homeland Security Investigations; </text></clause><clause id="id7CA3A5043B254506B1731F37E2D2EC06"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>1 of whom shall be a representative of social media platforms;</text></clause><clause id="id1ED4A8574FF544D59A3A5B98EAC71BDA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>1 of whom shall be a representative of local law enforcement agencies; </text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id8A7BA8C0ADC043398D5A337F392A839B"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>1 of whom shall be a representative of transparency advocates that comes from a nonprofit, non-governmental organization (commonly referred to as an <quote>NGO</quote>), or think tank which does not receive more than 10 percent of their funding support (including the value of any in-kind contribution) from a social media platform or related company;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idF628ADA8B4284B218B5842AD12546563"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>1 of whom shall be a representative from a State investigative agency; </text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idB3110FAFEBEF4F5D8290691207167CEC"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>1 of whom shall be a representative from the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idB4A42281ECBA4C548D6AFBDCEE3D4F17"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>1 of whom shall be a representative of victims or a victim's advocacy organization which does not receive funding support from a social media platform or related company;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id7ADFCA33D15B4F2E80010546BC27EB15"><enum>(x)</enum><text>1 of whom shall be a representative from the United States Marshals Service; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id2CD2D45FF1734AC9B2BF0CCDCF4397D3"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>1 of whom shall be a representative of the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3C9199CF6C3B4E128365FEB7139BC41B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Date</header><text>The Chair shall make the appointments described in subparagraph (A) as soon as possible after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF7468E84C2CC4678B42F342F48FB9A18"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Term limitation</header><text>An individual may not serve more than 3 terms as a member of the Advisory Committee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC2C573ED0B644A3C9CD6ED1EA2BE8ECD"><enum>(D)</enum><header>No compensation for members</header><text>Each member of the Advisory Committee shall serve without compensation in addition to any compensation received for the service of the member as an officer or employee of the United States, if applicable. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id67F259529239446086F0261ACAA0B27C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><subparagraph id="idC8C8472FD3694CA4A683648109FF6999"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall—</text><clause commented="no" id="idAA5456E6D5004773B502B073F4B758A8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide recommendations to the Commission on—</text><subclause commented="no" id="id11C466487A2C4FE8927B57E66BFC9DAA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>developing and updating reporting metrics in accordance with subparagraph (B); and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id1AC9B2F0065C43FE9C9F20DC7C2F4177"><enum>(II)</enum><text>periodically updating, as the Commission determines necessary, the reporting metrics described in subclause (I) through notice and comment rulemaking; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id3B3B15B513BB4B58A1400741E72CAF61"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, publish, in a single, publicly available report that allows comparison between social media platforms, the information provided under the reporting metrics described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4D2C0DEA4FAB466FBBCDE21365BBBBB0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reporting metrics</header><text>The reporting metrics described in subparagraph (A)(i) shall include, with respect to a social media platform—</text><clause id="id96C8660BDF734746B0E71D876D4D5E31"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of accounts on which the social media platform has identified an advertisement for or promotion of counterfeit substances or fentanyl, including the number of such accounts that were identified—</text><subclause id="id75CD1A1E2BC04CD7AC098A4CA4FAD5FE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>through a user report; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id4FDAE890207E4EB0ACF25454C38B5B45"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by the platform without the use of a user report;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idAB08FC7D5B4E4EDB807A40E85C143615"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>metrics relating to the social media platform's procedure, if any, for referring to law enforcement any account that advertises or otherwise promotes counterfeit substances or fentanyl, including—</text><subclause id="id2D923B6781C34CA2BED59F85E32BB3D6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>whether the platform notifies the account holder of such referral;</text></subclause><subclause id="idAE2A6F1052FE443B8F8841717FD9F371"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to which law enforcement agencies the platform makes such referral; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id931BE77D32FD4480A9CD1B0EAB83AB3F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>how many such referrals the platform has made during the previous 12-month period;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id197900780FA240E3A145DB80B5F225E5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>during the previous 12-month period, on average, the number of orders under section 2703(d) of title 18, United States Code, subpoenas, and search warrants received by the social media platform per month related to accounts on the platform that are being used for illicit activity;</text></clause><clause id="id613AEEF28CC94FA19AE82DE83CA8FB24"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the social media platform's average response time (not including any automated response or response confirming receipt by the platform) with respect to a subpoena issued by a law enforcement agency; and</text></clause><clause id="id1D7708464D414275A87D97A160DF7E8B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any other reporting metrics on illegal or illicit content (including human trafficking, child exploitation, or other crimes), as determined appropriate by the Advisory Committee.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF0AF875B908C42A4B57C9E76FDF50F44"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adoption of reporting metrics</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC8D8794D81BC44A082B34E1FF132B65F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Review of recommendations</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Advisory Committee provides its recommendations to the Commission under subsection (a)(3)(A)(i), the Commission shall submit to Congress a report that indicates—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7DA1D43A8A1F4C988C2B54F559E7047A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which recommendations of the Advisory Committee that the Commission implemented, plans to implement, or adopted; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55B51D7D09BC46A3B3235FB5075A6040"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which such recommendations the Commission did not implement, does not plan to implement, or does not adopt and a rationale for that determination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idD47C76E4079A49498D04D85C95FAE199"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guidance to social media platforms</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the Advisory Committee provides its recommendations to the Commission under subsection (a)(3)(A)(i), the Commission shall issue guidance to social media platforms describing the reporting metrics adopted by the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2B085112E74A4DFF8D0AD7B5470FA926"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the Commission issues guidance under subsection (b)(2), and annually thereafter, each social media platform shall submit to the Commission, in a publicly available manner, a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="idD3E846B955C34407BDD7060A836F6F3E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the reporting metrics required by the Commission as described in subsection (a)(3)(B); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA738DD549746436E8A8D519F9670FD18"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of any efforts taken by the platform to monitor advertisements or other information promoting illicit activity on an account on the platform. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id28C826F70301429FAB09D38B699665C6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subsection id="ide3057a655bb54298bad14fc827e03e55"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of section 2(a) or 3(c) or a regulation promulgated under this Act shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id5ce0b65cb74b4fd796175953e3c7b3c5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header><paragraph id="id0a9823bc0dd64497a1ead76ba9b5d243"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), the Commission shall enforce this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd65ebed4df6749e6b6253429d2f98bae"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), any person who violates section 2(a) or 3(c) or a regulation promulgated under this Act shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id2172ebeff9f84f53ba5aebcf53b763c7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Common carriers and nonprofit organizations</header><text>Notwithstanding section 4, 5(a)(2), or 6 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/44">15 U.S.C. 44</external-xref>, 45(a)(2), 46) or any jurisdictional limitation of the Commission, the Commission shall also enforce this Act, in the same manner provided in paragraphs (1) and (2), with respect to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id9150204d5d2e47c59eac3591b0a3265d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>common carriers subject to the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/151">47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) and Acts amendatory thereof and supplementary thereto; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idffc9b06354be4eb7802b1fe58ad1b5a0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>organizations not organized to carry on business for their own profit or that of their members.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide2e7cfe25d6641e3869fe08c3472b2f8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id696dab78ac2e4b21a648dfa86c94d2d1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Commission shall promulgate in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, such rules as may be necessary to carry out this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idF120E392B59D4FDA99BDA8B310543459"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idC421B5E7B8B344379E4CF9A01C50AABE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The term <term>Chair</term> means the Chair of the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4AB23F7FB43547189EE5452621F388FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id770A82E4580C475CAD0C830FD1E936A8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Controlled substance</header><text>The term <term>controlled substance</term> has the meaning given that term in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id192DD4D426D34ED2913E9101EF15CC7E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Counterfeit substance</header><text>The term <term>counterfeit substance</term> has the meaning given that term in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4C07AC9EE1BF429E9DE6B79F38642577"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Illicit activity</header><text>The term <term>illicit activity</term> means the unlawful production, manufacturing, distribution, advertisement, or sale of a controlled substance. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE9EF0CB020A0488DA2C96CEB05ADAA28"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Social media platform</header><text>The term <term>social media platform</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id046BC1FA51DF40D59E7F7FB8074A8785"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a website or mobile web application that—</text><clause commented="no" id="id36B9308575164D4AA4580B46DFCEB159"><enum>(i)</enum><text>permits a person to become a registered user, establish an account, or create a profile for the purpose of allowing the user to create, share, and view user-generated content (including goods or services offered for sale) through such an account or profile;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idD71F0C4BA5D341BD9FCC63A6B97CBFA3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>enables 1 or more users to generate content that can be viewed by other users of the platform; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id9AC886C7C187421DB52806FBCEBE7752"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>primarily serves as a medium for users to interact with content generated by other users of the medium and for the platform to deliver advertisements to users; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idC06765BC1634407BB6625EF69FC3EFC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a social network, an online chat room or message board, an online marketplace, and any other platform determined appropriate by the Commission. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

