<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25340-JS3-4M-9NF"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 166 IS: Demanding the immediate reinstatement of all veteran Federal employees involuntarily removed or otherwise dismissed without cause since January 20, 2025. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 166</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Demanding the immediate reinstatement of all veteran Federal employees involuntarily removed or otherwise dismissed without cause since January 20, 2025. </official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on February 13, 2025, the Department of Veterans Affairs (in this preamble referred to as the <term>Department</term>) issued a statement dismissing more than 1,000 employees, including Veterans Crisis Line workers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on February 24, 2025, the Department issued a statement dismissing an additional 1,400 employees, once again including Veterans Crisis Line workers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on March 4, 2025, the Department distributed an internal memorandum outlining plans to dismiss up to 83,000 employees this year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, at least 6,000 veterans have been dismissed across the Federal workforce because of the Trump administration’s sweep of mass terminations across the Federal Government;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, despite repeated demands for transparency and good governance, Members of Congress and the United States public have yet to receive—</text><paragraph id="id2133182a65454e6c81a420139b3e88e9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>data or justification about—</text><subparagraph id="ide93de5d4e9c94dc9a5dca0e04f90a90a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the decision-making process that lead to these involuntary dismissals; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5bae684ffa7e4f7a80f997c84e5176c1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the already existing disruptions to several critical Department programs; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4594797f49ca402ea01b183cf8cd7a0b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Administration’s plan for the future of the Department;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas veterans make up 30 percent of the Federal workforce, serving first in uniform and then choosing to continue to serve in the Federal Government; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is the duty of the United States to support our veterans by making sure they have the benefits and care they were promised: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That it is the sense of the Senate that any veteran Federal employee that was involuntarily removed or otherwise dismissed without cause since January 20, 2025, should—</text><paragraph id="id1255bd3aa7d4417c9de5014ab029e756"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be immediately reinstated with guaranteed full and timely back pay; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc55a5d767ae04491addc7c47b8ae52b1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>receive timely notice of their reinstatement with clear instructions on the path forward for their position, with clear understanding, communication, and oversight from their respective chains of command. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

