<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H63A1A75FB0004ADF92274C347DDD0021" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4050 IH: Advancing Skills-Based Hiring Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4050</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250617">June 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a voluntary compliance assistance initiative at the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission regarding the usage of employment tests and selection procedures by employers.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF3112A172E1C40848B50C5313B003D18" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H79BF3877DC6F4EB48A59FC97BDCB5913" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advancing Skills-Based Hiring Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC4CC022061224DFD99017408B7481435"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the purpose of this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="H99308F3291D34E509A7059F372B3088B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to empower employers to adopt a skills-based approach to hiring through a voluntary compliance assistance program regarding the appropriate use of employment tests and selection procedures, and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H52A6479FFF1045BEA80DECE6ABE089D6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to enable employers to proactively submit validation information to the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission for review to ensure use of such tests and procedures is job-related for the position in question and consistent with business necessity within the meaning of section 703(k)(1)(A)(i) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e-2">42 U.S.C. 2000e–2(k)(1)(A)(i)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HF968A7C914DA41039CF32B10061F06D3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Review by Equal Employment Opportunity Commission of information voluntarily submitted by employers</header> 
<subsection id="H6C51F0FC185340968C43D9CAB006683D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Voluntary submission and review of employer information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>) shall—</text> <paragraph id="HD1BBE5571C8349DA86FD69D2F6691C7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish a process for employers—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB1C31B5D9E2647D7835B1DC88F8DE073"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to voluntarily submit validity evidence to the Commission on the use, or prospective use, of competency-based assessments or other professionally developed selection procedures that are used to make employment decisions, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H325D5096BCFE4DE58532EA958B354705"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to obtain a determination by the Commission as to whether such use is job-related for the position in question and consistent with business necessity within the meaning of section 703(k)(1)(A)(i) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e-2">42 U.S.C. 2000e–2(k)(1)(A)(i)</external-xref>),</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6316060724754BB69DBBE0CB524200CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as part of such process, set forth the validity evidence that participating employers should submit, which may include—</text> <subparagraph id="H81F85EFA17504012A278A27434A05B7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a criterion-related validity study,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H37E0BC9A1A904E1094EDB3F1630CFAF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a content validity study,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H85AC067B45E84C0997FD1DD5404BD5C4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a construct validity study, or</text></subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H6E7A6187BE6849E49790BCEF3C94F057">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a transportability study that includes the validity evidence from a study,</text>
                    </subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">conducted by another entity, along with evidence from the employer that shows job similarity, and</continuation-text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H50DC7E4590DE4BAE9D56DAA218A3B87A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allow employers to submit validity evidence for review regardless of the existence of an adverse impact from the use of the assessment or selection procedure on protected groups, but require such submitted evidence to include any information available on whether the use has resulted in adverse impact.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEB35A5065DAF44B995586405D20A2581"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review of submitted employer information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the payment required by subsection (d), the Commission shall review the information submitted under subsection (a) and—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC4DCB0C99FD04DD78AEAB1EEDC5D3F6B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determine that the use of the assessment or selection procedure identified by the employer is job-related and consistent with business necessity, or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73E03BB6CD4A427CBBA2ED0F0DB70BE9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide technical assistance to such employer that includes, at a minimum—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0521D47A451E480B9FEFBA83A7F241D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an explanation of why the Commission cannot make such a determination, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H103C188AB3C348688E557040F9473A79"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">steps the employer could take, or changes the employer could implement, that will enable the Commission to make the determination in subsection (b)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCDBF9BCFC4F4476AABF848B18A727412"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Safe harbor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The determination from the Commission under subsection (b)(1) that the employer’s use of an assessment is job-related and consistent with business may be used by the employer to satisfy its burden of proof under section 703(k)(1)(A)(i) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e-2">42 U.S.C. 2000e–2(k)(1)(A)(i)</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1432CF3429D4416F865D52275D0B7429"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Fee payable for review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To obtain review under subsection (b), an employer with more than 100 employees shall pay to the Commission a reasonable fee determined by the Commission to offset the cost incurred by the Commission to provide such review.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB9E1A3EDA33749DF9CDC72670E432CDA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any information submitted by the employer under subsection (a) and any technical assistance provided by the Commission under subsection (b)(2) regarding the information submitted by the employer related thereto shall—</text> <paragraph id="HFBCC980D5F0B46FEBC7620791AEC100A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not be used against such employer as a basis for a future enforcement action, and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58A3AB16E5F74CA59F28CFB5F5342213"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be inadmissible in a Federal or State court proceeding without the consent of such employer.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H2B04209975D642F4A788AC9486B5EFEF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Education and technical assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission shall provide education and technical assistance on the use of employment tests or other selection procedures, including education and technical assistance on the methods of validation of an employment test or selection procedure and on the opportunity to voluntarily submit validity evidence to the Commission to seek a determination that use of an employment test or selection procedure is job-related and consistent with business necessity.</text></section> 
<section id="H146EE58FBE234E96A81FE37EC06CEB56"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, the term <quote>competency-based assessment</quote> means an assessment or selection procedure that purports to measure the knowledge, skills, abilities, or personal or behavior characteristics that are necessary for, or shown to predict, successful job performance.</text></section> <section id="HB39166092B0B41AB97D8CBEE632BB0A1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

