<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7EB670E76FC64F92A3186C7CC8F9DB35" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 554 IH: Supporting President Trump’s decisive actions to dismantle Iran’s nuclear weapons program and affirming unwavering support for the State of Israel’s right to self-defense.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 554</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250627">June 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001322">Mr. Baumgartner</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting President Trump&#8217;s decisive actions to dismantle Iran&#8217;s nuclear weapons program and affirming unwavering support for the State of Israel&#8217;s right to self-defense.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Islamic Republic of Iran remains the world’s leading state sponsor of terrorism and poses a direct and escalating threat to the national security of the United States, our servicemembers abroad, and our allies, particularly Israel, through its pursuit of nuclear weapons, ballistic missile development, proxy terrorism, cyberwarfare, and its open hostility toward United States values and interests;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Iran has continued to escalate its aggression across the Middle East, including by launching large-scale missile and drone attacks directly against the State of Israel and United States assets in the region;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Iran has expanded strategic cooperation with both the Russian Federation and the People’s Republic of China, including the supply of drones and missiles used by Russian forces in Ukraine and participation in joint naval exercises in the Persian Gulf and Indian Ocean;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Iran has signed a 25-year strategic agreement with China worth $400 billion which spans military, intelligence, cyber, and energy sectors, and has enabled Iran to evade Western sanctions and advance both its nuclear and ballistic missile programs;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Iran-backed Houthi rebels, also known as Ansar Allah, increased their missile and drone attacks against United States forces, Israeli civilians, and commercial shipping in the Red Sea, utilizing advanced Iranian-supplied weaponry to threaten vital maritime routes, regional security, and United States citizens lives;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on October 7, 2023, Hamas terrorists carried out the deadliest massacre of Jews since the Holocaust, killing over 1,200 Israeli civilians, including women, children, and the elderly, committing acts of rape and mutilation, and taking more than 200 hostages;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the attack was materially enabled by Iran’s longstanding support, including funding, weapons, training, military technology, and logistical coordination, as well as meetings between Hamas leadership and Iran’s Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) in Beirut in the weeks prior;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas senior Iranian leaders have repeatedly threatened the destruction of Israel and explicitly warned of nuclear strikes, including Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei’s statement on January 3, 2025, declaring that <quote>Israel will be wiped off the map</quote>, and statements by Iranian generals threatening nuclear retaliation against Israeli cities if attacked;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Obama administration’s 2015 Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPOA) provided Iran with international legitimacy to enrich uranium, allowed it to retain thousands of centrifuges, excluded its ballistic missile program from restrictions, and granted over $100 billion in sanctions relief, which the regime redirected to expand its military and terror networks;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Biden administration not only reversed key elements of the first Trump administration’s Maximum Pressure policy but also accelerated the Obama-era strategy of appeasement by easing sanctions enforcement and enabling a surge in Iranian oil sales, thereby emboldening Iran’s aggression;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas when a hostile regime like the Islamic Republic of Iran builds hardened nuclear enrichment facilities such as Fordow, installs advanced centrifuges capable of enriching uranium to weapons-grade levels, arms proxy forces with precision-guided munitions, and repeatedly signals intent to strike United States personnel and allies, the threat is no longer hypothetical, it is ongoing, imminent, and real;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Iran has engaged in a pattern of escalating behavior, including enrichment beyond JCPOA limits, obstruction of IAEA inspections, missile transfers to proxies, and public threats to destroy Israel and retaliate against the United States, demonstrating both capability and intent to conduct strategic attacks;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Islamic Republic of Iran has repeatedly rejected President Trump’s good faith diplomatic efforts by the United States and other parties to address its nuclear program;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Iran’s rejection of President Trump’s clear and fair ultimatum demonstrates its bad-faith approach and unwillingness to abandon its nuclear ambitions, thereby necessitating continued strong United States leadership and unwavering support for Israel;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in this context, on June 21, 2025, following Iran’s continued refusal to negotiate with the United States, the U.S. Air Force launched a targeted strike on three Iranian nuclear facilities, a proportionate and lawful act of national defense consistent with longstanding norms and United States law;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States strike on Iranian nuclear facilities was not an act of escalation, but a proportionate and lawful act of national and collective defense consistent with longstanding norms and preemptive self-defense;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas this strike dealt a devastating blow to the regime’s aspirations of achieving a nuclear weapon; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the House of Representatives stands firmly with Israel in its rightful acts of self-defense and affirms its support for President Trump’s effective Maximum Pressure strategy, which is successfully confronting the Iranian threat, restoring American credibility, and defeating Iran’s nuclear ambitions and regional aggression: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H6088F47E918D4F179D951DA0BB99AC64"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA606299A2EA04056AAB2F1CD6222D3ED"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HA7657D7A1B7749C09A54B559C97BDA8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">hails the success of Operation Midnight Hammer, commending President Trump and our Nation’s Armed Forces for their successful efforts to disrupt Iran’s nuclear weapons infrastructure, neutralize a continuing and imminent threat, and restore critical regional deterrence;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F1B860C63E245109FB075143F6434CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reaffirms that it must be the continued position of the United States to ensure that Iran is never permitted to build a nuclear weapon, and embraces the policy objective of preventing a nuclear-armed Iran through permanent, verifiable prohibition on all enrichment activities, weapons development, and ballistic missile delivery systems, by diplomatic means wherever possible, and through force only when necessary to protect the United States and allied security;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4F1A277F732D4FCEAF2ABC759FED59A8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reaffirms unwavering support for the State of Israel’s right to self-defense and calls for continued United States and Israel defense coordination, including timely replenishment of missile defense systems such as the Iron Dome and David’s Sling;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H018A7FD243FA404587C53A5BCE965042"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applauds the Trump administration’s renewed call for Iran to return to negotiations aimed at ending hostilities, curtailing proxy aggression, and dismantling its nuclear weapons program, and emphasizes that such diplomacy must be backed by sustained pressure and regional cooperation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H64A1ABC2E14B45EFB44EFEE8383E5AE4"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">urges the United Kingdom, France, and Germany to leverage their diplomatic influence with Iran to press for immediate deescalation and reengagement in serious negotiations, while coordinating with the United States on sanctions enforcement and contingency measures under Resolution 2231; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H89DADA5BCC244B3DA6BC0502083F80F7"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affirms that the United States does not seek war with the Iranian people, but rather seeks to end the regime’s nuclear weapons pursuit and regional aggression, and expresses solidarity with the Iranian people in their aspirations for peace, dignity, and fundamental freedoms. </text></paragraph> </section> </resolution-body></resolution>

