<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-HLA25682-V1F-53-T98">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 365 IS: Designating August 1, 2025, as “Gold Star Children’s Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>III</distribution-code>
        <congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. RES. 365</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action display="yes">
            <action-date date="20250801">August 1, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which
                was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the
                    Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
        <official-title display="yes">Designating August 1, 2025, as <quote>Gold Star Children’s
                Day</quote>.</official-title>
    </form>
    <preamble>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the recognition of Gold Star Families in the United States dates back to World War I, when the families of fallen members of the Armed Forces displayed a service flag with a gold star in the window of their homes;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, in 1936, President Franklin D. Roosevelt signed into law legislation declaring Gold Star Mother’s Day, now known as <quote>Gold Star Mother's and Family's Day</quote>, a national observance honoring the mothers of fallen members of the Armed Forces annually on the last Sunday of September;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, since 2010, the Senate has honored Gold Star Spouses by resolution annually on April 5, recognizing the unique sacrifices made by spouses of fallen members of the Armed Forces;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas many thousands of children of military families have lost parents who served in the Armed Forces and also deserve national recognition for the burden and legacy they carry; and</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, since 2021, the Senate has honored Gold Star Children by resolution annually on August 1, recognizing the debt of gratitude owed to children of fallen members of the Armed Forces by the people of the United States as part of the debt owed to the members of the Armed Forces who sacrificed all in protecting the freedom of the United States and the people of the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text>
        </whereas>
    </preamble>
    <resolution-body>
        <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1">
 <text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="id725006356dd247bc8fabb505ed66c1a1"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>designates August 1, 2025, as <quote>Gold Star Children’s Day</quote>;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="iddaa857aaa7d7443eb7a001c6146ba401">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>honors the sacrifices and hardships of the children of fallen members of the Armed Forces; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idbcf7ee5317dc4fae93ff0c0e7ead813e">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>encourages the people of the United States to observe Gold Star Children’s Day in support of children of the fallen members of the Armed Forces of the United States.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
    </resolution-body>
</resolution>

