<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H237BA1846E2B440AB9693722C583880E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5761 IH: Fair Warning Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5761</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251014">October 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act to support workers who are subject to an employment loss, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H84099A8073AA49EBB386E8B51CA56AAC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE545A6DAF43C46D4BA96111044D26F5D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Warning Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1EE93256757647A7ADC84DB10E618916"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions; provision of notice of site closings and mass layoffs</header> <subsection id="HC7CBE9C268A1433AB8B45264615A1EDC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Warn act amendments</header><text>Sections 2 and 3 of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2101">29 U.S.C. 2101</external-xref>; 2102) are amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block id="H3D06123AFCB74D9FB96946F04596DE8C" style="OLC">
<section id="H761546BEC4344EEDA4B6561A2B2D8E3B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions; exclusions from definition of loss of employment</header>
<subsection id="HA14277C8FB68422F8AC8310FAE5EB302"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>As used in this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H722C2D203F0041F79D48483F2EE7A8BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affected employee</header><text>The term <term>affected employee</term> means a full-time or part-time employee who may reasonably be expected to experience an employment loss as a consequence of a proposed site closing or mass layoff by the employee’s employer.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4B7B5EF1A707412B8002A6A88D5566FC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employer</header>
<subparagraph id="H5EE44AA2032B45FA9EF4728F637623D5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>employer</term> means any business enterprise of one or more entities that—</text> <clause id="H9DEDD6D051BB48438C265C5E79D9C665"><enum>(i)</enum><text>employs 50 or more employees, including part-time employees, in the aggregate; or</text></clause>
<clause id="HC42EAA8B430940C487AD99480820FCC5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has an annual payroll of at least $2,000,000.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H617D8549DEB14015B2A43100BA8E3EAB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Multiple entities</header> <clause id="H08A7B1343CBB4956B20401F28C17F1C5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a business enterprise of more than one entity, the entity subject to the requirements under this Act as an employer of an affected employee shall be the entity that directly employs such employee.</text></clause>
<clause id="H35784595B0BC4D6CAEB74EE569901148"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Parents, affiliates, and contracting companies</header><text>A parent, affiliate, or contracting company of the entity described in clause (i) may also be subject to the requirements under this Act as an employer of the affected employee described in such clause based on the degree of control or integration the parent, affiliate, or contracting company exercises outside of or at the single site of employment at which the site closing or mass layoff occurred. Such control or integration shall be indicated by such factors as—</text> <subclause id="HA6F3DDBE2C3B4176B6E59A19850B4607"><enum>(I)</enum><text>common ownership or financial control;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HC0871CBF6F0B4D628185DA72ED8B4B8E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>common directors or officers;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H20A222A2F3DD4874A59E7EF51C6C3265"><enum>(III)</enum><text>de facto exercise of control over the circumstances relating to such site closing or mass layoff;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HFFBD6CA6B1CE4D4093F2C40521B65D83"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>unity of personnel policies emanating from a common source; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HFCBFD058651346B6B0D46A376F118FA3"><enum>(V)</enum><text>dependency of operations.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H89D68C1CCD434B31BCE5540C159A9E50"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Additional definitions</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (B)—</text> <clause id="H862191171F6B4499A5FD4485C9222317"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the term <term>contracting company</term> means an ultimate or intermediate client of an independent contractor or a provider of financial services that participates directly or indirectly in making decisions that affect the provision of notice required under this Act; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H9FCCC5B9311B425BBD4C170F115F346A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the term <term>parent</term> means an ultimate owner or intermediate owner, regardless of amount of ownership interest, that participates directly or indirectly in making decisions that affect the provision of notice required under this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAD267DE77B78448BA5DAF3F857DB816C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>In allocating liability under this Act among multiple entities of a business enterprise, substantial weight shall be given to any decisionmaking responsibility an entity had for the failure to provide notice to affected employees as required under this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H135D20AE38084C82B204B70542DB4FD8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Employment loss</header><text>Subject to subsection (b), the term <term>employment loss</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HB6E8D5A6663D470A8C12C2AD633B47ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an employment termination, other than a discharge for cause, voluntary departure, or retirement;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9BC3A9F4A9E74527B48858978C4AE671"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a layoff through a mass layoff or site closing that is not a temporary mass layoff or temporary site closing in compliance with the requirements under paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 3(d); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2D0C69182A7D43E9B07D059E691DB7BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a reduction in hours of work of more than 50 percent during each month of any 90-day period that is not part of a short-time compensation program provided in the case of such a temporary mass layoff or temporary site closing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4EAD69F577B542758975139D28EEF2A1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Mass layoff</header>
<subparagraph id="H9F4BB1945BEF4994B90757DBBFACF0EB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>mass layoff</term> means a reduction in force that results in an employment loss during any 90-day period—</text> <clause id="H2DE79ABCA37C4F6280E348C8B2D71576"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for 10 or more employees of an employer at a single site of employment, as calculated under subparagraph (B); or</text></clause>
<clause id="H0EBB461B09A849F3B2ED01A4BA18E5AD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for 250 or more employees of an employer, irrespective of employment site.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB3ABAA2A76CE4114A3D55D5A5361881A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Calculation</header><text>The number of employees at a single site of employment who suffer an employment loss shall be calculated in a manner that includes—</text>
<clause id="H97B1D12F0645493A81E02EC5A4B60A3B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>all such employees who work at the physical location of the site; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA7B94FB57C664377A92B52628EEBE700"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all such employees who work remotely and—</text>
<subclause id="HB01C9E1C59424C0AAA6421CF7C6CAC23"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are assigned to or otherwise associated with the site;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC9443C6FFDAC4F0FB4EA86AAC4811F44"><enum>(II)</enum><text>receive assignments or training from the site;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H9DA460DAFA1C4D06BA509BCBD511199C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>report to a manager associated with the site; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H95914BFB0214474D993AC29882F23300"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>whose job loss was a foreseeable consequence of a reduction in force at the site.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0F8C2E6A9C6E4F02959899869AB89610"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Representative</header><text>The term <term>representative</term> means an exclusive representative of employees within the meaning of section 8(f) or 9(a) of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/158">29 U.S.C. 158(f)</external-xref>; 159(a)) or section 2 of the Railway Labor Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/152">45 U.S.C. 152</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3C8FF3417644AB18FB944DE85B38A48"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H49C18FF1B4014C84B48A97AE2EC25C66"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Short-time compensation program</header><text>The term <term>short-time compensation program</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H5CAD8816FBF14FBD9BD6F8FC7BFD38BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a short-time compensation program, as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3306">section 3306(v)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, that is operational; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H044E627A32FA4C92A85CF43DF63D2E6E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a program determined by the Secretary to be equivalent to a program described in subparagraph (A) that provides, in comparable amounts and with comparable restrictions to such a program, employees experiencing a temporary reduction in work hours with pro rata pay, unimpaired benefits, and supplemental income.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4F2380FA774F426DBBC98FAE7DB1B250"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Site closing</header><text>The term <term>site closing</term> means the permanent or temporary shutdown of a single site of employment, or one or more facilities or operating units within a single site of employment, that results in an employment loss at the single site of employment during any 30-day period for 5 or more employees, calculated in the same manner as described in paragraph (4)(B).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5CFAA22A2E054762B36E19B133144878"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Unit of local government</header><text>The term <term>unit of local government</term> means any general purpose political subdivision of a State which has the power to levy taxes and spend funds, as well as general corporate and police powers.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC05B04CD8D6348A0A2958E403604596B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exclusions from employment loss due to a site closing or mass layoff</header><text>An employee shall not be considered to have experienced an employment loss due to a site closing or mass layoff if the site closing or mass layoff is the result of the relocation or consolidation of part or all of the employer’s business and, prior to the site closing or mass layoff—</text>
<paragraph id="H840DC27EF02A40C3B9AA0A7F49C63476"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the employer offers to transfer the employee to a different site of employment within a reasonable commuting distance with no more than a 90-day break in employment; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H05F31410942F4BF3ADB052D3B81C3098"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the employer offers to transfer the employee to any other site of employment regardless of distance with no more than a 90-day break in employment, and the employee accepts within 30 days of the offer or of the site closing or mass layoff, whichever is later.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H553D33EA7BD041DFBBFE844D8B266471"><enum>3.</enum><header>Notice required before site closings and mass layoffs</header>
<subsection id="HDBCC5CCA3E5749B3A249E08853881F50"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notice to employees, state dislocated worker units, and local governments</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (c), an employer shall not order a site closing or mass layoff until 90 calendar days after the date on which the employer has served written notice of such an order to—</text> <paragraph id="H5366C89B9A1B439FACF3CE4D5774614E"><enum>(1)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4F6BB4198CAF472681D6B34DF594BB5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each representative of the affected employees as of the time of the notice; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7D11F9EA180E4B97B0B6FB74F5AF833E" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each affected employee;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC51FBB3B17504AB6B5D704FEEB85ED95"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary and the Governor of the State where the site closing or mass layoff is to occur;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB9AA37D2C40A48EAAC665D5CF860AAD0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the State or entity designated by the State to carry out rapid response activities under section 134(a)(2)(A) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3174">29 U.S.C. 3174(a)(2)(A)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD55680B941D1403C9B94A2D62357D55E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the chief elected official of the unit of local government within which such closing or layoff is to occur.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7E370A0E2BB942959C6F37503802ECFE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties upon receipt of notice</header><text>A State or designated entity that receives a notice under subsection (a)(3) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H8E2262BF351647BB8AEB9696B12987BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make the information in the notice publicly available within the jurisdiction of the local government involved;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAB8DD8FB9A5541A3A66DA3F055F0CE10"><enum>(2)</enum><text>transmit a copy of the notice to each affected local area (as defined in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>)), so that the information in the notice can be distributed through activities under section 134(c)(2)(A)(iv)(I)(aa) of that Act (29 U.S.C. 3174(c)(2)(A)(iv)(I)(aa)); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BABA89C0D0F44B2A40A02CFF2287D6D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H4CDDF050926C4F448DBF7D65B3F01DBB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an appropriate labor-management committee described in section 3(51)(C) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102(51)(C)</external-xref>) has been established or is established not later than 20 days after receipt of the notice; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD4FA0BCEAD240ADA6FAC2642757A6A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an individual is designated, by not later than 20 days after receipt of such notice, to coordinate rapid response activities described in section 134(a)(2)(A)(i) of such Act, in consultation with the labor-management committee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H6CACC131D8C648188DA7DA42BED7C56F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reduction of notification period</header>
<paragraph id="HFFF02FD55AD54635945D5AAFB53ADF6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Potential new business or financing</header><text>An employer may order the site closing of a single site of employment before the conclusion of the 90-day period described in subsection (a) if the employer can demonstrate that—</text> <subparagraph id="HC349C96526CB44B8B29FE496F059AE15"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as of the date that notice would have been required, and continuing until it was provided, the employer was being offered, on acceptable terms, new business or financing in an amount which, if obtained, would have enabled the employer to avoid the site closing; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDFA073E669A144B684CD7DD7F09D8DB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>had notice been given as of such date, the notice would have precluded the new business or financing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H76B95EE6F9B34AB187BB82D88B48D6E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unforeseen circumstances</header> <subparagraph id="HB8CB08293FA14F25BC179AA249B5A351"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Natural disasters</header><text>The 90-day advance notice under subsection (a) shall not be required if the site closing or mass layoff is due directly to any form of natural disaster, such as a flood, earthquake, or a drought ravaging the farmlands of the United States.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H551C7E3D39234C84B5981AC05628C687"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Terrorist attacks</header><text>The 90-day advance notice under subsection (a) shall not be required if the site closing or mass layoff is due directly to a terrorist attack that affects the operation of the site.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H92E922DB3495404FB48A02A672F53CCE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public health emergencies</header><text>The 90-day advance notice under subsection (a) shall not be required if the site closing or mass layoff is due directly to a catastrophic infectious disease outbreak or other public health emergency that affects the operation of the site.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H78E72F022FE54927904AEB953030F443"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Provision of notice</header>
<subparagraph id="H51D98909B8AA43298148107A4D913EDF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Potential new business or financing</header><text>An employer relying on paragraph (1) shall be liable under this Act for any portion of the 90-day period described in subsection (a) prior to the provision of notice in which it is unable to meet the requirements of such paragraph.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8CD464ACBF77444596DCA95DA82640DC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other requirements</header> <clause id="H091031CA4B0440E898A5A6DD2B09B3F0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An employer relying on paragraph (1) or (2) shall give as much notice as is practicable and at that time shall give a brief statement of the basis for reducing the notification period.</text></clause>
<clause id="H32F2868544674FFB859DFCA01648955E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Liability</header><text>An employer that fails to satisfy the requirements under clause (i) shall be liable under this Act for the full 90-day period described in subsection (a).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBB9AC782AF9349D292B53825AA33C262"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Temporary mass layoff or site closing</header> <paragraph id="H8CF7D484E5A54FAEA572E71B720EE55E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A layoff through a temporary mass layoff or temporary site closing shall be treated as an employment loss under this Act as of the date of the commencement of the temporary mass layoff or temporary site closing unless the employer complies with the requirements under paragraphs (2) and (3).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H63719BA885F647E3A2F9A1D6C0D42A1D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial period of temporary mass layoff or site closing</header><text>With respect to the period of a temporary mass layoff or temporary site closing that has not been extended as described in paragraph (3), the employer shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H54F01CCE2B3942BEBB082070CE6626CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at the commencement of such layoff or closing, provide a written notice as required under subsection (a) stating—</text>
<clause id="H76E513C22CB44904B410CD49476C17AF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date on which the employer expects to recall the affected employees to work, which date shall be less than 90 days after the date of such commencement; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF86C832211DB48F5A4EC27BC1369837F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that the employer will provide short-time compensation for the duration of such layoff or closing through a short-time compensation program;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE33516EE1ABA4543B59E19AC47A8CD10"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as soon as practicable, provide short-time compensation through such program, which shall continue to be provided for the duration of the temporary mass layoff or temporary site closing; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H422CCC144E1A453F8C2DCFAF7C9F6E29"><enum>(C)</enum><text>on or before the recall date stated under subparagraph (A)(i)—</text>
<clause id="HBBC12D09A1F64466904EEE44F3CBB94A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in good faith, recall the affected employees for at least 90 days of employment;</text></clause> <clause id="HF53EE9AEAE3E4DABAE3789C701D3F21A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>extend the period of the temporary mass layoff or temporary site closing in accordance with paragraph (3); or</text></clause>
<clause id="H8FD6BD9317024B9787276CD5C7C020B2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>except as provided in paragraph (4)(C), terminate the affected employees with not less than 90 days’ notice.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C96F4F5A888479C897822DCEB9E43F0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Extension of period of temporary mass layoff or site closing</header><text>In the case the employer seeks to extend the period of a temporary mass layoff or temporary site closing beyond the recall date stated under paragraph (2)(A)(i) or a subsequent recall date as provided under this paragraph, the employer shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H20B9E6B9764E4DB3B6453CF9979CA915"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prior to the pending recall date, provide to each individual or entity described in subsection (a) a written notice of such extension, stating—</text> <clause id="HB981D17747F0482F83ACB931F6AB7A8B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that the period of the temporary mass layoff or temporary site closing will be extended to a new recall date within 90 days of the pending recall date; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H81E6FAE0B9D245F99A9D30C60BF06912"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that the employer will continue providing short-time compensation as described in paragraph (2)(A)(ii);</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7CF3054597874D078095DEF2B2CEBC93"><enum>(B)</enum><text>continue providing short-time compensation as described in paragraph (2)(B); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBFFF95F64D104514B6619023757AB3A2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>on or before such new recall date—</text> <clause id="HFDAA7D7FA84945578200C5C550E7A27C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in good faith, recall the affected employees for at least 90 days of employment;</text></clause>
<clause id="H04A4E855F57F41BD80C07CB54E5A70E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>further extend the period of the temporary mass layoff or temporary site closing in accordance with this paragraph; or</text></clause> <clause id="H1B6A333A26B4487194BDEB20744AD1D3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>except as provided in paragraph (4)(C), terminate the affected employees with not less than 90 days’ notice.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H287471FE1C3A40B199C3CB67ED881274"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Temporary mass layoffs or site closings resulting in terminations</header>
<subparagraph id="H0994CDE660C64E4382E88FDFEE5B92F0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case the period of a temporary mass layoff or temporary site closing, including any extensions of such layoff or closing, culminates in the employer terminating an affected employee with less than 90 days’ notice in violation of paragraph (2)(C)(iii) or paragraph (3)(C)(iii), the employer shall, except as provided in subparagraph (C), be liable to such employee for back pay and benefits as described in section 5 for each day, for up to a maximum of 90 days, the employer did not provide notice and short-time compensation as required under this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD4AF561991C642FEBC9D809293366F86"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No reductions</header><text>Notwithstanding section 5(a)(2), no amount for which an employer is liable under subparagraph (A) shall be reduced by any payment received by an employee for short-time compensation during the period of the violation.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFD8E33377EB348F4A645B991D13423F1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>An employer may terminate an affected employee under paragraph (2)(C)(iii) or (3)(C)(iii) with less than 90-days’ notice as described in such paragraph if the employer can demonstrate the existence of a circumstance described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (c). The applicable requirements under paragraph (3) of such subsection shall apply with respect to any employer relying on such a circumstance in providing less than 90-days’ notice under paragraph (2)(C)(iii) or (3)(C)(iii).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2A967C31E3554C399DD2681E9EDF1D01"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Determinations with respect to employment loss</header> <paragraph id="HD4BA5D7ECB12404D81390068E0DADE52"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Multiple groups</header><text>For purposes of this section, in determining whether a site closing or mass layoff at a single site of employment has occurred or will occur, employment losses for 2 or more groups at the single site of employment, each of which is less than the minimum number of employees specified in paragraph (4) or (8) of section 2(a) but which in the aggregate exceed that minimum number, and which occur within any 90-day period, shall be considered to be a site closing or mass layoff unless the employer demonstrates that the employment losses are the result of separate and distinct actions and causes and are not an attempt by the employer to evade the requirements of this Act.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA6D61B3A077744C79D068ADC9DCE0EBE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of business sales</header>
<subparagraph id="H46B5E0FBB8394025A32764C927E59B39"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a sale of part or all of an employer’s business, the seller shall be responsible for providing notice for any site closing or mass layoff in accordance with this section up to and including the effective date of the sale. After the effective date of the sale of part or all of an employer’s business, the purchaser shall be responsible for providing notice for any site closing or mass layoff in accordance with this section.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H30E6B961ADE84FAAB4478BADBB6A1728"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Transfer of employees</header><text>In the case of a sale of part or all of an employer’s business, and notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, any person who is an employee of the seller as of the effective date of the sale shall be considered an employee of the purchaser immediately after the effective date of the sale.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H805395139F1B4400A9248B77E8551227"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Content of notices</header><text>An employer who is required to provide notice as required under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H4A6FC7BD0A654AFD8668181EDCFE8DA8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in each notice required under such subsection—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1665D96A68D84E9B9C892046BC9F6928"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a statement of the number of affected employees;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB4A29FC861FF4FD6869B1DCD3209372A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the reason for the site closing or mass layoff;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H573EBFBF983344EBA4B86B8CFF531A99"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether the layoff is permanent or temporary and, if temporary, the date on which the employer expects to recall the affected employees to work;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE5DDD128A858486B918C52023CDE660B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the availability of employment at other establishments owned by the employer;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H987E3197AAE54EAA83B7675707EA54A8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a statement of each employee’s rights with respect to wages and severance and employee benefits; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2F625AB6547748499C7B02546D540F85"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a statement of the available employment and training services provided by the Department of Labor; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H50F4963A5F92414A83CB8276F5BE0E62"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in each notice required under such subsection (except for paragraph (1)(B) of such subsection), the names, addresses, and occupations of the affected employees.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H01B19D4423CF431EBBFE2A3E3DD255DB"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Information regarding benefits and services available to employees</header><text>Concurrent with or immediately after providing the notice required under subsection (a)(1), an employer shall provide affected employees with information regarding the benefits and services available to such employees, as described in the guide compiled by the Secretary under section 13.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H73C6D9B4DCC047F5BAFA70F8294FF50A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Access of rapid response teams</header><text>An employer who is required to provide notice under subsection (a) shall permit, during work hours, reasonable on-site access to any Federal, State, or local rapid response team under section 134(a)(2)(A) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3174">29 U.S.C. 3174(a)(2)(A)</external-xref>) responsible for providing reemployment, training services, and related services to affected employees.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H796C5B5EA536416C97B2CE2D1722D2FB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>DOL notice to congress</header><text>As soon as practicable and not later than 15 days after receiving notice under subsection (a)(2), the Secretary shall notify the appropriate Senators and Members of the House of Representatives who represent the area or areas where the site closing or mass layoff is to occur.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HE734C42732054EB9B6DF4BCBDF878CC8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>WIOA amendment regarding the provision of information through local employment and training activities</header><text>Section 134(c)(2)(A)(iv)(I)(aa) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (29 U.S.C. 3174(c)(2)(A)(iv)(I)(aa)) is amended by inserting before the semicolon the following: <quote>and of information in notices described in section 3(a), and of access to the database established under section 5(e), of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2102">29 U.S.C. 2102(a)</external-xref>; 2104(e))</quote>.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HF12919F4F10E4369A6C473E5ACF54F97"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exemption</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 4 of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2103">29 U.S.C. 2103</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block id="H3DF7CD3644C14550997871209E8278EC" style="OLC">
<section id="H79B30F42F31C48FE8BC58B0FBD290D82"><enum>4.</enum><header>Exemption</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall not apply to a site closing or mass layoff if the closing or layoff is the result of the completion of a particular project or undertaking for which—</text> <paragraph id="H58F18905317A405FA800429C2667F42A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the completion point of the project or undertaking was—</text>
<subparagraph id="HBFF473D637554F70AB19F6BA023B29B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ascertainable; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H36D6169822384F538403311AC37C9301"><enum>(B)</enum><text>when an affected employee was hired, described to and acknowledged by the employee, in writing, as limiting the duration of the employment; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEAD58CD34B0544999523E974486285DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the approach of the completion point was reasonably obvious, without any notice other than under paragraph (1)(B), to any affected employee not less than 60 days before the occurrence of the completion point.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H29B51C31CA8A44DCBE034B11D8ADEF3D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Administration and enforcement of requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5 of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2104">29 U.S.C. 2104</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HE324A7784A7341EBBF8ED627DA52E48C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="HF8B4902D12D04A6699A8B0CB2925C6FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
<clause id="HD270FFEE904046DB8361D084956CFA32"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>plant</quote> and inserting <quote>site</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="HC99B54279A374E07AC931F55D4383BB8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text>
<subclause id="HACF12F836DF140D3BCDA277A8917B763"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>each day</quote> and inserting <quote>each calendar day</quote>; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H0A51551D5B7A42819FCE1FB27F80AE87"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="HF5685E20DB224309824EFAE7E924D29B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H8E8EA83C61154023AF7F376A498E8E4A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (B) the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H06CA7431C1BB467EB70FBB83B7199288" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subparagraph id="H0611EFA7BE394B4A9A1E38BAE86F2174" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">liquidated damages in an amount equal to 30 days of back pay, at the rate of compensation calculated under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> <clause id="H1E395F1E9A99456885C719BB5F93F53E"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the flush text following subparagraph (C) (as added by clause (iv)), by striking <quote>a maximum</quote> through <quote>event</quote> and inserting <quote>90 days, plus a day for each day that an employee is on parental, family, or medical leave during the period of violation and for each day that an employee has such leave curtailed due to such employment loss. In no event shall an employer be liable</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H14E380628F504A1FB74839FC90C99D31"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A), by inserting <quote>, which begins on the date of the employment loss</quote> after <quote>the violation</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60F43018A6BB4C51BB37E0B733B1AD04"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by inserting <quote>the Secretary, a State, or</quote> before <quote>a unit of local government</quote>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4127E50E8A754F19996EC3616DD440A1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text> <clause id="H6FD6E2E305EF4CEF996894FB55CEF3D8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>which has violated this Act</quote> and inserting <quote>that has violated the provisions of section 3 with respect to the Secretary, a State, or a unit of local government</quote>;</text></clause>
<clause id="HED2A70DE97E147FD8D1C4E9EE675A33C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>omission that violated this Act</quote> and inserting <quote>omission that violated such provisions</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="HAA72DF60751B44CAB872054717202DE5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>violation of this Act</quote> and inserting <quote>violation of such provisions</quote>; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H81E394745E4F4D418FC11A805536DD08"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by striking <quote>reduce the amount of the liability or penalty provided for in this section</quote> and inserting <quote>reduce the amount of the penalty under paragraph (3)</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC90E600FE27C4A219975FEA70679AFCA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (5) and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H7C27CD38373945A89624806E4DFB8FED" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="HC47AE5A1909A4869B883F150F574D1B1" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3D26D3F899E148AD99845F9BDECBAAB7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A person (including a representative of employees, the State where the site closing or mass layoff is to occur, the entity designated by the State to carry out rapid response activities under section 134(a)(2)(A) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3174">29 U.S.C. 3174(a)(2)(A)</external-xref>), or a unit of local government aggrieved under paragraph (1) or (3)) seeking to enforce the liability provided for in this section may, either for such person, for other persons similarly situated, or for both, sue in any district court of the United States for any district in which the violation is alleged to have occurred or in which the employer transacts business.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H56BAB16457624CD09AE15454E728C057" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A person’s right to institute (including on behalf of other persons) or benefit from enforcement under subparagraph (A) shall not be affected by any predispute agreement, including any predispute arbitration agreement or predispute joint-action waiver (as such terms are defined in section 401 of title 9, United States Code).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF145ECB418C84369BEB9F864E8D068C7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking <quote>prevailing party</quote> and inserting <quote>prevailing plaintiff</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD5A44E7B0DA247738500A1493D529460"><enum>(G)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking <quote>plant</quote> and inserting <quote>site</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4A66C5D37DC647DE875EF0F770B8396D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (b) as subsection (c);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3B2742703AB948FDB0FBED18780BB1C0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H99B59B1899DF44ABBCEBE623C43CA580" style="OLC">
<subsection id="H82EE64198C364C2E98A0D4CDEED73563"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>An action shall be brought under this section not later than 4 years after the date of the last event constituting the alleged violation for which the action is brought.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9E92183E3E74B35967E4598D08E490A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (c), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>plant</quote> and inserting <quote>site</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0AAC0379D1FE44E9B6B5330E06CB1BC4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HF261C74F6F9F4E72926E28D018FCDB6F" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H4B3B7F22A9A04DDA8034052C5890EB70"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exemption from liquidated damages</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a)(1)(C), an employer is not liable for the liquidated damages described in such subsection if the alleged site closing or mass layoff is caused by business circumstances (other than a financier’s decision) that were not contemplated nor should reasonably have been contemplated as of the 30th day before the site closing or mass layoff.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H693503C23DE64257BF6375E18DD27BD6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Database</header>
<paragraph id="H70F9F89D1CCD4F6E8E85DCB65970262A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Transmittals</header><text>A State or designated entity that receives a notice under section 3(a) shall transmit a copy of the notice to the Secretary.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA02C11378CF742E6906E5523B383FC5F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Database</header><text>The Secretary shall create and maintain a publicly available database that provides information from notices transmitted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDB46A7A37965479EB350D5ADBBAC8AB6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents of database</header><text>The database under paragraph (2) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H03B318EC9F09453EB5FC791C2847DB4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for each notice transmitted under paragraph (1), a copy of the notice, the date of the notice, the name of the employer involved, the unit of local government affected by the closing or layoff involved, the number of employees so affected, the sector in which the layoff occurred (as identified by the North American Industry Classification System code), and the type of the closing or layoff;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H208107D4EB0A40609FAD2950848C4417"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a search function that allows users to identify the geographic, annual, and sectoral breakdown of the notices; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC58BA3EF650148F1B63C57DEE793F53B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a function that allows the data to be downloaded in a user-friendly format.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H95AF8DE29F954F4E9D6F7DB29EB70005"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Access through website</header><text>The Secretary shall provide a link to the database through the internet website of the Department of Labor.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="H2C95E8150A0149E28111C2D7C4409FCE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Posting of notices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 11 of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2101">29 U.S.C. 2101</external-xref> note) is amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block id="H30BFB429E5794FF3B2E2BC6D7DC06233" style="OLC">
<section id="H63BA4ED5325145619781B7471849D9A0"><enum>11.</enum><header>Posting of notices</header>
<subsection id="H713A4B5FA7E842F8BFF0331A2EFC55D5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Posting of notices</header><text>Each employer shall post and keep posted, in conspicuous places upon the premises of the employer where notices to employees are customarily posted, a notice to be prepared or approved by the Secretary setting forth excerpts from, or summaries of, the pertinent provisions of this Act and information pertinent to the filing of a complaint under this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD717FCC3D8184B61BAD06A492C05FB2D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The Secretary may impose a civil penalty on any person who willfully violates this section of not more than $500 for each separate offense.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="H4E53BAAC0FCF46459DA92406F9EE5FC8"><enum>6.</enum><header>Non-waiver of rights and remedies; information regarding benefits and services available to employees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2101">29 U.S.C. 2101 et seq.</external-xref>) is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HA32EA00528184F23B8A009FC8CFDA123" style="OLC"> <section id="HD7BCA9D45A5344DB9D3AF71BB07190C0"><enum>12.</enum><header>Rights and remedies not subject to waiver</header> <subsection id="H73A787725CF34386A9E44E89AB946E82"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The rights and remedies provided under this Act (including the right to file or participate in a class action under rule 23 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure in Federal court) are substantive and may not be waived, deferred, or lost pursuant to any agreement or settlement other than an agreement or settlement described in subsection (b).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HF2B230EF5D9B426D8CABE2ADE66AB07B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agreement or settlement</header><text>An agreement or settlement referred to in subsection (a) is an agreement or settlement negotiated by—</text> <paragraph id="HFD98D40957964532A9F457684E71069A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a private attorney on behalf of affected employees; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H70293DA8542444A5983EE3AB8F62E630"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a designated representative of affected employees under the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/151">29 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) or the Railway Labor Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/151">45 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H9EDFE791FF094535BC0BA85D883F4390"><enum>13.</enum><header>Information regarding benefits and services available to workers</header> <subsection id="H36002A404A394A48B66B0C381529C9F2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall maintain a guide of benefits and services that may be available to affected employees, including unemployment compensation, trade adjustment assistance, COBRA continuation coverage, and early access to training services and other services, including counseling services, available under title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3111">29 U.S.C. 3111 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H216E7F4A99824E0A955A7A9D27482A15"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability of guide</header><text>The guide maintained under subsection (a) shall be available on the internet website of the Department of Labor and shall include a description of the benefits and services, the eligibility requirements, and the means of obtaining such benefits and services.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0CB71C04F04241CBBBF9764F3ECFB03B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transmission to employers</header><text>Upon receiving notice from an employer under section 3(a)(2), the Secretary shall immediately transmit such guide to such employer.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="HBACFF1AB0E2549A692B570009319208A"><enum>7.</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
<subsection id="HC633939BCD594BBFA5BC28BBCDFFA145"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Worker adjustment and retraining notification act</header><text>The Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD6EC750255744CC3B42A1A83D5C52945"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the table of contents in section 1(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2101">29 U.S.C. 2101</external-xref> note)—</text>
<subparagraph id="HD3C86727555C41258047E8F959DADB4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to section 3 and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEDEB9C4F22534137ADD3AB904748EE16" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 3. Notice required before site closings and mass layoffs.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H68343C1613BA41C79075F078AFCA07BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to section 11 and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE1E1A5BA96EB473694E09997B9B25811" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 11. Posting of notices.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">and</continuation-text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H79AA729F8CC744718C9323DC0C043F5C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H04F114D0123E4934B733E3251C7A2367" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 12. Rights and remedies not subject to waiver.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 13. Information regarding benefits and services available to workers.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">and</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H44CF853809DE43BE9B2CC1955E8A5FC1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 7 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2106">29 U.S.C. 2106</external-xref>), by striking <quote>plant</quote> and inserting <quote>site</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HCE9A99B7AF7A4C4E909C27113F3A86B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other laws</header><text>Section 3110(a)(5) of the USEC Privatization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2297h-8">42 U.S.C. 2297h–8(a)(5)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2101(a) (2) and (3) of title 29, United States Code</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 2(a) of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2101">29 U.S.C. 2101(a)</external-xref>), as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Fair Warning Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

