<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB4D0D373F0BC4F29A539788742D1116C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2426 IH: Veterans Mental Health and Addiction Therapy Quality of Care Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2426</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a study on the quality of care difference between mental health and addiction therapy care provided by health care providers of the Department of Veterans Affairs compared to non-Department providers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBF52FBBE490D4A0E99459EC1340657DF" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H00DDFF9734EA4D9091551FC481C62BF8"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Mental Health and Addiction Therapy Quality of Care Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD038E1F3991140719545624D6E690F13"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on quality of care difference between mental health and addiction therapy care provided by health care providers of Department of Veterans Affairs compared to non-Department providers</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF6361A6DAE74A408FC95CA35C946832"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall seek to enter into an agreement with an independent and objective organization outside the Department of Veterans Affairs under which that organization shall—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H35BA7D41DF794FD781C1171F2ECBB7EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct a study on the quality of care difference between mental health and addiction therapy care under the laws administered by the Secretary provided by health care providers of the Department compared to non-Department providers across various modalities, such as telehealth, in-patient, intensive out-patient, out-patient, and residential treatment; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE857A25A513E4595A79B2CB50DD0C687"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and publish on a publicly available website a report containing the final results of such study.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H43538B1FA0E041FEAAE500D102E339D7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the organization with which the Secretary enters into an agreement pursuant to subsection (a) is able to complete the requirements under such subsection by not later than 18 months after the date on which the agreement is entered into.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H091A2BDCF2FF44438B1C053CF5B73166"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report submitted pursuant to subsection (a)(2) shall include an assessment of the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H0237F7D1B6894208BAFA37F8A91B4613"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The amount of improvement in health outcomes from start of treatment to completion, including symptom scores and suicide risk using evidence-based scales, including the Columbia-Suicide Severity Rating Scale.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB05074D887414909A9EFAF515E7B45F9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Whether providers of the Department and non-Department providers are using evidence-based practices in the treatment of mental health and addiction therapy care, including criteria set forth by the American Society of Addiction Medicine.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF093C53480B94D0EB0A7BC2C34E314FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Potential gaps in coordination between providers of the Department and non-Department providers in responding to individuals seeking mental health or addiction therapy care, including the sharing of patient health records.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H74F491E9264D43DE95B2AFC41B4B5094"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Implementation of veteran-centric care, including the level of satisfaction of patients with care and the competency of providers with the unique experiences and needs of the military and veteran population.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEB92C2699C864F94805B97B170753EC7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Whether veterans with co-occurring conditions receive integrated care to holistically address their needs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H846CA98DAD7440FE9D41B83269CC0C46"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Whether providers monitor health outcomes continually throughout treatment and at regular intervals for up to three years after treatment.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB15068D220A744EDBDFB1B5ECE523F47"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The average length of time to initiate services, which shall include a comparison of the average length of time between the initial point of contact after patient outreach to the point of initial service, as measured or determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

