<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H70502A13D3F242619263D9A9C221F749" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 772 IH: Rural ER Access Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 772</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250128">January 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000590">Mr. Green of Tennessee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to revise regulations to remove the requirement under the Medicare program that an off-campus facility or organization shall be located within a 35-mile radius of a hospital or critical access hospital.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF3ECB0E7C1AD41FB899F7A39FE3805EB" style="OLC"><section id="H1257FA0FD6044FFC89647868B05A3C24" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may cited as the <quote><short-title>Rural ER Access Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H851243D0FAEE4FDF9D8ADCFEE6FB29CD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Removing location requirements under the Medicare program applicable to off-campus facilities or organizations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall revise section 413.65(e)(3)(i) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), to remove the requirement under the Medicare program that an off-campus facility or organization shall be located within a 35-mile radius of the campus of a hospital or critical access hospital that is the potential main provider to meet the location requirements to be eligible for provider-based status.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

