<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25F15-94G-XC-0S4">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2550 IS: Critical Minerals Partnership Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2550</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250730">July 30, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on
                    Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To provide for international cooperation to secure critical mineral supply
            chains, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="id6f0498d9585444e1866e8e3f50df8c51">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Critical Minerals Partnership Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id286b6e06d460457a87e5a658032d6b9b">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definition of critical mineral</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>critical mineral</term>—</text>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB0E55EC3C1664F02A58769AFF9FEC494">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the meaning given the term in section 7002 of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606</external-xref>); and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD2E5B3EA66B2437C897DD6DF579DE869">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes any other mineral or mineral material determined by the Secretary of State—</text>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id68777CD6132A49E9B16AC6DDA1FBB28B">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to be essential to the economic or national security of the United States; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="idB4FBC953DAD749A28D87702ADC1A165C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to have a supply chain vulnerable to disruption.</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC846D7DECE604E5593CE56E5524C5DEE">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Statement of policy on critical mineral
                supply chains</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text> <paragraph id="id4ad2c7d902504d8a9bbec0003ebcd01e"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>to collaborate with allies and partners of the United States to build secure and resilient critical minerals supply chains, including in the mining, processing, reclamation and recycling, and valuation of critical minerals;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id3b784e1c93084263bb1b7bcd8091926c">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>to prioritize the development and production of critical mineral resources domestically, including through improvement of systems for collecting and recycling critical minerals from used and discarded goods or equipment, both to supply domestic needs and for export to allies and partners that participate in secure and resilient supply chains for critical minerals;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idcb7f0937fc6a41f1879087f6ee73e5e3">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>to reduce or eliminate reliance and dependence on critical mineral supply chains controlled by the People’s Republic of China, the Russian Federation, Iran, or any other adversary of the United States;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idcfb64c24146b4a88b44b4e05db255bff">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>to work with allies and partners on enhancing evaluation capability and technology in trusted countries that produce critical minerals to avoid the export of critical minerals, or products or components that are dependent on critical minerals, that are controlled by adversaries of the United States;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idfffadf796ee44d799a7adb0d80101ab6">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>to identify and implement market-based incentives for the purposes of facilitating the creation and maintenance of secure and resilient critical mineral supply chains, including for reclamation and recycling of critical mineral resources from waste streams, in collaboration with allies and partners;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id581ad2f79dc94b7d81cd85727db19253">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>to prioritize securing critical mineral supply chains in United States foreign policy, including through the use of economic tools to invest responsibly in projects in partner countries in a manner that both benefits local populations and bolsters the supply of critical minerals to the United States and allies and partners of the United States; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ideb6033c9812d43a2aa9e90472e5bc268">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>that collaboration with allies and partners to build secure and resilient critical mineral supply chains shall not replace United States efforts to increase domestic development and production or recycling of critical minerals.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="id5813FAE96AAC49DA9A1BA49556B76AD1">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>International negotiations relating to protecting critical mineral supply
                chains</header>
            <subsection id="id41769a477b7148b0adc80a6af79c118a">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>The President is authorized to negotiate an agreement with international partners for the purposes of establishing a coalition—</text>
                <paragraph id="idDC75C5F113094EF69831FB983B41E412">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>to facilitate—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id59B4C873267F49D89026BF4358F27CA9"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the mining, processing, recycling, and enhanced access to the supply of critical minerals; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCF7A83F572D04D08B64783223F01C318">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advanced manufacturing that relies on the practical application of critical minerals; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idD0DB321E3E9E4E9BB9EA9C83C90B87ED">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>to secure an adequate supply of critical minerals and relevant products, manufacturing inputs, and components that are heavily dependent on critical mineral resource inputs for the United States and other members of the coalition (in this section referred to as <quote>member countries</quote>).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idE626EA93DF3C4140A6315A04900694BE">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Negotiating objectives</header>
 <text>The overall objectives for negotiating an agreement described in subsection (a) should be—</text>
                <paragraph id="id3E4E2BC22F3C4D2C85F6F247B6A556E8">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>to establish mechanisms for member countries to build secure and resilient supply chains for critical minerals, including in—</text>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC8095B0B4D1E4C9988E2FDF299ACA0CC">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the mining, refinement, reclamation and recycling, processing, and valuation of critical minerals; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6B8DF244C0B6468E9A5FEDB085EB6C46">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advanced manufacturing of products, components, and materials that are dependent on critical minerals;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idfe54db1855234aaf88ddd7e032db15dc">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>to improve economies of scale and joint cooperation with international partners in securing access and means of production throughout the supply chains of critical minerals and manufacturing processes dependent on critical minerals;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id3B23496A63AF45B9BA16DB7D97AD8396">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>to establish mechanisms, with appropriate market-based disciplines, that provide and maintain opportunities among member countries for creating industry economies of scale to attract joint investment among those countries, including—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="idFC13D9862116452D870C4AE84CACFAC4">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>cooperation on joint projects, including cost-sharing on building appropriate infrastructure to access deposits of critical minerals; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idD04714413D86499786DF4D0EE03676E7">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>creation or enhancement of national and international programs to support the development of robust industries by providing appropriate sector-specific incentives, such as political risk and other insurance opportunities, financing, and other support, for—</text>
                        <clause id="idAB5164E2B28E40558645355FBDFA7D65">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>mining and processing critical minerals;</text> </clause> <clause id="id0D44051B203349688CDB44B15D0DEB92"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>manufacturing of products, components, and materials that are dependent on critical minerals and are essential to consumer technology products or have important national security implications;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id4b209b748e054374a586d2642df82289">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>building capacities and creating incentives for recovering used, spent, or discarded equipment and consumer goods containing critical minerals to be safely handled and recycled; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="idDB60A4A43EDD4D4F93A98F1D7DF7664B">
                            <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>associated transportation needs that are tailored to the handling, movement, and logistics management of critical minerals and products, components, and materials that are dependent on critical minerals;</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idF7A5CC34B64B48AABC3BDF1EE893FC49">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>to establish market-based rules for member countries regarding adoption of qualifying tax and other incentives to stimulate investment, as balanced by market-based disciplines to ensure a fair playing field among those countries;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idA917BABC1A5A47EBBF8882EE0E8C62C3">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>to establish recommended best practices to protect—</text> <subparagraph id="id88ad669070e343cb89846837f3faaece"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>labor rights;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idA6BF51C0F65C47D399A730E2129E8B47">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the natural environment and ecosystems near critical mineral industrial sites; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id9B8C90BAFE024430A0D9253AA1658465">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>safety of communities near critical mineral industrial activities;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idCB2103CA180B424998AFC43B7EDCA76E">
                    <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>to advance economic growth in developing countries with critical mineral reserves and capacities for the recovery and recycling of critical minerals, including for the benefit of the citizens of those countries;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idC3647B7415C448C1A765B70B02818538">
                    <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>to establish rules allowing for the establishment of a consortium that is resourced and empowered to bid and compete in acquiring and securing potential deposits of critical minerals in countries that are not members of the coalition described in subsection (a) (in this section referred to as <quote>nonmember countries</quote>);</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id12A294C96D9643A39A97698F67C1AA7C">
                    <enum>(8)</enum>
 <text>to establish a mechanism for joint resource mapping with procedures for equitable sharing of information on potential deposits of critical minerals not less frequently than annually;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id170C71C91557475A81FCD3AB85A05511">
                    <enum>(9)</enum>
 <text>to establish appropriate mechanisms for the recognition and enforcement by a member country of judgments relating to environmental and related harms caused by mining operations within the territory of the member country in contravention of that country’s laws; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id61F970AE0BCD40A38DE3AEC87BE5E896">
                    <enum>(10)</enum>
 <text>to improve supply chain security among member countries by providing for national treatment investment protections among those countries that are equal to, or better than, the standards in the United States model bilateral investment treaty.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id09e3b78b4bf44ef6a02efbe158f6d890">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Congressional consultations required</header>
 <text>In the course of negotiations described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall consult closely and on a timely basis with, and keep fully apprised of the negotiations, the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="idF4C16C52A8914D87A79086069F4FB01F">
            <enum>5.</enum>
            <header>Minerals Security Partnership authorization</header>
            <subsection id="ida8cb365a728e43429684b85681655701">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Secretary of State, acting through the Under Secretary of State for Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment, is authorized to lead United States participation in the Minerals Security Partnership, for the following purposes:</text>
                <paragraph id="id72ee5439661c49bbaa68f934f25d2968">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>To identify and support investment and advocate for commercial critical mineral mining, processing, and refining projects that enable robust and secure critical mineral supply chains, in consultation with other Federal agencies, as appropriate.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id90E95D03CDA84A2AB3AEB070B0FE3A5F">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>To coordinate with relevant regional bureaus to develop regional diplomatic engagement strategies related to critical minerals projects and to identify projects that are priorities.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idCFA1C4A4ADE84BFCAF96DDE2E4B82093">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>To coordinate with United States missions abroad on projects, programs, and investments that enable robust and secure critical mineral supply chains.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id29BADA5D0F4641548040C2629B20777A">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>To coordinate with current and prospective members of the Minerals Security Partnership.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id1e77ec0c4fa2471b9b69d30457e94a4f">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>To establish a mechanism for information-sharing with members of the Minerals Security Partnership.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id5dc06355b80a40d6bf3175110fbaf5be">
                    <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>To establish policies and procedures, and if necessary, to provide funding to facilitate cooperation on joint projects with members of the Minerals Security Partnership and the Minerals Security Forum, including those related to cost-sharing agreements, political risk insurance, financing, equity investments, and other support, in coordination with other Federal agencies, as appropriate.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idF848F62A97604D41922FC61A2E367B07">
                    <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>If an agreement described in section 4 is entered into, to support the establishment of the coalition described in that section.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id473f7f13f4c845558d1c08b94977ee0b">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Database</header>
 <text>As part of the Minerals Security Partnership, the Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary, is authorized to establish and maintain a database of critical mineral projects for the purpose of providing high quality and up-to-date information to the private sector and, at the discretion of the Under Secretary, to members of the Minerals Security Partnership, in order to spur greater investment, increase the resilience of global critical minerals supply chains, and boost United States supply.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id1114DCEEEA06461585C8E669AC8DE2B4">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Qualifications for personnel</header>
 <text>With respect to staffing personnel to carry out the Minerals Security Partnership, the Secretary shall prioritize individuals with the following qualifications:</text>
                <paragraph id="id724EE592F6064E51963E8D81F1A218A7">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>Substantive knowledge and experience in issues related to critical minerals supply chain and their application to strategic industries, including in the defense, energy, and technology sectors.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id11302F8E2FC04D91A8E8F7865D656B15">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Substantive knowledge and experience in large-scale multi-donor project financing and related technical and diplomatic arrangements, international coalition-building, and project management.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id2FFA47D5E3954428B7F4361CE06F0065">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>Substantive knowledge and experience in trade and foreign policy, defense industrial base policy, or national security-sensitive supply chain issues.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id7e1a88b651d1441295f575944be92eff">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Private sector coordination</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall ensure close coordination between the Department of State, the private sector, and relevant civil society groups on the implementation of this section.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="ide6633c025e5042cdb04e3510a5a3aac4">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Project selection</header>
                <paragraph id="id419ac8dc1a5949a8aa09efa44d0d3739">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>The United States, through its participation in the Minerals Security Partnership, shall prioritize projects that advance the national and economic security interests of the United States and allies and partners of the United States.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id3644e20159314eb79bff226d008984ed">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Criteria requirements</header>
 <text>The United States should advocate for the Minerals Security Partnership to use environmental, social, or governance standards, including as criteria for project selection, that are consistent with United States law or international agreements approved by Congress.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="ide0207c36b0d0419caf9f33da132686aa">
            <enum>6.</enum>
            <header>United States membership in the International Nickel Study Group</header>
            <subsection id="idc7a59a0b5cf645dbbe66a7d481accbdb">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>United States membership</header>
 <text>The President is authorized to accept the Terms of Reference of and maintain membership of the United States in the International Nickel Study Group.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idbdc7a19f682c454a9571d145ef70b958">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Payments of assessed contributions</header>
 <text>For fiscal year 2025 and thereafter, the United States assessed contributions to the International Nickel Study Group may be paid from funds appropriated for <quote>Contributions to International Organizations</quote>.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="id65016CEDA1D146F4ADC58E5F55F68133" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline">
            <enum>7.</enum>
            <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of State $50,000,000 for fiscal year 2026 to enhance critical mineral supply chain security, including to implement this Act.</text>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

