<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL25048-X2N-0G-WTP"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S94 IS: Miracle on Ice Congressional Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 94</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250115">January 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To award 3 Congressional Gold Medals to the members of the 1980 United States Olympic Men’s Ice Hockey Team, in recognition of their extraordinary achievement at the XIII Olympic Winter Games where, being comprised of amateur collegiate players, they defeated the dominant Soviet ice hockey team in the historic <quote>Miracle on Ice</quote>, revitalizing morale in the United States at the height of the Cold War, inspiring generations, and transforming the sport of ice hockey in the United States.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H416BB18387DB47B195DB2081E5F52838"><section commented="no" section-type="section-one" id="H0928C6A1350B43D5AA52717B47F65BBD"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Miracle on Ice Congressional Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H5D6E7CAB9D154D859625B0A959EC37A2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H836E96D15FEA404F9341368485561A20"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Olympic Men’s Ice Hockey Team competed at the 1980 Winter Olympics, officially the XIII Olympic Winter Games and known as the 1980 Lake Placid games, from February 13 to 24, 1980, in Lake Placid, New York.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD83450CCCE4146A2862464168944047C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Team USA, comprised of collegiate players, defeated the defending Olympic champion the Soviet Union 4–3 on February 22, 1980, in the final round of the 1980 Winter Olympics men’s ice hockey tournament.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FCD59A3680742799C63344217D968D1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The 1980 United States Olympic Men’s Ice Hockey Team roster included—</text><subparagraph id="HBBC6785F2C414FF7A3E876715CFB3E2E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Bill Baker (Grand Rapids, Minnesota);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED5EA16F0F9B4971BA630096946A5A93"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Neal Broten (Roseau, Minnesota);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H087C6E62AC7042FBB7F0D4761C1457B6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Dave Christian (Warroad, Minnesota);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H624B3CDFF4D245618F9EC425C09BFF8E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Steve Christoff (Richfield, Minnesota);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC40501E8E8A4BC398B41DFC82B6364E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Jim Craig (North Easton, Massachusetts);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F31C4334FF04C4390C857F9C766EE37"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Mike Eruzione (Winthrop, Massachusetts);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCF7A507ABF847CEACB6B4829C4C5F49"><enum>(G)</enum><text>John Harrington (Virginia, Minnesota);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AD1182C9F854F4A83E5A25F74BF797E"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Steve Janaszak (Saint Paul, Minnesota);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC144EA7182214C13A1D0CACC0B0597D7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Mark Johnson (Madison, Wisconsin);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1301CBFBA744BE38A3F234A55D23B51"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Rob McClanahan (Saint Paul, Minnesota);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4CA75F258F64F46A043C029902B99B9"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Ken Morrow (Flint, Michigan);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6FA03A65CC54B958A2F485716FEB9BA"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Jack O’Callahan (Charlestown, Massachusetts);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF61891F355E4835B894C1C128BACA32"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Mark Pavelich (Eveleth, Minnesota);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23909BA107D24661AED06511B4F74C1B"><enum>(N)</enum><text>Mike Ramsey (Minneapolis, Minnesota);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H897C0030897349CF93FA87B52E1CB66B"><enum>(O)</enum><text>Buzz Schneider (Grand Rapids, Minnesota);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0E5EA1A8B8B4B74B9636038D9BB42DA"><enum>(P)</enum><text>Dave Silk (Scituate, Massachusetts);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6FF31E119BB4424998D82DC6B490DC0"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>Eric Strobel (Rochester, Minnesota);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95F4CA09B5B24EC79DDF22F792EA382C"><enum>(R)</enum><text>Bob Suter (Madison, Wisconsin);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE100659E04A48BF899E30440A64D089"><enum>(S)</enum><text>Mark Wells (St. Clair Shores, Michigan); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D7A789D25D4461980F6AED9D522F2C8"><enum>(T)</enum><text>Phil Verchota (Duluth, Minnesota).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2274A8B1223B4594ABED8569005B60D8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The <quote>Miracle on Ice</quote> United States and Soviet Union final round game aired on tape delay on Feb 22, 1980, from Lake Placid and drew 34,200,000 average viewers. The match is remembered as a <quote>miracle</quote> as collegiate ice hockey players defied expectations in defeating a Soviet team that won 4 consecutive gold medals dating back to 1964.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF440B870F904412194009F80AF81B558"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Team USA defeated Finland 4–1 in its final game to win the gold medal, its first gold medal since 1960 in men’s ice hockey.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8109DAFF3ADA44B088FCC2D58BECD7FD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Herb Brooks, the last player cut from the 1960 United States Olympic Men's Ice Hockey Team that won gold at Squaw Valley, guided the 1980 team to its historic gold medal. Known as a motivator, Brooks molded a team built around hard work, belief in oneself, and belief in teammates. He reminded his team when they played the Soviets, <quote>you were born to be hockey players, everyone one of you … and you were meant to be here</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CF14D4CAE1F47499C6DDAD31C6B3204"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The tournament occurred at a time when the United States was struggling with rampant stagflation, high gas prices, hostages held in Iran, and increased tensions with the Soviet Union whose invasion of Afghanistan led to the boycott of the 1980 Summer Olympics.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3EE77B313DAA49D892FE57F3778DB2C8"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Miracle on Ice was a turning point for ice hockey in the United States. The game was named the greatest sports moment of the 20th century by Sports Illustrated.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6E6F3602A52404EB0155157C7633F06"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The historic win brought ice hockey to the front-page of newspapers everywhere, and forever opened the door to the National Hockey League for players born in the United States. The impact of the event was far-reaching and is still being felt today.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEF7EE644DD547F5B6D64F3E20A09395"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Since 1980, interest in the United States in the sport of ice hockey has increased exponentially. Registrations with USA Hockey have increased by nearly 400 percent since 1980 from 136,000 to over 564,000, and the number of National Hockey League players from the United States has increased from 72 in 1980 to 245 in 2024.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H41A63CD6B4224EDBB27559E9FD933557"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional gold medals</header><subsection id="HF7CC3B1AB0704BDEABB2A3FB7A40E77D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Award authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the award, on behalf of Congress, of 3 gold medals of appropriate design to the members of the 1980 United States Olympic Men’s Ice Hockey Team, in recognition of their extraordinary achievement at the XIII Olympic Winter Games where, being comprised of amateur collegiate players, they defeated the dominant Soviet hockey team in the historic <quote>Miracle on Ice</quote>, revitalizing morale in the United States at the height of the Cold War, inspiring generations, and transforming the sport of ice hockey in the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB1385DD7041843F2A7A38EC19BBCC0C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text>For the purposes of the award referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike gold medals with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions to be determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H7DF7CF93925B486588DFE080C5CA5CC0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disposition of medals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the award of the gold medals under subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="H91DD963F584F44AAA3A764E2D0732103"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">one gold medal shall be given to the Lake Placid Olympic Center in Lake Placid, New York, where it shall be displayed and made available for research, as appropriate; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H070708E660254DD5A3692C483C0C1956"><enum>(2)</enum><text>one gold medal shall be given to the United States Hockey Hall of Fame Museum in Eveleth, Minnesota, where it shall be displayed and made available for research, as appropriate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BBA6A4EB0904153A6A0895FF8E34093"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">one gold medal shall be given to the United States Olympic &amp; Paralympic Museum in Colorado Springs, Colorado, where it shall be displayed and made available for research, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6D6F66D6C8DE434EB8F44E9049217851"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medals struck under section 3, at a price sufficient to cover the costs thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section><section id="HC065416BD0ED45469AEAF4D4814B24DD"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header><subsection id="H4042F37D91D7484A8541215AB3E13721"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>Medals struck under this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBB5F298D8D494A8DBF42AE4BBE3B8826"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section><section id="HEDDC7830000A4EB1B9A5C22E7BDC0261"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header><subsection id="H1335239BFA344484A698F7AAADEED297"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To use fund amounts</header><text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H31969AEA0599415EB481AE01B3922EFF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 4 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

