<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25229-TH2-3S-43C"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 125 IS: Commemorating the centennial of Delta Air Lines. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 125</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250312">March 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S414">Mr. Ossoff</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commemorating the centennial of Delta Air Lines. </official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on March 2, 2025, Delta Air Lines turns 100 years old, becoming the first United States airline to reach the centenarian milestone;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Delta Air Lines was founded on March 2, 1925, as Huff Daland Dusters—the world’s first aerial crop-dusting company;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Delta Air Service and the airline’s first flights took off 4 years later;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2025, Delta Air Lines's team of 100,000 people supports up to 5,000 daily flights serving more than 200,000,000 travelers per year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Delta Air Lines maintains hubs from coast to coast, including in Georgia, Massachusetts, New York, Washington, California, Michigan, Minnesota, and Utah;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, with thousands of peak-day departures to more than 290 global destinations on 6 continents, Delta Air Lines connects millions of people around the globe to and through the United States daily and helps keep the United States a top country for business and the economy of the United States strong;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for the past 100 years, the mission of Delta Air Lines to connect the world has included a commitment to being a strong partner in the communities where its people live, work, and serve; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2025, Delta was named North America’s most on-time airline by Cirium, the Top United States Airline by the Wall Street Journal, the World’s Most Admired Airline by Fortune, and the top-ranked airline on Time’s inaugural World’s Best Companies List: Now, therefore be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="ida177158ef25741cfa3281aa138b486e1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes Delta Air Lines for 100 years of connecting people to the world and to each other; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idefe1f93cc48f4e6b85f1cf53f3ec9d85"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commemorates the centennial of Delta Air Lines. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

