<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25897-FHV-PD-3N4">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2620 IS: Reforming Evergreening and Manipulation that Extends Drug Years Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2620</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250731">July 31, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on
                    Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to approval
            of abbreviated new drug applications.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="S1">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reforming Evergreening and Manipulation that Extends Drug Years Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>REMEDY Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id0C9AEC0F38DB4BE08DDD4E5C2FB8E8A6">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Amendments to ANDA approval provisions</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
            <paragraph id="idE965B48A76A74684A8AEDA1CB381772A">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)(2) by adding at the end the following: <quote>With respect to a drug approved on or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Reforming Evergreening and Manipulation that Extends Drug Years Act</short-title>, when a holder of an approved application first files information under this paragraph with respect to one or more patents described in subsection (b)(1)(A)(viii), the holder shall select one such patent with respect to which the owner or licensee may be eligible for the thirty-month period under paragraph (3)(C) or subsection (j)(5)(B)(iii), as applicable; for purposes of paragraphs (3)(C) and (3)(E)(ii) and subsections (j)(5)(B)(iii) and (j)(5)(F)(ii), such patent shall be referred to as the <quote>covered patent</quote>. The selection of such covered patent may not be changed or amended.</quote>;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id4EE2A51E125345D892B8EEF2876ADAE4">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)(3)(C)—</text> <subparagraph id="idFE478017C59E460A811DC08F320A6031"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>in the matter preceding clause (i)—</text>
                    <clause id="idc48fbec248d0411498a7fd0518fa6ae0">
                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>by striking <quote>an action is brought for infringement</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end of the first sentence and inserting <quote>with respect to a drug approved under this subsection before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Reforming Evergreening and Manipulation that Extends Drug Years Act</short-title>, an action is brought for infringement of any patent that is the subject of the certification and for which information was submitted to the Secretary under paragraph (2) before the date on which the application (excluding an amendment or supplement to the application) was submitted, or, with respect to a drug approved under this subsection on or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Reforming Evergreening and Manipulation that Extends Drug Years Act</short-title>, an action is brought for infringement of the covered patent (as described in paragraph (2)) that is the subject of the certification and for which information was submitted to the Secretary under paragraph (2) before the date on which the application (excluding an amendment or supplement to the application) was submitted.</quote>; and</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="id7a4a00bef32a442c93b89fa7ccce07a7">
                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>by striking <quote>an action is brought before</quote> and inserting <quote>an action with respect to a patent or a covered patent, as applicable, is brought before</quote>; and</text>
                    </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="id1141603A065D45BD90C6F902B0FA88A1">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>decides that the patent</quote> and inserting <quote>decides that the patent or the covered patent, as applicable</quote>;</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id96ACED06F8554467AC7A23340E2A2696">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>in the second sentence of subsection (c)(3)(E)(ii), by inserting <quote>with respect to any patent for which the requirements are met for the thirty-month period described in subparagraph (C)</quote> after <quote>action for patent infringement</quote>;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idCC951B38CF354E9F8056367AF151CF0B">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (j)(5)(B)(iii)—</text> <subparagraph id="id856E642F74A24CAB838F11F050660E52"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding subclause (I)—</text>
                    <clause id="id0A22A80FCE774EDDAAE9904D071FC31A">
                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>by striking <quote>an action is brought for infringement</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end of the first sentence and inserting <quote>with respect to a drug approved under subsection (c) before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Reforming Evergreening and Manipulation that Extends Drug Years Act</short-title>, an action is brought for infringement of any patent that is the subject of the certification and for which information was submitted to the Secretary under subsection (c)(2) before the date on which the application (excluding an amendment or supplement to the application), which the Secretary later determines to be substantially complete, was submitted, or, with respect to a drug approved under subsection (c) on or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Reforming Evergreening and Manipulation that Extends Drug Years Act</short-title>, an action is brought for infringement of the covered patent (as described in subsection (c)(2)) that is the subject of the certification and for which information was submitted to the Secretary under subsection (c)(2) before the date on which the application (excluding an amendment or supplement to the application), which the Secretary later determines to be substantially complete, was submitted.</quote>; and</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="id4711FD98AA2349B99921A15DF9958CE6">
                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>by striking <quote>an action is brought before</quote> and inserting <quote>an action with respect to a patent or a covered patent, as applicable, is brought before</quote>; and</text>
                    </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="id88B39F5E6A014C2B8FFDA56E812E5D06">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in subclause (I), by striking <quote>decides that the patent</quote> and inserting <quote>decides that the patent or covered patent, as applicable,</quote>; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id33DB01E1C6A7477697555B499260722D">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>in the second sentence of subsection (j)(5)(F)(ii), by inserting <quote>with respect to any patent for which the requirements are met for the thirty-month period described in subparagraph (B)(iii),</quote> after <quote>action for patent infringement</quote>.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

