<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H44F04CFF841243F6B55B15814828B66D"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4813 IH: Noncontiguous Disaster Shipping Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4813</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250729">July 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000404">Ms. King-Hinds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 46, United States Code, to provide for a waiver of navigation or vessel-inspection laws in noncontiguous areas upon a declaration of a major disaster or emergency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA52D844FCE6A4191918537A5354904FA"><section id="H52A8D44E9ED74811ADE4D020A4598415" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Noncontiguous Disaster Shipping Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H54E4D5371EC6418283D7286A11AD451C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Waiver in a noncontiguous area</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 501 of title 46, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HC598183B8E7D4D1F84B3A7D3AA1BD680"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) and (d) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7314D73DDD3C456798087B620C9941F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8BB75508797846569748006CC953546F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H760A9C6DA2A34FE09D662E1C748D0757"><enum>(c)</enum><header>In a Noncontiguous Area</header><paragraph id="H8B44A62621F94F7C9882CD7F89F89776"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon a declaration by the President pursuant to section 401 or 501 the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>; 5191) that a major disaster or emergency exists in a noncontiguous area of the United States, the head of an agency responsible for the administration of the navigation or vessel-inspection laws shall waive compliance with such laws for a vessel transporting cargo to or from the noncontiguous area affected by such major disaster or emergency for the purpose of disaster relief.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE8C1EFA132E425085F80A0EBC0D1ACA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration of waiver</header><subparagraph id="H2674CA2C57A740C98F0EB1F84A461A45"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), a waiver issued under this subsection shall be for a period of not more than 10 days.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1206EF819E134DEE866A421485960B8A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Waiver extension</header><text>Upon the termination of a waiver issued under this subsection, the head of the agency referred to in paragraph (1), in consultation with the Governor of the noncontiguous area affected by such major disaster or emergency, may extend the waiver for an additional period of not more than 10 days.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8398A69748FD4E6A8727826C7D6659CA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Aggregate duration</header><text>The aggregate duration of the period of all waivers and extensions of waivers under this subsection with respect to any one major disaster or emergency shall not exceed 45 days.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H77FDE29082A1484B8190BBBA38CDB11E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice to congress</header><subparagraph id="H630F47DDAFE744DC90DC13B54C2D1C6E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of the agency referred to in paragraph (1) shall notify the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate of the issuance of any waiver of the navigation or vessel-inspection laws under this subsection not later than 48 hours after such issuance.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B9F34CB3E074FD987B184BBD7E2841F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notification required for extensions</header><text>For the purposes of this paragraph, an extension issued under paragraph (2)(B) shall be treated in the same manner as a waiver issued under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H96E7BC31AA254D74B45742EAD0AB5CEA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Noncontiguous area of the United States defined</header><text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term <term>noncontiguous area of the United States</term> means Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Hawaii, and Alaska.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

