<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H302AA21EE74E4FF8B3FB06C83F7245EB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 96 IH: Buzz Off Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 96</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250103">January 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prevent agencies from using unmanned aerial vehicles to conduct surveillance of United States citizens, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBE2FE42E132A4D529728BF3CFC6733ED" style="OLC"><section id="H7F56E0A19F41404DA6D2056D547D79EE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Buzz Off Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H48E6BA331A0F44E6B930954AA63FCAD9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibiting use of unmanned aerial vehicles</header><subsection id="H4426B435EF384E059645D9113CB6518A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Surveillance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal law enforcement agency may not use an unmanned aerial vehicle to intentionally conduct surveillance of, gather evidence or collect information about, or photographically or electronically record a specifically targeted United States citizen or the specifically targeted private property of a United States citizen.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF7012F3E996643CCA4C6D7C203E05461"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), a Federal law enforcement agency may use an unmanned aerial vehicle to photograph, or otherwise record a United States citizen for the purposes of publishing or otherwise publicly disseminating such photograph or recording if the agency obtains the written consent of such United States citizen.</text></subsection><subsection id="H21F983127C8D4003A93E2914184BDFCB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply in the case that—</text><paragraph id="H9058F1DF5168487C823AF68A5444B553"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the President, acting through the Secretary of Homeland Security, authorizes use of an unmanned aerial vehicle to conduct surveillance if the Secretary certifies in writing under oath that the surveillance is necessary to counter a high risk of a terrorist attack by a specific individual or organization; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF4133AB5358418BB6289EF33058F065"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the head of a Federal law enforcement agency first obtains a search warrant signed by a judge authorizing the use of an unmanned aerial vehicle.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

