<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H67556FCA3454486FB72383C2335CF51D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1244 IH: Reducing Drug Prices for Seniors Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1244</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250212">February 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to require that coinsurance for drugs under Medicare part D be based on the drug&#8217;s actual acquisition cost and not the drug&#8217;s wholesale acquisition cost.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5F91D45161FD468097AF5A719366D7DE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4D676A4E659D4D39B84FB6AADCF117F5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reducing Drug Prices for Seniors Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA3DAA31A1BA348418047DE374940259A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring that coinsurance for drugs under Medicare part D be based on the drug's actual acquisition cost and not the drug's wholesale acquisition cost</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1860D–2 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-102">42 U.S.C. 1395w–102</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE2B82447932A4413815B4B449E06985C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="HCF70C6CFDBDF4097B58F25993134A701"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A), in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>and (9)</quote> and inserting <quote>, (9), and (10)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7A1E64913B164FE8BBFF18D1F62BCA23"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBBE3C76BA8F6438ABB66259B39D0FCBA"> <paragraph id="H0497F60ACE094AFDB7CC7572205CEC87"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Requirement that coinsurance for covered part D drugs be based on the actual acquisition cost of the drug</header> <subparagraph id="H05963DA1E79E48D49FB74F98A701D5FD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2026, for costs above the annual deductible specified in paragraph (1) and below the annual out-of-pocket threshold specified in paragraph (4), any coinsurance amount for a covered part D drug (insofar as such covered part D drug is included on the formulary and subject to coinsurance rather than a copayment) shall be calculated based on the actual acquisition cost (and not the wholesale acquisition cost) of such covered part D drug if such actual acquisition cost is lower than the wholesale acquisition cost of such covered part D drug. The preceding sentence shall not apply to a covered part D drug described in paragraph (8) or (9). </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8DBFE4C3CF0A465793852631741F22E2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Actual acquisition cost defined</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <quote>actual acquisition cost</quote> means, with respect to a covered part D drug, the negotiated price of the covered part D drug under the prescription drug plan or MA–PD plan, net of any manufacturer-provided price concessions (as defined under section 423.100 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation)), as reported for such drug in the Detailed DIR Report (or any successor report) submitted by the sponsor or organization offering the plan for the previous plan year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9B879F60DE9B480F9E90FCF5B508CCFD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE25A2541CB5243228E7E893613DF708C"> 
<paragraph id="H9B30DBCA983C43F6A21922AB6730D024"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Requirement that coinsurance for covered part D drugs be based on the net price of the drug</header><text>The coverage is provided in accordance with subsection (b)(10).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

