<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H55ACB694D85842CCAB62EC453392718E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 651 IH: Spectrum Pipeline Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 651</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250123">January 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Federal Communications Commission to auction spectrum in the band between 1.3 gigahertz and 13.2 gigahertz, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H163A67C99C994C808571939F12B71A1F" style="OLC"><section id="H456A53E985D941428AC4564FCF016CE1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Spectrum Pipeline Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB549E0CE673B48A59EBB3B5E1B754D11"><enum>2.</enum><header>Identification of spectrum for reallocation and auction</header><subsection id="H773B369A67D3481CB14DBC7142DF7C24"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HF08DF858F21F4412BD9CD10172A9E649"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1DE0B30B945A40099D5EB946FECE9B3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H64CA688107514027AC7D11A82742F5E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H66F3226177E74B8BAC0AD32AA23B1E1B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Assistant Secretary</term> means the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA49327B7E5434CEA9AA030A618042FE2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Communications Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF66972B1D85340219FED9BD909BA7255"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered band</header><text>The term <term>covered band</term> means the band of frequencies between 1.3 gigahertz and 13.2 gigahertz.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A4BE8CBB10D478B9E3D7814E3E4D0BD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Federal entity</header><text>The term <term>Federal entity</term> has the meaning given the term in section 113(l) of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/923">47 U.S.C. 923(l)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C09C970DA394CF3A691B7C36448132F"><enum>(6)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Full-power commercial licensed use cases</header><text>The term <term>full-power commercial licensed use cases</term> means flexible use wireless broadband services with base station power levels sufficient for high-power, high-density, and wide-area commercial mobile services, consistent with the service rules under part 27 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulations, for wireless broadband deployments throughout the covered band.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H753AE6CB33B340A689433EF63BE700CA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Identification for reallocation</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE73A23A6023B4ADF9C9E1DE620BF29C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary, in consultation with the Commission, shall identify not less than 2500 megahertz of spectrum in the covered band, that as of the date of enactment of this Act is allocated for Federal use or for shared Federal and non-Federal use, for reallocation for non-Federal use, shared Federal and non-Federal use, or a combination thereof, including not less than 1250 megahertz for full-power commercial licensed use cases.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H795597DA3B0446899EF28724E2A93DCE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Schedule</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall identify the spectrum under paragraph (1) according to the following schedule:</text><subparagraph id="HBD6300571DB945BD82EA2670A29F1200"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary shall identify not less than 1250 megahertz of spectrum.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D18CDED36824D05BB5F91C064B92011"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary shall identify any remaining spectrum required to be identified under paragraph (1) after compliance with subparagraph (A) of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6446CE725AC04D7481B91C7A19233582"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Auctions</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H951E12BD618942F6BCB26F9C6CE19ECE"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>With respect to the spectrum identified for reallocation under subsection (b) for commercial licensed use, the Commission shall grant licenses through systems of competitive bidding for not less than 1250 megahertz of the spectrum for full-power commercial licensed use cases.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7F16C6A3C754385B45AA040E92DAF37"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Schedule</header><text>The Commission shall auction the spectrum under paragraph (1) according to the following schedule:</text><subparagraph id="H6B3AB742FB1242A6ACDC0AF4238B1305"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall complete 1 or more systems of competitive bidding for not less than 600 megahertz of the spectrum.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBABD42D07EB4EFDA8C1A29FAA5E879B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Not later than 6 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall complete 1 or more systems of competitive bidding for any remaining spectrum required to be auctioned under paragraph (1) after compliance with subparagraph (A) of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1087F27E40DA486291E915EA8A32E6FB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Unlicensed use</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall make available on an unlicensed basis not less than 125 megahertz of the spectrum in the covered band.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD061B16B6E88453A97C3D22D778D7916"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Licensed or unlicensed use</header><text>Not later than 8 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall make available for use on a licensed or unlicensed basis any remaining spectrum that is—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7ED5205A50B042D7A05FC5EF9FD314A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identified under subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5D4A53B67698407B84D60E9AF57C8A97"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9D24BF18B944B85B6774FECE37C98FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">auctioned under subsection (c); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF1FE0F5AC76497181C5210BF39BC5D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">made available on an unlicensed basis under subsection (d).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDA079C677C3B481BA562E82B77A9F1A5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Auction proceeds To cover 110 percent of Federal relocation or sharing costs</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to relieve the Commission from the requirements under section 309(j)(16)(B) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/309">47 U.S.C. 309(j)(16)(B)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HAA58CB9210E4445CB586FC07E4B2073F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Auction authority</header><text>Section 309(j)(11) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/309">47 U.S.C. 309(j)(11)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HD341A937783C47ADA38DD442084B49C0" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>grant a license or permit under this subsection shall expire March 9, 2023</quote> and inserting <quote>complete a system of competitive bidding under this subsection shall expire September 30, 2027</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA08D8B6FDC2D4DCB8F43669DD8391D63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and with respect to</quote> and inserting <quote>with respect to</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDAC244CC7CEA4DB6AC7EAA7775AED219"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>, and with respect to the electromagnetic spectrum in the covered band (as defined in section 2(a) of the <short-title>Spectrum Pipeline Act of 2025</short-title>), such authority shall expire on the date that is 8 years after the date of enactment of that Act</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H84A6B9677DE645A0A6833CE31DADC814"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reporting requirements and quarterly briefings</header><paragraph id="H7360C518A5AC40E9AF61D290363412A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>NTIA progress report on spectrum identification</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF5F87706DB064DA89E1A619FF923E940"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>On each date as of which the Assistant Secretary, in consultation with the Commission, has identified the quantity of spectrum required under subparagraph (A) or (B), respectively, of subsection (b)(2), the Assistant Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report detailing the findings and conclusions that the Assistant Secretary used to support the identification.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H195FE071C0A04A8186D32D002930134E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall include in each report submitted under subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="HB449971A5A934998BC34EF1BE664BC58"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an analysis of the spectrum identified; and</text></clause><clause id="HC1769E5289744580BCABF575560B43E7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Federal entities with which the Assistant Secretary coordinated regarding the spectrum identified.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CD021E28297438BB93B65895FFDF77E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>Each report required under subparagraph (A) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA68D160562F947EAA19F61D67B0B7B1F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>NTIA and FCC reports on reallocation of spectrum identified</header><subparagraph id="HBE9E98DE3BEC410A89EB2850BB10A699"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial progress report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary, in consultation with the Commission, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the progress of the Assistant Secretary in identifying spectrum in the covered band for reallocation under subsection (b) that includes—</text><clause id="H4A25DAF6389148FB9830C60E5FF858C3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an assessment of the operations of the Federal entities and non-Federal entities that operate in the spectrum in the covered band; and</text></clause><clause id="HCEE841DB9E6D4117BCBAF386908866A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a preliminary analysis of which portions of the covered band are being considered for reallocation in accordance with subsection (b)(1).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88B1E42EA10147F69AEB679678B5BAF9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reports on 2 tranches of identified spectrum</header><text>Not later than 60 days after each date as of which the Assistant Secretary, in consultation with the Commission, has identified the quantity of spectrum required under subparagraph (A) or (B), respectively, of subsection (b)(2), the Assistant Secretary, in consultation with the Commission, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that includes—</text><clause id="H1BC8CF9859DE44BDA9A048A607563337"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an assessment of the operations of the Federal entities and non-Federal entities that operate in the applicable spectrum, current as of the date of the submission of the report;</text></clause><clause id="HF5CEC8ECC6404427B1FA71F95B07D005"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the steps the President has taken to begin the process of withdrawing or modifying the assignments of Federal entities in the covered band as necessary for the Commission to begin and complete the systems of competitive bidding under subsection (c);</text></clause><clause id="H98CECA349F284F8D80555F58F565B5AE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an estimate of the funding required for the relocation or sharing costs (as defined in section 113(g)(3) of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/923">47 U.S.C. 923(g)(3)</external-xref>)) expected to be incurred by the Federal entities described in clause (ii) in connection with the reallocation of the applicable spectrum; and</text></clause><clause id="H333CACFC1F104A7B80BB9E49B00480A0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>steps the Assistant Secretary is taking to ensure global harmonization with the spectrum to be reallocated.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D7C2D71063447B1A8AB43081ABE37C5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>Each report required under this paragraph shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCAF8EB20878043CFBD6C8CD83094B820"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual briefings</header><subparagraph id="HD348E7AD621F4CF4B18D9577950846A7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter until the date that is 10 years after such date of enactment, the Assistant Secretary and the Chairman of the Commission shall provide the appropriate committees of Congress with a briefing on the progress of the Assistant Secretary and the Chairman in complying with the requirements of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F9F189840384306BD1638AB0DC26219"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The Assistant Secretary and the Chairman of the Commission shall include in each briefing under subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H518484F5D7A54B2AA6143193A093A2F5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an update on the specific frequencies of spectrum under consideration or that have been identified to meet the requirements of subsection (b);</text></clause><clause id="H49852CDD7D024F74AA0F0051B988F86C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an explanation of the Federal entities and non-Federal entities that operate on the frequencies described in clause (i) and the specific services or systems utilized by those entities on those frequencies;</text></clause><clause id="H370B35D36B2849A49B20481B09B6B358"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the extent to which Federal entities are cooperating with the efforts of the Assistant Secretary and the Chairman of the Commission to comply with the requirements of this Act;</text></clause><clause id="H871E1B66C11B4A3C990E2095AA997C6F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an update on the progress of the systems of competitive bidding required by subsection (c); and</text></clause><clause id="H59D11AE8F2F740AFAC87B0C62FB24FC4"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any additional information related to compliance with this Act by the Assistant Secretary and the Chairman.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3992ECAFB9A4984B11B433755BECDF8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Form of briefing</header><text>Any classified information that would otherwise be provided in a briefing under subparagraph (A) shall be provided in a separate classified briefing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE8FE60F34A6C4420AC7EBDD164332B89"><enum>3.</enum><header>Spectrum Relocation Fund modernization</header><subsection id="H2D8FFB30BEAE40E4B9AC1C1283D23B23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Congressional notification timelines</header><text>Section 118 of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/928">47 U.S.C. 928</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE5D8A45185B849A4BFB9205A56DC1A89"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(2)—</text><subparagraph id="H9DA855407E034C68BC2017A68884AFFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>30 days</quote> and inserting <quote>15 days</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62C2B4315E96498B975F68B081AB1399"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter following subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>30 days</quote> and inserting <quote>15 days</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE227373835ED458EBE7E61E2F645078F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (f)(2)(B)(iv), by striking <quote>30 days</quote> and inserting <quote>15 days</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EBBC30CD94943FD9D7A61B9BAA54310"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(2)(D)(ii), by striking <quote>60 days</quote> and inserting <quote>15 days</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB7208C073AD1407C9E233CEBB9E66664"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Comparable capability</header><text>Section 113(g)(3) of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/923">47 U.S.C. 923(g)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H5DC05B7BACC84B91A47306469958A7EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><subparagraph id="H33DDA210B7584E36B69E927E2E983B88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (iv), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CD8FB7CB2D54E77BBAF6FD314494DA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (v), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6FD2840F6E54783803E99259FC1F93D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H69C73D67C8DC4FB2A6E2A0692515EC47" style="OLC"><clause id="H462673ACF2B24054AC9A3AC516688B43"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the costs associated with replacing systems and equipment with state-of-the-art systems and equipment, including systems and equipment with additional functions, only if the state-of-the-art systems and equipment allow for the reallocation of significantly more valuable spectrum frequencies from Federal use to exclusive non-Federal use or to shared Federal and non-Federal use than would be reallocated if systems and equipment were replaced with comparable systems and equipment or systems and equipment with incidental increases in functionality, provided the costs would not jeopardize the ability of the Assistant Secretary, in consultation with the Chair of the Commission, to reallocate eligible spectrum frequencies from Federal use to exclusive non-Federal use or to shared use.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H34C3002BE43C474DBD7445778F693C41"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(ii), by striking <quote>incidental</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

