<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25343-33C-8H-29C"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1062 IS: Suicide Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1062</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250313">March 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize a pilot program to expand and intensify surveillance of self-harm in partnership with State and local public health departments, to establish a grant program to provide self-harm and suicide prevention services in hospital emergency departments, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HF190AB3F6C904C1AADBC702737912902"><section section-type="section-one" id="H468C897E57A248338C53B720E3A6433C"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Suicide Prevention Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC02B21DB1D7E4DC58BD498BF5E7E58CA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Syndromic surveillance of self-harm behaviors program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title III of the Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 317V of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b-24">42 U.S.C. 247b–24</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3BF047E625504570B7302FC234657779"><section id="HECA8A8B884A9410E878BC632E7C204F4"><enum>317W.</enum><header>Syndromic surveillance of self-harm behaviors program</header><subsection id="HCFF59B35223A4677BEC20182714BD031"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants to State, local, Tribal, and territorial public health departments for the expansion of surveillance of self-harm.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9772859AE36144E6BEAB80094103778D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Data sharing by grantees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of receipt of such grant under subsection (a), each grantee shall agree to share with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in real time, to the extent feasible and as specified in the grant agreement, data on suicides and self-harm for purposes of—</text><paragraph id="H5CAA4CB8F1E94F57B27DDE7744B462DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>tracking and monitoring self-harm to inform response activities to suicide clusters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCED1ECB6A77469DB3B70A6266949083"><enum>(2)</enum><text>informing prevention programming for identified at-risk populations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81683D67ED30424BA6A1F71E0ACC69FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conducting or supporting research.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2F6F735AD6B949F0852750847DE81AF2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disaggregation of data</header><text>The Secretary shall provide for the data collected through surveillance of self-harm under subsection (b) to be disaggregated by the following categories:</text><paragraph id="H62E37D0754984D97A39B27D0210D065C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Nonfatal self-harm data of any intent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7228E2C4463A4D51886F76FC64570235"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Data on suicidal ideation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60B1B88B0F804D9CB762B2D648CA4690"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Data on self-harm where there is no evidence, whether implicit or explicit, of suicidal intent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCB4E9A447CA4DA897275DDEC92B45A1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Data on self-harm where there is evidence, whether implicit or explicit, of suicidal intent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43AE600723C244B8B248B9EBA28CA86A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Data on self-harm where suicidal intent is unclear based on the available evidence.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4F9CF8FDFEC643B1AD5611BD352BFB23"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In making awards under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that are—</text><paragraph id="HF82D88CEE07A4331A51342D9A3FE3EDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">located in a State with an age-adjusted rate of nonfatal suicidal behavior that is above the national rate of nonfatal suicidal behavior, as determined by the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8EE4D7BACD4D47F9A48B8DE23B896C20"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serving an Indian Tribe (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act) with an age-adjusted rate of nonfatal suicidal behavior that is above the national rate of nonfatal suicidal behavior, as determined through appropriate mechanisms determined by the Secretary in consultation with Indian Tribes; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC92E6D7A18EC4B39B4A719AF1C56D4EE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>located in a State with a high rate of coverage of statewide (or Tribal) emergency department visits, as determined by the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5CA4DBC1A603422687A07E7461E5B90A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Geographic distribution</header><text>In making grants under this section, the Secretary shall make an effort to ensure geographic distribution, taking into account the unique needs of rural communities, including—</text><paragraph id="H666404C92D1F41B28094D4ECDE03F924"><enum>(1)</enum><text>communities with an incidence of individuals with serious mental illness, demonstrated suicidal ideation or behavior, or suicide rates that are above the national average, as determined by the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CD94F0177134B3685F80689B20B5737"><enum>(2)</enum><text>communities with a shortage of prevention and treatment services, as determined by the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use and the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H723F421AF599470CB39FF7EC62F21752"><enum>(3)</enum><text>other appropriate community-level factors and social determinants of health such as income, employment, and education.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB3DD4D8BAB23496C803C14D3D2DF2E75"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Period of participation</header><text>To be selected as a grant recipient under this section, a State, local, Tribal, or territorial public health department shall agree to participate in the program for a period of not less than 4 years.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD43144C29C364914ACE6A24F25724E6A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary shall provide technical assistance and training to grantees for collecting and sharing the data under subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="HBB87A387C21B4796811BAEC758F3EC51"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Data sharing by HHS</header><text>Subject to subsection (c), the Secretary shall, with respect to data on self-harm that is collected pursuant to this section, share and integrate such data through—</text><paragraph id="H25D9A63347E94700B273DB3A237BFAE7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the platform of the National Syndromic Surveillance Program Early Notification of Community-Based Epidemics (ESSENCE) (or any successor platform);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2CF75767833467A80B762DB43C7F250"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the National Violent Death Reporting System (or any successor platform), as appropriate; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88088FBDA14D42D5A2F4EEEA92CED943"><enum>(3)</enum><text>another appropriate surveillance program, including such a program that collects data on suicides and self-harm among special populations, such as members of the military and veterans.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5801323BEAE486B8743C898F3CEA17E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rule of construction regarding applicability of privacy protections</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit or alter the application of Federal or State law relating to the privacy of information to data or information that is collected or created under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3994B55AB9604BE08F3483F399B96F6F"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="H0074D0E1194A433A9B173743CCDB1A59"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Suicide Prevention Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall evaluate the suicide and self-harm syndromic surveillance systems at the Federal, State, and local levels and submit a report to Congress on the data collected under subsection (b) in a manner that prevents the disclosure of individually identifiable information, at a minimum, consistent with all applicable privacy laws and regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BA7D40350564327B0943407DF90FFFA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In addition to the data collected under subsection (b), the report under paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HCB071847C3DC40E5BCC4974014C8B57E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>challenges and gaps in data collection and reporting;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2FCB9EF25EC4E3FB307361247D9C605"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations to address such gaps and challenges; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H818D147A1D284C89A5A0DB6918948662"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of any public health responses initiated at the Federal, State, or local level in response to the data collected.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCD2372ACB957424D8E9F6E4332B85489"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H979A37D175BF40C39CCFFC2C25F7F6B9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants to provide self-harm and suicide prevention services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart 3 of part B of title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-31">42 U.S.C. 290bb–31 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H236DA1395B97415596B18EDBA5C5F353"><section id="H9276380EBF1745D696E4EFA983DA3123"><enum>520O.</enum><header>Grants to provide self-harm and suicide prevention services</header><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63117DFCACED4076A7A95B23C24B4B13"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award grants to hospital emergency departments to provide self-harm and suicide prevention services.</text></subsection><subsection id="H928BB6D096E44E4E9E7A5B0C1B597410"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities supported</header><paragraph id="HC3B6E581EC41424C8AE085E39F080C47"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A hospital emergency department awarded a grant under subsection (a) shall use amounts under the grant to implement a program or protocol to better prevent suicide attempts among hospital patients after discharge, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="H1EE3838406054B8CBB8D5107BCD5377E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">screening patients for self-harm and suicide in accordance with the standards of practice described in subsection (e)(1) and standards of care established by appropriate medical and advocacy organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78DE37CDF4A44043BA714C16393E1B58"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing patients short-term self-harm and suicide prevention services in accordance with the results of the screenings described in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB37726BC08994594BE3D97394127823E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>referring patients, as appropriate, to a health care facility or provider for purposes of receiving long-term self-harm and suicide prevention services, and providing any additional follow up services and care identified as appropriate as a result of the screenings and short-term self-harm and suicide prevention services described in subparagraphs (A) and (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEAE38C612914B8BBFEB03F9AD469B1D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds to hire and train staff</header><text>Amounts awarded under subsection (a) may be used to hire clinical social workers, mental and behavioral health care professionals, and support staff as appropriate, and to train existing staff and newly hired staff to carry out the activities described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6431D5B8FF224F3581AD43839D82B589"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant awarded under subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="H77DE42AF00194DF1B2BC23075F3C2B52"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be for a period of 3 years; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09E0CCA7D595434BBC341399A0EEA6A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may be renewed subject to the requirements of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B47C6FBBEE7468089435C23697856EA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A hospital emergency department seeking a grant under subsection (a) shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H81342AE61C2E46D7B25B5E29243F668A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Standards of Practice</header><paragraph id="H318938273979427AA3F213397BBEF20D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall develop standards of practice for screening patients for self-harm and suicide for purposes of carrying out subsection (b)(1)(C).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90B03210C3E845ACA9782B5741B933CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall develop the standards of practice described in paragraph (1) in consultation with individuals and entities with expertise in self-harm and suicide prevention, including public, private, and nonprofit entities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2707DF648F9943E3B55F138653824EFB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting</header><paragraph id="H796149A33E0D44A1B7F678C06D4E6814"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports to the Secretary</header><subparagraph id="HA555B233BDF5473E9BDC3F245098AFDB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A hospital emergency department awarded a grant under subsection (a) shall, at least quarterly for the duration of the grant, submit to the Secretary a report evaluating the activities supported by the grant.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B786529B5EC4961BC0D85C0124E5840"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Matters to be included</header><text>The report required under subparagraph (A) shall include—</text><clause id="H72573A1948834ABBAEB4BEAEA8760114"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of patients receiving—</text><subclause id="H6287C61A4B8B4E0F8995BA739CA602C0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>screenings carried out at the hospital emergency department;</text></subclause><subclause id="HF3F15535FF694FC0BEA170A9511B30BB"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">short-term self-harm and suicide prevention services at the hospital emergency department; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H9BAA4FF139844AA88D1CBF551FE2048C"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">referrals to health care facilities for the purposes of receiving long-term self-harm and suicide prevention;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF9B05E8997494981B92020CAD6DD2814"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on the adherence of the hospital emergency department to the standards of practice described in subsection (e)(1); and</text></clause><clause id="HFE9655AA68F34917BD29968087D2C76F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>other information as the Secretary determines appropriate to evaluate the use of grant funds.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9D6C91AE6D7941A6BAFDA4D4EAE15966"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Suicide Prevention Act</short-title>, and biennially thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report on the grant program under this section, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H863863FE5A6F4C8499FDB9EC72769694"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a summary of reports received by the Secretary under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0B7ED21CC46A4CD8B83A863D8456E98C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evaluation of the program by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB41A3A6EA27A4FC7BD1ADE150ECEF016"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

