<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H544614431FBF4026BBEEED93AF6763FE"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3475 IH:  Bipartisan American Homeownership Opportunity Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3475</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250517">May 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000592">Mr. Golden of Maine</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish a new first-time homebuyer credit and to establish the starter home construction credit.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H748EF81430934AC0AFD429BE4B482C55"><section id="H89439EF4AFD049B697302B997B75CCE0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the<quote> Bipartisan American Homeownership Opportunity Act of 2025</quote>.</text></section><section id="H86DBC650197F483AA54B7A905F8F3382"><enum>2.</enum><header>First-time homebuyer credit</header><subsection id="HB5056ADD34F64FEBA35C3DE1D2C0CC32"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36">Section 36</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H0896DFB210A940329E2B996AEBD55AB4" style="OLC"><section id="HA614C2E38C1C456A98FC9EB60867CC28"><enum>36.</enum><header>First-time homebuyer credit</header><subsection id="H66F868989B0C4C0985EC9343E4E28881"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>ln the case of an individual who is a first-time homebuyer of a principal residence in the United States during a taxable year, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this subtitle for such taxable year an amount equal to so much of the amount of the down payment paid by such taxpayer to purchase such principal residence as does not exceed $50,000.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD662A3372D134D16816FD1151F02780A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><paragraph id="HEAD5B52DD96B4CC987345A4F6B5FECD5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount allowable as a credit under subsection (a) (determined without regard to this paragraph) for the taxable year shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the amount which bears the same ratio to the amount which is so allowable as—</text><subparagraph id="H5AF33E94CC0143F5871C59295F640348"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the excess (if any) of—</text><clause id="H83500824FBAF4EF5AFAC3CDF969A412F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the taxpayer’s modified adjusted gross income for the preceding taxable year, over</text></clause><clause id="HC66ACDAD4BB4490E8F3AB307A73E7A4B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the applicable threshold amount, bears to—</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DF3A2EA031B432C8497E9746D5CA4FB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>$100,000</header></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF903776E7DC47C8859F9B7A08B421E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Threshold amount</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>threshold amount</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H84964768563B41A1BA7E86AA010126F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$300,000 in the case of a joint return or surviving spouse,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70106C6ECDBB4E5FA46032033D0EBF19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$225,000 in the case of a head of household, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36888A3E98CB40CBB8192DB4041B4EEB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$150,000 in the case of any other individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H17B1CB0F580748C0A49C2B00049B221F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Modified adjusted gross income</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the term <quote>modified adjusted gross income</quote> means the adjusted gross income of the taxpayer for the taxable year increased by any amount excluded from gross income under section 911, 931, or 933.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H421A05F36B1E45D8B67BE1818D8F02BC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>No credit under subsection (a) shall be allowed to any taxpayer for any taxable year with respect to the purchase of a residence if—</text><paragraph id="HA4CB57E531BD4D90994EC43E6B367458"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the taxpayer is a nonresident alien,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12DE53E212794B018781F7FA846A2DF9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the taxpayer disposes of such residence (or such residence ceases to be the principal residence of the taxpayer (and, if married, the taxpayer’s spouse)) before the close of such taxable year,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H673EAE78024146D289D8C0191CDB5098"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a deduction under section 151 with respect to such taxpayer is allowable to another taxpayer for such taxable year, or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H480A2C20E20646EC83F6DCEA8BBE86EA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the taxpayer fails to attach to the return of tax for such taxable year a properly executed copy of the settlement statement used to complete such purchase.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC908AB4D39124CA080F6459AF04499BB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Election for advanced payment</header><paragraph id="H93129AB821AF4941846A7A2A8F72BD12"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>At the election of the first-time homebuyer, the Secretary shall transfer to a qualifying escrow account an amount equal to the amount that is allowable to such first-time homebuyer under subsection (a) in the present taxable year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H419AE4FB559B488A84F8FC73A04B5F71"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of transfer</header><text>The amount of the credit allowed under subsection (a) to any taxpayer for any taxable year shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the aggregate amount of payments made under this subsection at the election of such taxpayer during such taxable year. Any failure to so reduce the credit shall be treated as arising out of a mathematical or clerical error and assessed according to section 6213(b)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76CA84AC5A344C9B80D4E5ED9CE48D0F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualifying escrow account</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>qualifying escrow account</quote> means an escrow account established for the purchase of a principal residence by a qualified first-time homebuyer that meets the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="HBA9B4AFAE6CB4B8E9D41E3E5C86E1541"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Amounts in such account may only be used for a down payment on a purchase with respect to which a credit is allowed under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65565BFCACA94F2BBC318DE7A2FDEAEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Such account is administered by a bank (as defined in section 408A (n)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F8860AD449C42EA846C71C847AFCF41"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The administrator of the account shall transfer to the Secretary any amount in such account not used under subparagraph (A) on the earlier of—</text><clause id="HD275C378701B4EE3822A7D566887004F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date that is 180 days after the date on which such amount was transferred to such account under paragraph (1), or</text></clause><clause id="HF8F55170B9FD4CB5B709C7077896B5C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as soon as practicable upon request of the qualified first-time homebuyer.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8ED96026DC1C42559B367D8C804EBFE9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Recapture of credit</header><paragraph id="H95D097BD4D3343DCA33873E39BEA5F20"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>lf, during any taxable year, there is a recapture event with respect to any property with respect to which a credit was allowed under subsection (a), then the tax of the taxpayer to whom such credit was allowed under this chapter for such taxable year shall be increased by an amount equal to the amount of the credit that was allowed with respect to such property.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E36C6876F38490C99FB12AE7ECB7221"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recapture event</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>recapture event</quote> means, during the 5-year period beginning on the date of the purchase with respect to which a credit was allowed under subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H6AD4DF81F19C4799B9A9700FDA590946"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the sale, lease to a third party, or disposition of any part of the property with respect to which such credit was allowed, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49A444F018B7458E9D2B85CA65937CCA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such property ceases to be the principal residence of the taxpayer (or, in the case of a joint return, of the taxpayer’s spouse).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA80BD7AB5544CADBAF919BDC081FC6A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HD89E1A04DCFD4F98A560532B22F9888F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Purchase of new primary residence</header><clause id="H7A528869F24749A2AA50C5D7218B4294"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A sale of a property with respect to which a credit was allowed under subsection (a) which is incident to the purchase by a taxpayer of a new primary residence if the proceeds of such sale are used to carry out the purchase of such new primary residence.</text></clause><clause id="HD70477CC9A0F41AAB065B6392DEB258B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Treatment of new primary residence</header><text>ln the case of a purchase of a primary residence described in clause (i), for purposes of paragraph (1), such primary residence shall be treated as a property with respect to which a credit was allowed under subsection (a), except that the period described in paragraph (2) shall begin on the date on which the original purchase with respect to which the credit was allowed under subsection (a) occurred.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H397A7B8CAD744ACBB1AB60A6FD42CF8D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Death</header><text>Any taxable year ending after the death of the taxpayer (or, in the case of a joint return, of the spouse of the taxpayer).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40D5892E87624B389167FA02FE9D22CD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Divorce</header><text>A transfer of a residence to which section 1041(a) applies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2453E2194C5A4E51A6ED33FC0AD438CE"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Government orders</header><text>A recapture event relating to a principal residence occurring in connection with Government orders received by such individual, or such individual’s spouse, for qualified official extended duty service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4EB370DF71AB4495AE9A6DF7A9DB3D2D"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Qualified official extended duty service</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>qualified official extended duty service</quote> means service on qualified official extended duty as—</text><clause id="H88DC8770856A4E6A8CC68098CCB2D252"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a member of the uniformed services,</text></clause><clause id="HFAD756F749174AC993073E6B9468A7C0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a member of the Foreign Service of the United States, or</text></clause><clause id="HE9C2C708EDBC43698C5AFA977578F602"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an employee of the intelligence community.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA9498A78CC5948D098D2AC489645980C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H1EB4BE840E5442A8B4CBDDC26AC85AF0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>First-time homebuyer</header><text>The term <quote>first-time homebuyer</quote> means any individual if such individual (and if married, such individual’s spouse)—</text><subparagraph id="HC5BBFB4443644DD0AE18B53FA187FC1C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>had no present ownership interest in a principal residence during the 10-year period ending on the date of the purchase of the principal residence to which this section applies,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3415EAABCCB40F0BF4708521770A120"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has not been allowed a credit under subsection (a) for any preceding taxable year, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3714FD612E440CA8E38C8704E633E29"><enum>(C)</enum><text>attests that such individual (and if married, such individual’s spouse) has never had a majority interest in a residential property.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EB5E93E337649088B078355F6AB16A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Principal residence</header><text>The term <quote>principal residence</quote> has the same meaning as when used in section 121.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89511084D10D4FC0B4F892FB73FC463B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Purchase</header><subparagraph id="H4E93C92F745241EAB8CAF8AB9EAC8F7F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>purchase</quote> means any acquisition, but only if—</text><clause id="H48032C5E39F24C43A148691E91BA08CB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the property is purchased using a mortgage loan from a commercial lender,</text></clause><clause id="HD2C7EBA4FDEC4F98B30380D8D6D06750"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the property is not acquired from a person related to the person acquiring such property (or, if married, such individual’s spouse), and</text></clause><clause id="H941EB76DADB14D3C917893A374048C17"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the basis of the property in the hands of the person acquiring such property is not determined—</text><subclause id="HB8D1076812A34702A2D1F3E91B3177B2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in whole or in part by reference to the adjusted basis of such property in the hands of the person from whom acquired, or</text></subclause><subclause id="H6EBC85FD6C954DF5AF4B7DC1460EE28F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>under section 1014(a).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E212154748F4DD6821B1602A8882DFC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>A residence which is constructed by the taxpayer shall be treated as purchased by the taxpayer on the date the taxpayer first occupies such residence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H013DCB6089D1475090E1F4E266E37F8C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Related persons</header><text>A person shall be treated as related to another person if the relationship between such persons would result in the disallowance of losses under section 267 or 707(b) (but, in applying section 267(b) and (c) for purposes of this section, paragraph (4) of section 267(c)(4) shall be treated as providing that the family of an individual shall include only his spouse, ancestors, and lineal descendants).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H79660C5EA30F44769732EB6C6B63AF79"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Basis adjustment</header><text>For purposes of this subtitle, if a credit is allowed under this section in connection with any expenditure for any property, the increase in the basis of such property which would (but for this subsection) result from such expenditure shall be reduced by the amount of the credit so determined.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8D98E10457974EFABE6C7BA1987F2D75"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><paragraph id="H5D56A2AB09F841BCACE1B70FA7DBD4A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any taxable year beginning after 2025, the dollar amounts in this section shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text><subparagraph id="H4BAA2A05E8F94419810A54198801FC33"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H498C8B089B7D4501A532E13B064D38F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, determined by substituting “calendar year 2023” for calendar year 2016 in subparagraph (A)(ii).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H52DCF15605314B46A5036DB7AEF89AD3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>lf any increase under paragraph (1) is not a multiple of $100, such increase shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $100.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3214ACF0A1AD47D392947F8E29D0A29B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reporting</header><paragraph id="H392FA2C28F764CA8B2511586C1D1C75A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>lf the Secretary requires information reporting under section 6045 by a person described in subsection (d)(2) thereof to verify the eligibility of taxpayers for the credit allowable by this section, the exception provided by section 6045(e) shall not apply.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C09943C3361450FB4442128C9354531"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information from lender</header><text>The Secretary may require any lender issuing a loan for the purchase of a property with respect to which a credit is allowed under subsection (a) or with respect to which a first-time homebuyer has made a request for a transfer under subsection (d)(1) to provide such information relating to the related purchase as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC1905764B2674094B6D4ADBFB777210E"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H892AD1AAEF214A3E9FD8A081A70BA9CA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to residences purchased in taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H6280635DD85D48B3A26639933E673C2A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Starter home construction credit</header><subsection id="H680445489C7546EF88D46D0A39A6A80A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H03BD884B6D784AB2A224B72BC7607988" style="OLC"><section id="HC166D8AF2DA74EBAB62CF6034DA7050D"><enum>45U.</enum><header>Starter home construction credit</header><subsection id="HD8D6393678F5445C821848A411D76F10"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the purposes of section 38, the starter home construction credit determined under this section for any taxable year is an amount equal to 15 percent of the qualified home construction costs of the taxpayer for the taxable year.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE32AF4F1769548B1BE9849EDDBF7A0C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The amount allowable as a credit under subsection (a) to any taxpayer for any taxable year shall not exceed the amount allocated to such taxpayer for the calendar year in which such taxable year ends under subsection (d).</text></subsection><subsection id="H8694F5E0ECED4419BAAD1A30610EF0C6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Increase for first-Time homebuyer</header><text>ln the case of a unit of housing sold to a first-time homebuyer (as defined in section 36(g)(1)), subsection (a) shall be applied by substituting <quote>30 percent</quote> for <quote>15 percent</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA9379CC71DA44F4E9E9974672BBE5532"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Qualified home construction costs</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>qualified home construction costs</quote> means, with respect to a taxable year, amounts paid or incurred by the taxpayer for labor and material costs to construct a unit of housing placed in service during such taxable year—</text><paragraph id="H71105E452FEC4E2B9BDBA009858029E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the total square footage of which does not exceed 1200 feet, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H282680297B524338BD9099FC034065A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the sale price of which does not exceed 80 percent of the area median home price.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H230B7FE8F46049F08DA3017B3D953332"><enum>(e)</enum><text>Allocation.—</text><paragraph id="HB3FB1545CFC548809E3BF600B59957B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The aggregate starter home construction credit dollar amount which a housing credit agency may allocate for any calendar year is the portion of the State starter home construction credit ceiling allocated under this paragraph for such calendar year to such agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H544411E27C07414D88EA31E0A4187A70"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State ceiling initially allocated to state housing credit agencies</header><text>The State starter home construction credit ceiling for each calendar year shall be allocated to the housing credit agency of such State. If there is more than 1 housing credit agency of a State, all such agencies shall be treated as a single agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDE2AA3B57E042359FC34FC0ADCB2215"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State starter home credit ceiling</header><text>The State starter home credit ceiling applicable to any State for any calendar year shall be an amount equal to the sum of—</text><subparagraph id="H2F858C8E84E84BDA95F04B76BF4D580A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the unused State housing credit ceiling (if any) of such State for the preceding calendar year, plus</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H587F237DDF9845A58C3B05DBDA446C6B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$30 multiplied by the population of the State (determined in accordance with section 146(j)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A56C20660394AABB5B62DB366D3EFE0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Housing credit agency</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>housing credit agency</quote> has the meaning given in section 42(h)(8)(A).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE42CB984FFA4356B9643BDD82D5A0FE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><subparagraph id="HABB5437938C74ADEB953F59988F969EC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>ln the case of any taxable year beginning after 2025, the dollar amount in paragraph (3)(B) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text><clause id="H57B1C9747C534CFE808FDA3CFF19760B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></clause><clause id="HB81FA59EAB584DD79D5FE4A4DD39024D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2023</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE10F2E616244449A54645AD7D0B4761"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>lf any increase under subparagraph (A) is not a multiple of $5, such increase shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $5.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC3C112BCD12E4DFEB4D05365B6E726A5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Basis adjustment</header><text>For purposes of this subtitle, if a credit is allowed under this section in connection with any expenditure for any property, the increase in the basis of such property which would (but for this subsection) result from such expenditure shall be reduced by the amount of the credit so determined.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7F375C9767CC42E88A844C8FF26AD167"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H0C150491A99F4D449AA019C5B9C3F1E8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit To be part of general business credit</header><text>Section 38(b) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (32), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (33) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDAECD803B7A3403E9A6AF6C817F762FE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H867D03ADA4FE4CBB9A7EBE5F49C08266"><enum>(34)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the starter home construction credit determined under section 45U(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H3C406DE3F0184480BA4E4D52E578F152"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 45T the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB7A893450E7E449992A92D7672927ED6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry idref="HC166D8AF2DA74EBAB62CF6034DA7050D" level="section">Sec. 45U. Starter home construction credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H28A25EEF1FF442CF819BAF8ACFCB9686"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

