<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H44219CD0BDDB47E8A2B20A1B7BC855FC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1632 IH: Reciprocity Ensures Streamlined Use of Lifesaving Treatments Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1632</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250226">February 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to provide for reciprocal marketing approval of certain drugs, biological products, and devices that are authorized to be lawfully marketed abroad, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H80B57EC6C7A74B51903E0D478D55578C" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H4EFAACCACCCF4217AEA9508A42252E72"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reciprocity Ensures Streamlined Use of Lifesaving Treatments Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA716A1338DCA4962B091B4DEE89BA708"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reciprocal marketing approval for certain drugs, biological products, and devices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act is amended by inserting after section 524B of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360n-2">21 U.S.C. 360n–2</external-xref>) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9AF12E4C14494C74A968E4815338C905"> 
<section id="HD31AAD218FF54F93AFA913FA0DFB9359"><enum>524C.</enum><header>Reciprocal marketing approval</header> 
<subsection id="HB94368E71C68428B80DA5028F6D75D08"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered product with reciprocal marketing approval in effect under this section is deemed to be subject to an application or premarket notification for which an approval or clearance is in effect under section 505(c), 510(k), or 515 of this Act or section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act, as applicable.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC27C15E7C95B4FCCB13E4EE20B9B73E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, with respect to a covered product, grant reciprocal marketing approval if—</text> 
<paragraph id="HECC1302DD6BD432D8A1C093E403911AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the sponsor of the covered product submits a request for reciprocal marketing approval; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC4A095F24E1641B995B55C236A748072"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the request demonstrates to the Secretary’s satisfaction that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2D46B70DDC364F9BB1283D2BD0C41B15"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the covered product is authorized to be lawfully marketed in one or more of the countries included in the list under section 802(b)(1) or in the United Kingdom;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F41728F5E2D4BAC86AFA06404556850"><enum>(B)</enum><text>absent reciprocal marketing approval, the covered product is not approved or cleared for marketing, as described in subsection (a);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H758F259257DC4D31A75EB6253B36A6D7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary has not, because of any concern relating to the safety or effectiveness of the covered product, rescinded or withdrawn any such approval or clearance;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC98CB9D4ACEA48A092C3307E4F935D4C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the authorization to market the covered product in one or more of the countries included in the list under section 802(b)(1) or in the United Kingdom has not, because of any concern relating to the safety or effectiveness of the covered product, been rescinded or withdrawn;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H476AA080278542E6A1F7F164CE1C81F6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the covered product is not a banned device under section 516; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8CEB4F7A074741CFB8D53A5371C64BCE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>there is a public health or unmet medical need for the covered product in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD1E3C964AB46437186BAC39A68DCCDDC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Safety and effectiveness</header> 
<paragraph id="H856074F8BBB9455C96EF5B0B1FA127D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary—</text> <subparagraph id="H4ACDBC86C19D4286A9AFF078BDFFE8EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may decline to grant reciprocal marketing approval under this section with respect to a covered product if the Secretary affirmatively determines that the covered product—</text> 
<clause id="HE8AAE540E5FA4E0F86C3362933B0DCD4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a drug that is not safe and effective; or</text></clause> <clause id="H0589629280D4467CA934149C6DD36E9C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is a device for which there is no reasonable assurance of safety and effectiveness; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF53F3F137F5B4092935F12A538DDC0D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may condition reciprocal marketing approval under this section on the conduct of specified postmarket studies, which may include such studies pursuant to a risk evaluation and mitigation strategy under section 505–1.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H91A6E6D886394F0786B41EA2977C4825"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon declining to grant reciprocal marketing approval under this section with respect to a covered product, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H22E86C182B90429B993AC580BB4599D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include the denial in a list of such denials for each month; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB171A3AEC31440448FFF32D7C22B6BF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than the end of the respective month, submit the list to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HABC01A8C9FF14219A041A9F45BC19DDE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Request</header><text>A request for reciprocal marketing approval shall—</text> <paragraph id="H856B6D5B2424403384212F0270592D4A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be in such form, be submitted in such manner, and contain such information as the Secretary deems necessary to determine whether the criteria listed in subsection (b)(2) are met; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H2FE328569AE24ABE8D39B3177E191237"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include, with respect to each country included in the list under section 802(b)(1) where the covered product is authorized to be lawfully marketed, as described in subsection (b)(2)(A), an English translation of the dossier issued by such country to authorize such marketing.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H66BC41F1A47F4CA8A67D12441DB9E828"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Timing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue an order granting, or declining to grant, reciprocal marketing approval with respect to a covered product not later than 30 days after the Secretary’s receipt of a request under subsection (b)(1) for the product. An order issued under this subsection shall take effect subject to Congressional disapproval under subsection (g).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFB9E6C6C8B5E4093A7B3FC3DE5635C1A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Labeling; device classification</header><text>During the 30-day period described in subsection (e)—</text> <paragraph id="H9208BDC0B4A1460E89DAFCF45E8490A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary and the sponsor of the covered product shall expeditiously negotiate and finalize the form and content of the labeling for a covered product for which reciprocal marketing approval is to be granted; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD88B938D1D9F4FF7B051FE36DD4C7B6D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of a device for which reciprocal marketing approval is to be granted, the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HA7BCD97D8D0E459EB71D3B194179EE3F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>classify the device pursuant to section 513; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCEF6B3FD78BE49A98FC0F1AA2DE6509F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determine whether, absent reciprocal marketing approval, the device would need to be cleared pursuant to section 510(k) or approved pursuant to section 515 to be lawfully marketed under this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H804CA8FA630D46C0BCC08D4BECB8A9FE"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Congressional disapproval of FDA orders</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H70F1392281F2487595B3ECA093B88B2F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A decision of the Secretary to decline to grant reciprocal marketing approval under this section shall not take effect if a joint resolution of disapproval of the decision is enacted.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4E7F0EF481D43B9AE14C2CD34032C7F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedure</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H95BAEDCF582C41AAA7E09B81BA4C80AB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the procedures described in subsections (b) through (g) of section 802 of title 5, United States Code, shall apply to the consideration of a joint resolution under this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC06F153E340145289678785BD939211F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> 
<clause id="H3D1EB2F9BE1F4DA8A092D86C25870B56"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the reference to <quote>section 801(a)(1)</quote> in section 802(b)(2)(A) of title 5, United States Code, shall be considered to refer to subsection (c)(2); and</text></clause> <clause id="H0CE8022DA754457F8BCF5E4325625418"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the reference to <quote>section 801(a)(1)(A)</quote> in section 802(e)(2) of title 5, United States Code, shall be considered to refer to subsection (c)(2).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8CC2A2E84CBE40E283A737E0BF102DD0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effect of Congressional disapproval</header><text>Reciprocal marketing approval under this section with respect to the applicable covered product shall take effect upon enactment of a joint resolution of disapproval under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H41DBB97A31C8444EB8210F141DCB99AA"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Applicability of relevant provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of this Act shall apply with respect to a covered product for which reciprocal marketing approval is in effect to the same extent and in the same manner as such provisions apply with respect to a product for which approval or clearance of an application or premarket notification under section 505(c), 510(k), or 515 of this Act or section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act, as applicable, is in effect.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9433D64FCD3449629A1E0B835243BBE4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Fees for request</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of imposing fees under chapter VII, a request for reciprocal marketing approval under this section shall be treated as an application or premarket notification for approval or clearance under section 505(c), 510(k), or 515 of this Act or section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act, as applicable.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA4888F41D0F3430CA7D44C2AEC2EDBDD"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall conduct an outreach campaign to encourage the sponsors of covered products that are potentially eligible for reciprocal marketing approval to request such approval.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC1799766B89047F998FA31C1D63223B5"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Covered product defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered product</term> means a drug, biological product, or device.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

