<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25826-C0L-M8-6K6"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S842 RS: No Hezbollah In Our Hemisphere Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 53</calendar><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 842</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250304">March 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date date="20250428">April 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</sponsor>, with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To counter efforts by Hezbollah to conduct terrorist activities in Latin America, and for other purposes. </official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Hezbollah In Our Hemisphere Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id6351c8bba78447839c4f8560c8f97f3f" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id44e0650a43a8448b91a065f8535116aa"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Iran and Hezbollah, an Iranian proxy, have been allowed to build their Latin American regional networks with impunity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc5de56b63f674ffeb903a0e1f523fcea"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Hezbollah is not considered a terrorist organization in most countries south of the Rio Grande River.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfb66260e7fb84460918d8598d4b03283"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In Latin America, the only countries that have designated Hezbollah as a terrorist organization are Argentina, Colombia, Guatemala, Honduras, and Paraguay.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf848880f66df4f3ab306fad1e6337d9b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The ability of local authorities to monitor or prosecute Hezbollah and its local operatives is limited without such a designation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide08494ea00f849b8bf5f5df018205316"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Hezbollah has support from local authoritarian regimes aligned with the Islamic Republic of Iran, such as the Nicolás Maduro regime in Venezuela, which has essentially become Iran’s forward operating base in Latin America.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc434618f29d04e7ba6cad9829d650536"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Hezbollah’s infrastructure in Peru, Colombia, Chile, and the Tri-Border Area of Argentina, Brazil, and Paraguay continues to grow.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id33ef3cd8987a4d05830e04481d0b341a"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In recent years, Hezbollah’s focus in Latin America has been on infiltrating criminal networks, money laundering, and sophisticated smuggling operations. </text></paragraph></section><section id="id0d8291c944d64bf5ad4cf5d0d1dfe1e8" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of State should pursue aggressive efforts against Iranian proxy networks in the Western Hemisphere, including by—</text><paragraph id="id77d8d0e987cf4dfcb1663ec4f8c2e8a1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>demanding that governments put an end to the impunity enjoyed by designated individuals and entities or face the consequences described in this Act for their inaction;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf7c67af008294266b03388a0a5d104b0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>working with allies, potentially through international forums, such as the Financial Action Task Force, to greylist government entities that cooperate with Hezbollah;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb01b87c34ebb49c3b6ee18bc4eedce28"><enum>(3)</enum><text>engaging governments in Latin America to ensure they have adequate legislative tools to investigate terrorist activities and combat the financing of terrorism; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide4dc3304f0434041b3d2e0769c2556b0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>persuading allies in the Latin America to designate Hezbollah as a terrorist organization, using Argentina’s model for designation as a blueprint. </text></paragraph></section><section id="ida84651c3814140e28e7f0a95bc00447b" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>4.</enum><header>Defined term</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="id281451e5df6a467eba8b0eb0e4026470" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide3f3bdf156e2487394ddac5a8fd38e81"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id088ff3360ecd4e4ab376619eccbaf534"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id101d7c7781f946cea262335a78eda66d" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3026b8e0409c47c88a8ac8cb54134d01"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd2772343e1804f43bd55e73c537e9ac5"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>. </text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id099141ebcf684b8aba1db93c16642734" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>5.</enum><header>Determination with respect to terrorist sanctuaries</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id93993abf3a9d4e06b7a710577662119b"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Director of National Intelligence, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb3e27595aea248f2bbe963cd34edade6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct an assessment to determine whether any country, region, or jurisdiction in Latin America meets the definition of <quote>terrorist sanctuary</quote> under section 140(d)(4) of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656f">22 U.S.C. 2656f(d)(4)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a7101a474574657b5f68f93c2588459"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit the results of such assessment to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbab33bc48f1747bc957695b3c357c2cb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In making a determination pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary of State shall consider—</text><paragraph id="id83eaa5a21a714eb8b745aca23f4044a4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the extent to which Hezbollah or any other foreign terrorist organization (as designated pursuant to section 219(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189(a)</external-xref>)) operates freely, raises or transfers funds, recruits, or obtains safe haven within a given country, region, or jurisdiction;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id584a8534f12b4faebafba58a71fcbc85"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether the host government has knowingly tolerated, or has failed to take action to address, terrorist activities after learning of their existence; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4629913ca57e458885ff7af13e8b9442"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any other factors relevant to the definition of <quote>terrorist sanctuary</quote> under section 140(d)(4) of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656f">22 U.S.C. 2656f(d)(4)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id5cb95ccb50fe42d4a63457fd974ef5fd" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>6.</enum><header>Revocation of visas</header><subsection id="id9abe380b4c154e578a0b6e8fd2c1aa6c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any foreign individual the President determines is a government official of any foreign state, subdivision, or municipality designated as a terrorist sanctuary under section 5 unless such official has taken significant, verifiable steps to stop such activity or the relevant jurisdiction no longer meets the definition of terrorist sanctuary under section 140(d)(4) of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656f">22 U.S.C. 2656f(d)(4)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id23de598d8aab490ba3ce5665fe7e42b5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><paragraph id="idf392ce6b5a9b4029944e03a55dd4fde6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Ineligibility for visas and admissions to the united states</header><text>A foreign individual described in subsection (a) shall be—</text><subparagraph id="id1a0a7c38bf264bde94319cd9a3bd1f8c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id427eb30e60984449910db61adddd1a7d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf82ab08b3db14308a97a7895abc86670"><enum>(C)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4253d1de53e54cf5a1cfab8c437f5b26"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><subparagraph id="id8c4823ea3d774cd18db7ab2f02316662"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The issuing consular officer or the Secretary of State (or a designee of the Secretary), in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>), shall revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to a foreign individual described in subsection (a) regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation was issued.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id02056d50a5c04c72aa00f25deacb2a9f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A revocation under subparagraph (A) shall—</text><clause id="id1e0ba387dc8645d5bec2cd0a27a00f18"><enum>(i)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></clause><clause id="id65dfbe8fa51146dd817d99d16b64bd27"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the foreign individual’s possession.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4e34dcea540e41099a1e22661e2e2d31"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4d43a9d2d63245dd8bab267fdcb7e2f5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception To comply with law enforcement objectives and agreement regarding the headquarters of the United Nations</header><text>Sanctions under subsection (b) shall not apply to a foreign person if admitting the person into the United States—</text><paragraph id="idc2ccdfe1102b40478921b71e74027a09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>would further important law enforcement objectives; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id56f6d0ff703b4a99b7e97aefc4edb1ad"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8d92562a9c694ab6a7e52f8f564a9243"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver</header><paragraph id="idb367b46b7a774854aa3c8fdfdab69a74"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may waive the application of sanctions under subsection (b) with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="idb4000e19e609442ab460cda867f30e88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual, on a case-by-case basis for periods not to exceed 180 days, if the President determines that such individual’s entry or continued presence in the United States is vital to the national security interests of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c52d48ed2a248d6a58e5be17aa15fbc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a jurisdiction, including a foreign country, or any subdivision of such country, that is designated as a terrorist sanctuary pursuant to section 5, for periods not to exceed 1 year, if the President determines that waiving the application of sanctions with respect to officials or other residents of such jurisdiction is in the national interest of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id91d61a30a636446ab88631e2f6a7a2c1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 15 days before granting or renewing a waiver under paragraph (1), the President shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that includes—</text><subparagraph id="id10e4b85b2ae149408bee9c7302f6298a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name of the individual or the specific jurisdiction subject to the waiver;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddb1a12cc14cf443c937e06cf89e864d6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a detailed justification explaining how the waiver serves—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id640b2a685e8a4ae49c3c5a1fdb7251d9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the national security interests of the United States (for individuals); or </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3982ae47b53f4820bbec3c4eaadd0ff2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the national interest of the United States (for jurisdictions); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc8b9c2e847db43d080e456f8883cfae7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to renewals—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id78902465c3a34d27ab86278360155942"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the individual’s or jurisdiction’s activities during the most recent waiver period; and </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6bab616a58724f80857226bf541c50cf"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any conditions imposed to ensure compliance with United States interests.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida834dd18a4ed478c82fd0cc935253eb5"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Termination of sanctions</header><text>The President may terminate the application of sanctions under this section with respect to a foreign individual if the President determines and reports to the appropriate congressional committees not later than 15 days before the termination of such sanctions that—</text><paragraph id="id2e6d06e8780f48b4a4bc9b8690629b2d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the foreign individual is no longer engaged in the activity that was the basis for such sanctions or has taken significant verifiable steps toward stopping such activity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2ef3d1326b204ab6a1b40d4d566853e9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the President has received reliable assurances that such individual will not knowingly engage in any activity subject to sanctions under this section in the future; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1a58fbd1bd73432388884c327556a31c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the termination of such sanctions is in the national security interests of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id485f77e667fd4392ba327fb21e4f1d18"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The President shall issue such regulations, licenses, and orders as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9ef0befcc825465e8f6bd2efcca23471" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>7.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any sanctions imposed pursuant to this Act shall terminate 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body><legis-body display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause"><section id="id97b2bece-9603-4b50-9808-61623de4679d" section-type="section-one" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Hezbollah In Our Hemisphere Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idaca9f763-5ae7-4c96-9f65-a1d8ff2102dd" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id04ba43ac-25aa-487f-bfc7-9012930be205"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Iran and Hezbollah, an Iranian proxy, have been allowed to build their Latin American regional networks with impunity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcd4f1b4f-621f-46bd-a8df-612e3313a656"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Hezbollah is not considered a terrorist organization in most countries south of the Rio Grande River.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3489a2ba-d989-4679-bce2-4dd0efd59643"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In Latin America, the only countries that have designated Hezbollah as a terrorist organization are Argentina, Colombia, Guatemala, Honduras, and Paraguay.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc121ee38-4da6-4532-8bbb-c21ed614d7bd"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The ability of local authorities to monitor or prosecute Hezbollah and its local operatives is limited without such a designation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4a1a6263-811e-4143-8daa-7a4ffbfec6ef"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Hezbollah has support from local authoritarian regimes aligned with the Islamic Republic of Iran, such as the Nicolás Maduro regime in Venezuela, which has essentially become Iran’s forward operating base in Latin America.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide2bfaa55-5b25-41b6-b15a-93f8d5a55e56"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Hezbollah’s infrastructure in Peru, Colombia, Chile, and the Tri-Border Area of Argentina, Brazil, and Paraguay continues to grow.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9148a3ba-0a20-4a98-99b2-0f73aed489f2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In recent years, Hezbollah’s focus in Latin America has been on infiltrating criminal networks, money laundering, and sophisticated smuggling operations. </text></paragraph></section><section id="ida96f49d2-1cad-4821-a67d-df92c5f3eb58" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of State should pursue aggressive efforts against Iranian proxy networks in the Western Hemisphere, including by—</text><paragraph id="id7010aef1-f4bb-4ffc-9801-25814986a832"><enum>(1)</enum><text>demanding that governments put an end to the impunity enjoyed by designated individuals and entities or face the consequences described in this Act for their inaction;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5734dcc2-b9ca-45e6-828f-2b91d9de9d0a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>working with allies, potentially through international forums, such as the Financial Action Task Force, to greylist government entities that cooperate with Hezbollah;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbce331f2-6809-44ed-8a76-f9511a7a8ddf"><enum>(3)</enum><text>engaging governments in Latin America to ensure they have adequate legislative tools to investigate terrorist activities and combat the financing of terrorism; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7a30059d-e9e8-4bcd-a11d-471a64d63dc4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>persuading allies in the Latin America to designate Hezbollah as a terrorist organization, using Argentina’s model for designation as a blueprint. </text></paragraph></section><section id="iddf97069c-d394-4e0e-b699-a61b504c9cae" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>4.</enum><header>Defined term</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="id278f0813-5153-4f3e-bc12-af3569d2d710" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id32a59f47-b79f-4d65-ae3e-377637a7108b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id867ed9e7-b5dc-4341-8cec-3deace20dd42"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5db7ebaf-7bb1-4271-b759-379e16de0584" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id527aeef4-80a0-4ec7-ad48-c0267cbc54ef"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida15808ed-b86d-4d5f-913f-089533547210"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>. </text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida29e8e4e-af9f-470d-920c-864139e0d1ab" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>5.</enum><header>Determination with respect to terrorist sanctuaries</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2af4d513-5ed2-4692-afa0-bc2c013ee0f0"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Director of National Intelligence, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd3357cbc-77ce-42d2-b52a-cb6eab848e6b"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct an assessment to determine whether any country, region, or jurisdiction in Latin America meets the definition of <quote>terrorist sanctuary</quote> under section 140(d)(4) of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656f">22 U.S.C. 2656f(d)(4)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc4f8e15a-f641-44ee-8d79-39c1dcd52116"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit the results of such assessment to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id71403805-ed0c-4f9d-bf3b-c5accea69bac"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In making a determination pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary of State shall consider—</text><paragraph id="id52c36f9d-d305-4a88-bd88-ba819d4425ee"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the extent to which Hezbollah or any other foreign terrorist organization (as designated pursuant to section 219(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189(a)</external-xref>)) operates freely, raises or transfers funds, recruits, or obtains safe haven within a given country, region, or jurisdiction;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide6ecf6c0-48c5-42e8-b4ae-3cdea6ef939b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether the host government has knowingly tolerated, or has failed to take action to address, terrorist activities after learning of their existence; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc7964aec-efc1-49fe-84a0-89b11a91fda1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any other factors relevant to the definition of <quote>terrorist sanctuary</quote> under section 140(d)(4) of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656f">22 U.S.C. 2656f(d)(4)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idf45d2e89-bf85-4293-ab53-f3f9838e64b9" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>6.</enum><header>Revocation of visas</header><subsection id="idc1d8aba6-68c1-4349-94d1-a7cd1b7f2c38"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any foreign individual the President determines is a government official of any foreign state, subdivision, or municipality designated as a terrorist sanctuary under section 5 unless such official has taken significant, verifiable steps to stop such activity or the relevant jurisdiction no longer meets the definition of terrorist sanctuary under section 140(d)(4) of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656f">22 U.S.C. 2656f(d)(4)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id80c528bc-8e06-48de-9b68-1a618793b4d1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><paragraph id="idb4b84e5d-2866-4b38-bf18-2d097f30f806"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Ineligibility for visas and admissions to the united states</header><text>A foreign individual described in subsection (a) shall be—</text><subparagraph id="id945353cd-8ede-42ef-8ac8-58db7b85d314"><enum>(A)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideae9485c-bbcf-435e-8b7a-86fccc52eefe"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id67df8942-3e94-4b71-8895-4affab20fabe"><enum>(C)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id66ef4628-7824-4012-8b0f-de54844593b7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><subparagraph id="idb032ea1d-ce96-4d79-b402-2b85430d2b6c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The issuing consular officer or the Secretary of State (or a designee of the Secretary), in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>), shall revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to a foreign individual described in subsection (a) regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation was issued.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb1f3c649-bbab-46ed-9b3b-719e3e92e6cf"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A revocation under subparagraph (A) shall—</text><clause id="idf5237525-9d1e-4a09-a0e4-350f9c31ca45"><enum>(i)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></clause><clause id="id233fa337-131a-4fba-8322-1852e9e3c068"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the foreign individual’s possession.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbf6998b8-1a36-42da-aac1-3b18c5db30a7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd96c75ee-aed1-4dff-90c6-d90172cd2235"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception To comply with law enforcement objectives and agreement regarding the headquarters of the United Nations</header><text>Sanctions under subsection (b) shall not apply to a foreign person if admitting the person into the United States—</text><paragraph id="id7de4b312-0cda-47d4-827b-cc04a8887826"><enum>(1)</enum><text>would further important law enforcement objectives; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5426e1f3-ef61-4eac-acc8-0c5d6f571a12"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0320b3c8-9647-405a-a786-46ab5ff1814e"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver</header><paragraph id="ida44606ef-f4a5-4a81-af3c-95efd14e0962"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may waive the application of sanctions under subsection (b) with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="id8e263067-b5e7-417a-b17c-ddd9702b1262"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual, on a case-by-case basis for periods not to exceed 180 days, if the President determines that such individual’s entry or continued presence in the United States is vital to the national security interests of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6e40a22e-8e44-4f8e-93b8-33b23e08be1b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a jurisdiction, including a foreign country, or any subdivision of such country, that is designated as a terrorist sanctuary pursuant to section 5, for periods not to exceed 1 year, if the President determines that waiving the application of sanctions with respect to officials or other residents of such jurisdiction is in the national interest of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ac4ed42-050f-4b30-96f3-671892356a89"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 15 days before granting or renewing a waiver under paragraph (1), the President shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that includes—</text><subparagraph id="id37de1531-305f-43ff-aa50-7525970ae19f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name of the individual or the specific jurisdiction subject to the waiver;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide3005363-9e80-48ca-88c7-931dedb9fb3c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a detailed justification explaining how the waiver serves—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9a95ab85-bf38-43c9-b840-af9f1ba360cf"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the national security interests of the United States (for individuals); or </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id02fa0d5f-695a-4b3d-848a-bd2817ee18d2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the national interest of the United States (for jurisdictions); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id177181a7-44a3-4d99-8352-d7687069ee82"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to renewals—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9b07e454-2df0-486f-87f7-5058bff9e727"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the individual’s or jurisdiction’s activities during the most recent waiver period; and </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47106126-d867-4ad1-898e-36cf02ae6ac2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any conditions imposed to ensure compliance with United States interests.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id57a5050d-5495-48fa-89b7-889143f0f62c"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Termination of sanctions</header><text>The President may terminate the application of sanctions under this section with respect to a foreign individual if the President determines and reports to the appropriate congressional committees not later than 15 days before the termination of such sanctions that—</text><paragraph id="idc20cadae-5a8c-4aaf-a344-1c76e35c8d7e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the foreign individual is no longer engaged in the activity that was the basis for such sanctions or has taken significant verifiable steps toward stopping such activity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf2c7e913-41ba-4480-9173-cebf2e3b419a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the President has received reliable assurances that such individual will not knowingly engage in any activity subject to sanctions under this section in the future; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id81fb2945-93d9-4045-9801-7f85d27bf03c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the termination of such sanctions is in the national security interests of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id83e8e044-8d80-4ebe-b8dc-e950e1e0fe80"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The President shall issue such regulations, licenses, and orders as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1e975c7a-1b8b-4212-95dd-d1010463c731" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>7.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any sanctions imposed pursuant to this Act shall terminate 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date date="20250428">April 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

