<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEN25525-6L2-5H-2W3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2842 IS: Stop CMV Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2842</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250917" legis-day="20250916">September 17 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for congenital Cytomegalovirus screening of newborns.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H8EA6C5EFFA3646A387A9E09CD6200EBB"><section section-type="section-one" id="H66CB52D6F71745B0B617FEB9B9A2B658"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>Stop CMV Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H809EAC08F517453997D3D77CD20B6FCF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Screening of congenital Cytomegalovirus</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part A of title XI of the Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 1116 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300b-15">42 U.S.C. 300b–15</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9BA76A58C70F440F9BFFD59BF02E3FFF"><section id="HBC2297A97C6247DEA1301EDB589F9F3E"><enum>1116A.</enum><header>Screening of congenital Cytomegalovirus</header><subsection id="HB0252005CF434ED1B5111A8E324858C1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each hospital or other health care entity caring for infants who are 21 days or less of age (as designated by the Secretary) may administer, or cause to have administered, to every such infant in its care a test for congenital Cytomegalovirus in accordance with this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H79BFC32E44184EC1B2810E1A56DD8396"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Process</header><paragraph id="HD6AEA43B93A347648902DCE2BB6B57DF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out this section, the chief executive officer for health in each State may prescribe standards and procedures for the administration of testing under subsection (a), including recording the results of such tests, tracking activities, conducting follow-up reviews, and carrying out educational activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4BF18EE42C348869A5E55484BCDB102"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dissemination of information</header><text>In carrying out this section, the chief executive officer for health in each State may prescribe standards and procedures setting forth the manner in which testing information is disseminated to a parent or guardian of the infant to be tested.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3D91BB42BB2440E95B317725606B278"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Failure to prescribe</header><text>If a State has not prescribed standards and procedures that are approved as provided for in paragraph (4) by the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Stop CMV Act of 2025</short-title>, the Discretionary Advisory Committee on Heritable Disorders in Newborns and Children established under section 1111 (referred to in this section as the <quote>Advisory Committee</quote>) shall prescribe appropriate standards and procedures which may be implemented by such State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D7AC73875884D4ABCCDF44352B09F8E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Review and approval</header><text>The standards and procedures prescribed under this subsection shall be subject to review and approval by the Advisory Committee. In reviewing or prescribing standards and procedures as required under this subsection, the Advisory Committee shall consider standards and procedures adopted in other States with respect to the screening of congenital Cytomegalovirus, the standards and procedures adopted in such State with respect to the screening of infants for other heritable diseases, and any scientific evidence the Advisory Committee considers relevant to provide for the screening of infants for congenital Cytomegalovirus.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd5b0e9b7af6a4c8892b5e61c9d58916d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grants</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc87be720571042cd90c87e13b16d14e3"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Health Resources and Services Administration</header><subparagraph id="id59639b45182d4f29b90b314ca8fcced5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall award grants to States that prescribe standards and procedures in accordance with paragraphs (1) and (2), to be distributed by the States to entities described in subsection (a) to administer tests in accordance with that subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id40a9448e3df04bbc91fdd452021f39e2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out subparagraph (A) such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2026 and 2027.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddec6905215394f2d9ea9e7a0ef96e4aa"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Centers for disease control and prevention</header><subparagraph id="idab25feed9b4648a18b775ab1af9ccd3d"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall award grants to, or enter into cooperative agreements with, States to provide technical assistance to State agencies or designated entities of States—</text><clause id="id576c6de9bfdd455a804d9bebea72aa70"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to develop, maintain, and improve data collection systems relating to congenital Cytomegalovirus; and</text></clause><clause id="idbf136aaa455c4bcda25b07d8d1377aad"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>to assist in the education and training of health care providers, patients, and the general public regarding the risk reduction or prevention, symptoms, diagnosis, and treatment of congenital Cytomegalovirus, including, as necessary, through the publication of scientific, evidence-based educational materials on internet webpages maintained by State agencies or designated entities of States.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id09FE0A37C43B465DB576CC557E28F887"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out subparagraph (A) such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2026 and 2027.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9712e99a80a448aa9f9fbcc8fe7c2a37"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National Institutes of Health</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbcf0c7eb00574ed38d38b05a17cacb19"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Institutes of Health shall—</text><clause id="idabc8116035f84371a70f749dca0abda6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for the purposes of this section, establish a program, or expand existing programs, of research and development on the efficacy of new screening techniques and technology relating to congenital Cytomegalovirus, including clinical studies of screening methods, studies on efficacy of intervention, and related research; and</text></clause><clause id="idad82f688b32d4463bb445aeafc0b908d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establish a program, or expand existing programs, of research and development into congenital Cytomegalovirus diagnostics, prevention, treatments including public health awareness campaigns, risk reduction, and vaccine development, and cures or treatments (during pregnancy and after birth).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb2aeec8177804461bfd9cacffaf7edc0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Institutes of Health shall carry out subparagraph (A) using amounts available to the Director and not otherwise obligated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H0F1FF8B89F48465C9CC5087D837E0410"><enum>3.</enum><header>Advisory committee on heritable disorders in newborns and children</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1111(b) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300b-10">42 U.S.C. 300b–10(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H63DE99467783486DB2AF0EEACC0A55BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (7) by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BBB9F10F9DF4F90AFA6D1B4DDB90961"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (8) as paragraph (9); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H833DC70C3DCE4BC69594C7EE00BD92D7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (7) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF620150AE7924E8CB2FF422D8A08EED8"><paragraph id="H58360FB6C9DD49F781A9EF4C8921A67F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>carry out activities under section 1116A; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

