<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4EE8D77AB9F74E83BF8834F2D8EB6F4E" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 785 IH: Expressing support for designation of the week of October 4, 2025, through October 10, 2025, as “World Space Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 785</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251003">October 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for designation of the week of October 4, 2025, through October 10, 2025, as <quote>World Space Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas this year marks the 26th annual international World Space Week, which was declared by the General Assembly of the United Nations by resolution 54/68 on December 6, 1999, to celebrate each year at the international level the contributions of space science and technology to the betterment of the human condition;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the theme for World Space Week 2025, <quote>Living in Space</quote>, will highlight groundbreaking advancements for sustainable living in space, from life support systems and space habitats to research on human adaptability and resource utilization in extraterrestrial environments, and consist of a myriad of space-related events held by space agencies, aerospace companies, schools, planetaria, museums, and astronomy clubs in a common timeframe to achieve greater student and public impact through synchronization;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the study of Earth and space sciences leads to an improved understanding of the Earth’s and the universe’s natural systems and the connections between humanity and these systems;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Earth and space sciences contribute to the understanding of Earth as a planet in the solar system and in the universe;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas space research, exploration, and technology leads to the development of innovative new technologies and industries that fuel the United States economy and improve quality of life, including in health and medicine, transportation, public safety, consumer goods, information technology, mining, and energy;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Earth and space sciences leverage capabilities such as geologic mapping and remote sensing technologies which provide the foundational knowledge of Earth’s natural systems that is integral to the discovery, development, and conservation of natural resources, such as energy, water, and minerals;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Earth and space science researchers and educators drive creativity and passion for the science, technology, engineering, and mathematics fields among students of all ages through diverse and innovative education and public outreach efforts;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas space scientists and researchers in the Nation’s labs, universities, research institutions, and Federal agencies, including the U.S. Geological Survey, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the National Park Service, the National Science Foundation, and the Department of Energy, continually push the frontiers of human knowledge of the universe, help develop and incubate the concepts and programs that keep United States companies and industries at the innovative forefront of the world’s economy, and inspire future generations of researchers, scientists, and informed citizens;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the space sciences and technology make vital contributions to the understanding of the universe, its history, and the potential for life on other planets; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Earth science using space-based observations for research and application makes vital contributions to the understanding of, and respect for, nature and the Earth: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H2B982B1EC8A2494F862008424E313DA0"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H322F745BD7B64722BB41B1646C469E32"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H5382CF3C58754F7BA3FAC920BAEB8809"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>World Space Week</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA49D547D312A496CBD15D24A4D356D09"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses strong support for the goals and ideals of World Space Week and its aims to increase understanding of, and interest in, space sciences and technology at the local, State, national, and international levels;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HABEE61CDC2BE40C38626BF61B2F794AF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the importance of international cooperation in space missions and outreach and education in furthering knowledge and discovery of new worlds and development of sustainable living solutions for space;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC68831E7DA304600A566DCD83D8BC9C0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of education and public outreach efforts to ensure that the United States public gains a better understanding and appreciation for the impact of the space science and technology on their daily lives;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFD252A6E4FDE443E9285FD10879AB6CA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages K–12 students to participate in local, State, and national events in connection with World Space Week and to get involved in the celebration by exploring academic applications of and opportunities in space science and technology; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H14A84DF297144772A90CD0C5B552320E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to observe World Space Week with appropriate activities to gain a better understanding and appreciation for the space sciences and technology and their contributions to society.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution> 

