<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H02E2ACBB0A514E489E7FC4E600B55BDC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5519 IH: Welles Remy Crowther Congressional Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5519</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250919">September 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000598">Mr. LaLota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To award posthumously a Congressional Gold Medal to Welles Remy Crowther, in recognition of his bravery, heroism, and sacrifice in the face of one of the gravest tragedies in American history.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFE54DA42303F40D8864CBEB1E1984199" style="OLC"><section id="H0F6F452D8E7C48E4A55A16DC81A511BC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Welles Remy Crowther Congressional Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD2A857FD774D44AF8020AE98BB98CA8F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HF0454282F831423BBBF51B7399DFC7A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Welles Remy Crowther grew up in Upper Nyack, New York, where he served his community as a volunteer firefighter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB7587A55F914E9B9AFCDA25930C47B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>After graduating from Boston College, he returned to New York to begin working as an equities trader at the World Trade Center.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5EFE78E2F764A89B1483E7A2FBBD8C5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The events of September 11, 2001, have forever changed our Nation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F363AA52BDC44EBA55B868273D68204"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In New York City, in the skies over Pennsylvania, at the Pentagon and in surrounding areas everyday Americans responded to the unprecedented tragedy around them with extraordinary acts of heroism and sacrifice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E1D06610AB644BE8E3FB1EDCE75C90A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>When Flight 175 hit the World Trade Center’s South Tower on the morning of September 11, Welles acted with remarkable calm and compassion that was starkly remembered by all those he encountered that morning.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE576FD395D634D96A6DB62AD88ECA2ED"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Welles found other survivors on the 78th floor Sky Lobby and helped lead them to safety, carrying an injured woman down the stairs on his back. Donning his red bandanna to help with the smoke, he repeatedly returned to the Sky Lobby to help rescue others.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H683C6A418305403E85079F5A1DC90445"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When Welles arrived at ground level, he stayed to join firefighters in attempting to fight fires, administer first aid, and return to save others, until his eventual death when the tower collapsed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7043322564049D6A35B4026A7246D05"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Through survivors accounts of a <quote>Man in the Red Bandanna</quote>, Welles mother, Alison, began to piece together what had happened and identified him with those he had aided.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0C7E0FC847D4FC0AA353EEB8689F275"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The red bandanna has become a symbol of his heroic efforts and an inspiration to so many who have been touched by Welles story.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3F5D194A8974780A7B1FB75310C852D"><enum>(10)</enum><text>In the face of tragedy, Welles Remy Crowther demonstrated exceptional bravery, leadership, heroism, and sacrifice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5230F71B329944269E58EEEBF268C875"><enum>(11)</enum><text>As the <quote>Man in the Red Bandanna</quote>, he has been enshrined in the history and hearts of America as an embodiment of the virtues we all are called to emulate as individuals and as a Nation.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HB6DD28340C53491AAA97511D79717829"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header><subsection id="H4B5D4A0BBCF34FF89F5846244F560FD9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Presentation authorized</header><text>The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the posthumous presentation, on behalf of Congress, of a gold medal of appropriate design in commemoration to Welles Remy Crowther, in recognition of his bravery, heroism, and sacrifice in the face of one of the gravest tragedies in American history.</text></subsection><subsection id="H33E0073833F54E9A8D4DC95F954C5391"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text>For purposes of the presentation referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions to be determined by the Secretary. The design shall bear an image of, and inscription of the name of, Welles Remy Crowther.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4BD0A9995C87460EBA19BBD4A966BBC5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disposition of medal</header><text>Following the presentation described in subsection (a), the gold medal shall be given to the mother of Welles Remy Crowther, Alison Crowther.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD7C2AE063A554CCF9E53FABCF8D48036"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to section 3 at a price sufficient to cover the costs of the medals, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section><section id="H9C51B3B0EC4540F99DCE49F129BB1C0D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header><subsection id="H951C727A86E547A1ABC21549EBD29D34"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>The medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA493ECCADFC14207822795CA9EB00BC2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section><section id="H7251DB9F25F94C058AAE45F40A1E5D46"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header><subsection id="HB1FC46BCC86B415FB8D40B119FFA95CC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To use fund amounts</header><text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck pursuant to this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H389D96EB5D544B9DBE5BC52BB906EB99"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under this Act shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

