<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H95793BEC760843A59F1547AD4EB356B9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4691 IH: Responsive Counterterrorism Policy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4691</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Department of State’s Bureau of Counterterrorism to develop and maintain written counterterrorism strategies for countries and regions where there is a significant terrorist threat or ongoing United States counterterrorism engagement.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2CAA1BDA69A84B15B58D7E728C335AB7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H05AE618D31BE444AA2653AC1FCD3C0EE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Responsive Counterterrorism Policy Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HFA58EC0F912E44CFAA2D00B522BF9747"><enum>2.</enum><header>Counterterrorism strategies</header> 
<subsection id="H43696CCCC0794403919A45325C77DA01"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header> 
<paragraph id="HE84580D987CD440A8B746B322BD52B2B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State shall direct the Department of State’s Bureau of Counterterrorism to develop and maintain a written counterterrorism (CT) strategy for each country or region where there is a significant terrorist threat or ongoing United States CT engagement in order to enhance the effectiveness, coordination, and accountability of United States CT policy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H137F3D4BFD434546A7697D335715C88D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>Each strategy required by this subsection is intended to be distinct from the Department’s annual Country Reports on Terrorism and is to serve as a forward-looking, operational planning document that is specific to the Bureau of Counterterrorism.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD45FD9CF61784CE4933113F219CB65C0">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Matters To be included</header>
        <paragraph id="H15FAFF4DBEAC4676A7B7C15B6E4C86CB">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
 <text>Each strategy required by subsection (a) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HD2B7A8BB7C0443A4B312658C13C73B03"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>identify the specific threats posed, articulate clear objectives, outline coordinated actions with interagency partners and international partners, and describe metrics for assessing progress and success;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H8A6A2833225A431F8AC7E88F808C34F0">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>specifically describe how coordination with such partners will be carried out, including clearly defined roles, responsibilities, and mechanisms for collaboration;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H39EDB5A79CBA4BBE99474E1BB7001328">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>take into account local political, economic, and social dynamics and should align with broader United States foreign policy goals; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H81DEC963C58847AD874E075DAB8E2352">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>ensure that the Bureau of Counterterrorism shall serve as the lead entity with respect to such strategies.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HAAFEAFE9C1974CB0A621EA38D1253239">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Interagency and international partners</header>
 <text>For the purposes of paragraph (1)(A)—</text> <subparagraph id="H35EDBA075F3843B2B34C7C64F1B99EF3"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>interagency partners shall include all relevant bureaus, offices, and components of United States Government departments and agencies that contribute to CT efforts in any capacity; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H97E154AD444949D8A6DDBFEC7950B153">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>international partners shall include all foreign government entities and local actors that are actively engaged in, and demonstrably committed to, CT efforts within their respective countries or regions.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HBA9D83384B5C406A81856C4C41634B2B">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>References</header>
 <text>Any references to other United States Government department or agency or international partner is intended to articulate the Bureau of Counterterrorism’s understanding of ongoing efforts, coordination mechanisms, and areas of engagement, and not to imply shared authorship or responsibility for any strategic documents.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF91B48E603864BA58C05D1D89EE14A1A">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Updates</header>
 <text>Each strategy required by subsection (a) shall be reviewed and updated on an annual basis, or more frequently if significant changes in threat dynamics or policy priorities occur. Each such update should incorporate lessons learned and reflect changes in operational context or strategic priorities.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H4A1509BE2BFA4BC6B9F6334951C52409"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Congressional briefings</header> 
<paragraph id="HA28970745BD248B98BCF402FF2E41310"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial briefing</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Bureau of Counterterrorism shall brief Congress on the countries and regions for which it plans to develop the strategies required by subsection (a), including the criteria used to prioritize such strategies.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE2E5D0236DC4AF7B0177C345ECCC7A1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual briefings</header><text>The Bureau of Counterterrorism shall brief Congress annually on the development, implementation, and updates to the strategies required by subsection (a), including how the strategies inform programmatic funding and diplomatic engagement.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

