<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDA79141B1ACD4EC6A8AE1377E5F04F6B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3920 IH: Lawless Cities Accountability Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3920</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250611">June 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000829">Mr. Wied</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide that Federal funds may not be made available to lawless jurisdictions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4326354F9DCA4301BD0CECB1B357E109" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5C0482442FBE400E8E804A9CA31FB7FE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Lawless Cities Accountability Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HDB8CB66746DE4F8CB5A55D2F790D88B3"><enum>2.</enum><header>No Federal funds for lawless jurisdictions</header> <subsection id="HED2EB11DD60541379605332CB4D6F9FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal funds may be made available to a jurisdiction that the Attorney General determines is a lawless jurisdiction.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB01BD0B37CE244E8A64EFA509146BB85"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Attorney general determinations</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and not less than quarterly thereafter, the Attorney General shall make determinations on which jurisdictions are lawless jurisdictions, and shall make such determinations, and an explanation of each determination, publicly available.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8968684C07B646EB9E6C1003875A1A5B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reinstatement of Federal funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A jurisdiction that the Attorney General determines is a lawless jurisdiction may begin receiving Federal funds on the later of—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFB8AAA20C60E4B51BA71D11D093CA767"><enum>(1)</enum><text>180 days after the date on which the Attorney General first determines that the jurisdiction is lawless; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF99A67FF82E44E78581CB2B3F511D45"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date on which the Attorney General determines that the jurisdiction is no longer a lawless jurisdiction.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H190DC0C7281F4F6D951492F72FA3F6C4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>lawless jurisdiction</term> means a State or political subdivision of a State that—</text> <paragraph id="HD5CA80755B9A491EA6664E9A99A7BBE2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">forbids a law enforcement agency from intervening to restore order amid widespread or sustained violence or destruction;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90E7CF2F91ED4B79A5229AAC6199BB88"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has withdrawn law enforcement protection from a geographical area or structure that law enforcement officers are lawfully entitled to access, but have been officially prevented from accessing or permitted to access only in exceptional circumstances, except when law enforcement officers are briefly withheld as a tactical decision intended to resolve safely and expeditiously a specific and ongoing unlawful incident posing an imminent threat to the safety of individuals or law enforcement officers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF3DB450B9B54105A4F28D897EBFBC94"><enum>(3)</enum><text>disempowers or defunds law enforcement agencies; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8235EDD9E4804C3B8E788C25609547FC"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">refuses to accept an offer of law enforcement assistance from the Federal Government amid widespread or sustained violence or destruction in the jurisdiction, during which the jurisdiction has been unable to restore order.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

