<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5A0BE6287A784B04A8B7F00DDE9315CC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4770 IH: Regulatory Evidence-based Standards for Thorough Accountability and Reassuring Tests—Securing Updated and Necessary Statutory Evaluations Timely Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4770</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250725">July 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Small Business</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/6">chapter 6</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, to provide additional requirements for the periodic review of rules, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6763AB551F6D4177B6D81A7B74C16C40" style="OLC"><section id="H4E98F2C920684898B5004D3A402BC82F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Regulatory Evidence-based Standards for Thorough Accountability and Reassuring Tests—Securing Updated and Necessary Statutory Evaluations Timely Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RESTART SUNSET Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFE4004B7B62740A9884FACD134A9AA7A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Additional requirements for periodic review of rules</header><subsection id="HB932F16859DA44F68E0581A5959494EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Periodic review of rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 610 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H7B10F0B66FD84B55961EA408D63864CD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="HD44BA4332727491F991CBF63A58514F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by striking <quote>Within one hundred and eighty days after the effective date of this chapter, each agency shall publish in the Federal Register a plan for the periodic review of the rules</quote> and inserting <quote>Each agency shall periodically review the rules</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C62C0D98E3B443E9AB26CFB6A7B1D77"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the second sentence;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA5410FF4EC24E58A58F967B48E1191C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The plan shall provide for the review of all such agency rules existing on the effective date of this chapter within ten years of that date and for the review of such rules adopted after the effective date of this chapter within ten years of the publication of such rules as the final rule.</quote> and inserting <quote>Each agency shall review all such agency rules existing on the date of enactment of the RESTART SUNSET Act of 2025 within ten years of that date and review such rules adopted after the date of enactment of the RESTART SUNSET Act of 2025 within 10 years of the publication of such rules as the final rule.</quote>; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89B08EE4419E444B8D09505DE36FC6C5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by adding at the end the following: <quote>Each year, each agency shall publish in the Federal Register a list of the rules which do not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities, and the basis for such conclusion.</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B0665DD62A64A9093EBFA20BA3844DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 611(a) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H7840A04F25354FC78F308E76A424A251"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by inserting <quote>except as provided in paragraph (5)</quote> before <quote>the court shall order</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H83D32257A1A64609BF3604BA1AA94A5B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (5) as paragraph (6); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59AF98C4BB284D16AD2E352DA0FE862A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H9032FC9C4493448994CFF957835AEA30" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HEBA3F3B60D4548A28ADB1A6CA66F75EE"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, if the court finds that the agency failed to comply with section 610 with respect to a rule, the court shall enter an order prohibiting enforcement of such rule.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

