<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE03166F17BA04E72BEB9E67BDC1F698D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5338 IH: Union Auto Workers Job Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5338</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250911">September 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require information about the motor vehicle plant in which vehicles are assembled for Federal procurement, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA00A570B8A994AD7B490DBEB7DE84F80" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H22546991A49D4D3EB3D1C5354BF7A365" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Union Auto Workers Job Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9E0BF6DC35CB4942A10BA09CB2EFB915"><enum>2.</enum><header>Location information required for bids and contracts</header> <subsection id="HD5CBF7749BE349679DC054CA442C1926"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Bid requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of an executive agency shall require the following information be included with respect to any bid for a covered contract:</text> 
<paragraph id="H144B3E126A014D1C9882BDC4FEFE4674"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The mailing address of each motor vehicle plant in which any motor vehicle purchased under the contract is made or assembled.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H04834764DC8642C8B97AACCDC5524005"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If more than one motor vehicle plant is included pursuant to paragraph (1), a description of what is made or assembled in each such motor vehicle plant.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5D2D73A829DD49CBB27439E4BEC69853"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The average hourly wage of hourly employees employed by such motor vehicle assembly employer at each such motor vehicle plant.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAFDA9A23AA784714B7154D53622756F5"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The minimum hourly wage of hourly employees employed by such motor vehicle assembly employer at each such motor vehicle plant.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5F55969D40374C329E521E3C8CEAAD25"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The maximum hourly wage of hourly employees employed by such motor vehicle assembly employer at each such motor vehicle plant.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2584281185D043F5822045B3234CFD77"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of temporary non-permanent employees employed by such motor vehicle assembly employer at each such motor vehicle plant.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEFD593C6954D41C98A6BB396E0939229"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A disclosure of any National Labor Relations Act violations by such motor vehicle assembly employer at each such motor vehicle plant.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H227D1FCF83E34FB3B44A83C746B4741F"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A disclosure of any Occupational Safety and Health Administration violations by such motor vehicle assembly employer at each such motor vehicle plant.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC881CA5F20FB48A69D61AD429471C9C4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contract requirements</header><text>The head of an executive agency shall require the following be included in any covered contract entered into by that agency:</text> <paragraph id="H16D2B4176B17487485B2BF73972C9805"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The information provided in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A851AD956564EE3B5D452D195E8C854"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an awardee of a covered contract seeks to make or assemble any motor vehicle in a motor vehicle plant other than what is included in the contract pursuant to paragraph (1), the awardee must seek written permission from the relevant executive agency before any change of motor vehicle plant.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC8C1FC81457342D78C86E0AABF9EAE8F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A request for written permission described in paragraph (2) shall include the information described in paragraphs (3) through (8) of subsection (a) for the proposed motor vehicle plant.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC21D700FC79E4D1CB8509E5693DEC078"><enum>(4)</enum><text>If the awardee submits a request for written permission described in paragraph (2), on the same day the permission is requested, the awardee shall notify any labor organization directly affected by such change of motor vehicle plant.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEEFAD2057B11483481E3917980B1ABF3" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An explicit policy of neutrality by an awardee regarding any labor organizing by employees at a motor vehicle plant covered by the contract, including with regards to any decision by such employees to form or join a labor organization.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3A9DCA90A56B450BA95C8063D649E947"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HEA04C5B2ECBD41F8B90879CEA3C8C29E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered contract</header><text>The term <term>covered contract</term> means a contract relating to the assembly of a vehicle.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4B63F957BE8E4CC3BA775E6C8C4AF9C1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Executive agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>executive agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 133 of title 41, United States Code, and includes the United States Postal Service.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF4D4A00969C4CF7B37565F08DB8CF3D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Labor organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>labor organization</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/152">29 U.S.C. 152</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFDD3C1EB7EC04334943DF93673FE20AA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Motor vehicle</header><text>The term <term>motor vehicle</term> has the meaning given that term in section 30102 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HADAEABF4F3EF4D8F901FCCE99F896136"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Motor vehicle assembly employer</header><text>The term <term>motor vehicle assembly employer</term> means an employer who employs employees to assemble motor vehicles at a motor vehicle assembly plant.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F9F6F7194504FB1A2B0C965A24C210A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Motor vehicle plant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>motor vehicle plant</term> means a location that makes or assembles motor vehicles.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HE7334BA5D7614AEBA0F45841382E69D3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on spending</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No Federal funds, including any funds in the Postal Service Fund, may be obligated or expended for the purchase of delivery vehicles unless the Postal Service issues a change order on the contract with Oshkosh Defense that requires Oshkosh Defense to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H182B8DDC740C438BBED20C9205B1797D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>agree that its execution of and compliance with a bona fide union neutrality agreement is material to the Government’s payment decisions for purposes of section 3729(b)(4) of title 31, United States Code; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD5A939120064A198E026B8095F762F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>certify that it will execute and comply with a bona fide union neutrality agreement covering all production employees within the scope of the contract.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

