<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE6F2A138DF3C4FB0977A9922B30C7003" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5567 IH: Affordable Housing for Our Troops Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5567</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250926">September 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001123">Mr. Cisneros</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Defense to provide a briefing to Congress on plans to expand access to affordable housing for members of the Armed Forces through partnerships with local governments and housing providers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2C495A17BB5F47529E157380D46FE319" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC5D4036A42574B0D97E1F2AFA81CE0AE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Affordable Housing for Our Troops Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section>
<section id="H6C7363E5E3E44F50B88B5F701B5C40C3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Briefing on affordable housing for members of the Armed Forces</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall provide to Congress a briefing on actions that have been taken and are planned to be taken by the Department of Defense to expand access to affordable housing for members of the Armed Forces through partnerships with local governments and housing providers. Such briefing shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H94C7E04E43634AFEB051C4810B4A436B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an identification of high cost-of-living locations and rural locations near remote and isolated installations where members of the Armed Forces face the greatest housing affordability challenges;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H084678CA6B4D4AE19B91FD94735A9F16"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a summary of any current or planned efforts between military installations and local municipalities or housing providers aimed at providing rental relief or lease flexibility for members of the Armed Forces, including any memoranda of understanding;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6F87B84E27A46C1BF8A09BBDFD387DA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an identification of existing public-private partnerships or community development initiatives that could be leveraged to support off-installation housing for members of the Armed Forces;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8AD38C2DC9E04D6FAA543C79046F55F8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an assessment of potential incentives that could be offered by participating landlords or cities, including waived security deposits, lease rates that are below the monthly rate for the basic allowance for housing, application fee discounts, and flexible lease terms;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF89F706EE1BD4DF6831B4C6BB9EF9A8A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an overview of the efforts of the Department of Defense to collaborate with local governments and housing developers to incentivize the construction of affordable off-installation housing tailored to the needs of members of the Armed Forces; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H43F48708A894479CB125CEBE6B66BB1F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>recommendations for any legislative or policy changes needed to enhance local housing partnerships and reduce housing insecurity for members of the Armed Forces.</text> </paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

