<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H94B2846429A54B4A9BC0250762153768" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5784 IH: Artificial Intelligence Wisdom for Innovative Small Enterprises Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5784</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251017">October 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="D000634">Mr. Downing</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Small Business Act to help small business concerns critically evaluate artificial intelligence tools, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF674C0C6D4F948468765287F676F0BFF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3A83674AFB8141E4B34D6AE0B8481CE3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Artificial Intelligence Wisdom for Innovative Small Enterprises Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>AI–WISE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H69EE38F2E97045FE90F1E67521CAB7BA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Artificial intelligence educational resources and modules for small business concerns</header> <subsection id="H7BF3A4200FC946BEAC61D7AF9314F8D4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/631">15 U.S.C. 631 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEBE7D634AC324B8BBBD384A90C0236E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 49 as section 50; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB50390DC248040638980F06CD7EDB7CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 48 the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE51330D3901C4B689B4D380B4D156504" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H8EC4585D7A234B99913E89BF92991E41"><enum>49.</enum><header>Artificial intelligence educational resources and modules for small business concerns</header> 
<subsection id="H4EC512866BAA4430BF409F5ECA4A4094"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text> <paragraph id="HC7F508EF26674037B12A98C628F80BCD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish and maintain educational resources and modules for small business concerns with information on artificial intelligence tools; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE3471CDAB65144D3BABF1A460D000341"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make such educational resources and modules publicly available on an existing online learning platform of the Administration.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFBFE6B53CB204A268D667967B3A52897"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The educational resources and modules established under subsection (a) shall include, to the extent practicable, information on—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEDBE64DB70C84D39B3D0415779F57DEB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>how artificial intelligence models work, including the limits of the capabilities of such models, and how such limits affect the outputs of such tools;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H236A1FCDD2A046D88A8129163743447E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how to determine if software outputs are generated with the use of artificial intelligence;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8127D5813F3B4E588AE3533563471E72"><enum>(3)</enum><text>how to remain updated on the emergence, development, and technological maturation of artificial intelligence;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1547A505FE1F4EEE9F5903694734CBA5" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>how to understand and remain updated on the policies, terms, and conditions applicable to users of artificial intelligence;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H580060295E9F450AA8DC33612A118872"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">best practices in coordinating with third-party providers of artificial intelligence tools;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F1ACC9383AF4FED9EDA9362984F0628"><enum>(6)</enum><text>how to effectively identify, evaluate, and manage the risks of artificial intelligence;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9111FA427486463884357E7C67906542"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how to ensure the privacy of user inputs to artificial intelligence tools;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C8459D8F37441C981B60CFF44091BA1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>how to retain human involvement in important decisions informed by recommendations made by artificial intelligence;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCB23E31A1F2947BB8573571049B50F7D"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how to identify tasks and functions that artificial intelligence can reliably and effectively perform, including whether artificial intelligence can improve operations, productivity, or customer service; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HE438658024B342C0944FCA6463D27DA7"><enum>(10)</enum><text>how to determine whether an artificial intelligence tool adequately fills a need and is worth adopting.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H5F9C0B815FAF46A4A65F6A31B72CA865"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Accuracy and maintenance</header> 
<paragraph id="H7E0C53947ECD4C2D9C896AC8CEED83CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent practicable, the Administrator shall ensure that the information contained in the educational resources and modules established under subsection (a) is factually accurate and current, including by consulting with—</text> <subparagraph id="H4009489807DD4E32A0B11D9F53BF5DFB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA669368885844531932B9D98B509D85A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Advisory Working Group established under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE52993E183A4A32B12F20E5D725EDFB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advisory Working Group</header> <subparagraph id="HAD5CF1A2ADC144E6B2664C2CBBE60947"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall establish a working group (in this paragraph referred to as the <quote>Advisory Working Group</quote>) with which the Administrator shall consult on an ongoing basis regarding the information contained in the educational resources and modules established under subsection (a).</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC48552B186BB4081BD63CFA9E956F5A3" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The duties of the Advisory Working Group shall include the identification and recommendation of relevant information to the Administrator for inclusion in the educational resources and modules established under subsection (a).</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1A9AC99444594EBF937A425668B3FC44" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Working Group shall be comprised of the following members, who shall be selected by the Administrator:</text> 
<clause id="H697B2A09C1E946AAAE62B8E41F19EC96" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Individuals with demonstrated expertise in artificial intelligence, including—</text> <subclause id="HC0BE56F1F21F4F34BC9DCE17A9DB9DC5" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not less than one individual from the private sector;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA044BF3447554B89B33844ACD44AF735"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than one individual from academia;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8FF98E470A4F4676B41BA7996A4E47E3" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than one individual from an organization with demonstrated expertise in ensuring artificial intelligence outputs—</text> 
<item id="H0315DBF02783498DAC2BAAC8DE5ADAD4"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>are reliable, secure, transparent, and not used for illegal purposes; and</text></item> <item id="H89777F9986454318A93B1C2281E60364"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>which protect user privacy; and</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF224623087B24695A637F3D51A0BF81C" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>not less than one individual with demonstrated expertise in the creation of educational or professional development materials regarding artificial intelligence.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H87F679BCDA224D33A52F10CDF3297AF7" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Individuals with demonstrated expertise in outreach to small business concerns, including—</text> 
<subclause id="HCEC1391B02BC431FA009F2A3DDB64887" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not less than one individual from each resource partner;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H60A63E07E9F14FFBB84D3680F7137A06" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not less than one individual from a district office of the Administration; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H44652DF2FAC140EEB66C027F22CA17C8" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>not less than one individual from an association representing small business concerns.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF5DA301CDA3147748F50ED9615DBDC81" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any vacancy in the Advisory Working Group shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H58D5E8E6355D45CAB067D58B3B2D72A5"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Inapplicability of FACA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to the Advisory Working Group established under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0121EE2360D42E38B5773F8C5610F99" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Incorporation of information in educational resources and modules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing and maintaining the educational resources and modules under subsection (a), the Administrator—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC7CCD17C8AF2452AAF84E0FE25984724" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall consider relevant, existing information developed by resource partners;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7AC403B1E98148E2AB7239AED6DE84BD" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may consider relevant, existing information developed by private entities; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5F042005C0164E219F24DC0DB0BC9BEE" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may incorporate information described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) into such educational resources and modules.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H2283F1174B594675A92A2DF053F67B38"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Resource partner involvement</header> <paragraph id="HA9BF94CBF4CB4D3CB6AC78DEF587509F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall coordinate with resource partners to disseminate information to raise the awareness of small business concerns about availability of the educational resources and modules established under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBF369CD2552A4486AD19EC255A748FED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specialized and localized educational resource development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Resource partners may develop specialized and localized training resources to more effectively disseminate the information in the educational resources and modules established under subsection (a), including by incorporating information on uses of artificial intelligence tools common to the community served by such resource partner.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HFB3117D93BCE483580E2DF0BC72D6132"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Manner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall ensure that the information in the educational resources and modules established under subsection (a)—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6F80DA1A95BD43328236238144253B5E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is actionable and presented in a manner that is easily comprehensible by small business concerns;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB0407A2203347BEA74E3EA25FDA61AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not give preference to a particular artificial intelligence model or tool over similar such models or tools; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H05651972D02F49C780815F5090C8C581"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not give preference to an artificial intelligence model or tool developed by a specific entity or group of entities over an artificial intelligence model or tool developed by another entity or group of entities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD957ABC02FBE4CECB9871E84D44FA255" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given such term in section 5002 of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>).</text> </subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBF60095FF963404C837C4A87D04D7E0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall establish the educational resources and modules required by section 49 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/631">15 U.S.C. 631 et seq.</external-xref>), as added by this Act, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> </section> <section id="H4D2D3983A1DD483FBF04BFB7C75FAAAB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Compliance with cutgo</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional amounts are authorized to carry out this Act or the amendments made by this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

