<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL25869-CLN-9G-NW8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2390 IS: Unlocking Housing Supply Through Streamlined and Modernized Reviews Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2390</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to reclassify the application of certain requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 for housing-related activities.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Unlocking Housing Supply Through Streamlined and Modernized Reviews Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id21a83ead5f7843eca2fb3eb409c33e8a"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide79b3ccf8c1545379dc3afd5803c8dc2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Infill project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>infill project</term> means a project that—</text><subparagraph id="idc6bbea042ba14d34ad320af2de873386"><enum>(A)</enum><text>occurs within the geographic limits of a municipality;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id76e0d0611da54868b8ff89c7a55f7bb7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is adequately served by existing utilities and public services as required under applicable law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3f195ab694674ec8b6b4013779dc140c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is located on a site of previously disturbed land of not more than 5 acres and substantially surrounded by residential or commercial development;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4256c403579a4cceb5e9301d0ef248c2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>will repurpose a vacant or underutilized parcel of land, or a dilapidated or abandoned structure; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc9db2ae7081c4550b4eb3f6cd862c9be"><enum>(E)</enum><text>will serve a residential or commercial purpose.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7283414bd37b47c5a42d2bd36c5fa06d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph></section><section id="ide4ebf3b5f23a4fcbbe6f2ca991b9d244"><enum>3.</enum><header>NEPA streamlining for hud housing-related activities</header><subsection id="idc00e4140dae5440b898248fbc778eafb"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall, in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, and section 103 of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4333">42 U.S.C. 4333</external-xref>), expand and reclassify housing-related activities under the necessary administrative regulations as follows:</text><paragraph id="id39aadceae4514677b93448c2937b9d9d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The following housing-related activities shall be subject to regulations equivalent or substantially similar to the regulations entitled <quote>exempt activities</quote> as set forth in section 58.34 of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on January 1, 2025:</text><subparagraph id="id3b16352c2e114b60bec81a811d72ffef"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Tenant-based rental assistance, as defined in section 8(o) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb1609d239d654656b1b8c085c1ea57d3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Supportive services, including health care, housing services, permanent housing placement, day care, nutritional services, short-term payment for rent, mortgage, or utility costs, and assistance in gaining access to Federal Government and State and local government benefits and services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3d8467e481094bc1b79ec78b2479fafd"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Operating costs, including maintenance, security, operation, utilities, furnishings, equipment, supplies, staff training, and recruitment and other incidental costs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5c2ee037d13c4270b1da56b2d8718983"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Economic development activities, including equipment purchases, inventory financing, interest subsidies, operating expenses, and similar costs not associated with construction or expansion of existing operations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2823645f46ba45f38053d80d6c93fc9b"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Activities to assist homebuyers to purchase existing dwelling units or dwelling units under construction, including closing costs and down payment assistance, interest rate buydowns, and similar activities that result in the transfer of title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb2d659acf4c74b10a86a811c3e388923"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Affordable housing pre-development costs related to obtaining site options, project financing, administrative costs and fees for loan commitment, zoning approvals, and other related activities that do not have a physical impact.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2ae2cc3cb10e4dd8bb6789584ac8d19d"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Approval of supplemental assistance, including insurance or guarantee, to a project previously approved by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id871191b5fb7f4176b987f61fa22e1273"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Emergency homeowner or renter assistance for HVAC, hot water heaters, and other necessary uses of existing utilities required under applicable law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id077a64972fad428b85ae552abbac9904"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The following housing-related activities shall be subject to regulations equivalent or substantially similar to the regulations entitled, (i) <quote>categorical exclusions not subject to section 58.5</quote> and (ii) <quote>categorical exclusions not subject to the Federal laws and authorities cited in sections 50.4</quote> in section 58.35(b) and section 50.19, respectively of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on January 1, 2025, if such activities do not materially alter environmental conditions and do not materially exceed the original scope of the project:</text><subparagraph id="idfdd8a18dc0cf4e96a0110a6877da75cb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Acquisition, repair, improvement, reconstruction, or rehabilitation of public facilities and improvements (other than buildings) if the facilities and improvements are in place and will be retained in the same use without change in size or capacity of more than 20 percent, including replacement of water or sewer lines, reconstruction of curbs and sidewalks, and repaving of streets.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1fdeb4b9983b4849b4465094436c6339"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Rehabilitation of 1-to-4 unit residential buildings, and existing housing-related infrastructure, such as repairs or rehabilitation of existing wells, septics, or utility lines that connect to that housing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd19ff28d3d1b47cb9023f3df60e395cd"><enum>(C)</enum><text>New construction, development, demolition, acquisition, or disposition on up to 4 scattered site existing dwelling units where there is a maximum of 4 units on any 1 site.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id80ccf689c1514470b6139bc323e3c8ce"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Acquisitions (including leasing) or disposition of, or equity loans on an existing structure, or acquisition (including leasing) of vacant land if the structure or land acquired, financed, or disposed of will be retained for the same use.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d9e2af2456e4eecad6fef77b913117c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The following housing-related activities shall be subject to regulations equivalent or substantially similar to the regulations entitled, (i) <quote>categorical exclusions subject to section 58.5</quote> and (ii) <quote>categorical exclusions subject to the Federal laws and authorities cited in sections 50.4</quote> in section 58.35(a) and section 50.20, respectively, of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on January 1, 2025, if such activities do not materially alter environmental conditions and do not materially exceed the original scope of the project:</text><subparagraph id="id52aadb8c6fcc47c3b3de28894f191bc7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Acquisitions of open space or residential property, where such property will be retained for the same use or will be converted to open space to help residents relocate out of an area designated as a high-risk area by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9a8a630c0aa44c25849e870ad48fa2ea"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Conversion of existing office buildings into residential development, subject to—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd2fd7e5e6a2d432cb5c895ad5bd1d622"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a maximum number of units to be determined by the Secretary; and </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3d6506331ec7434289df908917ec5619"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a limitation on the change in building size to not more than 20 percent.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf6d0e6d5502940eea35ea84602895308"><enum>(C)</enum><text>New construction, development, demolition, acquisition, or disposition on 5 to 15 dwelling units where there is a maximum of fifteen units on any 1 site. The units can be 15 1-unit buildings or 1 15-unit building, or any combination in between.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida86598a60e3c43e89d43a3222c663496"><enum>(D)</enum><text>New construction, development, demolition, acquisition, or disposition on 15 or more housing units developed on scattered sites when there are not more than 15 housing units on any 1 site, and the sites are more than a set number of feet apart as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddaf61550b3eb42519673e2f18be184c3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Rehabilitation of buildings and improvements in the case of a building for residential use with 5 to 15 units, if the density is not increased beyond 15 units and the land use is not changed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0d69ea24056443ed92519b7e95c4c8b2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Infill projects consisting of new construction, rehabilitation, or development of residential housing units.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbb33c3f067304613864f0b0c760cdac7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Buyouts, defined as the voluntary acquisition of properties properties located in a (i) floodway, (ii) floodplain, or (iii) other area, clearly delineated by the grantee, that has been impacted by a predictable environmental threat to the safety and wellbeing of program beneficiaries caused or exacerbated by a Federally-declared disaster.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id9ec61c909ce64b038541174bc6b68063"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit to the chairs and ranking members of the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives an annual report during the 5-year period beginning on the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act that provides a summary of findings of reductions in review times and administrative cost reduction, with a particular focus on the affordable housing sector, as a result of the actions set forth in this Act, and any recommendations of the Secretary for future congressional action with respect to revising categorical exclusions or exemptions under title 24, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

