<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-GAI25104-648-V1-S8T"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S311 IS: Achieving Choice in Education Act </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 311</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250129">January 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide incentives for education.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H5D58B88F880D430DBFA6F8C3299F8754"><section section-type="section-one" id="idd9d55b34c98b4e82bf2d21a28da90d58"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Achieving Choice in Education Act </short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ACE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD0AEE96B294A464C8C189C898098E8A7"><enum>2.</enum><header>529 account funding for homeschool and additional elementary and secondary expenses</header><subsection id="HF6BE48AA70B44A7C8CF67C5C07293C57"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/529">Section 529(c)(7)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC47015A5C2D0472286A8C7FEFCA28DA8"><paragraph id="HE315280BA27346408E22B48C9FD89932"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Treatment of elementary and secondary tuition</header><text>Any reference in this section to the term <term>qualified higher education expense</term> shall include a reference to the following expenses in connection with enrollment or attendance at, or for students enrolled at or attending, an elementary or secondary public, private, or religious school:</text><subparagraph id="H8007B1D507E941F6ADD0CB9828B26287"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Tuition.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DE8E2B73995485E984605A3E054B672"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Curriculum and curricular materials.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17F832302894400A8DDD6323BC3E31CF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Books or other instructional materials.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H116E4FDF1485405793505E3BC8B7C55D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Online educational materials.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75EE84DB23E541089DFA5F3F25B8A3A1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Tuition for tutoring or educational classes outside of the home, including at a tutoring facility, but only if the tutor or instructor is not related to the student and—</text><clause id="H76BF628A6667413EA2888A164459E126"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is licensed as a teacher in any State,</text></clause><clause id="HF7F885156A284125BFCC0404D7B2A9ED"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has taught at an eligible educational institution, or</text></clause><clause id="H0B26215BF27840EE935D529936536597"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is a subject matter expert in the relevant subject.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE914D5953BEF4B9DB391827F18B26AA2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Fees for a nationally standardized norm-referenced achievement test, an advanced placement examination, or any examinations related to college or university admission.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29567ED15B9348E39F6D74E91C34AC42"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Fees for dual enrollment in an institution of higher education.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06C65751655E4E51B3B33C908C6A4BA3"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Educational therapies for students with disabilities provided by a licensed or accredited practitioner or provider, including occupational, behavioral, physical, and speech-language therapies.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Such term shall include expenses for the purposes described in subparagraphs (A) through (H) in connection with a homeschool (whether treated as a homeschool or a private school for purposes of applicable State law).</continuation-text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H908844DADD8745BDBCE5D73465E27799"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by this section shall apply to distributions made after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD14D9AD1DE9642CDA5C085E396D71BAA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Increase in limitation on distributions from 529 plans for elementary and secondary school expenses</header><subsection id="H7AB30C87BBA94273901136324918E5C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/529">Section 529(e)(3)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>$10,000</quote> in the flush matter at the end and inserting <quote>$20,000</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF3E489D3CC4742C1994D7B9305B65B3D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2026.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD6926EB4BDE84948B76CD6D0807AD273"><enum>4.</enum><header>Gift tax exclusions</header><subsection id="H0441373DEE8F44FFB1490271ED0CF8F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Gift tax exclusion for contributions to 529 plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/2503">Section 2503(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C3035BC077A472292CE8AD5DEEFC3FD"><paragraph id="HC1D33999C1514657BDDACF4313760FB1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exclusion for contributions to 529 plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The dollar amount in effect under paragraph (1) with respect to gifts (to which such paragraph applies) made to any person during any calendar year shall be increased (not in excess of $20,000) by the amount of such gifts made during such calendar year to qualified tuition programs (as defined in section 529) with respect to which such person is the designated beneficiary.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H2501923BDCB84C0FB06922E36F535B7B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to gifts made after December 31, 2026.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5979377C59F047B8B4A86CCC90328BD2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Tax-exempt bonds restricted to States that implement school choice laws</header><subsection id="H54C949AF16E04A8DA1ED23CCD46AECEA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/103">Section 103</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H371A171B1C2B4F1FA68E5244F1988FC2"><subsection id="H899FB2048CC44EEA85932DF950AD8A15"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Restriction to States that implement school choice laws</header><paragraph id="HDF58FABCC2094110ABBAF9F117A74D19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) shall not apply to any State or local bond unless such bond is issued by a minimum school choice State or a political subdivision of such a State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H695C1B1FA3894B538BC538767954C2BA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Partial exclusion with respect to certain States</header><subparagraph id="HAB9203A703AD40A4A7769CFDC1604272"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any State or local bond issued by a minimum school choice State which does not meet the requirements of subparagraph (B) (or issued by any political subdivision of such a State), subsection (a) shall be applied by substituting <quote>50 percent of the interest</quote> for <quote>interest</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14CABB7D1EFF4070A6BD863EA691E7F8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A minimum school choice State meets the requirements of this subparagraph if the Secretary determines that—</text><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE2F15D387E2140A1B6E981730DAD444E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at least 65 percent of the specified school age children are eligible for one or more of such State’s school choice programs, and</text></clause><clause id="HDD2936C19CCB4EE884E23EFAE68F287A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the average amount spent by such State on the education of each specified school age child eligible for one or more of such State’s school choice programs is at least 75 percent of the average amount spent by such State on the education of each specified school age child not eligible for one or more of such programs.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H73D739D09CEA46B6BE508FABF3254ECF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Minimum school choice State</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>minimum school choice State</term> means any State if the Secretary determines that—</text><subparagraph id="H39191CCD924D42BDA2A83E0461CA1A57"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such State has enacted one or more school choice programs,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H078F92D0AC4F46918499CF35DE827141"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at least 40 percent of the specified school age children are eligible for one or more of such State’s school choice programs, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B110543B5694563830AE41852B78BC8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the average amount spent by such State on the education of each specified school age child eligible for one or more of such State’s school choice programs is at least 60 percent of the average amount spent by such State on the education of each specified school age child not eligible for one or more of such programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7343E0CA54754264BEC7EF257895E79A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>School choice programs</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>school choice program</term> means, with respect to any State, each of the following with respect to elementary and secondary education in such State: </text><subparagraph id="H74C8F1998DA0463197C79E3C782D964F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Tax credit scholarship programs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BE787B3308148B688270B3B2D3949DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Voucher programs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DD80B97709246DFB7771E4A11C62A33"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Education savings account program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78A2E4F4774E4590B7D50315923BE498"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Refundable tax credit for private education expenses.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D1A363F22704ED3A3E7D0633B564911"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Specified school age child</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>specified school age child</term> means, with respect to any State, any individual residing in such State who has not attained age 18.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HAE5232C532C240CBB7982F5297D7939B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to bonds issued after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

