<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9A9E1CCF3DE7408E8627695160DB50AB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 711 IH: Fairness, Anti-discrimination and Individual Rights Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 711</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250123">January 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for equal protection of the law and to prohibit discrimination and preferential treatment on the basis of race, color, or national origin in Federal actions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9E02776B772D45EC86A7275C42AD13FA" style="OLC"><section id="H371129D9305B498D960BE2F074996705" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fairness, Anti-discrimination and Individual Rights Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FAIR Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H33ABA545ACFF4E76BFAE2BD6F29F387B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition against discrimination and preferential treatment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, neither the Federal Government nor any officer, employee, or agent of the Federal Government shall—</text><paragraph id="HDE35F7C0208C48A9AD9B3460EBC1DF6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>intentionally discriminate against, or grant a preference to, any person or group based in whole or in part on race, color, or national origin, in connection with—</text><subparagraph id="H4C587BC3B116473B8A0A74DEA66A525C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Federal contract or subcontract;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33A354BDB23942AAAC63FB2AD1B0E306"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Federal employment; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6B9F6BA90BB45D995FE4FD6A86DF681"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other federally conducted program or activity; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8E8D2ECC9E54E2BA1B57EC4BDD18BB3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require or encourage a Federal contractor or subcontractor, or the recipient of a license or financial assistance, to discriminate intentionally against, or grant a preference to, any person or group based in whole or in part on race, color, or national origin, in connection with any Federal contract or subcontract or Federal license or financial assistance.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HBA864AFBF2D04593A788C164CA169CF9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition relating to recipients of Federal aid</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A State or private entity that receives Federal financial assistance may not discriminate against, or grant a preference to, any person or group based in whole or in part on race, color, or national origin, in connection with—</text><paragraph id="HEFDDF2A38142498E8D6F0CCD96E770B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any contract or subcontract;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0A61C1BA6F24F95B2CCB699406D01E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>employment; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3F61B5044E2423DBD2A1B75BA5EB51F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>admission to any educational institution.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5D94A88FB5414827B2E163E428B866AA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act does not affect any law governing immigration or nationality, or the administration of any such law.</text></section><section id="H4733B4423F324DCAAB01131A7E4BA5B0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Compliance review of policies and regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the head of each department or agency of the Federal Government, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall review all existing policies and regulations that such department or agency head is charged with administering, modify such policies and regulations to conform to the requirements of this Act, and report to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate the results of the review and any modifications to the policies and regulations.</text></section><section id="H768EA9B9F6A64D349E773B0C1AD75A91"><enum>6.</enum><header>Remedies</header><subsection id="H724FD94C939446D084E7CF5A63CF12D3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any person aggrieved by a violation of section 2 or 3 may, in a civil action against the violator (including a violator that is a governmental entity), obtain appropriate relief (which may include back pay). A prevailing plaintiff in a civil action under this section shall be awarded a reasonable attorney’s fee as part of the costs.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB09C78E49F4D4B8BB272E1CEA7CB38D6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>This section does not affect any remedy available under any other law.</text></subsection></section><section id="HF8EDA0DF8F4A4936A91ECC0A4E022288"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effect on pending matters</header><subsection id="H257C9D31FA0D44BA9DE0C40C3C3D76F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pending cases</header><text>This Act does not affect any case pending on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5C36E22DE90840A79425D7A2341E17C5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pending contracts and subcontracts</header><text>This Act does not affect any contract or subcontract in effect on the date of enactment of this Act, including any option exercised under such contract or subcontract before or after such date of enactment.</text></subsection></section><section id="HDAC64D2DE52E4967BE69A8ED2A40C26F"><enum>8.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the following definitions apply:</text><paragraph id="H12DE3AB642634840B4E9458808EE0F05"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal government</header><text>The term <term>Federal Government</term> means executive and legislative branches of the Government of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H62159C31E1B2408FB14FBB9DF0F6DEFE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Preference</header><text>The term <term>preference</term> means an advantage of any kind, and includes a quota, set-aside, numerical goal, timetable, or other numerical objective.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

