<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H518555BB290540369EC3DD8D5EFB20B3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 472 IH: Restore Department of Veterans Affairs Accountability Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 472</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250116">January 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001039">Mrs. Cammack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000404">Mrs. King-Hinds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001098">Mr. Hamadeh of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000603">Mr. Luttrell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to modify personnel action procedures with respect to employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8451A732718B49DA8C4B9B86469FC08F" style="OLC"><section id="H1B89A861A43540A89B9AFAD3E533ECBC" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Restore Department of Veterans Affairs Accountability Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Restore VA Accountability Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H571B0262FD3847AA9B541769F4D336A3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>2.</enum><header>Supervisors: removal, demotion, or suspension based on performance or misconduct</header><subsection id="HBA328869B88C4C00A154AE1BDB965C29"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Discipline of supervisors</header><paragraph id="H99D3599CF7EE40E5A0C31B23436C7188"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after section 711 the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H79183860CBAE41B892960409E50D1D3C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H5B163CD1911F4CF8AFFFCE9807195371"><enum>712.</enum><header>Supervisors: removal, demotion, or suspension based on performance or misconduct</header><subsection id="H714A07FF8E7F467D8347978F029DB4A6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may remove from civil service, demote, or suspend a covered individual who is an employee of the Department if the Secretary determines by substantial evidence that the performance or misconduct of the covered individual warrants such action.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDB3FE0AE85734C51A6A554273E4F1E9E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rights and procedures</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7A2DF02C15F64A9C8EBCD0AFEAEE8D0A"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H47CC2CA27D174EDEB1C8AA1E1BEED8C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>When making an initial decision under subsection (a) with respect to determining whether a covered individual should be removed, demoted, or suspended, the deciding employee of the Department shall exclusively apply the following factors:</text><clause id="H058864B87F5D4F21A76913DF0990425B" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The nature and seriousness of the offense, and its relation to the covered individual’s duties, position, and responsibilities, including whether the offense was intentional or technical or inadvertent, or was committed maliciously or for gain, or was frequently repeated.</text></clause><clause id="H55E06469EF5D46928EAFA9133F3E6BD3" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The covered individual’s job level and type of employment, including supervisory or fiduciary role, and prominence of the position.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1999D08290D44B908023E2E2EDE3867A" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary shall review the initial decision and uphold such decision if it is supported by substantial evidence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC254C90965C14552A2CB225C496B515A" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A covered individual subject to an action under subsection (a) is entitled to—</text><subparagraph id="H0D79E1652A964094A6B0D82736301A1E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advance notice of the action and a file containing all evidence in support of the proposed action;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CF9B072A2614F3AA6ABA56C16775FCA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be represented by an attorney or other representative of the covered individual’s choice; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC780A22C61534D92B9124E53C9D00697"><enum>(C)</enum><text>grieve the action in accordance with an internal grievance process that the Secretary, in consultation with the Assistant Secretary for Accountability and Whistleblower Protection, shall establish for purposes of this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB051CA06707D42659751D481982CF5C8" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A final decision by the Secretary under paragraph (1)(B) that is not grieved, and a grievance decision under paragraph (2)(C), shall be final and conclusive.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE278D9BE47C405BA3D102E5D70033DE" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The procedures under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/43">chapter 43</external-xref> of title 5 shall not apply to a removal, demotion, or suspension under this section, and the Secretary may carry out such a removal, demotion, or suspension without first placing a covered individual on a performance improvement plan.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H79757DEA4FCF40368AB7E0C9AAE40D97"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Timing</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA04B5711933F471D960AF512C78945CA"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1AE0949FD9A74CA7861E46EA65D930FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The aggregate period for notice, response, and final decision by the Secretary of an action under this section may not exceed 15 business days.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE31F0DB7F67B45E5BD3428DEDC93CF3A" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The period for the response of a covered individual to a notice under subsection (b)(2)(A) shall be 7 business days.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55CD5444C20F4861AF8BEBC410371E1E" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The final decision by the Secretary under subsection (b)(1)(B) shall—</text><clause id="H74E13C64EB994504810EA8BBE1C5C928"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be issued not later than 15 business days after notice is provided under subsection (b)(2)(A); and</text></clause><clause id="HE2DE5B40B59D437B9CB2E0FB89B8A6EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be in writing and shall include the specific reasons for the decision.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDC191E05A5D48A8AA72802302D9053C" indent="up2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the grievance process established under paragraph (2)(C) takes fewer than 21 days after the final decision.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C790043D30B43B6A67B49EF1F4812D8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB79999B54FC1402C80146D8D0B962E8F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A covered individual adversely affected by a final decision under this section that is not grieved, or by a grievance decision under subsection (b)(2)(C), may obtain judicial review of such decision.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H58E21862AE1B4978AB5AA036CCCB316D" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any removal, demotion, or suspension under this section is not appealable to the Merit Systems Protection Board, or to any administrative judge or other person appointed by the Merit Systems Protection Board.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22D10F386AE445E2AB08FB076F771838" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In any case in which judicial review is sought under paragraph (1), the court shall review the record and may set aside any Department action found to be—</text><subparagraph id="HF1C66589B88845C0978A0A2788A8008A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>arbitrary, capricious, an abuse of discretion, or otherwise not in accordance with a provision of law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DDD8C90A8974426B98057DBC31F350E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>obtained without procedures required by a provision of law having been followed; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA275B42886B740C8ACF81F14EED52B3B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>unsupported by substantial evidence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H764B88CA688D47C998461614AC74FC42" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except to the extent that an appeal under this subsection presents a constitutional issue, such court may not review a challenge to the penalty imposed against the covered individual or mitigate such penalty. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H697D98C0E8634BFF82F3733EA86C6560"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Demoted individuals</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2B96232A9A3A4EE4A5BF93E63F68DE0E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A demotion under subsection (a) shall be carried out as a reduction in grade for which the covered individual is qualified, that the Secretary determines is appropriate, and that reduces the annual rate of pay of the covered individual. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B27FA6D0593436586FF114683A85AF6" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any covered individual so demoted—</text><subparagraph id="H24408F1613874214B10E5229C1C4662F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall, beginning on the date of such demotion, receive the annual rate of pay applicable to such grade;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5609EC2808874BDF9A473A814F321BCD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not be placed on administrative leave during the period during which an appeal (if any) under this section is ongoing, and may only receive pay if the covered individual reports for duty or is approved to use accrued unused annual, sick, family medical, military, or court leave; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47EAE50D721B4000858E8118F545986B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>who does not report for duty or receive approval to use accrued unused leave shall not receive pay or other benefits.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H15D62A84C53C4C9C86962F06EA72674E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Whistleblower protection</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7AD5C0C9819D4077BCFA375E8365DF2E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the case of a covered individual seeking corrective action (or on behalf of whom corrective action is sought) from the Office of Special Counsel based on an alleged prohibited personnel practice described in section 2302(b) of title 5, the Secretary may not remove, demote, or suspend such covered individual under subsection (a) without the approval of the Special Counsel under section 1214(f) of title 5.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E59A1CF1013461AAD6B5D01EB931E3D" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In the case of a covered individual who has made a whistleblower disclosure to the Assistant Secretary for Accountability and Whistleblower Protection, the Secretary may not remove, demote, or suspend such covered individual under subsection (a) until—</text><subparagraph id="H26188AD9FC2847B3A2D0DD3BC2098DB4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case in which the Assistant Secretary determines to refer the whistleblower disclosure under section 323(c)(1)(D) of this title to an office or other investigative entity, a final decision with respect to the whistleblower disclosure has been made by such office or other investigative entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H618893D6C24E4A2ABF6178B870162E2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case in which the Assistant Secretary determines not to refer the whistleblower disclosure under such section, the Assistant Secretary makes such determination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC6FCDEEA5B1D4EE3839D93E2266B9226"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination of investigations by office of special counsel</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC1B1951132C84276A6AECAAA8DEECAEA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Special Counsel (established by section 1211 of title 5) may terminate an investigation of a prohibited personnel practice alleged by an employee or former employee of the Department after the Special Counsel provides to the employee or former employee a written statement of the reasons for the termination of the investigation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5E5A2844FE2465A82AF48FEF9911AB1" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Such statement may not be admissible as evidence in any judicial or administrative proceeding without the consent of such employee or former employee.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBF338FB929C04E00A950F58B15D12DA4"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall apply to any performance or misconduct of a covered individual beginning on the date of enactment of the Department of Veterans Affairs Accountability and Whistleblower Protection Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/41">Public Law 115–41</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HE717CC2DAF9740C18F75729A6B429134"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H53776EC21E874CA3BEBC35061C25D98E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>civil service</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 2101 of title 5.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5DFBD6E4A624E26B9D30D1CEE25EECE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>covered individual</term> means an employee of the Department who is a supervisor or management official as defined in section 7103(a) of title 5 occupying a position at the Department, including individuals appointed pursuant to this title, title 5, and hybrid employees appointed pursuant to section 7401 of this title, but does not include—</text><subparagraph id="HEA906A9E2C78475E990AC39EE583A4D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual occupying a senior executive position (as defined in section 713(d) of this title);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H362958A8E37249E89E296B9F2121BC66"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an individual appointed pursuant to section 7306, 7401(1), 7401(4), or 7405 of this title;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7686CD17E7D4558AC05053773B94759"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an individual who has not completed a probationary or trial period; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEC49972F1584670B36136921622C641"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a political appointee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C7B4CC64E684392898A197B5BF07001"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>grade</term> has the meaning given such term in section 7511(a) of title 5.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7916FE7259724D328BD2DFEDEA371AD0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>misconduct</term> includes neglect of duty, malfeasance, or failure to accept a directed reassignment or to accompany a position in a transfer of function.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7F929AD7B4E437EBFC547C6B86938E0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>political appointee</term> means an individual who is—</text><subparagraph id="HF83870E0A7AE401786041122843FADA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>employed in a position described under sections 5312 through 5316 of title 5 (relating to the Executive Schedule);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8FC60E591D54770AE52486A192C03A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a limited term appointee, limited emergency appointee, or noncareer appointee in the Senior Executive Service, as defined under paragraphs (5), (6), and (7), respectively, of section 3132(a) of title 5; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00E279755AD444B89A4E48C8E4704337"><enum>(C)</enum><text>employed in a position of a confidential or policy-determining character under schedule C of subpart C of part 213 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H20338EB9189B499084D1A5BBF0887A25"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <term>suspend</term> means the placing of an employee, for disciplinary reasons, in a temporary status without duties and pay for a period in excess of 14 days.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE86F5FA5ECC64E12B7DDEBDCD7D0E8FF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The term <term>whistleblower disclosure</term> has the meaning given such term in section 323(g) of this title.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H7837DC3CBA7946F8B265972F615601FA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 711 the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HC2E03C58FFA24B3BB615BB413D59B7EF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">712. Supervisors: removal, demotion, or suspension based on performance or misconduct.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H13B1834020FA4C62A27E6E76C63F9EC7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Senior executives: modification of procedures to remove, demote, or suspend based on performance or misconduct</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 713 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H4728949163A345738A1EA066871D126C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="HA70EC6C507DE4137A1CEB5DCEDEEB001"><enum>(A)</enum><text>after <quote>determines</quote>, insert <quote>by substantial evidence</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23BFB340018B4D1E9E88BAF97E204CCF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HF6990EDBE43E4ECEBB96661B2BB586D0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H1884AF8E5A0B43A38D4F93E4CD1ED451" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When making an initial decision under this subsection with respect to determining whether a covered individual should be reprimanded or suspended, involuntarily reassigned, demoted, or removed, the deciding employee of the Department shall exclusively apply the following factors:</text><subparagraph id="HF02989F320B849F785F198BFBA98F390"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The nature and seriousness of the offense, and its relation to the covered individual’s duties, position, and responsibilities, including whether the offense was intentional or technical or inadvertent, or was committed maliciously or for gain, or was frequently repeated.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C3C4F39810B4CA38914F265B183DEE1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The covered individual’s job level and type of employment, including supervisory or fiduciary role, and prominence of the position.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC7682087EAF4C4E8354CFAE7648BF04" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary shall review the initial decision and uphold such decision if it is supported by substantial evidence.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F6B0989E153428A8E60B87CD5D52A30"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H92DD42EED337451C8B757FD8BFE5D3AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by inserting <quote>after the final decision</quote> after <quote>21 days</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE6930CE43304776B2BD72E90AB44AC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HE569C3D5E6594DB9BD3DAE08F6004FD4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HA07D6A0DFECE4F0C8502B2B0E0D63C2E" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except to the extent that an appeal under this subsection presents a constitutional issue, such court may not review a challenge to the penalty imposed against the covered individual or mitigate such penalty. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE792BCCDF36641958750C7C8DCCC94BB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>insert after subsection (c) the following (and redesignate subsection (d) as subsection (e)):</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H89A439E9D5534BBFABCDB73C90135CCA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HE82C61818C954F439E2DE2356C0C55C2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall apply to any misconduct or performance of a covered individual beginning on the date of enactment of the Department of Veterans Affairs Accountability and Whistleblower Protection Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/41">Public Law 115–41</external-xref>).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H69F998474194405CBD8AD300F346C809"><enum>4.</enum><header>Modification of disciplinary procedures for employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="H12BFD30772384C91B9C9CD0B04D92FCE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs employee discipline modifications</header><text>Section 714 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H980D381CA9414168B707537BF1624ED7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a),</text><subparagraph id="H4F7B699E42A6460D9DAEFA6E6056A6F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>by substantial evidence</quote> after <quote>the Secretary determines</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9A505F266A5493487D1557B1EF198E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HA07FAE2EAA044DB094672C67C0BA8884" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HE3DFB69D15C44321B24DB12845F4F034" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H355861E696424EEEB145A11EB51F1476"><enum>(A)</enum><text>When making an initial decision under this subsection with respect to determining whether a covered individual should be removed, demoted, or suspended, the deciding employee of the Department shall exclusively apply the following factors:</text><clause id="H8FC01C47C211429D85FEA9B58FA1DED0" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The nature and seriousness of the offense, and its relation to the covered individual’s duties, position, and responsibilities, including whether the offense was intentional or technical or inadvertent, or was committed maliciously or for gain, or was frequently repeated.</text></clause><clause id="H5CAC31BC60FC4F219A7A9561C5B745B1" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The covered individual’s job level and type of employment, including supervisory or fiduciary role, and prominence of the position.</text></clause><clause id="H3B53F6EFC96E46C4A7C5D2CEE3DDBDBD" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The covered individual’s past disciplinary record.</text></clause><clause id="HE19D2208A4C84E19B4715D9EAF552337" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The covered individual’s past work record, including length of service, performance on the job, ability to get along with fellow workers, and dependability.</text></clause><clause id="H398E03C1EA994867A074011D7A73794E" indent="up1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Mitigating circumstances surrounding the offense such as unusual job tensions, personality problems, mental impairment, harassment, or bad faith, malice, or provocation on the part of others involved in the matter.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C4BBF7225104B3294FEAA9784D4BFDF" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary shall review the initial decision and uphold such decision if it is supported by substantial evidence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8FD11C0C457431881CF0C4743021489"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="H1846DF24BFFD428ABCD1A0D5F1E665AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (1)(D); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1441EE48284146DA98A9669B83602A49"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by inserting before the period the following: <quote>, and the Secretary may carry out such a removal, demotion, or suspension without first placing a covered individual on a performance improvement plan</quote>; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB11863D0DBD44DE0B27EF2CFBCCF7117"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text><subparagraph id="H03D4E8C995E74BC082E78E656EEEE080"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HDC89B832ABDC4A8384B99A2BB1BA5D46" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HA003C6C5453E44D3A072C3FAEE0961EE" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except to the extent that an appeal under this subsection presents a constitutional issue, the administrative judge may not review a challenge to the penalty imposed against the covered individual. </text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70B1F3A95F1B4D6D9F211621CA6314B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HBD354DE4DDD5483C9235E0E58F66E43F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H5E4531B5FD274AC9BB49C46FEDE37CCF" indent="up2"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except to the extent that an appeal under this subsection presents a constitutional issue, the Merit Systems Protection Board may not review a challenge to the penalty imposed against the covered individual. </text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4386296040F84B8687A2486FF0BECA08"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H7DFE8F0617B842D5AD5D08AEC33E1EE4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HC3BF61B06EE645F7BBE357A758E02E31" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except to the extent that an appeal under this subsection presents a constitutional issue, such Court may not review a challenge to the penalty imposed against the covered individual or mitigate such penalty. </text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC89072D6C0E43AB809D43A052BC81DF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (10);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H96D088CEDF364920878CF11830504EEF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (h) as subsection (j); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD215C63E92BB44B29C84503A8C8B74AD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (g) the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H3B6CFACFB0A645429935489D55ADACD9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HB97DC96DB0364DADB956EA8A89CCF49F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Collective bargaining agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The procedures in this section shall supersede any collective bargaining agreement to the extent that such agreement is inconsistent with such procedures.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3102A9C288FE45FC964229041B9CDA53"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Application</header><text>This section shall apply to any performance or misconduct of a covered individual beginning on the date of enactment of the Department of Veterans Affairs Accountability and Whistleblower Protection Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/41">Public Law 115–41</external-xref>).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H32A0D788D62F41C6B486DA3927DAC263"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) of subsection (j), as redesignated by paragraph (4)—</text><subparagraph id="HC290C4F71C354A2AA8E3813F7C69E800"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>including individuals appointed pursuant to this title, title 5, and hybrid employees appointed pursuant to section 7401 of this title</quote> after <quote>Department</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA9D4EA32C1E4492A3AA931F55A63514"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DFC83B4A8E3499F99DF4CAFC90CAE08"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding after subparagraph (D) the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HC6BE8035A80F4BDAAD48083C7836C06D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HBDE6D5479A1C4F3BAAEF5E1F67C758D2"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a supervisor or management official as defined in section 7103(a) of title 5.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE9A05844666C42BF8925B40C9563DC00" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>VHA employee discipline modifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7403(f)(3) of such title is amended—</text><paragraph id="H7C17E32E408B4985A2873392104E7E57" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Notwithstanding any other provision of this title or other law,</quote> and inserting <quote>(A) Notwithstanding any other provision of this title or other law, and consistent with subparagraph (B),</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0479DFEF373340008622AF310500C032" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H8F9C7FD3C6754D01A6A4365C37A306E3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H59726091B7BB498881076ED727486C88" commented="no" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any covered individual (as that term is defined in section 712 or 714) appointed to such positions, such matters shall be resolved, at the Secretary’s sole discretion, under—</text><clause id="HD6E4EB4A507945C78CF33C7B97C20701" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>section 712;</text></clause><clause id="H71DBDB6EAB0C46A18AC97595BECD450C" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>section 714; or</text></clause><clause id="H37C801EDFFE6407BAAEE71C0E969415A" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">title 5 as though such individuals had been appointed under that title. </text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

