<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-NEW25646-S0K-7C-XF8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 298 ATS: Congratulating the Oklahoma State University men’s golf team for winning the 2025 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Men's Golf National Championship.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 298</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250624">June 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the Oklahoma State University men’s golf team for winning the 2025 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Men's Golf National Championship.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Oklahoma State University men’s golf team (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>Cowboys</quote>), under the direction of Alan Bratton, the head coach of the Cowboys, won the 2025 National Collegiate Athletic Association (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>NCAA</quote>) Division I Men's Golf National Championship (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>National Championship</quote>);</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the 2025 National Championship win is the 12th national championship title for the Cowboys, and the first since 2018;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Cowboys competed in a 72-hole stroke play format, earning them a spot in the top 8 teams to compete for the National Championship;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, after securing a spot in the top 8, the Cowboys competed in a match play bracket where they ultimately defeated the University of Virginia with a 3 to 1 victory to secure the National Championship win;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Cowboys have appeared in 4 NCAA Division I men's golf national championship matches since 2009, winning twice;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Cowboys ended the 2025 season on a 5-tournament winning streak and won 7 events overall during the year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Cowboys 11-man team was comprised of young talent, including 5 freshmen and 5 sophomores;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Filip Fahlberg-Johnsson, Eric Lee, Preston Stout, Gaven Lane, and Ethan Fang participated in the final matches of the National Championship, all playing a key role in securing the team title;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Ethan Fang and Preston Stout were honored as 2025 First-Team All-Americans;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 3 Cowboys golfers received Golfweek All-American honors, including Preston Stout who received First-Team honors, Ethan Fang who received Second-Team distinction, and Eric Lee who was an honorable mention;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 4 Cowboys golfers were named NCAA Division I PING All-Region honorees, including Ethan Fang, Gaven Lane, Eric Lee, and Preston Stout; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Cowboys head coach Alan Bratton was a recipient of the Dave Williams National Coach of the Year Award: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id5464a6e44c5b4b1a97222cb9f656934c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commends the 2025 Oklahoma State University men’s golf team (referred to in this resolution as the <quote>Cowboys</quote>) for winning the 2025 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Men's Golf National Championship;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0952b5df475d4c45a1d72a5bf5dbf16d"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the Cowboys for their hard work and dedication to the sport of golf and for the excitement they bring to Oklahoma State University, the State of Oklahoma, and to fans of the Cowboys everywhere; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idff15bf9e461648a39794ed73198e30f1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>congratulates the Cowboys on a wonderful 2025 season.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

