<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-CAN25035-7C8-L2-1V8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S283 IS: Illegal Red Snapper and Tuna Enforcement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 283</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250128">January 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Under Secretary of Commerce for Standards and Technology and the Administrator of National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to develop a standard methodology for identifying the country of origin of seafood to support enforcement against illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="not-changed"><section id="id2fab8d34-2155-46ce-8f48-419b8a10c291" section-type="section-one" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Illegal Red Snapper and Tuna Enforcement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9d71c1b0-24d5-430a-898b-630e51a7ea3a" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Methodology for identifying the country of origin of seafood</header><subsection id="id4ee4d303-cf6c-4c4d-a513-69c449f6af57" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section: </text><paragraph id="ide398b789-575f-4bbb-ae66-34bc45183cba" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idad00afd0-8a1c-4a71-9d37-7dd587c3944c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2d03f596-46cc-4477-91c1-e7b08dc5be60" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc9d3e97-ce73-4180-af0a-5436bf020977" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idaf287ff4ca8d4f1cb3005b8650987e00"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Key agency leadership</header><text>The term <term>key agency leadership</term> means the Administrator and the Under Secretary in consultation with the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and the Commandant of the Coast Guard.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id171717a0a91f4cf78e0798d69b287d93"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Red snapper</header><text>The term <term>red snapper</term> means the species Lutjanus campechanus.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbf2aaee089d54a638b8f75973cd4558c"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Tuna</header><text>The term <term>tuna</term> means the following species of tuna: </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida8155957d3164de7888696d7db1bccf4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Bigeye tuna (Thunnus obesus). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc4ed115562124cdd8ca75d81f6e4992a"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Yellowfin tuna (Thunnus albacares). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f4292b62c26453e8588efedffde2185"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Bluefin tuna (Thunnus thynnus).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb2e0c000-5032-4165-8fc9-7384336fb7eb" changed="not-changed"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Under Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Under Secretary</term> means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Standards and Technology and the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5325f402753c441ba381493e92109ae1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Standard methodology for identification</header><paragraph id="id4b773918eb324bc8af539c84ccb2cf20"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Key agency leadership shall, in accordance with this section, jointly develop a standard methodology, based on chemical analysis, for identifying the country of origin of seafood to support enforcement against illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide9e535524eb243038fce242f5e43d218"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Key agency leadership shall ensure that the methodology developed under this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="ide0295aab268c493faed6f43e59668305"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is consistent with the needs of Federal and State law enforcement agencies in combating illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id508824d443534c21b476b7e4d224c7eb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>minimizes processing time;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id04aab1a2f3b340ceb59a14c52bdca286"><enum>(C)</enum><text>involves the use of a field kit that can be easily carried by one individual; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida7febba03ff743dbabe8ab9623e02fa2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, can be used to test prepared food, including raw preparations of seafood such as ceviche, sashimi, sushi, and poke.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfb3cff222a104d2f8b205f3fe9b88a53" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Initial species for identification</header><text>In developing the methodology under this subsection, key agency leadership shall conduct pilot studies on red snapper, as an example of a stationary stock, and tuna, as an example of a highly migratory stock.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3cbe225a-8137-404a-818c-9832fe27321e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that includes the following: </text><paragraph id="ide29205d6-43f2-4f4d-9a89-20ba77c99c81" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A summary of the methodology developed under subsection (b). </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id189b101e-4b06-4a47-a7b5-72fe93e9c5c8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A plan for operationalizing the methodology developed under subsection (b). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id05f3657d2b0f4cfc808173b10853f591"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In the event that any aspect of the methodology developed under subsection (b) is impracticable, an explanation of why, whether additional research would make developing such a methodology practicable, and whether a different approach other than chemical analysis might be practicable.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id6428bb8d584349baa1abeecf4bcc2f78" changed="not-changed"><enum>3.</enum><header>Technical assistance for IUU fishing enforcement</header><subsection id="ida13a1614a32648f38cb319174d246944" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense is authorized to, in coordination with the United States Coast Guard, expend funds appropriated for the Department of Defense for operation and maintenance to provide maritime technical assistance to maritime forces from other nations in efforts to combat illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing (commonly known as <quote>IUU fishing</quote>) and other transnational organized crime. Such technical assistance may include providing observers, shipriders, and specialized personnel to deploy with such maritime forces, in addition to remote sensing, analysis of data, and operational intelligence, as appropriate and consistent with United States law and policy. </text></subsection><subsection id="id16c09fb19b524948a2c64bb65f874c68" changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application of authority</header><text>The authority provided under subsection (a) shall apply to the use of the United States Coast Guard members deployed to and operating aboard Department of Defense, partner nation, or international partner platforms, as well as partner nation personnel operating aboard United States military and Coast Guard assets or international partner vessels, as appropriate. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

