<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4706410D32A24593817A72AB2E919B85" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 315 IH: Recognizing the 159th anniversary of the Civil Rights Act of 1866.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 315</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 159th anniversary of the Civil Rights Act of 1866.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on April 9, 1866, the Civil Rights Act of 1866 was passed and enacted into law;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this year marks the 159th anniversary of the Civil Rights Act of 1866;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Civil Rights Act of 1866 was the first Federal law to define citizenship and affirm that all citizens are equally protected by the law;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the intent of the Civil Rights Act of 1866 was to combat the attempted suppression of the Emancipation Proclamation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas President Andrew Johnson established a reconstruction policy that forced former Confederate States to maintain abolition, swear loyalty to the United States, and pay their war debts in order to rejoin the Union;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas under President Johnson’s policy, Southern States adopted and enacted a series of laws designed to restrict freed Blacks and ensure their availability in the labor force;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these laws severely denied Black citizens equal protection under the law;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas under restricted laws, Blacks were refrained from owning property, entering contracts, and benefiting from labor rights;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a brave set of legislators believed the Federal Government had a role in shaping a multiracial society in postwar South;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Senator Lyman Trumbull of Illinois introduced the Civil Rights Act of 1866 in the Senate on January 5, 1866;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on February 2, 1866, the Senate voted in favor of the bill 33–13;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on March 13, 1866, the House of Representatives voted in favor of the Civil Rights Act of 1866 by a vote of 111–38, with 34 Members not voting;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on March 27, 1866, President Andrew Johnson vetoed the Civil Rights Act of 1866;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on April 6, 1866, the Senate voted 33–15 to override President Johnson’s veto;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on April 9, 1866, the House also voted to override President Johnson’s veto by a vote of 122–41 with 21 Members not voting; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas as a result of both Chambers voting to override President Johnson’s veto, the Civil Rights Act of 1866 became the law of the land: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H8C1D49CBD2114AA9B5EA5F07A13F455B"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H3A86085AC8164D188490148101DA6588"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HF17B7C791B484C8891B847C892E2CBB9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the significance of the Civil Rights Act of 1866 and its impact on establishing that all Americans, despite their race, are protected equally under the law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA13C209E85441CCA2F3F92D355C04E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes that the Civil Rights Act of 1866 is the framework from which the Thirteenth and Fourteenth Amendments were crafted; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06DD92A2319347CDA3D74ECEBF568995"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of the rule of law and advocates to support, protect, and defend the rights of all Americans.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

