<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG25382-FM1-K9-NH3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 S1245 IS: Servicemembers and Veterans Empowerment and Support Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1245</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250401" legis-day="20250331">April 1 (legislative day, March 31), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to expand health care and benefits from the Department of Veterans Affairs for military sexual trauma, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H8F46C00BFCD440C6890D3A0A65B36039"><section section-type="section-one" id="id221a5338-2639-428d-b8e1-bf139c1fb81a" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="idc04a6803-1c11-43d4-8130-d10af2451524" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Servicemembers and Veterans Empowerment and Support Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="idbd059fbd-622e-43bd-bb28-1cf63d4e2906" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="id221a5338-2639-428d-b8e1-bf139c1fb81a">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id2387b6a159d94cacbab0e0bea4940273">TITLE I—Defining military sexual trauma</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idc24e4274ad7143cfb4a40fb24834f3c2">Sec. 101. Report on military sexual trauma in the digital age.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id5a5cfa77-4b02-44f5-9093-72b833122258">TITLE II—Disability compensation and claims processing</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ida7f9353b-0ef2-46e3-8b6d-e8bafe010eed">Sec. 201. Definition of military sexual trauma.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id0331fe71-030b-49a6-b787-80e5590adb2c">Sec. 202. Conforming changes relating to specialized teams to evaluate claims involving military sexual trauma.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idaadba611-3def-4b56-94f2-3faabecacd8e">Sec. 203. Evaluation of claims involving military sexual trauma.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id26db3ca3-99c9-4bcb-a7d4-3a4fbcc5e340">Sec. 204. Choice of location of Department of Veterans Affairs medical examination for assessment of claims for compensation relating to disability resulting from military sexual trauma.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id425C0A715E654244B46D72EE2AC311C5">Sec. 205. Communications from the Department of Veterans Affairs to individuals who have experienced military sexual trauma.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id1acaa9c0-1c01-4e54-abd9-08b1c81762b4">Sec. 206. Study on training and processing relating to claims for disability compensation relating to military sexual trauma.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id594b2da5-fe72-4173-a084-1d26bd0f8c07">Sec. 207. Annual special focus review of claims for disability compensation for disabilities relating to military sexual trauma.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id36447aee1e5a494c81f3606caf99a364">Sec. 208. Workgroup on medical examinations for claims for disability compensation for disabilities relating to military sexual trauma.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="idA8776D558F444195B2E8AC1A00CE12E6">TITLE III—Access to health care</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id940C70795B5E4B208EC67EAC589F52AD">Sec. 301. Expansion of eligibility for counseling and treatment for military sexual trauma to include all former members of the reserve components of the armed forces.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id62204DDAE94248FC92CAC9286786F3AA">Sec. 302. Connection to veterans health administration when a disability claim related to military sexual trauma is submitted to veterans benefits administration.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id2d6d7040c51c46b9932bed6b2fb24225">Sec. 303. Care relating to military sexual trauma for individuals who withdraw from or otherwise do not complete service at service academies.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><title id="id2387b6a159d94cacbab0e0bea4940273" changed="not-changed"><enum>I</enum><header>Defining military sexual trauma</header><section id="idc24e4274ad7143cfb4a40fb24834f3c2" changed="not-changed"><enum>101.</enum><header>Report on military sexual trauma in the digital age</header><subsection id="id58dfde012ce84245aeaa402b846b6c0b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on military sexual trauma in the digital age.</text></subsection><subsection id="idbe29b7cf8a5649839f66f92cdff5aac2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="idcd7abb2956cf48b1b22b540f29e85556" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A comprehensive evaluation and assessment of current Department of Veterans Affairs statutes, regulations, and agency guidance relating to military sexual trauma for the purposes of access to health care under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, and compensation under chapter 11 of such title to identify—</text><subparagraph id="ide7f1bcd585624cd3a3ccfaa4c7b281dd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>gaps in coverage for health care and compensation eligibility relating to military sexual trauma involving online or other technological communications; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id26b9de8184c04022ad843890f27ee329"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the feasibility and advisability of expanding health care and compensation for trauma that is nonsexual in nature involving online or other technological communications. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3973b2762c7c42a7b80918fa75d16167" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Recommendations for revising statutes, regulations, and agency guidance in response to the evaluation and assessment under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc7e59369576e430bbce93741a58e6d3a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><paragraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id53a3ef6956354e6caf35decf18ca285a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall consult veterans service organizations and such other stakeholders as the Secretary considers relevant and appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idda1df3ef95e749fea557c9875b5defa7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relation to FACA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id16962e312e27429db9f495261aae427c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Military sexual trauma defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>military sexual trauma</term>—</text><paragraph id="id6947d4b2831f4a4db0e837d33df203e1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>with respect to eligibility for health care, has the meaning given such term in section 1720D(f) of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 301; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id53292948c4a54ca69e2ba6b593973f88" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to eligibility for compensation, has the meaning given such term in section 1166A(i) of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 203(a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="id5a5cfa77-4b02-44f5-9093-72b833122258" style="OLC" changed="not-changed"><enum>II</enum><header>Disability compensation and claims processing</header><section id="ida7f9353b-0ef2-46e3-8b6d-e8bafe010eed" changed="not-changed"><enum>201.</enum><header>Definition of military sexual trauma</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title, the term <term>military sexual trauma</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1166A(i) of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 203(a).</text></section><section id="id0331fe71-030b-49a6-b787-80e5590adb2c" changed="not-changed"><enum>202.</enum><header>Conforming changes relating to specialized teams to evaluate claims involving military sexual trauma</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1166 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide7ac5fef634949d4a91cef053b7d643a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1), by striking <quote>for compensation for a covered mental health condition</quote> and inserting <quote>for compensation for a condition, which may include a covered mental health condition,</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id074b2ebeef6445b289ce2761a57b6c6d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subsection (d) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id25AF69A284DD4F978C7D6F1EC20A1B9B"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="id199dfa5872f24c00adfa04acb33cb035"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the terms <term>covered mental health condition</term> and <term>military sexual trauma</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 1166A(i) of this title.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="idaadba611-3def-4b56-94f2-3faabecacd8e" changed="not-changed"><enum>203.</enum><header>Evaluation of claims involving military sexual trauma</header><subsection id="idc7908b67-c1c7-43d0-a1bb-17ee9c30adf9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter VI of chapter 11 of such title is amended by inserting after section 1166 the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5dc711bd-ea65-48c4-a2a2-0705e7a8c881" changed="not-changed"><section id="ide514d4df-24c4-484e-bcf9-dac024ccb47e" changed="not-changed"><enum>1166A.</enum><header>Evaluation of claims involving military sexual trauma</header><subsection id="idc39e634f-f192-44df-ad56-89bf04c22105" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id9a5ffc26-da96-4daf-8299-da55130b1b9c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the case of any veteran who claims that a covered mental health condition based on military sexual trauma was incurred in or aggravated by active military, naval, air, or space service, the Secretary shall consider the following:</text><subparagraph changed="not-changed" id="id313909D834094443A345283056F803DA" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A diagnosis of such mental health condition by a mental health professional.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="not-changed" indent="up1" id="idE326C14A54574A11A99E62A4F6C89316"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A link, established by medical evidence, between current symptoms and a military sexual trauma.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="not-changed" indent="up1" id="idFB9F7527B7CB441C9D43A4C061D175DF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Credible corroborating evidence, in accordance with subsections (b) and (c), that the claimed military sexual trauma occurred.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" id="id21ca42b4-ed52-4cc3-8512-43e1e7782eba" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The reasons for granting or denying service-connection in each case described in paragraph (1) shall be recorded in full. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide0de036f-46c4-46ea-932e-a12e02037506" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Nonmilitary sources of evidence</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id174ad60c-ac9d-455f-8489-57e92859aac1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For purposes of subsection (a), evidence from sources other than official records of the Department of Defense regarding the veteran's active military, naval, air, or space service may corroborate the veteran's account of the trauma. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1f97ad41-0ecd-4dd7-980b-665990f6dd93" indent="up1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Examples of evidence described in paragraph (1) include the following:</text><subparagraph id="id8624b7d9-3405-4f65-86d7-53b3db5491ad" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Records from law enforcement authorities, rape crisis centers, mental health counseling centers, hospitals, and physicians.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idde4c0412-4b1f-412d-beb2-5ed1ea07d797" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Pregnancy tests and tests for sexually transmitted diseases.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id47c64a28-f857-428b-be1a-13de625a4a65" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Statements from family members, roommates, other members of the Armed Forces or veterans, and clergy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id348cace4-2b54-4a88-93fd-86392410e8d1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Evidence of behavior changes</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id5f92d728-c407-4b7c-8872-fa62abcad31e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For purposes of subsection (a), evidence of a behavior change following military sexual trauma is one type of relevant evidence that may be found in sources described in such subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb74ec6d3-5165-474e-bf04-24bc3764e2b7" indent="up1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Examples of behavior changes that may be relevant evidence of military sexual trauma include the following:</text><subparagraph id="ide3d0a54d-bc39-4cab-a71b-744503cfdced" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A request for a transfer to another military duty assignment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf042ba7d-b0f2-4e74-9b91-cefdf4640161" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Deterioration in work performance.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8b4fcb8b-9ca6-4380-b4a7-f40ffd1e92fa" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Substance abuse or substance use disorder.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide24cfb51-9c36-45d7-b9bc-336132282913" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Episodes of depression, panic attacks, or anxiety without an identifiable cause.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfdd98434-5d50-4dd8-8154-80f9070d4b53" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Unexplained economic or social behavior changes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1c00ba70-5e7a-4a50-8993-dbf064513aec" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice and opportunity To supply evidence</header><text>The Secretary may not deny a claim of a veteran for compensation under this chapter for a covered mental health condition that is based on military sexual trauma without first—</text><paragraph id="idd372f99f-4cd7-45d5-8610-54ef90ee2b4e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>advising the veteran that evidence described in subsections (b) and (c) may constitute credible corroborating evidence of the military sexual trauma; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id180e2f9f-a09c-4b30-ad52-561e59158c09" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>allowing the veteran an opportunity to furnish such corroborating evidence or advise the Secretary of potential sources of such evidence.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc02b118f-98a2-4ab1-8b5d-0fa1efcb979d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Review of evidence</header><text>In reviewing a claim for compensation described in subsection (a)(1), for any evidence identified as part of such claim that is described in subsection (b) or (c), the Secretary shall submit such evidence to such medical or mental health professional as the Secretary considers appropriate, including clinical and counseling experts employed by the Department, to obtain an opinion as to whether the evidence indicates that a military sexual trauma occurred.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide3c92432-55b6-4c3e-a586-3a0b16dc638e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Point of contact</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that each document provided to a veteran relating to a claim for compensation described in subsection (a)(1) includes contact information for an appropriate point of contact with the Department.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id8a1e10b8-5e60-404b-93c2-9dc719c378f8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Specialized teams</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that all claims for compensation described in subsection (a)(1) are reviewed and processed by a specialized team established under section 1166 of this title.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb053f8b6-c46c-44e1-ad80-eb738d98931d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rule of construction regarding application to nonsexual personal assault</header><text>The Secretary shall not construe this section as supplanting the standard of proof or evidence required for claims for post-traumatic stress disorder based on nonsexual personal assault, which the Secretary shall continue to define in regulation. </text></subsection><subsection id="id3e977e9f-9018-4256-a53d-1c97208af51e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section: </text><paragraph id="id7cdea06eb51c450085a1f1949fdcdddd" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>covered mental health condition</term> means post-traumatic stress disorder, anxiety, depression, or other mental health diagnosis that the Secretary determines to be related to military sexual trauma and which may be service-connected under section 1110 of this title.</text></paragraph><paragraph changed="not-changed" id="idCBAC391C93514BE8931388D5044DB17B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>mental health professional</term> means a provider in the field of mental health who meets the credential, licensure, education, and training requirements established by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddac58bd566034e968c08d55e627b0527" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>military sexual trauma</term> means, with respect to a veteran, a physical assault of a sexual nature, battery of a sexual nature, or sexual harassment that occurred while the veteran was serving in the active military, naval, air, or space service.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id83ea4c6b-04d5-4722-952f-1ee2e6627e78" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Outreach</header><paragraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idac6bb94a51be417ab2cc2bfc0c234cc7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall implement, with input from the veteran community, an informative outreach program for veterans regarding the standard of proof for evaluation of claims relating to military sexual trauma, including requirements for a medical examination and opinion.</text></paragraph><paragraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id29750e49b3194ca4942e69fcf224324f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Targeted outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In implementing the program under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, target outreach to veterans who submitted a claim relating to military sexual trauma that was denied.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idee854b80-4841-485c-8e53-7401294ef2eb" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 11 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1166 the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5ab94b86-437b-4cc2-89ba-dd28bd2579c9" changed="not-changed"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration" changed="not-changed"><toc-entry level="section" changed="not-changed">1166A. Evaluation of claims involving military sexual trauma.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="id26db3ca3-99c9-4bcb-a7d4-3a4fbcc5e340" changed="not-changed"><enum>204.</enum><header>Choice of location of Department of Veterans Affairs medical examination for assessment of claims for compensation relating to disability resulting from military sexual trauma</header><subsection id="ida6f4a0ca-7258-4140-96ed-ecf25ab944a7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1165 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="id5667b521-1ac5-410f-8cdc-99ce31ad4cd1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the section heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">and location of medical examination</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">examiner</header-in-text></quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7766714c-ab31-43f7-9fee-e677266293bd" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>a physical assault of a sexual nature, battery of a sexual nature, or sexual harassment</quote> and inserting <quote>military sexual trauma (as defined in section 1166A(i) of this title)</quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide897b3ec-0ea3-4968-837e-cfc697415046" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (c) as subsection (d); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc37a53ce-d58d-46a6-855b-57f75c7ee941" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following new subsection (c): </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3cd8690fc68143ddb50c9c6228755f3e"><subsection id="id4831182e-b0d0-425a-8f26-8447921ef707" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Choice of examination location</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that a veteran who requires a medical examination in support of a claim described in subsection (a) may request that the medical examination take place at a medical facility of the Department by a qualified employee of the Department rather than at a location designated by a contractor of the Department that performs such examinations on behalf of the Department.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id664fc564-f39b-409d-bd3b-3ea7e07a5aeb" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 11 of such title is amended by striking the item relating to section 1165 and inserting the following new item: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f4f7944-9163-4e42-8ac2-a79b1b40c5b2" changed="not-changed"><toc changed="not-changed"><toc-entry bold="off" level="section" changed="not-changed">1165. Choice of sex of medical examiner and location of medical examination for certain disabilities.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="id425C0A715E654244B46D72EE2AC311C5" changed="not-changed"><enum>205.</enum><header>Communications from the Department of Veterans Affairs to individuals who have experienced military sexual trauma</header><subsection id="id0B5668DA730747A19189B20A6836E08E" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review workgroup</header><paragraph id="id0837F3D4081447888DE8E5B3029FA962" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish a workgroup to review correspondence relating to military sexual trauma. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idBB625FFC6B4F48F78F0DDF7079B7DA43" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The workgroup established under paragraph (1) shall be composed of members who shall be appointed by the Secretary from among employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs who are experts in military sexual trauma and mental health, of whom—</text><subparagraph id="id44E15C2A5B444990BF0F410148CDA901" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>one or more shall be appointed from among mental health providers of the Veterans Health Administration; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id340C2F08124F4855BACE9581C7B0D9E6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>one or more shall be appointed from among experts on sexual assault and sexual harassment of the Veterans Benefits Administration; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ACCD8FF1DE54E68849073B28D78BE91" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>one or more shall be appointed from among experts on sexual assault and sexual harassment of the Board of Veterans’ Appeals. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idDA557D7701D94AD584FAD5AB78757E68" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The workgroup established under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="id8A216534BBBD47F09BC53D25BA1970F8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review standard correspondence, which may include templates for notices under sections 5103, 5104, 5104B, and 7104 of title 38, United States Code, from the Department to individuals who have experienced military sexual trauma for sensitivity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA32EEB099E4F4939BC2FCF5309C37A26" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that the correspondence— </text><clause id="id58153CEFDF6F42BDB65E7EB3E1A30DD4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>treats such individuals with dignity and respect; and </text></clause><clause id="id00ADAAEE13594B29A7FC0D7B2B5D1182" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not re-traumatize such individuals.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idFDD049F8ADC243FA9DC8D013CE9388C7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Individual who has experienced military sexual trauma defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>individual who has experienced military sexual trauma</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id61EC2E9C1564404BBF8F41B1A2790DC4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual who has filed a claim for compensation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/11">chapter 11</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, relating to military sexual trauma; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCF5A2AA34A2C4846A98A5765194BDC8D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a veteran who has been awarded compensation under such chapter relating to military sexual trauma; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2AF33FE6900A47F1BE2E36D4A6B1DC18" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a member of the Armed Forces (including a member of the National Guard or Reserves), a former member of the Armed Forces, or a veteran who is receiving care from the Department relating to military sexual trauma. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4590770E21D646B3BC6F6368C20AAFA0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of certain written communications to individuals who have experienced military sexual trauma</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id51E0786B595A40888585664D640579DC" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice to claimants of required information and evidence</header><text>Section 5103 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="idDF87B305EC744759AF5DC2EDA7577B02" act-name="" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="idE59108DE1BFE427D8BE6D0E15D6A89A3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Written communications to individuals who have experienced military sexual trauma</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id0DF0CBE102DE439D879114D73EFEACB1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall ensure that any written communication under this section from the Department to an individual who has experienced military sexual trauma includes each of the following:</text><subparagraph changed="not-changed" indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d30cae694d346c883baa55feac3386d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Contact information for each of the following: </text><clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6704509e9e5844d388787e3c58f6e44a"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The military sexual trauma coordinator of the Veterans Benefits Administration.</text></clause><clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id73c0321d6e934dd1952cf13a12a26388"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The military sexual trauma coordinator of the Veterans Health Administration.</text></clause><clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5e7633464c304bea8a38cb5e4f4cd754"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Veterans Crisis Line.</text></clause><clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id177ba6298000401bb6c2e633c8b214f1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The facility of the Veterans Health Administration closest to where the individual resides.</text></clause><clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1420fbba80ce472ba46a7e22f022a5cc"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Vet Center closest to where the individual resides. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="not-changed" indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8eb18197f6a5461cbb985f03ccc02f38"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information on the eligibility of the individual for services provided through the Vet Center described in subparagraph (A)(v).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" id="id8BC9722EA78E4F5D95E1FC3CF21C2E84" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In this subsection: </text><subparagraph id="idAA32903FD0CC4C2EA57613065189817C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>individual who has experienced military sexual trauma</term> means—</text><clause id="id51F803A4F98B4150866B4B4F81691441" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an individual who has filed a claim for compensation under chapter 11 of this title relating to military sexual trauma;</text></clause><clause id="id67C976379E9E4C6FBA0B51D228D3A8FA" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a veteran who has been awarded compensation under such chapter relating to military sexual trauma; or </text></clause><clause id="id9E3E8F93648B44EB9E1FC0975BD28058" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a member of the Armed Forces (including a member of the National Guard or Reserves), a former member of the Armed Forces, or a veteran who is receiving care from the Department relating to military sexual trauma. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA7F18DF1C1144CE99CCA347C553B9381" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>military sexual trauma</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1166A(i) of this title. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaac757fa743a4e2ea3d1ff866b5cedbf"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term <term>Vet Center</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1712A(h) of this title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id138344A7D11245C99A9BC041DFA6A61D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The term <term>Veterans Crisis Line</term> means the toll-free hotline for veterans established under section 1720F(h) of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC5C899C5DB244777A0D44182E0A5D4B1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Decisions and notices of decisions</header><text>Section 5104 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="id267F04906E824B308AA96AF6AFD81278" act-name="" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id0D68535264224B6DB79E937E78E51415" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idC1C3E41151DC4A5FA9A174B39C8A40CF" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall ensure that any written communication under this section from the Department to an individual who has experienced military sexual trauma includes each of the following:</text><subparagraph changed="not-changed" indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfe189f1e09be462b8b41526564de9d4b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Contact information for each of the following: </text><clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd8be9337fb8e4fe7b06bb3a7d5ea7d30"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The military sexual trauma coordinator of the Veterans Health Administration.</text></clause><clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49c032dfb43446468339b8c740fb4112"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Veterans Crisis Line.</text></clause><clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id025f64bab2f74f369728e8f86828dd63"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The facility of the Veterans Health Administration closest to where the individual resides.</text></clause><clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id891e65d7248e4a989f79029b5d1f506b"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Vet Center closest to where the individual resides.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="not-changed" indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4122d62d133a4b849d5e62a167646072"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information on the eligibility of the individual for services provided through the Vet Center described in subparagraph (A)(iv).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" id="id4C7E5B8B816C4BCEAD94F05D08D0EA48" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall ensure that any written communication under this section from the Department to an individual who has experienced military sexual trauma that includes notification of an award of compensation under chapter 11 of this title relating to military sexual trauma includes—</text><subparagraph id="id2F206F7205AD4C898AD3D3EAB1599D09" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text> the contact information described in paragraph (1); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB2890EC82A854C98AB417ED324437FB0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the contact information for the military sexual trauma coordinator of the Veterans Benefits Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" id="idE5A68326892B4481BF41812AF8B4859A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In this subsection: </text><subparagraph id="id0AB1068768074A57B6EBCE1A477F3E5F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>individual who has experienced military sexual trauma</term> means—</text><clause id="idFB9D6AA4111B45F48B187FD0A4F860FF" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an individual who has filed a claim for compensation under chapter 11 of this title relating to military sexual trauma;</text></clause><clause id="idD8ED90ED56DD410AB85917EC99A615D8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a veteran who has been awarded compensation under such chapter relating to military sexual trauma; or </text></clause><clause id="id48B8B16F5FBA4B3982A22F108B59FFAC" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a member of the Armed Forces (including a member of the National Guard or Reserves), a former member of the Armed Forces, or a veteran who is receiving care from the Department relating to military sexual trauma. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2B6E4130B655439188F46C6612B82498" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>military sexual trauma</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1166A(i) of this title. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7dfa5303065a48649dde42a64dbd9a5f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term <term>Vet Center</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1712A(h) of this title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEE3F189656224B869EA8D7013C873C42" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The term <term>Veterans Crisis Line</term> means the toll-free hotline for veterans established under section 1720F(h) of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD2821866FDB642E784529AC2D0EA8A6A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Higher-level review by the agency of original jurisdiction</header><text>Section 5104B of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="id71AF7DB6B228486AB03149E03586C849" act-name="" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id932DF1A3703B4B6197FB02A551F21E8B" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Written communications to individuals who have experienced military sexual trauma</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idB74DF778701F4963B6D5E3201450DEE3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall ensure that any written communication under this section from the Department to an individual who has experienced military sexual trauma includes each of the following:</text><subparagraph changed="not-changed" indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb0d89593f8dd4a0a8a95922d732652bd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Contact information for each of the following: </text><clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9bdf0ae9292e476fb8b90e12c8d8e791"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The military sexual trauma coordinator of the Veterans Health Administration.</text></clause><clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id17b787e787ce4769abfc9d42885b6d1b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Veterans Crisis Line.</text></clause><clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4c47cc0ad5094d64aa8edb2dfc263fcd"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The facility of the Veterans Health Administration closest to where the individual resides.</text></clause><clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id68c9f97bba044ec0bf289d75f6a890da"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Vet Center closest to where the individual resides.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="not-changed" indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id04f52c9e2a194168b1ae9cef152e82f6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information on the eligibility of the individual for services provided through the Vet Center described in subparagraph (A)(iv).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" id="idB541BDADE0B74F34B869A93312C45701" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall ensure that any written communication under this section from the Department to an individual who has experienced military sexual trauma that includes notification of an award of compensation under chapter 11 of this title relating to military sexual trauma includes—</text><subparagraph id="id8DE9BE12D82D4A9BA9247D7CFDF1CFB5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text> the contact information described in paragraph (1); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id986A19948F95435ABDB6F362C2FE9A14" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the contact information for the military sexual trauma coordinator of the Veterans Benefits Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" id="id78366C0E8B8E43BF876A90EC7D283B2F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In this subsection: </text><subparagraph id="id8DCE43CA20D54189981F1708E52ADF35" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>individual who has experienced military sexual trauma</term> means—</text><clause id="id41A722EF97F04805BF7D4DD688652F1F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an individual who has filed a claim for compensation under chapter 11 of this title relating to military sexual trauma;</text></clause><clause id="idF22EACB2E1AB41B991C98D81CB3F21CF" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a veteran who has been awarded compensation under such chapter relating to military sexual trauma; or </text></clause><clause id="id7A0F0B36B5FC4E6B89FC8F4E2EDCFCA0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a member of the Armed Forces (including a member of the National Guard or Reserves), a former member of the Armed Forces, or a veteran who is receiving care from the Department relating to military sexual trauma. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id01B39088E5CD41F5A698E15723182562" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>military sexual trauma</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1166A(i) of this title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd88c5c79d6d84e75b42d31f9f44cbf3e"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Vet Center</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1712A(h) of this title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id098E368C5C5849AAB8E1864B5778BEC9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The term <term>Veterans Crisis Line</term> means the toll-free hotline for veterans established under section 1720F(h) of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8A7F677AA9B242449F32886A4B7BFD1E" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Board of Veterans’ Appeals</header><text>Section 7104 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection: </text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2CB9F6553F0D4F49BE9D1348B843417D" changed="not-changed" act-name=""><subsection id="id1123F711F8C1401BB477E3B3D748421D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(g)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idA9C4DB4BA6DA4898AB2117510F2CC2D9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall ensure that any written communication under this section from the Department to an individual who has experienced military sexual trauma include each of the following:</text><subparagraph changed="not-changed" indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23cdd5f5e66e4eb2be1bd0142bb6a929"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Contact information for each of the following: </text><clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9f3dcff7817a4d69a0a15dfed2da8352"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The military sexual trauma coordinator of the Veterans Health Administration.</text></clause><clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id57d5204e09544d20a7652e3e603e70b4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Veterans Crisis Line.</text></clause><clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb2e26ee7be574aa79f47f6ff7137d1a6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The facility of the Veterans Health Administration closest to where the individual resides.</text></clause><clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idff33e7f974eb4e3ba9adda4cabe869b4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Vet Center closest to where the individual resides. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="not-changed" indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5d97f04299f04aa0a8b38369bd47026d"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information on the eligibility of the individual for services provided through the Vet Center described in subparagraph (A)(iv).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" id="id28E74B23AED748C2B4AA77836AECDE19" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall ensure that any written communication under this section from the Department to an individual who has experienced military sexual trauma that includes notification of an award of compensation under chapter 11 of this title relating to military sexual trauma includes—</text><subparagraph id="id36AB2758DF4F4053996B2B9E8306F336" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text> the contact information described in paragraph (1); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5728B7BA250C44DAABF206574EE6B6E5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the contact information for the military sexual trauma coordinator of the Veterans Benefits Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" id="id637D046A4B864C95BC16F028FFBC298F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In this subsection: </text><subparagraph id="id1578F86E6306432A84B7F169B6C09220" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>individual who has experienced military sexual trauma</term> means—</text><clause id="id680131DF7D334306B322BC24DF5A13B6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an individual who has filed a claim for compensation under chapter 11 of this title relating to military sexual trauma;</text></clause><clause id="idE6C8341F2D1C4840B4C8E6CA9B42C400" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a veteran who has been awarded compensation under such chapter relating to military sexual trauma; or </text></clause><clause id="id25239586032B433CAD04ED3D4A925262" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a member of the Armed Forces (including a member of the National Guard or Reserves), a former member of the Armed Forces, or a veteran who is receiving care from the Department relating to military sexual trauma. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id11B32EDCFDB4433BAA12A58E2679754F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>military sexual trauma</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1166A(i) of this title. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6bd3c793370a471e9a77afc1669f90cb"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term <term>Vet Center</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1712A(h) of this title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id241D4B72E00F45B6B3E127B2EC13854D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The term <term>Veterans Crisis Line</term> means the toll-free hotline for veterans established under section 1720F(h) of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id1acaa9c0-1c01-4e54-abd9-08b1c81762b4" changed="not-changed"><enum>206.</enum><header>Study on training and processing relating to claims for disability compensation relating to military sexual trauma</header><subsection id="idd2a70b7f-50ee-48b5-8190-e70f9ed13ecc" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study required</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall conduct a study on—</text><paragraph id="id4a9713aa-a83d-4258-96d5-c8c4a9b9ce0a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the quality of training provided to personnel of the Department of Veterans Affairs who review claims for disability compensation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/11">chapter 11</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, for disabilities relating to military sexual trauma; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbf43e488-1466-4dca-86fd-8b76c9513ab6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the quality of the procedures of the Department for reviewing the accuracy of the processing of such claims. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idea83255e-e491-47b2-a8c5-9ff726af2f7e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The study required by subsection (a) shall include the following: </text><paragraph id="idd33aee80-9f22-4cc6-a47a-04582591cb4b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>With respect to the quality of training described in paragraph (1) of such subsection: </text><subparagraph id="idbd807eb8-fcb8-47b2-a6ec-082273f1dfd1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Whether the Department ensures personnel complete such training on time. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id11dcce3c-5c40-4467-ad69-e99097d44e6b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Whether the training has resulted in improvements to the processing of claims described in such subsection and issue-based accuracy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id48749a81-d299-4c2b-9fa7-d2b3b43a9fb2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Such recommendations as the Secretary may have for improving the training. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbb82766a-1484-4912-b5e3-03ee1106b00e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>With respect to the quality of procedures described in paragraph (2) of such subsection: </text><subparagraph id="id462693d1-0652-4728-b115-0159f4f5e623" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Whether the procedures of the Department for reviewing the accuracy of the processing of claims described in such subsection comport with generally accepted statistical methodologies to ensure reasonable accuracy of such reviews.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfe3e2c2d-0dc7-46a0-bab2-4b15943619e3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Whether such procedures adequately include mechanisms to correct errors found in such reviews.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0515ed55caa94d81bac390804ef3e8d0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A summary of quality assurance reviews and reports conducted as part of such procedures.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide561dd0fe3244f81b1c83408ad17b640"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such recommendations as the Secretary may have for improving such procedures. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idad02082e-2587-42ac-9c9d-3614a7eb8582" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report detailing the findings of the Secretary with respect to the study conducted under subsection (a). </text></subsection></section><section id="id594b2da5-fe72-4173-a084-1d26bd0f8c07" changed="not-changed"><enum>207.</enum><header>Annual special focus review of claims for disability compensation for disabilities relating to military sexual trauma</header><subsection id="idd153da6d-ae64-4b59-9cf5-c2be74893096" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual special focus review</header><paragraph id="id3380cdba-ceb3-487d-af9b-d8d9332fde19" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each year, the Under Secretary for Benefits of the Department of Veterans Affairs shall conduct a special focus review on the accuracy of the processing of claims for disability compensation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/11">chapter 11</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, for disabilities relating to military sexual trauma. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7cb97334-6620-4f58-8d40-43163675326e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Each review conducted under paragraph (1) shall include a review of the following: </text><subparagraph id="idc976387e-971a-4ec7-97d1-3e839f998dea" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A statistically significant, nationally representative sample of all claims for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs relating to military sexual trauma filed during the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year in which the report is submitted.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb0b01370-4f91-4793-b5ef-83b424bd67e3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The accuracy of each decision made with respect to each claim described in subparagraph (A). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idebb027e7-c29f-47e6-948f-f91f2800b150" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The types of benefit entitlement errors found, disaggregated by category.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id819c301d-1836-4bbd-99b0-3b809de26b32" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Trends from year to year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc3341229-4dbf-47f2-9e53-7eb13369eed7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Training completion rates for personnel of the Department who process claims described in paragraph (1). </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idaed526cc-51c6-4c5b-aff9-a95e290a6a52" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reprocessing of claims</header><text>If the Under Secretary finds, pursuant to a special focus review conducted under subsection (a)(1), that an error was made with respect to the entitlement of a veteran to a benefit under the laws administered by the Secretary, the Secretary shall return the relevant claim of the veteran to the appropriate office of the Department for reprocessing to ensure that the veteran receives an accurate decision with respect to the claim. </text></subsection><subsection id="id6eff0923-6224-4cb6-910a-819b31de06e8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Section 5501(b) of the Johnny Isakson and David P. Roe, M.D. Veterans Health Care and Benefits Improvement Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/315">Public Law 116–315</external-xref>; 134 Stat. 5048) is amended—</text><paragraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb936dfd35129498aaf95ca7d27ef879a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>through 2027</quote> and inserting <quote>until the date described in section 207(d) of the <short-title>Servicemembers and Veterans Empowerment and Support Act of 2025</short-title></quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbacce11b61a64e0bbae22309d2823dac"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by adding at the end the following new subparagraph: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="id1c79ee4b-18f9-4144-a66d-5b21940d46ac" act-name="" changed="not-changed"><subparagraph id="idbe4a55a6-fb47-4d04-9fed-2a2fc29d505a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The findings of the most recent special focus review conducted under subsection (a)(1) of section 207 of the <short-title>Servicemembers and Veterans Empowerment and Support Act of 2025</short-title>, including— </text><clause id="id529aa75e-aabe-44a5-94c5-fccbf9bdb3db" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the elements under subsection (a)(2) of such section; </text></clause><clause id="id23c3defe-82d9-4ef5-bf40-31532b8fc12c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of claims returned for reprocessing under subsection (b) of such section; and</text></clause><clause id="idc602e261-a0ed-4df7-9233-9c2b223d97ad" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of claims described in clause (ii) for which the decision relating to service-connection or entitlement to compensation changed as a result of reprocessing the claim.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id06b0b7fe9f2d4f21ba3f687ae3e0d3c2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>On the date that the Under Secretary determines, pursuant to special focus reviews conducted under paragraph (1) of subsection (a), that the accuracy rates under paragraph (2)(B) of such subsection have been 95 percent or greater for five consecutive years, subsection (a)(1) shall cease to be in effect. </text></subsection></section><section id="id36447aee1e5a494c81f3606caf99a364"><enum>208.</enum><header>Workgroup on medical examinations for claims for disability compensation for disabilities relating to military sexual trauma</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e4ade15369b40338c3f082caae0c981"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish a workgroup on medical examinations for claims for disability compensation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/11">chapter 11</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, for disabilities relating to military sexual trauma (in this section referred to as the <quote>workgroup</quote>). </text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd4ab04552fd64821844f5ce6080a8521"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The workgroup shall be composed of the following: </text><paragraph id="id278B75839D5741B4AF85C8D7F1DB3F9E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Staff of the operations center for military sexual trauma of the Department of Veterans Affairs who have experience reviewing the quality of medical examinations in support of claims for disability compensation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/11">chapter 11</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idDC74396A7B8B4B779F5EA056D9DBB0FD" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Staff of the Medical Disability Examination Office of the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0659B5C3EF274D89B9AD60AE44FDF4D7" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Veterans service officers who have experience with claims described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB6D1C128E99A406F8829A8798A9E55C6" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Medical examiners who have experience with such claims. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA6195C5CD0A84846AE1F1C06B0D5B182" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Staff of the Veterans Experience Office of the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id07AF3C18361B4937820E64B5F65AE8A0" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Such other individuals as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd479facdd1542e3997bb5abb70fd27a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Workgroup shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4a9bd0aa22fe48989ed67ad61bb9787d"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review the quality of medical examinations described in subsection (a); </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd3b14562a1f14867aff6324178f32333"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review the feasibility of minimizing re-examinations for conditions relating to military sexual trauma; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id73ede91dbd104c0697b31aa1c5803d6e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>submit to the Under Secretary for Benefits of the Department and the Secretary recommendations on how to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5e3de15c3393405ba04101ff8130aab9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">eliminate re-traumatization of individuals who file claims described in subsection (a); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1b4e20330c944a3ebb13feacb71119bc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reduce the overdevelopment of such claims.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6682131dac43492fa9b714c5378c724c"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes the following:</text><paragraph id="id016f20faa363414583595d6b10f7f32b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The views of the workgroup on efforts by the Department to eliminate re-traumatization of individuals who file claims described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3af01cccca5849399bcadadb6a76cfb2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Legislative proposals to improve the experience of such individuals in pursuing such claims.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD08A3BACCB354A5D840895764C074466" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The recommendations submitted under subsection (c)(3). </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4881afdc414b4c2e8aac51dd17f25b3d"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The plan of the Under Secretary for Benefits of the Department and the Secretary to implement such recommendations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1dda5d48aeb74ad2ad3ed4b8692bff58"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Review and implementation</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary for Benefits of the Department and the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id574b6bb1cc0648b2aa818d266c4b2617"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review the recommendations submitted under subsection (c)(3); and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3d8bab68e27a4e4c9d19eb642b08eb4e"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implement the recommendations that, as determined by the Under Secretary and the Secretary, would improve the claims process for individuals who file claims described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="idA8776D558F444195B2E8AC1A00CE12E6" style="OLC" changed="not-changed"><enum>III</enum><header>Access to health care</header><section id="id940C70795B5E4B208EC67EAC589F52AD" changed="not-changed"><enum>301.</enum><header>Expansion of eligibility for counseling and treatment for military sexual trauma to include all former members of the reserve components of the armed forces</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1720D of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="idF5A1220677BB4831B493852CC45D5D27" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="idC49C356A6C634EBE8F5F577487EB1FCE" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>a physical assault</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote>military sexual trauma.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAB7E3E48B9604B74B6ABB2C87054CE07" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A), by striking <quote>was suffered</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote>resulted from military sexual trauma.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7CC096C0E7E8426EB025075ECC5EE972" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subsections (f) and (g) and inserting the following new subsection (f):</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id14F1CF5B3C8642FCBAFF7DD19998229A" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="idDFDE7C7E367E439E968D1F49F22CAC3D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id906F4B88EF7545C5B1CB7DDC3D7D429D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>former member of the Armed Forces</term> means a person who served on active duty, active duty for training, or inactive duty training, and who was discharged or released therefrom under any condition that is not—</text><subparagraph id="id14E1286D7A5840329D6F82937C6BA370" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a discharge by court-martial, unless the Secretary determines an exception to the bar to benefits applies; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFA619D395C53433D98FA6BCF453403E7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a discharge subject to a bar to benefits under section 5303 of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id23ECAB6404C440E8AC5C0798B7DA959B" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>military sexual trauma</term> means, with respect to a member of the Armed Forces or former member of the Armed Forces, a physical assault of a sexual nature, battery of a sexual nature, or sexual harassment which occurred while the member or former member was serving on duty, regardless of duty status or line of duty determination (as that term is used in section 12323 of title 10).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD745CF4F1B1F4589B4C11D4C6417273E" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>sexual harassment</term> means unsolicited verbal or physical contact of a sexual nature which is threatening in character.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="id62204DDAE94248FC92CAC9286786F3AA" changed="not-changed"><enum>302.</enum><header>Connection to veterans health administration when a disability claim related to military sexual trauma is submitted to veterans benefits administration</header><subsection id="id73EE3E65E2A04FC79CBF5859DC80CAC4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 14 days after the date on which a veteran submits a claim for disability compensation to the Veterans Benefits Administration for a disability related to military sexual trauma, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall send a communication to the veteran with the following information:</text><paragraph id="idC4678E04FA1B47EFA970D1D7315FA8B6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The contact information for the nearest military sexual trauma coordinator for the veteran at the Veterans Benefits Administration and a description of the assistance such coordinator can provide.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id85B945FD60804EC193F07589E7DB8727" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The contact information for the nearest military sexual trauma coordinator for the veteran at the Veterans Health Administration and a description of the assistance such coordinator can provide.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id694F2AA2BBFE44C590689FF2D9B74812" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The types of services that individuals who have experienced military sexual trauma are eligible to receive from the Department of Veterans Affairs, including the nearest locations, including the nearest Vet Center, and the contact information for such services. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idFCB94572356340AFB55C3C13DDC069FB" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The contact information for the Veterans Crisis Line established under section 1720F(h) of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id436E3722ACFF4015A7993796F6568558" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Such other information on services, care, or resources for military sexual trauma as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8846D7C2768D43A4938A022ADFCEC6ED" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section: </text><paragraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6bb997ec185d4395a03979db23febac2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Military sexual trauma</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>military sexual trauma</term>—</text><subparagraph id="id48c60ded13a44ad5a7f22ddb1cc2164d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to eligibility for health care, has the meaning given such term in section 1720D(f) of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 301; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id72e406cea4764505bfe5e77a4c31192e" changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to eligibility for compensation, has the meaning given such term in section 1166A(i) of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 203(a). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfb7636460b464c55b7a2055c40302d01"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vet center</header><text>The term <term>Vet Center</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1712A(h) of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id2d6d7040c51c46b9932bed6b2fb24225"><enum>303.</enum><header>Care relating to military sexual trauma for individuals who withdraw from or otherwise do not complete service at service academies</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddad38738b6d14d6f86637dc0e1e5b625"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Transportation, shall ensure that each individual who withdraws from, or otherwise does not complete service at, a service academy is provided—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idee0d2781503047ed85f607a54ddc408f"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on the potential eligibility of such individual for care and counseling relating to military sexual trauma provided through the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f23203b3a754055b2b74db859c18ee4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the option to receive copies of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf8f3099c1cfb42f68eeceb4958e3c7a6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the individual's service treatment records or military personnel records that document military sexual trauma;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida9117b37a39346d9b8a10da7a31193b0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reporting forms of the Department of Defense, the Department of Homeland Security, or the Department of Transportation on sexual assault or sexual harassment for which the individual was the victim; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8f75bc62085d4cabb35a58fa3b9a206d"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any investigative reports into military sexual trauma that occurred during the individual's service in the Armed Forces and for which the individual was the victim. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5943c1242bfc470b9c1a2e64ab1ac97d"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section: </text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5420374d1b0e47dc999aef1cbe742559"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Military sexual trauma</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>military sexual trauma</term>—</text><subparagraph id="id2421062B3BA2421087A44BEF53EE9A3D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to eligibility for health care, has the meaning given such term in section 1720D(f) of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 301; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id71ABFA151F6C42F382BBEEA5AC802FE2" changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to eligibility for compensation, has the meaning given such term in section 1166A(i) of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 203(a). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbb91f9a59be84f1083a06bdb8e17c6a1"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Service academy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>service academy</term> means any of the following: </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id46b232d094a443d68c231c61765b517e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Military Academy. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e4afefe737542b8a01d689562a35737"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Naval Academy. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e41acc11af8484a8796d95c3d7f3042"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Air Force Academy. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idead6b937938143648b36534c6e720213"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Coast Guard Academy. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8ead129d91924f25b49b80589905a378" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Merchant Marine Academy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

