<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA3E2C888A6564099BE818A62A47193B8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5506 IH: Courtney Wild Reinforcing Crime Victims’ Rights Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5506</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250918">September 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To strengthen the rights of crime victims, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H81E8CB6199A34B8B98F658C57E502C47" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC70DD78F1AD846429C125611F567A2E4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Courtney Wild Reinforcing Crime Victims’ Rights Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD8ECA07B4C63406A9AD698E81C906997"><enum>2.</enum><header>Crime victims’ rights</header> <subsection id="HD47EF0F9048F420D95C830822E99E5C4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/237">Chapter 237</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7A28070D464E4D1D9E0ABB70833C38B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 3771—</text> <subparagraph id="H2E38CF0DE1894329BD034B8630B56384"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> 
<clause id="HAB015F5E71D14F0090A7432C2C5C0AEF" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A crime victim</quote> and inserting <quote>Upon the suspected or alleged commission of a Federal or District of Columbia offense, a crime victim</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H33495E1A0EAD42FD94808803AFD63599"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>Government in the case</quote> and inserting <quote>Government, including the right to confer about any agreement that could resolve the case or investigation, plea bargain, plea offer or agreement, pretrial diversion offer or agreement, or voluntary dismissal is presented to the court or is otherwise formally executed</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD87CD433B9A2426DBB4F962543DCF9AC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (9) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HF730433AE6514D71AFB9C4F8B9FDCD67" style="USC"> <paragraph id="H3BC25EF76F4947D8AE986A51B0647116"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The right to be informed in a timely manner of any plea bargain, plea offer or agreement, deferred prosecution agreement, or other agreement that resolves the case or investigation, pretrial diversion agreement, or the referral of a criminal investigation to another Federal, State, Tribal, or local law enforcement entity.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> 
<clause id="H6CF9B959FCF8498C8CA2E3DD52C43D3C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in paragraph (10), by striking <quote>contact information for the Office of the Victims’ Rights Ombudsman of the Department of Justice</quote> and inserting <quote>a crime victims’ rights card listing the rights described in this subsection, contact information for the Office of the Crime Victims’ Rights Ombudsman of the Department of Justice, and information about sources of legal assistance (including pro bono legal assistance) related to the exercise of these rights, including that the victim has the right to seek the advice of an attorney with respect to these rights</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H06319B7B300945CC9122F31D6E2B984E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), by inserting after the first sentence the following: <quote>The court shall also confirm that the Government has complied with its obligation to accord the rights described in subsection (a) and may issue any reasonable orders to cure noncompliance.</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4D8F5A10BE2C4103B0C7BC8EFCB84AE7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <clause id="HC0A745FB15664832B3708E4427BC6B75"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H7465197522BF457D9D8479CA7AC0126A" style="USC"> 
<paragraph id="H9E9C1AFEE6414B019608D3E0F1BA3D35"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Government</header> 
<subparagraph id="H13ACF7F5C62144739EF5165473B142DA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Officers and employees of the Department of Justice and other departments and agencies of the United States engaged in the detection, investigation, or prosecution of crimes shall make their best efforts to see that crime victims are notified of, and accorded, the rights described in subsection (a).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6EDE41A1D614484B99FA614AEF16B2CF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Request for delay</header> <clause id="H3F2128CAEDDC48CDB3218BA7AAFB1DA5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Circumstances</header><text>If charges pertaining to the victim have not been publicly filed, and the Government determines that according one or more of the rights described in subsection (a) would threaten the safety of an individual, interfere with an ongoing investigation or prosecution, compromise national security, or result in premature disclosure of material nonpublic information, the Government may request leave from the court to delay according the right for the limited period of time necessary to avoid the harm or until charges are publicly filed, whichever comes first.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H963FCEA758754AD388226D06A6A1504E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Court procedure</header><text>The court shall review a submission made by the Government along with its request, the court may grant such request if it is supported by clear and convincing evidence. The Court shall maintain a record of the Government’s request and its ruling on the matter, which shall be provided to the victim at the conclusion of the delay.</text></clause> <clause id="H26C224B19B9443ED9CC8DF2A20CFDE3F"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>An order by a court granting a request for a delay under this subparagraph shall be for a period that does not exceed 90 days, except that the Government may, for good cause, apply for an extension of the delay period. The granting of a delay under this subparagraph shall not constitute grounds for failing to ultimately accord a right to any victim.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5A339591F1FE49C2A078A332632D1420"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Court-ordered remedies</header><text>If a court finds that the Government failed to comply with subparagraph (A), it may order an appropriate remedy under the circumstances, as set forth in subsection (d).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE7D76DD0E14C4FAC8B0823354A264CE9"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Pro bono legal representation for victims</header><text>To the extent practicable, and consistent with applicable ethical standards and rules of professional conduct, the Government shall provide to the crime victim general information on how to seek available pro bono legal representation for the purpose of asserting the rights under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> 
<clause id="H0B3A1BECF16241048FCED9587ED82668"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HD847FA60A29E48E39CD8277DEA3CD8F1" style="USC"> <paragraph id="H2D93B5D1C10E4F02A0D9191D7FC02F9F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advice of attorney</header><text>Officers and employees of the Department of Justice and other departments and agencies of the United States engaged in the detection, investigation, or prosecution of the alleged crime shall inform the crime victim in writing that the crime victim can seek the advice of an attorney with respect to the rights described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE8396622D4F0438FB87D015A52567EAD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text> <clause id="HBFCA854F5677497EB512F86417735C5F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HC4D4189991904F0E8BC09E2C71D9C435" style="USC"> 
<paragraph id="HB78B3F57043E4E39954F1C0DD105A908"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rights</header> 
<subparagraph id="HD589245790EB4FF98F1D8CA688F3283F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The crime victim or the crime victim’s lawful representative, and the attorney for the Government may assert the rights described in subsection (a). A person accused of the crime may not obtain any form of relief under this chapter.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFFEE3755FE3C4F22A7C94F5A7FD3D877"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Representation by victim’s attorney</header> <clause id="HEC3D3DAACF874E0BA9AF535086C9B4B7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An attorney may enter an appearance of behalf of a crime victim or crime victim’s lawful representative in the district court in which a defendant is being or has been prosecuted for a crime in the same manner as any other party to the proceedings, or if no prosecution is underway, in the district court for the district in which the crime occurred.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0F506C860954448A9FA4B1B589CD0E81"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirements of parties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each party to the proceeding shall serve the attorney for the victim with a copy of each pleading that relates to the crime victim's rights under subsection (a). </text></clause> <clause id="HB427C592E83540118E8F8FA068FD2CA9"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Requirements of the clerk of the court</header><text>The clerk of the court shall provide to the attorney a copy of any court order related to such rights and notify the attorney of any hearing that may affect such rights.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF8CC20DDBEE244219938C4FDAB0DDC3E" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Requirements of the court</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The court shall—</text> <subclause id="H784621ED35D24C29944AC1955EBBE653"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provide the crime victim’s attorney or lawful representative access to all case records in the action; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H6F8483053DBE4967BA821197CF6F4D33"><enum>(II)</enum><text>serve the crime victim’s attorney or lawful representative with any filings that are directly relevant to or implicate the crime victim’s rights described in subsection (a).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> <clause id="HD68BFC2D6B2849F0A6A820C957715685"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting after the period at the end the following: <quote>The procedure fashioned by the court under this paragraph shall have no effect on the duty of officers and employees of the Government to make their best efforts to accord crime victims the rights described in subsection (a).</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA940803D0BCC46AC966FE995D5E725ED"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (3) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H752F2447803C40AFB66275D6BB088139" style="USC"> <paragraph id="H1BEA441DF94246049F5E2064FE5D7212"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Motion for relief and writ of mandamus</header> <subparagraph id="H8C84D6C62477450CA8262F96C34FAC02"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Motion for relief</header><text>The rights described in subsection (a) shall be asserted in the district court in which a defendant is being prosecuted or has been prosecuted for the crime. If no prosecution is underway at the time of the motion for relief, the rights described in subsection (a) shall be asserted in the district court in the district in which the crime is alleged to have occurred. The motion may be filed in an existing criminal case or, if no complaint, information, or indictment has been filed at that time, by a separate rights enforcement action.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H465FDC61A87646A0A7E30C09D309AE5D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Review of motion for relief</header> 
<clause id="H63F8D07B2D384AFC9125D00B9DE99267"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The district court shall take up and decide any motion or separate rights enforcement action asserting a victim’s right forthwith.</text></clause> <clause id="HEF890ABD0FC748EF9E70E07BD2B0FAA8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Additional information</header><text>If the district court determines that additional information is relevant to the movant’s assertion of the right, the Government shall promptly provide all such additional information to the court and movant. The court may, for good cause, allow the Government to provide a substantive summary of such information instead of providing the information itself. Upon the Government’s request, the court shall enter an appropriate protective order governing dissemination and use of any information or substantive summary provided under this clause.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H582FB1839E774E579D2FFC4016292EAC"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Written opinion required for denial of relief</header><text>If the district court denies the relief sought by the movant, the court shall enter a written opinion, which clearly states the reasons for the denial.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDC6FD89007E343E8A25B7CABC44CA4BA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Writ of mandamus</header><text>If the court denies a motion described in subparagraph (A), the movant may petition the court of appeals for a writ of mandamus. The court of appeals may issue the writ on the order of a single judge pursuant to circuit rule or the Federal Rules of Appellate Procedure. The court of appeals shall take up and decide such application forthwith within 72 hours after the petition has been filed, unless the litigants, with notice to the court, have agreed to a longer time period for consideration. In deciding such application, the court of appeals shall determine the merits of the application and, in making such determination, shall apply ordinary standards of appellate review to any procedural or substantive issues. If the court of appeals denies the relief sought, the reasons for the denial shall be clearly stated on the record in a written order or opinion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> 
<clause id="H0E580DE68CAC4C288D61721407F1D5A2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (5) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HFB33426585AF4F68AE0A6F3FE0E03E2D" style="USC"> <paragraph id="H2A68E9CF4D9A449AB7B358DE50BBEDF7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Re-opening proceedings</header> <subparagraph id="H92C692AF21BC4A69BF97DCBBE4ADA208"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In no case shall a failure to afford a right under this chapter provide grounds for a new trial.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB3090F9D41B44A0585A3A979ED60F026"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Victims who received timely notice</header><text>A victim who received timely notice of the relevant proceedings may make a motion or file a separate enforcement action to reopen a plea or sentence only if—</text> <clause id="HA7FD751E4CFE4AB293BF77374DE8909C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the victim has asserted the right to be heard before or during the proceeding at issue and such right was denied;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HABA9D723A3C0435DB86B282791FAACB5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the victim petitions the court of appeals for a writ of mandamus in a timely manner; and</text></clause> <clause id="H5AA51B98D97F4C379A0E83F48AF5A5EB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of a plea, the accused has not pleaded guilty to the highest offense charged, and in the case of a sentencing, the accused has not been sentenced to the statutory maximum.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE60F402225F2467CB6C59D964C38D17F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Victims who did not receive timely notice</header><text>A victim who did not receive timely notice of the relevant proceedings may make a motion or file a separate enforcement action to reopen a plea or sentence, only if—</text> <clause id="H4016818AF01E4B19A719F74F75082F6D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the victim makes such a motion or files such a separate enforcement action in a timely manner; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H97AB537F94BF4362BA0A3E5E23C70401"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a plea, the accused has not pleaded guilty to the highest offense charged, and in the case of a sentencing, the accused has not been sentenced to the statutory maximum.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> <clause id="H5C91F6FF33E1471BB62FB442004429EB"><enum>(v)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (6) as paragraph (9); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD9B7F087284E4FD98EC44665C095BA88"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (5) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HAA8EADC731D240DDA35D438660307575" style="USC"> <paragraph id="H64083F5A25BD440B814087AD196CE3AA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Motion to annul deferred prosecution and nonprosecution agreements</header><text>A crime victim may make a motion requesting that the Government seek to annul a deferred prosecution agreement or nonprosecution agreement by filing a motion with the court in writing asserting that they were not accorded the reasonable right to confer in subsection (a)(5). Upon a finding by the court that the victim’s right under subsection (a)(5) was violated, the Court shall hold a hearing to evaluate whether the agreement should be annulled.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H669560F69C6140AFA6F7C13933102288"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Remedies</header><text>Upon a finding that a victim’s rights under this section have been violated, the court shall order a just and appropriate remedy, which may include reopening a proceeding, to address such violation, except that any such remedy may not violate a defendant’s constitutional rights and shall account for the interests of other victims and the public. An order under this paragraph, or under paragraph (5) or (6), shall not be construed to impair prosecutorial discretion under paragraph (9).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H62217F939E1E4DFAAC036E154BFE4180"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Attorneys’ fees</header><text>A crime victim who prevails against the United States in an action to enforce a right under this section shall be entitled to an award of reasonable attorneys’ fees and expenses, as provided in section 2412 of title 28.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFAB36104E45D4176BB8A4DCA3E0900A1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text> <clause id="H3A67123B92354A2C84C65FA09F327A46"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HC132AA5A2D09431BA888A77919A88543" style="USC"> 
<paragraph id="HA70D1066D94C4755A01CA7FEC62D2134"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Court of appeals</header><text>The term <term>court of appeals</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H33590B54A28C45AC82B258F3CEFDCF78"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the United States court of appeals for—</text> 
<clause id="H8E720CF9A1AB4B6C94D26B22B6DF2065"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the judicial district in which a district court has rendered a decision for which the victim seeks appellate review;</text></clause> <clause id="HF1C7F22A7FEB499A95836C3F800A71DE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if no such decision has been rendered, the judicial district in which the defendant is being prosecuted; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0F4B1702007C450BBF0AB27EC8974DC8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if there is no such prosecution, the judicial district in which the offense was alleged to have been committed; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6DD2F6EDF8ED48AC9EE8CFB31DCE0AE4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for a prosecution or offense committed in the District of Columbia, in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, or the District of Columbia Court of Appeals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> 
<clause id="HDA10798C55E74E3093059A1C8349060B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (2)(A) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HA766719F690442E997F424F840D48443" style="USC"> <subparagraph id="H11A17CE179D74DB99E793CE9AA471D27"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>crime victim</term> means a person directly and proximately harmed as a result of a suspected or alleged Federal or District of Columbia offense, or such an offense with respect to which an individual has been charged or convicted. </text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> 
<clause id="HB2423CF5326B4238888A2879C2DA195B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HAEDF4964BFBF484A887E58FCBB2FCACE" style="USC"> <paragraph id="HF14F3152FFE24A28BB3BDBBE0895241A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Crime victim’s lawful representative</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>crime victim’s lawful representative</term> means an individual or entity designated or appointed to represent a crime victim or take their place in a court proceeding or other legal proceeding—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE8AAD858768A44B6A6C2C8B635205A77"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by the crime victim;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7A217F5A55E040C69703F483E6F319BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by the parent or legal guardian of the crime victim, in the case of a crime victim who is a minor, incapacitated, or deceased; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5DD7E7B6CF964C0FADE09109145074D5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by the court. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2A81B84D8D2B4C2E82C21D7CF816D59F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Timely</header><text>The term <term>timely</term> means sufficient time for the victim to exercise their rights under this section, and in accordance with any applicable rules of procedure.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3EE3DBB716724BDB8A71808CE54EE561"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Suspected or alleged</header><text>The term <term>suspected or alleged</term> means, with respect to an offense, that there is an investigation of an offense, but no charges have been filed.</text></paragraph> <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H447DEF81C42F43119DE7A4060AF48DD6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in subsection (f)—</text> 
<clause id="HDDAB268401234F559D33CDAA20EA1104"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (2)(A) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H9A64565329DD4CEC992EC03216645C4C" style="USC"> <subparagraph id="H7F9D89274C9B499483A0AC2239B26759"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designate an administrative authority in the Department of Justice (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Administrative Authority</quote>) under the independent supervision of the Inspector General of the Department of Justice to receive and investigate complaints relating to the provision or violation of the rights of a crime victim;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> 
<clause id="HBE174237DAAE4E82B71CAE7C7165378C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (2)(B) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H746A1CF6CA574CBF998072603F5CF944" style="USC"> <subparagraph id="H7520459B12F14FABAC1740E53136C440"><enum>(B)</enum><text>require a course of training for employees and offices of the Department of Justice engaged in the detection, investigation, or prosecution of crimes that pertains to the treatment of crime victims, incorporates trauma-informed methods and practices, and otherwise assists such employees and offices in responding more effectively to the needs of crime victims;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> 
<clause id="H73DDDF2094F647BF8E27525E97CCE833"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H9EC48A5B897D4A3BACC32E6C5C795DA3" style="USC"> <paragraph id="HEC99D9E941794EE9BEEC3AFFDB2FA45A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Adjudication of complaints</header> <subparagraph id="H41546D8ED3474203BE578100928AF3A6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Complaints</header><text>A crime victim or a crime victim’s lawful representative may submit to the Administrative Authority a complaint alleging that an attorney for the Government violated the rights of a crime victim under subsection (a), which complaint shall include the following:</text> 
<clause id="H24324561093C4F709A7C741C707EFA3C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The full name, address, telephone number, and electronic mail address of the complainant.</text></clause> <clause id="HEECEF81D169D49EEAE92D993596C703D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The name and title of the individual who violated the rights of the crime victim.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H34EDC403EF3A4414AC1DAC2A913B82DB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The right of the crime victim that was allegedly violated.</text></clause> <clause id="H5A6C12FCD10245869731D75578B5ADA5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The details of the allegation, including the name of the court case and the jurisdiction in which the misconduct occurred, if applicable.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2D1887DCD49D4EB8B72BEFDDE4395180"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Copies of any document that supports the complainant’s allegation.</text></clause> <clause id="HFD6A47B5DFB94C7F9004130B2FCDBC3B"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Any other information relevant to the complaint.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5FDD56FD3E8A48C3BBF22F40950D39C4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Period to submit complaints</header><text>A complaint under subparagraph (A) may be submitted beginning on the date of the violation and ending on the date that is 180 days after a final judgment is entered in the underlying criminal proceeding (including any appeal), except that the Administrative Authority may extend such filing period for good cause.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9C87F4A1294C4C2587A9AA3B11945A51"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Log of complaints</header><text>The Administrative Authority shall maintain a log of each complaint submitted under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE1BE6D0D7036447591C13C982544F0A6" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Decisions</header> 
<clause id="HE5A77DE97C2C4EBCB6B380387617435E" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrative Authority shall issue a decision with respect to the alleged violation within 180 days of receiving a complaint under this section. </text></clause> <clause id="H4FD48C31452840C9A10212B64F53FE04" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Fines and costs</header><text>Upon a finding by the Administrative Authority that the rights of a crime victim were violated, the Administrative Authority shall have the discretion to impose fines or reimburse the victim for costs associated with the violation.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9814044CBC58467986455B46856D3209" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Form and notice</header><text>Upon issuing a finding by the Administrative Authority resolving a complaint under this section, the Administrative Authority shall provide the crime victim with a written copy of the decision, including any imposed sanctions or disciplinary measures, and advise the crime victim of their right to appeal to the Inspector General of the Department of Justice under subparagraph (E).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D82BDEF73ED463EB805519D08A38440"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Appeal to the inspector general</header> <clause id="HE155C9C03DAE4C49BAD3625B781BCF6E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 10 business days after the issuance of an order under subparagraph (D), the complainant or the attorney for the Government may appeal the order to the Inspector General of the Department of Justice.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H224DCE914DC94AEA9E6FE120764E7DB9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Time for review</header><text>Not later than 30 days after an appeal is filed under this subparagraph, the Inspector General shall review the order.</text></clause> <clause id="H57D75F57E5224311AA3A409ACBCE43C5"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Notice to congress</header><text>In the case that the Inspector General does not uphold the decision of the Administrative Authority, the Inspector General shall notify Congress as soon as practicable, but in no case later than 10 business days after completing review.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFEB4D7F3C14D417E9B87963C8E2A5B0C"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Failure to review</header><text>If the Inspector General fails to review an order pursuant to an appeal filed under this subparagraph, the order shall be deemed to have been upheld by the Inspector General on the date that is 45 days after the appeal is filed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCCFE51AE04D24C1B8256024DB7C94D9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HB2438ED65F8643359DCA01B263B5B61F" style="USC"> 
<section id="H407EF8534CA447AB845C1396737D30FB"><enum>3772.</enum><header>General provisions</header> 
<subsection id="HDA0ABCF22AA74616B88F69F1C89A6369"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rule making</header><text>The Attorney General shall issue such rules as may be necessary to carry out this chapter.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5593A6DC5FBA4542A235262119C0E33A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports to congress</header> <paragraph id="HA1768E25F59E44A8BC9D67B8A53C1260"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General, in consultation with the Inspector General of the Department of Justice, shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees on steps taken to improve the efforts of the Department of Justice in according crime victims their rights during the period covered by the report.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCA7039496B104B7CB6AAC92EE3EC8E5A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report contents</header><text>The report shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HBB601FA39D54413791FAAF3A4B528316" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of complaints filed with the Administrative Authority designated under subsection (f);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC62638164A6F4988B4D6661A7D9AD6DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the outcome of those complaints (including any disciplinary action);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H82F96B59B2354DC299588E03AA630F6B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information pertaining to individual Federal districts and Federal prosecutors that are the subject of complaints, including—</text> 
<clause id="H1F84D1B599AE4D2CBFBBE8A85F47D5EA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of complaints filed with the Administrative Authority that were subsequently referred to a State bar association;</text></clause> <clause id="HC76243D31F434A85B0E819CDEBEA76EE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a list of Federal districts in which misconduct was alleged to have occurred and the number of complaints with respect to each such district; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8708A2D6CE9D48FAA7750E37AC48B6AF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a list of attorneys against whom 3 or more complaints were submitted to the Administrative Authority; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB0B905CE6A984AC19B4E66911A5CC721" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a list of all cases in which a court or the Administrative Authority determined that there was a failure to accord a crime victim a right under section 3771, and the best efforts made by officers and employees of the Department of Justice in each such case.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD32E56228A5347C2A59390FCBE9DF53F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual and biannual reports</header><text>The report described in paragraph (1) shall be submitted—</text> <subparagraph id="H0540C8DABD36436BBADB845EE5BBF148"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE185DF1EAF6D41D8A5E5AB9EBA960681"><enum>(B)</enum><text>annually thereafter for a period of 2 years; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF8B152432AB44B17AE67AFD474272A00"><enum>(C)</enum><text>biannually after the end of the period described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFA0D4FBBDFE848309C1EACD459E73DB0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC6B2249068DC4C54A7DB5AD0A8DE1B34"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/237">chapter 237</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HF18317C861904DFCAC32CCD284FA1179" style="USC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">3772. General provisions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

