<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H836D4DAB60BF4903A3913CEDD0BB4EA1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1708 IH: Rebuild America’s Health Care Schools Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1708</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000585">Mr. LaHood</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000470">Mrs. Fischbach</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to adjust allowable direct and indirect costs for nursing and allied health education programs.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H65AE8F9F4FBE4DC484DAA24866F4B8B6" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HC755A16521B7433CB9ADA65E18BA5BD3"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rebuild America’s Health Care Schools Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2B8CDC4C164445E7B200E44CA83A06F9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Adjusting allowable direct and indirect costs for nursing and allied health education programs</header><subsection id="HC23FC9C7718641FB98B74A74972C16B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1861(v)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(v)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB8F12C1FFE74DCC85B030A7E1186F58"><subparagraph id="H3825C6A99C994D7BB773E5208EB837DA" indent="up2"><enum>(X)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA2CAA78F0FC4495DABEE0332DB285E78"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining such reasonable costs for nursing and allied health education furnished by a hospital, beginning with respect to cost reporting periods beginning on or after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Rebuild America’s Health Care Schools Act of 2025</short-title>, the Secretary shall include as reasonable costs all direct and indirect costs incurred by a hospital participating in a nursing and allied health education program licensed by State law or accredited by a national or regional professional organization, including costs that—</text><subclause id="HACE226BB446246C4913ECC8518EF4BB5" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">were directly incurred by the hospital;</text></subclause><subclause id="H5769E044CCDF477DA25C90ADFB4DE6FC" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>were allocated to the hospital by a related entity holding the applicable State license or accreditation by a national or regional professional organization; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H52A93D8EEF9D4E5DA6FAA4E57362E79B" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">were associated with the training of a program participant at the hospital or at a related entity.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H7470F6CBBBCC4F2F98717AF42365BA23" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>For purposes of clause (i), the term <term>related entity</term> means, with respect to a hospital, any entity that is related by common ownership or control to—</text><subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E7AF7C797AD4376A9A95FC84559C181"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the hospital itself; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H9D85FE9A7EE74557ABD5D38B7A351401"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an entity—</text><item commented="no" id="H6847A4400434486099E67200061B790F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in which the hospital (or another entity that is a related entity with respect to the hospital) is the sole corporate member;</text></item><item commented="no" id="H5B7FAE8F744D467C94DB6416B065A29C"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>that is the sole corporate member of the hospital;</text></item><item commented="no" id="HF322A278EA7D4851AFC47A560DD89E52"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>that is part of the same legal entity as the hospital; or </text></item><item commented="no" id="HEA137355B1B5422F8284FAA3451B821E"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>that shares a board with the hospital.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H95229ECD324E4F9181B5C27087E41E0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allowing health systems and hospital-Based schools To provide clinical training and support</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue such rules as are necessary to carry out the amendments made by subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H81E13E31AE074EA9A977D1E6D14E6D41"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibiting recoupment of certain costs under Medicare</header><paragraph id="HCE35233BB3CB4263941A670A18C17D7F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Health and Human Services may not recoup or reduce payments made to a hospital under part A of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395c">42 U.S.C. 1395c et seq.</external-xref>) for costs related to an approved nursing or allied health education program that are included on the Medicare cost report for such hospital if such costs would be allowable after the amendments made by subsection (a) take effect. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H725582E44E5D45C2BC23F19E7E0C23D1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Refund of amounts recouped</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, during the 6-year period ending on the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary recouped or reduced payments made to a hospital under such part A for costs described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall refund to the hospital the amount so recouped or reduced.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

