<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF6D705C028674CBE9E55CD59ECECD4B2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 213 IH: To prohibit the use of Federal financial assistance for a certain high-speed rail development project in the State of California, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 213</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250106">January 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000401">Mr. Kiley of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the use of Federal financial assistance for a certain high-speed rail development project in the State of California, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7593E696A39C49818DE5F53656F28219" style="OLC"><section id="H56F16843D6534697A8591B1B2AB34B57" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibition on provision of Federal financial assistance for certain high-speed rail development project</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No Federal financial assistance may be provided to the State of California for a high-speed rail corridor development project that is the same or substantially similar to the project that is the subject of Cooperative Agreement No. FR–HSR–0118–12–01–01 entered into between the California High-Speed Rail Authority and the Federal Railroad Administration.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

