<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H377CBB9B5FDE4E4B9001ACA5A9004E22" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5527 IH: Stop Censoring Military Families Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5527</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250919">September 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Defense to restore access to curricula, books, and other learning materials at schools operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB41311D19714487F8988C77C02C27B68" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0B142831C197431D89B1A1A6A99C8324" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Censoring Military Families Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HA5EEC596F6B042199186397E4BDC7099"><enum>2.</enum><header>Restoration of access to curricula, books, and other learning materials</header> 
<subsection id="HB3F0AF7D50584D8C8612D182BAAB61D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Restoration and temporary limitation on further restrictions</header> 
<paragraph id="HBBD7651665AF43BA8C78A47FA09E927A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Restoration</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, but not later than 30 days after such date, the Secretary of Defense shall restore access to all curricula, books, and other learning materials that were available at covered educational institutions before January 20, 2025.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H525A1DB2E4054B5F889D4738A84EFD5F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary of Defense may not take any action that would limit the availability of the materials described in paragraph (1) until after the beginning of the 2026–2027 academic year.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFA45B43723234026A87CA83A456C5C1E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text> <paragraph id="H321A3150238D4E62BEBD404647E3FB8B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identification of all curricula, books, or other learning materials identified for potential removal pursuant to instructions issued by the Secretary of Defense after January 20, 2025;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H063F09491B884F88B4122EAB269B370C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detailed account of the processes and instructions used to carry out such actions; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H451D6FCBB16C4852AED81EAB87C73B8B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the case of any such actions affecting schools operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity, an explanation of whether such actions complied with the requirements of section 2164a of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9820F3411AFA4224A5E2F9FE922E34C1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H1C27F892813146F6BD3269BFC0AC041F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>covered educational institution</term> means a school operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H290A6AE8DF6F4FE59D59C00AB0DF0A61" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H629DACA4853C48C5830A5DD4F918659B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFEC4049420634D809E04F77000C81984"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> </section> <section id="H08E3DEF8896745E2A1809ABF1E178F6B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitations on further restrictions to curricula, books, other learning materials, and cultural events</header> <subsection id="H51005ADC5170448A96C6D878192E22A6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 2164 of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB23C6EFD7ED45C6BC22264062FDCACD"> 
<subsection id="HDED37BA18CAE4A348AE9E65B51A60467"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Limitation on restrictions to curricula, learning materials, and cultural events</header> 
<paragraph id="HCFFB89EBD6114F87A1EBB55AAB849499"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense may not issue any directive affecting the curriculum, program of instruction, administration, or personnel of two or more schools operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity until one year after the following requirements have been met:</text> <subparagraph id="HD062A2589637400C8FFAD7E1FD1BCC1F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary has submitted to the School Advisory Committee (or the equivalent advisory body) and Installation Advisory Committee of the schools involved and to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives written notice of the Secretary’s intent to issue such directive together with a description of and justification for the directive.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H97B6E444228F48E7A3CC291460CF8F02"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Each School Advisory Committee (or the equivalent advisory body) that received the notice under subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="HD0132710A7DA4BA1B874B5189C4485D0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a directive pertaining to curricula or programs of instruction, has voted to initiate the CMRC process with regard to the directive; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H87D7E984D78F47D0955187F84ACC444D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to a directive pertaining to administration or personnel—</text> <subclause id="H4B8928F68D414E83AAF57D942C6EF716"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has voted to initiate the CMRC process with regard to the directive; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H797915AB10FE493B984751E9D84CBF44"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in lieu of initiating such process, has conducted a review to determine how the directive will affect the school involved, produced a written response setting forth the results of the review, and approved such response via an official vote.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3600C6BAFD9E4B13BC9547A1E24F1390"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The findings of such process or review (as the case may be) were submitted to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives not later than 90 days after the process or review was initiated, and such Committees have had an opportunity to consider potential legislative responses to the proposed directive.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE03E75D23DE45ADB4386191647998F2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense may not issue any directive affecting the curriculum, program of instruction, administration, or personnel of two or more schools operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity unless—</text> <subparagraph id="HA8EA8E0624C9406B954EFCEFDEA8E30C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary submits to the School Advisory Committee (or the equivalent advisory body) of the schools involved and the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives written notice of the Secretary’s intent to issue such directive together with a description of and justification for the directive; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1BC9BDC0CD2641BF972C7EF90BA4F597" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a period of 90 days has elapsed following the date on which such notice was submitted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE5375AECD524AB0B76BA7CE270D9B32" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) shall apply to directives affecting two or more schools operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity regardless of whether such directives are issued collectively or separately to individual schools.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9ADE7B07B1B646098BBAC2A21E9EDD6F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense may not issue any directive affecting the selection or removal of library resources, textbooks, or other printed or published instructional materials at any individual school operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity unless—</text> <subparagraph id="H338AA025414846C086FDC31D690E3CDD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary submits to the School Advisory Committee (or the equivalent advisory body) of the school involved written notice of the Secretary’s intent to issue such directive together with a description of and justification for the directive; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H606796D081204557BD96D5339FAFDFA7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a period of 30 days has elapsed following the date on which such notice was submitted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA49ADDCB9C494B3B9C88605A9D56F203"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense may not—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB6ECE5BD0F0949A68105D22314C2BA10"><enum>(A)</enum><text>limit the authority of an individual school to plan or hold commemorative events or cultural events that have been duly approved by the principal, faculty, staff, or School Advisory Committee (or the equivalent) of the school involved; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H83752A51890443F7A715D2B90C06B249"><enum>(B)</enum><text>withhold funding or take other action against a school solely because such school plans or holds an event described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H058BBECE15E74FD7B6342DAF4BDF1842"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>CMRC process</term> means the procedures described in Department of Defense Education Activity Administrative Instruction 2992.01 relating to ‘Information Center and Classroom Supplemental Materials Selection Policy and Challenge Procedures’, dated February 12, 2010.</text></paragraph> </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H5514BD7AB131469EB63D542D1282E258"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date and applicability</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply beginning with the 2026–2027 academic year for schools operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD6818B74B6D14E8DA085E5D4E8D0826A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Nullification of certain Executive Orders</header> 
<subsection id="H6CF3D87FD2C74CE9B3663124C2EC6036">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Executive orders specified in subsection (b) shall have no force or effect with respect to the Department of Defense and no Federal funds may be used to implement or enforce such Executive orders, or any substantially similar directives, within the Department of Defense.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H2C90F62E146144E4BD53E1346CF1A23D">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Executive orders specified</header>
 <text>The Executive orders specified in this subsection are the following:</text> <paragraph id="H9523B642FD76494BAA02DB8436C2AB1E"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 14190 (90 Fed. Reg. 8853; relating to ending radical indoctrination in K–12 schooling).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H04D6E51FDAC540A7B9280B1BA95F0AA7">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Executive Order 14280 (90 Fed. Reg. 17533; relating to reinstating commonsense school discipline policies).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H4031422CC7DD410FABFACB97E4E61188">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>Executive Order 14281 (90 Fed. Reg 17537; relating to restoring equality of opportunity and meritocracy).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H118E2FE780F84CFA9DAA3B5AB4C93A15">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>Executive Order 14185 (90 Fed. Reg. 8763; relating to restoring America’s fighting force).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HA47D28F3EA0B45E490E40C03A1DA2083">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>Executive Order 14183 (90 Fed. Reg. 8757; relating to prioritizing military excellence and readiness).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HC7DEB2FE235E4AA2A96D8DA24912DF08">
                    <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>Executive Order 14168 (90 Fed. Reg. 8615; relating to defending women from gender ideology extremism and restoring biological truth to the Federal Government).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H1F955CE4E0014E03BD0C4E23811055DD">
                    <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>Executive Order 14201 (90 Fed. Reg 9279; relating to keeping men out of women’s sports).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection></section> 
<section id="H5B313A7C25914D7B958E18BB881F997A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Study and report on potential establishment of independent body to implement curricula for DODEA schools</header> 
<subsection id="H94B5598C2980436A83751F39C4A5A25D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study to determine the feasability and advisability of establishing an independent body to design and implement educational curricula for schools operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity. The study shall address—</text> <paragraph id="HFCD98B288D6040AE8C0AF816802DD527"><enum>(1)</enum><text>how such an independent body could be established and structured;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE4DDE5D6A9264904B82B0AFB2A46B65F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>who should be appointed to such a body;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB0763000F7BB407DB2DA06A29EEDE77A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>how such body could maintain independence to ensure it is insulated from political influence and changing priorities of the Executive Branch; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA22AE26033D546278106564DD9013567"><enum>(4)</enum><text>such other factors as the Comptroller General determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDCDEADEAE1924EF48C3AC293C558BC52"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the results of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H59BB1E3D75A94BB1B9167A1B9225782E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H4670299D35E74A2CABD1A8A8125C522A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7931E957C1DD46699A32936F3AD309B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

