<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H57EAA104F3EB46E0AC29D1041393B9EB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 926 IH: Fort Pillow National Battlefield Park Study Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 926</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250204">February 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To conduct a special resource study of Fort Pillow Historic State Park in Henning, Tennessee, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1A0BBB71897A4A8FA826B8DF7D12AC2C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA6BCB3D76A8D470CA3070F1526AF35AC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>Fort Pillow National Battlefield Park Study Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBDCD3D2379894F9095DBD309242FDA7C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="HCE9800368EB444C7899DAF6E0E1AEA25"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Fort Pillow was originally built by Confederate troops in 1861 and named after General Gideon J. Pillow of Maury County, Tennessee.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H92E5C938864D4EFE8AC2557E119155A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The battle of Fort Pillow was fought on April 12, 1864, at Fort Pillow in Henning, Tennessee, during the American Civil War.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF7A28548E02E44A2A25A7A7CAD4C9C2E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At Fort Pillow, Tennessee, Confederate forces never defeated the Union Navy. Instead, they perpetrated a heinous massacre after violating a flag of truce by advantageously repositioning rebel troops and by looting government buildings and private storefronts surrounding the fort.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD58AB0DC5C064657A220561DA057E948"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the 1864 Report <quote>Fort Pillow Massacre</quote> from the United States Congress Joint Committee on the Conduct of the War, <quote>The officers and men seem to vie with each other in the devilish work; men, women and even children, wherever found, were deliberately shot down, beaten and hacked with sabers. …</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H920D5493E5ED4888BCD492DC610520FF"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Union garrison consisted of 19 officers and 538 troops of whom 262 were United States Colored Troops (U.S.C.T.).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H134B112B30064719B500D9FB502093DA"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Per the report, <quote>Of the men, from three hundred to four hundred are known to have been killed at Fort Pillow, of whom at least three hundred were murdered in cold blood after the fort was in possession of the rebels and our men had thrown down their arms and ceased to offer resistance.</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2B0BEF9F8E58448C9018AC9A2C572BA7"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The massacre at Fort Pillow demonstrated to all U.S.C.T. that surrender was not an option. The massacre at Fort Pillow became a rallying cry and motivation for the 209,147 U.S.C.T.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D09A99A80D447778DA99182A13D46F0"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 209,147 U.S.C.T. fundamentally contributed to the Union’s defeat of the Confederacy.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFDFE71D2D74145799F2708DFB49CDB44"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In 1971, Fort Pillow became a State park.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2835559550004BB7ADDA4E9571DCD359"><enum>(10)</enum><text>In 1973, Fort Pillow was added to the National Register of Historic Places.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDC4C4F38A44B424DAB80140BFF08937D"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The following year, in 1974, Fort Pillow was designated as a National Historic Landmark.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H56EB475662CC4110A7F8368490304C14"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Fort Pillow Historic State Park consists of 1,642 acres.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H51D6D492234B4BE686FA9E5E3C71A325"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Park contains several attraction areas such as a Civil War museum, hiking trail, camping ground, and picnic area.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA3AE1134EDD14933A0C6C951AA1E36DB"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This site deserves to become a National Battlefield Park due to its profound effect on U.S.C.T. and all Union forces in their fight to preserve the United States of America.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H6DE594B99D2943698F5179D9BABBB030"><enum>3.</enum><header>Fort Pillow Special Resource Study</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall conduct a special resource study of Fort Pillow Historic State Park in Henning, Tennessee. Fort Pillow is a State park that features the American Civil War history and the Massacre at Fort Pillow. The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="HE8B58526F0734745B4D69C7AB285A4C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluate the site's national significance; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1161443FBEB54F6FA16453C6A0F39AB2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determine the suitability and feasibility of designating it as a unit of the National Historic Park System.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

