<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0DB9B52BD05A4C5AB051F54D145A1178" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1245 IH: Disaster Survivors Fairness Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1245</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250212">February 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Small Business</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve individual assistance provided by the Federal Emergency Management Agency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEEB04CFDFE474D488F109FD8426C6BE9" style="OLC"><section id="HA6D059EE296A46B3BC9CD60D91D5E13D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H5E0D0BA4118B4985A6E6629DC0E8D9DE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Disaster Survivors Fairness Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></subsection><subsection id="H819D66C7BF64462C9999D1A6FC3441B3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="HA6D059EE296A46B3BC9CD60D91D5E13D" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB3E207245CF74F7F869C2C3A297194A3" level="section">Sec. 2. Information sharing for federal agencies.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HAD2C788A30024388A181FAB9665BB52A" level="section">Sec. 3. Universal application for individual assistance.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H217D3EFF43A94C75B37C57126C656EC8" level="section">Sec. 4. Repair and rebuilding.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H3CB9D4B6EC14445BB676AF86E36F4AE2" level="section">Sec. 5. Direct assistance.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7A0617B19F6B44D49E701C6AFE856EBE" level="section">Sec. 6. State-managed housing pilot authority.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2F858FE3A5894A3FB621C51C918CE4AE" level="section">Sec. 7. Management costs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HCAA97281354743CE8538AD3B6AF0F7B5" level="section">Sec. 8. Funding for online guides for post-disaster assistance.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H69CDBD0C1DDD4BAEBBB4739A5172641C" level="section">Sec. 9. Individual assistance dashboard.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD6D391E4FA064A038327DBE28AA2A3C4" level="section">Sec. 10. FEMA reports.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H85A8ED4FFAF3440E85D18F89E5CB6CE4" level="section">Sec. 11. Sheltering of emergency response personnel.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H13A695D16AF546A1A105F135B3885D28" level="section">Sec. 12. Improved rental assistance.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB19132B304DC4C44970140BE08300363" level="section">Sec. 13. GAO report on preliminary damage assessments.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H76CFC125118B42A09833C70B45F65195" level="section">Sec. 14. Applicability.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HFA21CDD363394600B30EF87918FBED6B" level="section">Sec. 15. GAO report to Congress on challenges under public assistance alternative procedures.</toc-entry></toc></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA61EBB4ED0AF43A0A87B6FB4A629B3C0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Except as otherwise provided, the terms used in this Act have the meanings given such terms in section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="HB3E207245CF74F7F869C2C3A297194A3" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Information sharing for federal agencies</header><subsection id="HDD1DB23C682B42429BB4EB3B77136220"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of unified disaster application system</header><paragraph id="HB59979FE8FA348CD94BBD709B3123E60"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall establish and maintain a web-based interagency electronic information sharing system, to be known as the <quote>unified disaster application system</quote>, to—</text><subparagraph id="HE98280D4CB24493AB5986B538278FD0A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facilitate the administration of the universal application for direct Federal disaster assistance established under section 3;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC82D74AE926044E5A83E36E4E9DA2712"><enum>(B)</enum><text>carry out the purposes of disaster assistance programs swiftly, efficiently, and in accordance with applicable laws, regulations, and the privacy and data protections provided under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD30017343724D7F91E766C57D5160D3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>support the detection, prevention, and investigation of waste, fraud, abuse, or discrimination in the administration of disaster assistance programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD52FE328AA9347B28A203ED83B06B53D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorities of administrator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing and maintaining the unified disaster application system under this subsection, the Administrator may collect and maintain disaster assistance information received from a disaster assistance agency, a block grant recipient, or an applicant for a disaster assistance program and share such information with any other disaster assistance agency or block grant recipient using such system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66E177A8CF354A8A9BD05C65C9E2A25D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall ensure that the unified disaster application system established and maintained under this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="H02D53ECEB89E4F61B0D44F5C0CB06BBA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>allows an applicant to receive status updates on an application for disaster assistance programs submitted though such system; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8358818F67884B16BC00B0BA5F677AD6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>allows for applicants to update disaster assistance information throughout the recovery journeys of such applicants in accordance with established application timeframes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BDDFF8CD2FE4405A8F22FEB051DEC71"><enum>(C)</enum><text>allows for the distribution to applicants of information about additional recovery resources that may be available in a disaster stricken area; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41228ED7984D4EBBA8AF4C4E7A6C2944" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provides an applicant with information and documentation relating to an application for a disaster assistance program submitted by such applicant; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CCE10557EE84DBCA1CDE278C6AE722F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>contains any other capabilities determined necessary by the head of a disaster assistance agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6DB38C428B084DB49DEAC6F9C93F7412"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Data security</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may facilitate the collection of disaster assistance information into the unified disaster application system established under subsection (a) only after the following requirements have been met:</text><paragraph id="HE8098784D26B4084AB487E4E38015765"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator certifies that the unified disaster application system substantially complies with the data security standards and best practices established pursuant to subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, and any other applicable Federal information security policy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52317C1CC1334556A120B68300919675"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security publishes a privacy impact assessment for the unified disaster application system, in accordance with section 208(b)(1)(B) of the E-Government Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/44/3501">44 U.S.C. 3501</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75055671B3AA4EF6A5FD6FF6443F0EF8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Administrator, after consulting with disaster assistance agencies, publishes standard rules of behavior for disaster assistance agencies, block grant recipients, and personnel granted access to disaster assistance information to protect such information from improper disclosure.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCB37DCB6B7B442049BDCDE291C790FF0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Collection and sharing of additional records and information</header><paragraph id="HB742FA5ED1184614B8EBC7EA15256637"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may authorize the additional collection, maintenance, sharing, and use of disaster assistance information by publishing a notice on the unified disaster application system established under subsection (a) that includes a detailed description of—</text><subparagraph id="H890DA2BF898B4757BD5DE1912DF0563E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the specific amendments to the collection, maintenance, and sharing of disaster assistance information authorized;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B20389D0C06436AB22C606DC8E92C25"><enum>(B)</enum><text>why each such amendment to how disaster assistance information is collected, maintained, or shared is necessary to carry out the purposes of a disaster assistance program and consistent with the fair information practice principles; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5443574AACDF4D6391DBC0A5D804DEC5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the disaster assistance agencies and block grant recipients that will be granted access to the additional information to carry out the purposes of any disaster assistance program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD27690ACD9BF4CB2A8A546716C42B8A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice and publication requirements</header><text>The publication of a notice under paragraph (1) of a revision to the unified disaster application system of records prior to any new collection, or uses, of Privacy Act categories of records, to carry out the purposes of a disaster assistance program with regard to a disaster declared by the President under section 401 or 501 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>; 5191), shall be deemed to satisfy the notice and publication requirements of section 552a(e)(4) of title 5, United States Code, for the entire period of performance for any assistance provided under a disaster assistance program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05FBB5787A694FAC891F6B949A976DF3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Waiver of information collection requirements</header><subparagraph id="HD24D21ADD09E4856A8BC9FEC218B468C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the declaration of a major disaster or emergency pursuant to sections 401 or 501 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>; 5191) by the President, the Administrator may waive the requirements of subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, with respect to voluntary collection of information for the entire period of performance for any assistance provided under a disaster assistance program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9137160D6B9E4961A46BD6F96DE8AF2B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Transparency</header><text>Upon exercising the waiver authority under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall—</text><clause id="HAE54084AD2584A59AFE34BF89870B13A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>promptly post on a website of the Federal Emergency Management Agency a brief justification for such waiver, the anticipated period of time such waiver will be in effect, and the disaster assistance offices within the Federal Emergency Management Agency to which such waiver shall apply; and</text></clause><clause id="HFBBE130A48C44122955398F74B0C574F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>update the information relating to such waiver, as applicable.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H174FC890D24846239C016CF4EEA57B43"><enum>(4)</enum><header>GAO review of waiver of information collection requirements</header><subparagraph id="H394EA587C15B4F369128FABEC853B758"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall issue a report describing the benefits and potential risks associated with authorizing the waiver of the information collection requirements described in paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFC48D423F37408AA1EABB57BFC89BFB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required under subparagraph (A) shall include an assessment of the extent to which a waiver described in paragraph (3) would—</text><clause id="HCBE504317EBD449489FBEC8BB2D098C0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>affect the paperwork burden for individuals, small businesses, State, local and tribal governments, and other persons;</text></clause><clause id="H6973FE575E40402287B8C3EBE12322A0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>affect the consistent application of Federal laws relating to—</text><subclause id="H1C0E27F3653A426E98B6297B14563F2B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>privacy and confidentiality;</text></subclause><subclause id="HE4EADC8F50BE4C119DC95A78F950C4BC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>security of information; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H9AAA57FA9AAC4738907A425254F1D090"><enum>(III)</enum><text>access to information; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H15E728A124D448A98FAFA87E8AAB9288"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>encourage or deter a State or other entity from participating in the voluntary collection of information for the duration of a major disaster or emergency.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B647EFCC3E7440FBF27D361892531CB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use by other Federal agencies</header><paragraph id="H1BB875B6C05E43B8835CA22A88F6AF53"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may permit a Federal agency other than a disaster assistance agency listed in subparagraphs (A) through (D) of subsection (f)(3) to use the unified disaster application system established under subsection (a) for the purpose of facilitating disaster-related assistance if such agency enters into an agreement containing the terms described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF8F3C1349E24CEF99874274010DD4F2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency agreement</header><text>An agreement entered into under paragraph (1) shall contain the following terms:</text><subparagraph id="H0DF7F1784BA04191901FDB98B90849AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Federal agency shall—</text><clause id="HD435C56A3A884999A6D14029769CE1AF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>collect, share, maintain, and use disaster assistance information in compliance with this section and any policies of the Federal Emergency Management Agency and any information protection and use policies of such Federal agency; and</text></clause><clause id="HAC1E13F2F1A44F31BA9705C94400088F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>train any personnel granted access to disaster assistance information on the rules of behavior established by the Administrator under subsection (b)(3).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CDB0F45F4AD4B34853133F6EABD5D03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the event of any unauthorized disclosure of disaster assistance information, the Federal agency shall—</text><clause id="H589AA4C7E6D74931BCB10B89A4AE63F2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>notify the Administrator within 24 hours of discovering any such unauthorized disclosure;</text></clause><clause id="H121CE0D5C51A413792C380D2F1BC5471"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>cooperate fully with the Administrator in the investigation and remediation of any such disclosure;</text></clause><clause id="H53F86F9681FD44429D38ED9DE9E7A750"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>cooperate fully in the prosecution of a person responsible for such disclosure; and</text></clause><clause id="HC3CCF8E590E34ACEB1C7D3C373248719"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>assume the responsibility for any compensation, civil liability, or other remediation measures, whether awarded by a judgment of a court or agreed as a compromise of any potential claims by or on behalf of an applicant, including by obtaining credit monitoring and remediation services, for an improper disclosure that is—</text><subclause id="H0528E646D6A44308B93FB9DAB9BEF5C3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>caused, directly or indirectly, by the acts or omissions of officers, employees, and contractors of the agency; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H9708F1C16CD34D8588BE7FE56503A39C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>from any electronic system of records that is created or maintained by the agency pursuant to section 552a(e) of title 5, United States Code.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A6E32D4A5654B9B86B00EB6998D89B5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publication of agency agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall publish an agency agreement entered into under this subsection on the same website as the unified disaster application system established under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H61A934BCE2D14C8192F69E5B5A9AE66B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>The sharing and use of disaster assistance information that is subject to the requirements of section 552a of title 5, United States Code, by disaster assistance agencies and block grant recipients—</text><paragraph id="H3A8C59670E4B405DBD3CF46911BB530A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall not be—</text><subparagraph id="HBC8AE7DD1D144CDF83345B8A5FDC3497"><enum>(A)</enum><text>construed as a matching program for purposes of section 552a(a)(8) of such title; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF42F3C76FD5E467EBFBA65E80CC6D2B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to the remaining computer matching provisions of section 552a of such title; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1A461512779403E94F026DE6BE896DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be in addition to any other law providing for the sharing or use of such information.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H92E60A73CE98427F81D3E25CE8368658"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H23F65151FAEC42F49258B1AF7A2EA045"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicant</header><text>The term <quote>applicant</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H0560315403D24BD5B78E60F9CCD63573"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a person who applies for disaster assistance from a disaster assistance program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09C5A631912F4B0A8668D071C71B376A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a person on whose behalf a person described in subparagraph (A) has applied for disaster assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB594176143A945C1986D85884AC56B3C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Block grant recipient</header><text>The term <quote>block grant recipient</quote> means a State, local government, or Indian Tribe that receives assistance through the disaster assistance program described in paragraph (5)(B)(i).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA12862CD9AD48E3AD36DFADD7D1BE4D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disaster assistance agency</header><text>The term <quote>disaster assistance agency</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H9304DEA630AC4EBEAEF0ECECEE26498B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal Emergency Management Agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE35822786987422C8831FB2B0937E875"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of Housing and Urban Development;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73E5BA3169374037BF9B884425567DB8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Small Business Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E2C268F1EFA4C32A9070F7CA304A24D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Department of Agriculture; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H499192EECEC94A1CB8A80333A5F05426" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other Federal agency that the Administrator permits to use the unified disaster application system under subsection (d).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2518AA9F217D42B69CF7876E6338ADAC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Disaster assistance information</header><text>The term <quote>disaster assistance information</quote> includes any personal, demographic, biographical, geographical, financial information, or other information that a disaster assistance agency or block grant recipient is authorized to collect, maintain, share, or use to process an application for disaster assistance or otherwise carry out a disaster assistance program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5130FA9AFDB949119987C87F03C1D1EB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Disaster assistance program</header><text>The term <quote>disaster assistance program</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H57B844C5FF74434EABFD9AF2E26AA344"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any program that provides assistance to individuals and households under title IV or title V of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AADC55318064F939C0C1D07B03CC30C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other assistance program carried out by a disaster assistance agency that provides assistance to an individual, household, or organization related to a major disaster or emergency declared under sections 401 or 501 of such Act, including—</text><clause id="HD876AF8AA45C49F0B20C5D46F85BD7F8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>assistance for activities related to disaster relief, long-term recovery, restoration of infrastructure and housing, economic revitalization, and mitigation that are authorized under title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5301">42 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="H204768E37AEE4DFA81B6EE2C5A364077"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any loan that is authorized under section 7(b) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(b)</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause id="H4A157720181C4C88B63572B81B2566EC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the distribution of food benefit allotments as authorized under section 412 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5179">42 U.S.C. 5179</external-xref>) and section 5(h) of the Food Stamp Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2014">7 U.S.C. 2014(h)</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAD2C788A30024388A181FAB9665BB52A" section-type="subsequent-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>3.</enum><header>Universal application for individual assistance</header><subsection id="HE6D1F7195ED54FB896E5FA0D40DD2E5B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Universal application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall develop and establish a universal application for direct Federal disaster assistance for individuals in areas impacted by emergencies or disasters.</text></subsection><subsection id="H60678AE3B3B24EA7A81493BEAA60238F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation and support</header><paragraph id="H3F18A2015F214CBA9C574411615466BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Administrator shall consult with the following:</text><subparagraph id="H49810FE836464E84B75A53EA2FEE0E1E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB103225C48D4395A1F032043AE08406"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Small Business Administration.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BCF17F78445400487BB3E8FEBE77BD5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA80A87C07080407EBCC11B7450E7BA24"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Secretary of Agriculture.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H49A635E74BA54D0EBD0BB4D804A5A564"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Support</header><text>The entities described in paragraph (1) shall provide prompt support to the Administrator.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H24E256E17F13447D9ADD5097A13B3FAD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Survey</header><text>The application established under subsection (a) shall include a voluntary survey to collect the demographic data of an applicant.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3BD6A94E7D5D40AA884F65E40A6B7A8E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>GAO assessment on identity theft and disaster fraud in disaster assistance programs</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text><paragraph id="H91447C5F7704449B8917B15F809F5240"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct an assessment of improper and potentially fraudulent Federal disaster assistance for individuals made to survivors of major disasters declared in 2020 and 2021, including through identity theft; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8CE94413D09F4FCF813949E720AF5D71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report that describes—</text><subparagraph id="HF0BA9C77FC7D447081EB4975BAFC2F28"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the prevalence of improper and potentially fraudulent Federal disaster assistance for individuals made to registrants who used invalid information to apply for disaster assistance, including through identity theft;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA7FDED4D19045B1857D3EEE74E45CE0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of disaster survivors whose claims for Federal disaster assistance for individuals were denied due to another individual filing a fraudulent application using their personal identifying information;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B67D5EC46EC498EB059226501283F5D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the adequacy of existing fraud prevention protocols in place on the Federal Emergency Management Agency’s online application for Federal disaster assistance for individuals; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A4CE9C85FB040F0AFE15061648F8590"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for improving the identity verification protocols in place for Federal disaster assistance for individuals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H217D3EFF43A94C75B37C57126C656EC8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Repair and rebuilding</header><subsection id="H6F9766F611DE4109BD9B4F1E5A9D5234"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 408(b)(1) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HCD1FEFE58ED946FA936F9CD7C20BD6CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>rendered uninhabitable</quote> and inserting <quote>damaged by a major disaster</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF3474074BD34A8082881737D906EF6B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>uninhabitable, as a result of damage caused by a major disaster</quote> and inserting <quote>damaged by a major disaster</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H79214452F80D415CB255616364E9AACF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Hazard mitigation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 408 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HCBADA17F37E6450DB58C4C0CA7356608"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c) by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8B40C0B84FE64E6686ABDFE0203B8D43" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HC41C8570944A47ED93EAA156062F4B7E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Hazard mitigation</header><subparagraph id="HC71E935E121043ABB1D378B8A4364F16"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may provide financial assistance to individuals and households whose primary residence, utilities, or residential infrastructure are damaged by a major disaster, for cost-effective hazard mitigation measures that reduce threats to life and property, or future damage to such residence, utilities, or infrastructure in future disasters.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H662F74E0F28A4039AB930833F239898C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Relationship to other assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A recipient of assistance provided under this paragraph shall not be required to show that the assistance can be met through other means, except insurance proceeds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H3EB543F34D0A44F3840357E7B22E78F9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (h)—</text><subparagraph id="HF30CEE80F327482FA93D3EAD19D1002C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) by inserting <quote>, financial assistance for hazard mitigation under subsection (c)(5)(A),</quote> after <quote>subsection (c)(1)(A)(i)</quote>; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B6A76B02E244473BA8729A204C6AFBE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3) by striking <quote>paragraphs (1) and (2)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (1), (2), and (3)</quote>; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8070EBAEFD3F42879C81D414AB96EF1C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE12A3C4DB4204E8486267CDCBA50B0ED" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H3E231B1A1B604301976EE5A6FAEEA25D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Hazard mitigation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The maximum financial assistance any individual or household may receive under subsection (c)(5) shall be equivalent to the amount set forth in paragraph (1) with respect to a single major disaster. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3CB9D4B6EC14445BB676AF86E36F4AE2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Direct assistance</header><subsection id="H91FBDF37CEFA4AD898415F734F9DE6AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 408(c) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174(c)</external-xref>) is further amended by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8ADF80C1053D47F4B1A0068DDBA3EB97" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HB0540B45F2C94419938406C6976352AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Repairs</header><subparagraph id="HB84BFF70F37A4BE8A85D473D4AA3DEC0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Financial assistance for repairs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may provide financial assistance for the repair of owner-occupied private residences, utilities, and residential infrastructure (such as a private access route) damaged by a major disaster, or with respect to individuals with disabilities, rendered inaccessible by a major disaster.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A7DC1EB70DF48F2A97376666D488795"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Direct assistance for repairs</header><clause id="HCEF5523A07D248D1A8DBFAA11FA9563B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may provide direct assistance to individuals and households who are unable to make use of financial assistance under subparagraph (A) and when there is a lack of available resources, for—</text><subclause id="HB5AAAC34EFE1468BA8F161FF58AF55E3"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the repair of owner-occupied private residences, utilities, and residential infrastructure (such as a private access route) damaged by a major disaster, or with respect to individuals with disabilities, rendered inaccessible by a disaster; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HAB72E7D9B1464CCEAB4D4D41C088EC56"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">eligible hazard mitigation measures that reduce the likelihood and future damage to such residences, utilities, and infrastructure.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H7B1A983F93324CC495020403A0CED470"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A recipient of assistance under this subparagraph shall not be eligible for assistance under paragraph (1), unless otherwise determined by the Administrator.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AADC355B21B4794B53923BCB9551686"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Relationship to other assistance</header><text>A recipient of assistance provided under this paragraph shall not be required to show that the assistance can be met through other means, except insurance proceeds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H2C3FF01106594B56B58C67D8D49E08B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State- or indian tribal government-Administered assistance and other needs assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 408(f) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HA3C5B3550DCF4C5FADCFA892352E1CF8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsections (c)(1)(B), (c)(4), and (e)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>paragraphs (1)(B), (2)(B), and (4) of subsection (c) and subsection (e)</quote>; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF70B749224240D799803B6603E92283"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(A) by striking <quote>subsection (c)(1)(B), (c)(4), or (e)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (1)(B), (2)(B), or (4) of subsection (c) or subsection (e)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7A0617B19F6B44D49E701C6AFE856EBE" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>State-managed housing pilot authority</header><subsection id="HBE0E1254DE5C4CBA9950B7EEC17B286E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 408 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB137FC4FC6F044CC9F01913146FB44EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (f)(3)—</text><subparagraph id="HF098BC39D95748888903F1A7A2DDCA9B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="HFD6DDBF3514A48CBAF36880FCAFCCAD9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A State</quote> and inserting the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA47278B88C4B41BEA4C5D1E9C5254A94" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="H19DD99EBE80941B6A2BFB61C4DB28A16"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="H03A1174E3A514CD1B57F193CF26DCDEE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H887E9A5D7C584C49B48E8B7804647EED" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="H7838717E90D34CEF9FC070FA69291819"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Transparency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall make public the criteria used to evaluate applications under clause (i) and determine if a State or Indian tribal government meets the criteria described in subparagraph (B) to administer grants described in paragraph (1)(A). </text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B6C21DE4F844B6CA04B1B9D1DF58ABC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)(ii)—</text><clause id="H1082177990594FE28688E7F99E662E14"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subclause (I) by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></clause><clause id="H44B07BAFACF145539308E7EA896F0BF5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subclause (II) by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></clause><clause id="HC247C4BF87EA4C33BA1F7AF7658CC26C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9559CF21DC4449BDA1CAE37D43D91CE2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subclause id="H814EF8F7D3C24C829F2C42AD0822090A"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">outline the approach of the State to help disaster survivors create a permanent housing plan; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H17DED6A5DBDA4A6DB89A86D5403593E2"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>outline the approach of the State to provide individual disaster survivors some choice of communities and properties, as practicable.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H635CB50F8B274591AB04D2586E04A400"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (F);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57D3D47169BF4BA4BAACB8657A4DA46C"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subparagraphs (G), (H), (I), and (J) as subparagraphs (F), (G), (H), and (I), respectively; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86BB51E685C94510886A413C08866A73"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I), as so redesignated—</text><clause id="HD495DC2829354A23933061CF3710F238"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (ii) by striking <quote>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the</quote> and inserting <quote>The</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H7341004DDB5F4B30BB3F67E5C2ECD914"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (iii) by striking <quote>2 years</quote> and inserting <quote>10 years</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F7181171F034D90B4391671CDCED217"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (g)—</text><subparagraph id="H000C850EF8C6495CB3D972233DA7D7B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) by striking <quote>paragraph (2)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (2) and (3)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BE738C4506E4D50A15AA64A4565C7AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H08CE3CC2ED8A4D3BA8235CF45E5C6342" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HB4136FA9764F4CC0967E18AD7F98FD60"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disaster assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of assistance provided under subsections (c)(1)(B), (c)(2)(B), and (c)(4), the Federal share shall be not less than 75 percent. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H288DECFBF5004F64B9F41D386F0C4201"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the expiration of the authority to carry out section 408(f) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174(f)</external-xref>) as a pilot program, the Comptroller General of the United States shall issue a report on the effectiveness, successes, and challenges of any pilot program carried out pursuant to such section and make recommendations on how to improve the provision of assistance under such section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H2F858FE3A5894A3FB621C51C918CE4AE" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header>Management costs</header><subsection id="H730E4A29416C49C799320A8CE8049663"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 324(b)(2) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5165b">42 U.S.C. 5165b(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HABF60217C5BC472DB5BBB058BF4E0819" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HD4AD50D743A84A1B80B063CBC59F79DD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Individual assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grantee under section 408(f) may be reimbursed not more than 12 percent of the total award amount under each such section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A140EFAA7F5418FAE92A5EC70010A08"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Crisis counseling assistance, training, and case management services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grantee and subgrantee, cumulatively, may be reimbursed not more than 15 percent of the total amount of the grant award under either section 416 or 426. </text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HDA2ADA56EBE04872B139666670E5E5F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 408(f)(1) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174</external-xref>), as amended by section 5(b) of this Act, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB5BC7E4D8490429D82C151EA1BC77D9E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(A) <header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">Grant to state.—</header-in-text></quote> and all that follows through <quote>subsection (g),</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to subsection (g),</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BDDF71E79084064945FE76C8BAB635A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCAA97281354743CE8538AD3B6AF0F7B5"><enum>8.</enum><header>Funding for online guides for post-disaster assistance</header><subsection id="H7340A3AB1B2C4D9589F8E1F5B0FDDA60"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Use of services of other agencies</header><text>Section 201(a) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5131">42 U.S.C. 5131(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE07336DE0F8247C796C7F34E59A93A57"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FACD698A85D4478B05E1527BADD2ADB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16112F538E964FC8B2D179C2C0E9AB2D"><paragraph id="H289EFF800EF54A6BA60D9F054F27D862"><enum>(8)</enum><text>post-disaster assistance.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H14B3A061E1684DCDA8C7E9BB6A2D674F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants for online guides for assistance</header><text>Section 201 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5131">42 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFE507D7CFE324224B49E4CEEC54DEE99"><subsection id="HB8D41697E20748CF99C5A2047F1F3439"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Funding for online guides for assistance</header><paragraph id="H418B33AA48DD45F1918E3C1E5A0105EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency may provide funding to a State agency established under subsection (c) to establish, update, or operate a website to provide information relating to post-disaster recovery funding and resources to a community or an individual impacted by a major disaster or emergency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63E644FC99E04B27B30764A734C436C7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management</header><text>A website created under this subsection shall be—</text><subparagraph id="H50CA43E42B4644B1890BAFAEA239C03C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>managed by the State agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H617ABA54DAFD4CA7A62038CE6611C842"><enum>(B)</enum><text>suitable for the residents of the State of the State agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9C1477F5959463A8E765AE12013D702"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Content</header><text>The Administrator may provide funding to a State agency under this subsection to establish a website that contains only 1 or more of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H2768CD1D0A0B4D8C81A1984613C2ADB8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A list of Federal, State, and local sources of post-disaster recovery funding or assistance that may be available to a community after a major disaster or emergency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H517097B2D9794C2E9E48A2312615FFB8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A list of Federal, State, and local sources of post-disaster recovery funding or assistance that may be available to an individual impacted by a major disaster or emergency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H862A20E8F7EA460F9D494B1008C3B006"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A technical guide that lists and explains the costs and benefits of alternatives available to a community to mitigate the impacts of a major disaster or emergency and prepare for sequential hazards such as flooding after a wildfire.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4173EAEBBE0343AFAB4303BF11984B1B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cooperation</header><text>A State agency that receives funding under this subsection shall cooperate with the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, and the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency in developing a website under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B4C259C8F12425E9CD6CD3BF5ED1280"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>A State agency that receives funding to establish a website under this subsection shall update the website not less than once every 6 months.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H69CDBD0C1DDD4BAEBBB4739A5172641C"><enum>9.</enum><header>Individual assistance dashboard</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title IV of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD0E7502C191F41F1ACE03DA67DBD657F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HEF13503CA128426CBA35D95B294DD091"><enum>431.</enum><header>Individual assistance dashboard</header><subsection id="HBBB41CEA5E0547AFA745712E9F232503" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after a declaration by the President that a major disaster exists under section 401, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall publish on a website of the Agency an interactive web tool displaying the following information with respect to such disaster:</text><paragraph id="H138AAB244EDC44D9AAA2355A18EF7EEF" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of applications for assistance under section 408, including a description of the number of applications for assistance related to housing under such section and the number of applications for assistance to address other needs under section 408(e).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H486B3060BC504D36977828EDF8B76291" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of applications for such assistance that are approved.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC575AF4EB9224C2282B144E0B78D6BA7" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of applications for such assistance that are denied.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F1F7A81934B490AAD535A9775785072" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A ranked list of the reasons for the denial of such applications, including the number of applications for each reason for denial.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8FB93E01BE84432ADD4AE39F6EDBC36" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If available, the dollar amount of assistance provided pursuant to section 408 to applicants who are— </text><subparagraph id="H6F8E2361CA844CE49E939C6B7903985B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>property owners with a household annual income—</text><clause id="HCAFAD102DD5E49D59762D759D549CB98" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>above the national median household income; and</text></clause><clause id="H1F78CDDB0968412D8542CF880EA1EB7B" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">below the national median household income; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5ADFF139ABA948E5912C5C19E0230789" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>renters with a household annual income—</text><clause id="H5A9C4BC4096848558F7C5AAC959F83D1" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>above the national median household income; and</text></clause><clause id="H6B377BB4EEEB4A50B76299405763A58F" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">below the national median household income.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H648AF6578C5A4E78B15385B1A0A4B72E" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The estimated percentage of residential property that was destroyed as a result of the major disaster, if available.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E58E700884B479F8B45CEE079AD0B1A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any other information that the Administrator determines to be relevant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC6315924560542A6AAFF9E7EC7D2E909"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Personally identifiable information</header><text>The Administrator shall ensure that none of the information published under subsection (a) contains the personally identifiable information of an applicant.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HD6D391E4FA064A038327DBE28AA2A3C4" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>10.</enum><header>FEMA reports</header><subsection id="H27ABC32B6B224BDC9E1D3D2240AE4FDE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Government Affairs of the Senate a report with respect to fiscal year 2016 through the most recent fiscal year ending before the date of enactment of this Act, and an annual report for any fiscal year beginning on or after the date of enactment of this Act, describing—</text><paragraph id="HE9A96512E70B47FB85C88485F7C6AB86"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average amount of individual assistance and individual and household assistance provided under section 408 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>) to, and the rate of denial of individual assistance and individual and household assistance provided under such section for—</text><subparagraph id="HC7B354D3357F4A50A0ED9B6535BB0817"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all individuals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H155EC6FB10C14226993D0706157B51B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">households;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C672720B8CD480F9CD7339F3208F02F" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">individuals and households with a reported annual income under 75 percent of the national median household income;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H287E6DD2C16C4FE388F1F64BE4CCB60E" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">individuals with a reported annual income over 125 percent of the national median household income; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB99C492D27D43A4931ADFFE4E97A2F1" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">individuals with a reported annual income between 75 percent and 125 percent of the national median household income; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HADD0974D1AD547F785BC7110F3CDAC4D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an explanation for any factors causing an increase in the rate of denial of the assistance described in paragraph (1), if applicable.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H73DC1FF9803741C7B97DC87D06AC9E1B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information required</header><text>In the report submitted under subsection (a), the Administrator shall describe the number of homeowners and the number of renters for each category of individuals and households described in subparagraphs (C) through (E) of subsection (a)(1).</text></subsection></section><section id="H85A8ED4FFAF3440E85D18F89E5CB6CE4"><enum>11.</enum><header>Sheltering of emergency response personnel</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 403 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170b">42 U.S.C. 5170b</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H85BFBE8372B649EEA8CF53C9B65A8A5E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H001FB93BF6C748B3B59B10AF6142F268"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sheltering of emergency response personnel</header><paragraph id="HC336E57F8A904EBEABF72A51A0B697AE" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For any major disaster for which the President has authorized emergency protective measures for an area within the jurisdiction of a State, tribal, or local government, the Administrator may reimburse the State, tribal, or local government for costs relating to sheltering emergency response personnel, including individuals that are a part of the same predisaster household as such personnel, in exclusive-use congregate or non-congregate settings if the Governor of the State or chief executive of the tribal or local government determines that the damage or disruption to such area is of such a magnitude as to disrupt the provision of emergency protective measures within such area.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBF7D664371E44619D36808A5F573709"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation of assistance</header><subparagraph id="H5120633C23E1488798FBB8C8A56CFB66"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator may only reimburse a State, tribal, or local government for the costs of sheltering emergency response personnel under paragraph (1) for such a period of time as the Administrator determines reasonable based in the individual characteristics of and impacts to the affected area, including the extent of damage, the availability of alternative housing options, the availability of utilities, and disruptions to transportation infrastructure.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1DD37C467684BA7AD15DC7362B43399"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Maximum duration of reimbursement</header><text>The period of reimbursement under subparagraph (A) may not exceed the 6-month period beginning on the date on which the incident period ends.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B1B66F65293499485ED4A08A891FA3C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <quote>emergency response personnel</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H841DC4DB5E7649819987DCBF08034237"><enum>(A)</enum><text>employees or contracted employees providing law enforcement, fire suppression, rescue, emergency medical, emergency management, or emergency communications services; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B065C8E149D4BD1A24800BF52F2E7F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>elected officials, except members of Congress, responsible for the overseeing or directing emergency response operations or recovery activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H13A695D16AF546A1A105F135B3885D28" section-type="subsequent-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>12.</enum><header>Improved rental assistance</header><subsection id="HAEABEDA295C443039F6C87D1BE0A07F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 408(c)(1)(A)(ii) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174(c)(1)(A)(ii)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, including local post-disaster rent increases,</quote> after <quote>accommodation provided</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDE014392D0C84FAFAE8103A8E054175D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall conduct a study to examine the unique challenges of renters when seeking Federal disaster assistance and any disparities of assistance provided to homeowners and renters pursuant to section 408 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174</external-xref>) and develop a plan that addresses any identified challenges and disparities, including any recommendations for legislative action.</text></subsection><subsection id="H78245E91A0144FE1A4DBE5B26D757C53"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon completion of the activities carried out under subsection (b), the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report containing the study and recommendations required under subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="HB8705B3C67DE4EE79A2F156F8F6A5B3F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In completing the study and report required under subsections (b) and (c), the Administrator shall consult with appropriate Federal entities and stakeholders involved in disaster housing.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB19132B304DC4C44970140BE08300363"><enum>13.</enum><header>GAO report on preliminary damage assessments</header><subsection id="HD4994DFC481F46D48CC807B928F421C2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the practices, including the accuracy of such practices, that the Federal Emergency Management Agency uses when conducting preliminary damage assessments for the purposes of providing assistance under section 408 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H9844F0BF2F6E48D59BA77B0A60AFED80"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General shall include in the study conducted under subsection (a) the following:</text><paragraph id="HC14E11AD385E45CB80C97FD49E86E792"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comparison of the process and procedures used by the Federal Emergency Management Agency to complete preliminary damage assessments to the process and procedures used by private insurance companies following a major disaster.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BF9327709484DDDBFFA52EAA1FAB5FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A review of training provided to individuals conducting preliminary damage assessments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB998D4913BC444458A40100C37C647B2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A comparison of damage estimates for homes owned by individuals above the national median income to homes owned by individuals at or below the national median income.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H76CFC125118B42A09833C70B45F65195"><enum>14.</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by sections 4, 5, 7, 8, and 11 shall only apply to amounts appropriated on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section><section id="HFA21CDD363394600B30EF87918FBED6B"><enum>15.</enum><header>GAO report to Congress on challenges under public assistance alternative procedures</header><subsection id="H91F2CD7B9F0241FE8C638623D66DCAEC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the challenges to States and Territories of the United States in obtaining assistance under section 428 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5189f">42 U.S.C. 5189f</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H1765523AD1844ECCBC5DFD515FE5371B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In conducting the study described in subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall study the challenges for assistance described in subsection (a) faced by the following:</text><paragraph id="HAA2F391B059741F5AB54E204261EEEBE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Rural areas, as such term is defined in section 423 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5189a">42 U.S.C. 5189a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5284F0BFD806484797A6AE3F7C974AE5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Small impoverished communities, as such term is defined in section 203 of such Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85C4ECBB6C1F411F9232D616AD17A9E6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Other communities, areas, or individuals that the Comptroller General determines pertinent.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD92952FECED843D79CEF5149AFA1F060"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report describing the results of the study required under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

