<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0D60BBC279D0435293BB5782471B75DA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2701 IH: Fallen Servicemembers Religious Heritage Restoration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2701</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250407">April 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001222">Mr. Miller of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000483">Ms. Friedman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the American Battle Monuments Commission to establish a program to identify American-Jewish servicemembers buried in United States military cemeteries overseas under markers that incorrectly represent their religion and heritage, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H796C81E77A084D6885F37CEA42CF1052" style="OLC"><section id="H0FE12792C100414A8BAEC2D62D2F273C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fallen Servicemembers Religious Heritage Restoration Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFF66422930BF427CBD6C3A53809B7D13"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H0F36751EA2D54358B2B5EDA16BC8EE85"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An estimated 900 American-Jewish servicemembers of the Armed Forces, killed in World War I and World War II and buried overseas in United States military cemeteries were, for various reasons, mistakenly buried under Latin Crosses. In most instances, those mistakes were made inadvertently.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EBEE05218614710BAFF1B43BDDA4ED5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In 2022, more than 2,000,000 people visited the United States World War I and World War II cemeteries in foreign countries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27397FFB695F4121ADCC692F2EBC2455"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">American-Jewish servicemembers played a vital role in the Allied victories in World War I and World War II.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F1D32EDAE04483D8F4E8005A6E7D7D6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">American-Jewish servicemembers who fought and died for the United States must have their heritage properly recognized and honored.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H82F781FD76DA46238EACA36D4EA4890D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Government has a solemn responsibility to ensure that every American servicemember killed in action and buried overseas is properly honored.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE84E6A79C3F433DA3F386DCE6638A4F"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The work of properly identifying American-Jewish servicemembers buried overseas is vital and integral to the responsibility of the American Battle Monuments Commission to ensure that past mistakes in honoring those servicemembers who died in the line of duty are corrected.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H7936EBC9C46C4BE3AF7086A526769B02"><enum>3.</enum><header>Fallen Servicemembers Religious Heritage Restoration Program</header><subsection id="H702DF5BDB413471FBAFC7F2FF0408CCE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The American Battle Monuments Commission shall establish a program to identify covered members and to contact survivors and descendants of such covered members. Such program shall be known as the <quote>Fallen Servicemembers Religious Heritage Restoration Program</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H32BAAA01EDFD47B38BE8DCF4956E6A4C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall carry out the Fallen Servicemembers Religious Heritage Restoration Program during the first 10 fiscal years that begin after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H361B2E9F700E4420A34ACCE42238F67D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contracts</header><paragraph id="H1B0AA4DD9D9E4EB6A19FEA08E24A29D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>During each fiscal year described in subsection (b), the Commission shall seek to enter into a contract with a nonprofit organization under which such nonprofit organization shall carry out the purpose described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51C0FCB6AA694A8AAD9221FCAB58B029"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Term; amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each contract under this subsection shall be for one year and in the amount of $500,000 to the nonprofit organization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A6C358C43404B9191C5D2A1266C6629"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding a contract under this subsection, the Commission shall give priority to a nonprofit organization that has demonstrated capability and expertise in carrying out the purpose described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H20C2801EBEBB453DB3BEB570A4C84946"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Commission $500,000 for each fiscal year described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="HDDBD4A1C7B204DF38F8756763C0F6698"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HEA5CD7FA255649AFB0CB2B89EA5E41E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered member</quote> means a deceased member of the Armed Forces who was Jewish and buried—</text><subparagraph id="HD8E20E02D38645CEA9E81947B46EFADB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in a United States military cemetery located outside the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8B18AE1A49F48088270E25CAB2C2D47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>under a marker that indicates such member was not Jewish.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H54053003457B4FA39C3EC284A5030218"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>nonprofit organization</quote> means an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

