<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBF44F7CB4ACE491587B3FA8AC75878A0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1217 IH: Orphan Well Grant Flexibility Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1217</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250211">February 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to address measuring methane emissions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC3593A239A414F5B81A6C7400E6BBCBA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD15C8FAF4B664ABF9CA0E38374174AC6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Orphan Well Grant Flexibility Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H1761AC13743E41DF95D332CBA2972851"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pre-plugging methane emissions for grant eligibility</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 349 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15907">42 U.S.C. 15907</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H75B663CC219E4527BF157266C3E7DC6B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)(2), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B56C52E01574F8B9E64A63E91DDA10A"> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H50C865C599634506A887CA10B7ADAA20"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Activities not required</header><text>Nothing in this section requires a State to measure methane emissions or conduct other activities described in subparagraph (A), which are activities a State may conduct but is not required to conduct, as a condition of eligibility for a grant under this subsection.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H38AC9EB322F145E0A693314F693C2191"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (f)(2), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>, which may include estimates derived from pre-plugging or post-plugging monitoring data that States may, but are not required to, collect using funding from grants awarded under this section,</quote> after <quote>estimate</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE761E6B3B8B640F594FEE3D68D0A6B43"><enum>3.</enum><header>National Academies study on community impact of orphaned well grant program</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H89E706AD44404590BEDDB970E50F9F3A"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior shall—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3FD9DC2DCCFB47C78AF35D649530FC4A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seek to enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine under which the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine shall carry out a study on the effect of the plugging and remediation activity conducted under section 349 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15907">42 U.S.C. 15907</external-xref>) on economic development, housing trends, and other potential benefits (such as improvements in water quality) in areas where the plugging and remediation activity conducted under that section reclaimed a high number of sites, as determined by the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2375AE33093C49C4B1A206D6569272ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, provide the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine with information necessary to carry out the study described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A238411F01D4A63A25C8A4163085752"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Key inputs</header><text>The National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine shall ensure that at least 1 State from each region of the United States (Northeast, Southwest, West, Southeast, and Midwest) shall be key inputs to the study carried out under subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H50C04E8DBFF545949C0FC9925AF10305"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out the study under subsection (a), the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine shall consult with—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57BA5F563AC248F5A1AF297DFB89ED60"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Department of Housing and Urban Development, with respect to—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A1E4DF4779C40FFA5C78888FBFE38C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the plugging and remediation activity conducted under section 349 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15907">42 U.S.C. 15907</external-xref>) has affected economic development and housing trends; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7811C51E0D124C22A751A39A684D56DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how data on locations of plugging and remediation priorities from the Department of the Interior may be valuable to the Department of Housing and Urban Development;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0AEFBE2B00934061867A40F6F58A4D3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Interstate Oil and Gas Compact Commission, to provide data required to carry out the study under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6C5B8542838B4D35AD2F3B34869A0569" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>other Federal agencies, as determined by the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB97DE962A16446CB2324167E2BF4CD2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date on which the last grant is awarded under section 349 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15907">42 U.S.C. 15907</external-xref>), the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine shall submit to Congress a report detailing the findings of the study carried out under subsection (a).</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H72FA0EB53071444AB3633CB9E841030F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of existing funds</header><text>This section shall be carried out using amounts otherwise made available to the Secretary of the Interior.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

