<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H8716EA74BBFE44A8AD38C53DA09D6390" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3616 RH: Reliable Power Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 256</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3616</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–302]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250529">May 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001306">Mr. Balderson</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000482">Ms. Fedorchak</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250917">September 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000634">Mr. Downing</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000619">Mr. Rulli</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000600">Mr. Langworthy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001327">Mr. Bresnahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000177">Mr. Onder</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250917">September 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on May 29, 2025</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to review regulations that may affect the reliable operation of the bulk-power system.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HIF00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HB9F1BBB2B6D74114979A1AAE75C8FFAD"><section id="HB10CEA7A5DC042EAB369C63C337CBB5F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reliable Power Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6915484BF7124EC49B23452CFE58418B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Commission review and comment for covered agency actions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 215 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824o">16 U.S.C. 824o</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H6AF989F31CEF4EF88BBAF10EC6B9D5CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (g)—</text><subparagraph id="HDFFC1527ACED45B2A5F02CA59C8F398B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The ERO</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="HDECF40B582FF435A9A7168ECE4D6192E" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00"><paragraph id="HB6F5759E9ED34349AD21BFAAF1111F99"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The ERO</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2253C5127F9F4DED9784572C7BCD7D32"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H6A7EA35671AB4632A51F93E1E7A5AAC1" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00"><paragraph id="H8D87A64F42C7401498A54551C4FAD216"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual long-term assessment</header><text>The assessments under paragraph (1) shall include an annual long-term assessment, which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HB52206B4314D407FBE9B56CAA6B11E74"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an analysis of the ability of the bulk-power system to supply sufficient electric energy necessary to maintain an adequate level of reliability, taking into account generation resource mix, transmission development, and electric energy demand trends;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEBCF376142047E49FCA8288F7C64641"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the risk of future electric energy supply shortfalls under normal and extreme weather conditions, and the risk of any such shortfalls within each region of the bulk-power system; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E0A6704156E4499AC2E3CF61AA1B237"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a determination of whether additional generation resources are necessary to supply sufficient electric energy to maintain an adequate level of reliability during the assessment period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD24336D3E8EF4BF3A566F82A184FB588"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice of generation inadequacy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting a long-term assessment under paragraph (2), if the ERO finds that the bulk-power system is at risk of not having adequate generation resources to supply sufficient electric energy to maintain an adequate level of reliability, the ERO shall publicly notify the Commission that the bulk-power system is in a state of generation inadequacy. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44BB43CB71FB4E63B44C6259406BBDD1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Data collection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To conduct a long-term assessment under paragraph (2), the ERO may collect information and data from users, owners, and operators of the bulk-power system.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF220A4BE661047DFA64218EDD7C92001"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (h) through (k) as subsections (i) through (l), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED1158E7B31F4935BBCBE5073927A030"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (g) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H9584DA41B04A427A9C7D478723802255" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00"><subsection id="H9D11564AA1A8437AB32C981B74E343BE"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Commission review and comment for covered agency actions</header><paragraph id="H4D1FB0107DA94BE29A5CE08EC11C8AE4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice to federal agencies</header><text>If the ERO notifies the Commission under subsection (g)(3) that the bulk-power system is in a state of generation inadequacy, the Commission shall promptly notify the Department of Energy, the Environmental Protection Agency, and any other Federal agency the Commission determines appropriate of such state of generation inadequacy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC990E45AE8249348667BA83B66B7CB6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>Upon receiving notice under paragraph (1), the head of each Federal agency that received such notice shall provide to the Commission for review and comment any covered agency action by the Federal agency—</text><subparagraph id="HBE8F5C4BB9FD4F14909FA06E7B5A1DE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on the first date on which such covered agency action is provided to the Office of Management and Budget or any other Federal agency for review and comment; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D561B602CC7424CB836D0502FB1745B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if such covered agency action is not provided to the Office of Management and Budget or any other Federal agency for review and comment, not later than 90 days before the date on which the covered agency action is published in the Federal Register or is otherwise made available for public inspection or comment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1B8F413368B46CDA8A1CE94A0DE15A0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Commission comments</header><text>The Commission, in consultation with the ERO and transmission organizations, shall, by order, provide to the agency head that provided to the Commission a covered agency action under paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="HD58835D931D0420F995A4716BB077AAD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>comments on such covered agency action, which such comments may include an assessment of the effect of the covered agency action on rates, terms, and conditions for services pursuant to the authority of the Commission under sections 201 and 206; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA3E6FB04BA041DD8FABC616509A3D64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if applicable, recommendations for modifications to the covered agency action to prevent a significant negative impact on the ability of the bulk-power system to supply sufficient electric energy necessary to maintain an adequate level of reliability.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA2BA08310C44902BAD19960DFBC66DF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Agency response</header><text>The head of a Federal agency may not finalize a covered agency action that is provided to the Commission under paragraph (2) until—</text><subparagraph id="HF63585F6502847CBB2346D80BC98E40E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the agency head responds in writing to the Commission with an explanation of how the agency head modified, or why the agency head determined not to modify, such covered agency action in response to any comments and recommendations provided by the Commission under paragraph (3); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA524256C50F4406E9CE45A481376B236"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Commission finds that the covered agency action will not be likely to have a significant negative impact on the ability of the bulk-power system to supply sufficient electric energy necessary to maintain an adequate level of reliability.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H19C782FB245A4AE8A23ADDC7FD64BCB4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Public availability of comments and responses</header><text>An agency head shall include any comments, recommendations, and responses for the covered agency action when—</text><subparagraph id="H59974631A19A496C8726E2CF7F8B0884"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submitting the covered agency action to the Federal Register for publication; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA05F1F97EA1E46CF959328854D0263A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>otherwise making the covered agency action available for public inspection or comment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CCF29E9E6D54BDABBFC73B63537653D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="HFF1ED4FB1A484DB6AAF94E4FD4241EE6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered agency action</header><text>The term <term>covered agency action</term> means a regulation that—</text><clause id="H70862D51CCEB4368BC18FCE70E41114B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>relates to, or otherwise directly affects, any generation resource in the bulk-power system; and</text></clause><clause id="H97C4C5B6C73745008428A195AFB72CEE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is under development to be proposed or otherwise under consideration in a rulemaking prior to finalization on the date on which the Federal agency receives notice from the Commission under paragraph (1).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H894C8CFDB6214C6487AE4D9B25BB9499"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Federal agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal agency</term> means an Executive department (as that term is defined in section 101 of title 5, United States Code) or any other Executive agency that is in the President’s cabinet.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20250917">September 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

