<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2FB8BF6BB3B94AD5ABAE68FA3C00D4DC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1246 IH: Investing in Rural America Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1246</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250212">February 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000470">Mrs. Fischbach</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Farm Credit Act of 1971 to provide support for facilities providing healthcare, education, child care, public safety, and other vital services in rural areas.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCAAF3CBD372343BEAA814F265CE2AE71" style="OLC"><section id="HE7AEBD51B4DB438E8EDF9E8AD4130F80" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Investing in Rural America Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HCAB33DD5D33340E79CCE751DFF19748A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authority of farm credit system institutions to provide financial support for essential rural community facilities projects</header><subsection id="HAE71276899DE4078964A5B4ADDDFECC9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Farm Credit Act of 1971 is amended by inserting after section 4.18A (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/2206a">12 U.S.C. 2206a</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2B6FE296B1094A9FAC29B8686F4BE022" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H70EFAD4AB1FE4D0DBA65A4EF3AA18C20"><enum>4.18.</enum><header>Essential community facilities</header><subsection id="H9823472275284A4DB1383C07B907B0D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Farm Credit Bank, direct lender association, or bank for cooperatives chartered under this Act may, for the purpose of making available capital to develop, build, maintain, improve, or provide related equipment or other support for essential community facilities in rural areas, make and participate in loans and commitments, and extend other technical and financial assistance for projects for essential community facilities eligible for financing under section 306(a) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H08929C14768F4D3AA0FC14D483B8852D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Only an entity eligible for financing under section 306(a) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act may receive financing or any other assistance under subsection (a) of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC2817630F4F947E690CE804CAB7079A5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations</header><paragraph id="HC989B2AD5DCE4A0BAFEA91C9FDCF85BD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Financing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Farm Credit System institution described in subsection (a) shall not provide financing or assistance under this section in an aggregate amount that exceeds 15 percent of the total of all outstanding loans of the institution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36243E8F3D9B4166877F8EB377D112FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Offer requirement</header><subparagraph id="H9296058ACF7949E2A2388E4309A08854"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Farm Credit System institution shall not provide financing or assistance under this section unless the institution—</text><clause id="H21D88D9C41924DD0B841ED988293819D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has offered, under reasonable terms and conditions acceptable to the borrower involved, an interest in the financing to at least 1 domestic lending institution not referred to in subsection (a) other than the Department of Agriculture; and</text></clause><clause id="H83748AA307D746BBB588B99276069BA2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has reported the offer to the Farm Credit Administration.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BD080E3E4EA46FABA4085273510EF7A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rural community bank priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In offering an interest in a financing to a domestic lending institution described in subparagraph (A)(i), the Farm Credit System institution shall give priority to community banks located in the service area of the essential community facility being financed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H05D2331217C94832A23B9FA5A1304C3B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section and annually thereafter, the Farm Credit Administration shall provide a report to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate on the activities undertaken pursuant to this section by Farm Credit System institutions during the period covered by the report, including through partnerships between such an institution and other lending institutions, which shall also be posted on the website of the Farm Credit Administration.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HD5DFF13AC39149669369B869A507A470"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect on October 1, 2025.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

