<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF3549316A2A0433D811FCF4198F3D42C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 582 IH: Community Protection and Wildfire Resilience Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 582</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250121">January 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a community protection and wildfire resilience grant program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6E7D855F76EF492A92FE86E34BDDA57D" style="OLC"><section id="H2A6B1DFE274140039B632EDE3BDE3D9D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community Protection and Wildfire Resilience Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2454A337B22949C2A283063D6F7507D6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HBAF2365168724702A9FF83204B835695"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA2F34B8F3A4425EB3F1DAACB79FA3BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chief</header><text>The term <term>Chief</term> means the Chief of the Forest Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A1FD86B4DF54E24B326798E81C5198E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Community protection and wildfire resilience plan</header><text>The term <term>community protection and wildfire resilience plan</term> means a plan that—</text><subparagraph id="H0B63DD901E2848B092390836132FB3C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is developed by an eligible entity in coordination with—</text><clause id="H5DFE70186CC3488EB66EB1C637DAA00C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the local community and government;</text></clause><clause id="HB4C1EA8E67D0482DB0471A065AE93701"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>local Indian Tribes;</text></clause><clause id="HBB37C03F065442D981C1912F946F5C93"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>local law enforcement, firefighters, first responders, fire managers, and utilities;</text></clause><clause id="H87AB2D5AB46347628B528B989EED42DB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>non-governmental organizations carrying out relevant projects or relevant operations locally; and</text></clause><clause id="HA0E3AFFB16E54535AC2954053D6007DD"><enum>(v)</enum><text>State agencies responsible for—</text><subclause id="H0B7A4E9C84B34142BD598258D33188B9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>fire prevention and emergency response;</text></subclause><subclause id="HFE7E39A4E5B54653BFB647691E5B221F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>other emergency response;</text></subclause><subclause id="H87EBF39E81CF4ADFA26E28E2EB7D6BAE"><enum>(III)</enum><text>public safety;</text></subclause><subclause id="HF063778D94D44E058922BA9E7B882217"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>environmental protection; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HB1F41E7A59A24637B8181D6946F7E320"><enum>(V)</enum><text>forest management.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2601555FDDAA4CFCA32DFC9B2FECB221"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes strategies and activities relating to—</text><clause id="HA998EE6491354BEA80934F420C849B46"><enum>(i)</enum><text>improving early detection technology, public outreach and education, alerts and warnings, evacuation planning, evacuation execution, and access for first responders;</text></clause><clause id="HB5C40581543B492BA430263DE526A383"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>addressing vulnerable populations, including the elderly, children, individuals with disabilities, and homeless individuals;</text></clause><clause id="H890D5D930AD74D6C89539C1AA2406FEA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>hardening and increasing the resiliency of critical infrastructure and homes, including through incentive programs;</text></clause><clause id="HA2B1E297FAED4D26857E3941D9F1A72C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>applying community-scale defensible space projects, developed collaboratively with the entities described in clauses (i) through (iii) of subparagraph (A), across contiguous areas;</text></clause><clause id="H6506CE67590A4E73B25C1F855E1B9D59"><enum>(v)</enum><text>building local capacity to implement and oversee the plan;</text></clause><clause id="H4FBAC3AB89354D61B25E55892FC2CC4C"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>implementing strategic land use planning;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F18590092654D01B34CD7F14F91AB15"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>educating community members about ways to improve community resilience;</text></clause><clause id="H9EC7CB5D052B4B42B1C6F5D3A661D9DA"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>coordinating any existing wildfire plans, such as a community wildfire protection plan or a community emergency evacuation plan; and</text></clause><clause id="HB328824E0ABC4E60AEFA0F79895DFCE5"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>incorporating information from a map generated pursuant to section 210(a) of division O of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6501">16 U.S.C. 6501</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/141">Public Law 115–141</external-xref>); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H574444A2C4764AFDAC376628997AAFB1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may consist of existing plans or other efforts, provided that any such plan complies with subparagraphs (A) and (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7B8540EEAE742139BB40E266D27B18E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Critical infrastructure</header><text>The term <term>critical infrastructure</term> means any public safety, health, education, transportation, communications, or water or power utility infrastructure or any private infrastructure necessary to preserve community safety, resilience, or continuity of operation of such infrastructure with respect to a wildfire threat.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAABD4AC1C0E34B66A337FBFE45A7240D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Defensible space project</header><text>The term <term>defensible space project</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H2E3E68EA663B43F7BF32B7A1B24DB1E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a project that is conducted within a radius of not more than 100 feet around a home, business, or administrative facility, and is comprised of vegetation pruning, such as annual removal of tree seedlings and saplings, lower limbs of mature trees, cutting of grasses and reducing density and continuity of shrubs, and removal of most small twigs and leaves; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDCF1C6A40E94E708159DC70BD26B4C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at the discretion of the Administrator, if a project funded under the program is being carried out in a State that has established, by law, a more restrictive definition of the term, has the meaning given the term in State law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2E9240D512B47C69C0610C8D967FDE9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HAD3BB1BA29DC49799D01B8ED91450ED4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E68FA72DAEF4DDAA2111DBEA65C1DC4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC686E2232C7A4DDCBE344E28D6BCD2C7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a unit of general local or regional government, including a fire protection district or a municipal fire department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H994402CD1F7A4A00BC7B5AEA173F8950"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a volunteer fire department; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F3E5AE91F9F4AB09070282AEA750584"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a collaborative effort of not less than 2 entities described in subparagraphs (A) through (D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF21ECA24A434A6AB1F7630623589878"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>program</term> means the grant program established under section 3(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E517772CD864031ACAB253AE9D327DB"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, Guam, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HCE604B0E009B4D98B720FABB60BA6763"><enum>3.</enum><header>Community protection and wildfire resilience grant program</header><subsection id="HC341691446484CF09E94E737E95ABF1F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator, acting through the United States Fire Administrator and in coordination with the Chief, shall establish a program, which shall be separate from the program established under section 203 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5133">42 U.S.C. 5133</external-xref>), under which the Administrator shall award grants to eligible entities to—</text><paragraph id="HEA441D9F13E74606B23965E14A381E52"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible entity that has a community protection and wildfire resilience plan, carry out projects described in the community protection and wildfire resilience plan of the eligible entity in accordance with subsection (c); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8798322D6915435989F42BC83BA6782E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an eligible entity that does not have a community protection and wildfire resilience plan, develop a community protection and wildfire resilience plan in accordance with subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5A34F8D6FF1B41BDA7B22FCA9F170DDA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criteria for grants</header><paragraph id="H03A0F4ECADC7462484906E80B3699085"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator, acting through the United States Fire Administrator and in coordination with the Chief, shall establish criteria to award grants under the program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D30DA9743D74825AE579CC672451255"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Communities</header><text>Amounts provided under the program shall be used to conduct projects and activities only in communities in existence on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EF7243314114B4C93EF849CEC183CD9" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under the program, the Administrator shall give priority to eligible entities that will carry out projects or plans supporting a community located in an area with a high risk for fire or wildfire, as evidenced by a State wildfire hazard map or a map generated pursuant to section 210(a) of division O of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6501">16 U.S.C. 6501</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/141">Public Law 115–141</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1FE7E3C15381484CA2083F959F923779"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Community protection and wildfire resilience grants</header><paragraph id="H1634636474CE4C519C5835EB9FBEA98F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Use of grant funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under the program must use grant funds to carry out projects that support a diverse portfolio of community protection and wildfire resilience strategies described in the community protection and wildfire resilience plan of the eligible entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB9045ACA9DF43C583F15FBDBD0854F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant amounts</header><text>A grant under this subsection shall be for not more than $10,000,000.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H80576018D70C4B9C913B7F7151FC2342"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Community protection and wildfire resilience plan development grants</header><paragraph id="HF2D281930A614453A518440807286021"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Use of grant funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under the program may use grant funds to develop a community protection and wildfire resilience plan for the eligible entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H079AF34BB7C049BB8A6FBE0633D228E4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant amounts</header><text>An award under this subsection shall be for not more than $250,000.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4963C49AA5F247C088CD80C770854338"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Preference for local contractors and labor</header><text>In carrying out a project using a grant awarded under the program, the grant recipient shall, to the maximum extent practicable, give preference to contracting with entities, and hiring individuals, from the area in which the project is being carried out, including by partnering with local corps groups such as AmeriCorps or a conservation corps.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3150E7BA23344D83A1AE29FAA0718E35"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Cost-Sharing</header><paragraph id="H6E926220779C46B689750E6713B0111D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Non-Federal share requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The non-Federal share of the cost (including the administrative cost) of carrying out a project using funds from a grant awarded under the program—</text><subparagraph id="HD9DF3A3F77E14B99A0B3B1B9931F70C7"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE253900A2E3B4E27BD021A10E1D43C7C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be not less than 25 percent of the cost of the project to be carried out using grant funds in accordance with subsection (c); and</text></clause><clause id="H030002A84F4C4CD18E1D8E7C0591481A" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be 0 percent of the cost of the project to be carried out using grant funds in accordance with subsection (d);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB43673FDC9540CF96D1B9FB3B2E9DF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be provided by—</text><clause id="HAE4D182C5CA644CBB58867802AE00E7B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a State, a unit of local government, an Indian Tribe, a nonprofit organization, private industry, or a combination of those entities; or</text></clause><clause id="H8008A7FB86E749B7931EC349357D9D9D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>volunteer hours and in-kind donations; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45A4AB9E991B40A086D40B9F6CAE9AEE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may, in the case of a project that serves a low-income community, be in the form of a low-interest Federal loan to the eligible entity carrying out the project through the Community Disaster Loan program authorized under section 417 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5184">42 U.S.C. 5184</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D7FDABDCDFA409C9A9B1B79C012B66F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver; reduction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program, the Administrator may waive or reduce the non-Federal share amount required under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H54DBAD37D4044987861E1E709E40201A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the program $1,000,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029.</text></subsection></section><section id="H082E9EAECAAA40A38AC652038FE3A5A4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Government accountability office report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall publish a report—</text><paragraph id="H31A90632091D43729C171D3C57A8B268"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on authorities and programs of the Federal Government that are available to protect communities from wildfires; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F4A871B0DB047C5AEF7230DD24FE54C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that includes an assessment of the Comptroller General with respect to impediments to the implementation of such programs, including gaps in funding.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H6AC6ACABFC8041348BC68E8DEBC2F726"><enum>5.</enum><header>Government accountability office study</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall publish a study that includes—</text><paragraph id="HCB35BA74E2C04F95AFF2320C87CB2CB3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the Comptroller General with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="H95AA34C378654CCAB3EE5A87CC09A050"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the potential for a community protection and wildfire resilience plan to qualify for a certification identifying a level of wildfire survivability and resilience; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE2E911BD4084F25B3D43170B96C81FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">methods that could be used by the Federal Government to incentivize insurance companies to accept such a certification; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6972A2C445145768AF0ECD5F3AB9BF8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an identification of any metrics that could be provided to insurance companies as assurance that a community has wildfire resilience measures in place.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC43C17A929224BCB817F48734ED4B3C3"><enum>6.</enum><header>Updating list of at-risk communities</header><subsection id="H328F96A745264025B4B304652D9AC7BC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subparagraph (A) of section 101(1) of the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6511">16 U.S.C. 6511(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB950C62873A149CD9FF36529E4E704C4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H489B85E1325242B2BACEB91C62E9EA71"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is comprised of a group of homes and other structures with basic infrastructure and services (such as utilities and collectively maintained transportation routes) within or adjacent to Federal land;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H1312BBABBB3B4A69B7983DE09A6D787A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Map</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 5 years thereafter, the Administrator, acting through the United States Fire Administrator and in coordination with the Chief, shall develop and publish a map depicting at-risk communities (as defined in section 101 of the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6511">16 U.S.C. 6511</external-xref>), as amended by this section), including Tribal at-risk communities.</text></subsection></section><section id="HAD130565DBA94FBD8AC08452026BC784"><enum>7.</enum><header>Report on radio communications</header><subsection id="HC55E3158CF484974B959D9F702870A94"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator, acting through the United States Fire Administrator and in coordination with the Chief, shall prepare a report relating to insufficient radio frequencies, barriers to interoperability of radio frequencies, and available products and technologies for overcoming barriers to interoperability for wildfire management.</text></subsection><subsection id="H42367D5ED1E74CCDAE53C4322FC5FD8D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cooperation</header><text>In preparing the report under subsection (a), the Administrator shall cooperate with—</text><paragraph id="H922191189B8F4616B9D27A74B1499F4A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AA7456A87FD4FFAAE8FF4052C54B23D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>agencies responsible for the management of Federal land;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19AD2B7B167D428C8C4B10F16351E374"><enum>(3)</enum><text>State fire marshals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7377026E7AAA47BB9DB8E3014E9DBF87"><enum>(4)</enum><text>State and local emergency response agencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2432305FA8494BA48ECCE6F8120D677F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Tribal fire departments and emergency managers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H82C49B0BA15546D7ACBD52CD3776A068"><enum>(6)</enum><text>municipal fire departments, fire protection districts, and volunteer fire departments in relevant communities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9D868DB35DB1423CA428C79815990104"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compatibility; additional frequencies</header><text>The report under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="H97DF9615CBD54120856B8A96A67F5727"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a determination on whether the entities described in subsection (b) have the ability to communicate by way of radio during a potential fire suppression effort for a community conflagration;<italic></italic></text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C38BDAF5D41420AB5D9E630405EC85E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a determination on whether—</text><subparagraph id="H3D199C9A25B34C9493F300395390BF10"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the reserved radio frequencies are sufficient for wildfire management; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5717D45BCC75439B980D2113F8D532B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>additional frequencies, listed by type and location, are recommended to be reserved or obtained;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD14850CCB8BA4DDE9DAE676E84AD5A25"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an analysis of commercially available technology and products to enable radios from multiple agencies operating on different radio frequencies to be interoperable; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H791FEB6897864B9BA7C32162CEEED270"><enum>(4)</enum><text>if the Administrator determines under paragraph (1) that any entities do not have the ability to communicate, a plan for ensuring such entities would be able to communicate adequately during a fire suppression effort for a community conflagration.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE5D06F49F7614867AEC275936E853C31"><enum>8.</enum><header>Amendment to community wildfire defense grant program to allow structure hardening</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 40803(f) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6592">16 U.S.C. 6592(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HCFF19AD9DA164D0C95ACB9AB1F493338"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(B), by striking <quote>projects</quote> and inserting <quote>projects (including covered projects)</quote> ; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A4094EC6FC84FCA8BC12AAC1D17CF50"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF427898716C548C8A84CA13F30E82891" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H435D72F184024B6F9B81356F5903B687"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Covered projects defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>covered projects</term> means the following:</text><clause id="H2B524509275741E480B175F1FCE9134A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The construction, modification, or maintenance of a structure to make the structure resistant to the intrusion of flames or embers.</text></clause><clause id="H1B0D2BB56B2040D7B298E43E38BF28B1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The modification of a structure or an area adjacent to a structure, (including vegetation and miscellaneous structures, such as garages, sheds, and fencing) if such modification is carried out—</text><subclause id="H58AD9A27646A4FE7A3EC435966688F77"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to reduce the exposure of the structure to direct contact from flame, radiation, or embers from wildfire; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HBA9624F4A9F743FC8F515F064FDA26AB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>with consideration for the potential effects on the structure of nearby combustible features (including vegetation, vehicles, and miscellaneous structures, such as garages, sheds, and fencing).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

