<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H086F6D97FFF248EFB40E246DAC29487B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5637 IH: No Work, No Pay Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5637</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250930">September 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000403">Mr. Kennedy of Utah</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the pay of Members of Congress during periods in which a Government shutdown is in effect, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6A167A0AAB6949BDA9EFC18FAF3D78CA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE4663618C44D480DBED47DDD805BB9E1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Work, No Pay Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H52AF9C52D16C40FE9FDC8BA95403A030" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibiting pay of Members of Congress in response to government shutdown</header> <subsection id="HD1272BF9140B4C568220255078A21468"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition of Pay</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If on any day during a pay period a Government shutdown is in effect, the payroll administrator of each House of Congress shall exclude from the payments otherwise required to be made with respect to that pay period for the compensation of each Member of Congress who serves in that House of Congress an amount equal to the product of—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD2C37C07EFF744D0B709D1E48DB4987A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an amount equal to one day’s worth of pay under the annual rate of pay applicable to the Member under section 601(a) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCFC9713C539F4747B2589276A4FB80DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of 24-hour periods during which the Government shutdown is in effect which occur during the pay period.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6288225F603242F987478128AFC7B1E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Role of Secretary of the Treasury</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall provide the payroll administrators of the Houses of Congress with such assistance as may be necessary to enable the payroll administrators to carry out this section.</text></subsection> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E0A52991301479C990CC748D4DD1E59"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Payroll administrator defined</header><text>In this section, the <quote>payroll administrator</quote> of a House of Congress means—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFE3456EF05384CABA792342CBB0C9F2E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of the House of Representatives, the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, or an employee of the Office of the Chief Administrative Officer who is designated by the Chief Administrative Officer to carry out this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H990FA31365664125959CD66D56679F70"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of the Senate, the Secretary of the Senate, or an employee of the Office of the Secretary of the Senate who is designated by the Secretary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H98C1FF74FD2B464C81AB9D10C44D9DEA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall apply with respect to days occurring during the One Hundred Twentieth Congress and each succeeding Congress.</text></subsection></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBFCA09A5AD784342BDA510FE169BA466"><enum>3.</enum><header>Determination of Government shutdown</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, a Government shutdown shall be considered to be in effect if there is a lapse in appropriations for any Federal agency or department as a result of a failure to enact a regular appropriations bill or continuing resolution.</text></section> 
<section id="H4576491A4469426E8B06199F241210A3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Member of Congress defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>Member of Congress</term> means an individual serving in a position under subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of section 601(a) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501</external-xref>).</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

