<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF632BCEC88CD4B998A3ED9430DDD23FA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1505 IH: Public Safety Employer-Employee Cooperation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1505</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250221">February 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000592">Mr. Golden of Maine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000398">Mr. Kean</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000590">Ms. Lee of Nevada</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide collective bargaining rights for public safety officers employed by States or their political subdivisions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6E9FAC9AB3F74CACA7AE64D7815A7060" style="OLC"><section id="H9DBE14E66B964A4BA8FF4E9CE14964CF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Safety Employer-Employee Cooperation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8FD549E5A67349889B52793838B8B80F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose and policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress declares that the following is the policy of the United States:</text><paragraph id="H48CEAA96A06B4333921CC465ED40E23C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Labor-management relationships and partnerships are based on trust, mutual respect, open communication, bilateral consensual problem solving, and shared accountability. Labor-management cooperation fully utilizes the strengths of both parties to best serve the interests of the public, operating as a team, to carry out the public safety mission in a quality work environment. In many public safety agencies, it is the union that provides the institutional stability as elected leaders and appointees come and go.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB6E9D2A25B845B2AEBC5DF15AE6EDC2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>State and local public safety officers play an essential role in the efforts of the United States to detect, prevent, and respond to terrorist attacks, and to respond to natural disasters, hazardous materials, and other mass casualty incidents. State and local public safety officers, as first responders, are a component of the National Incident Management System, developed by the Department of Homeland Security to coordinate response to and recovery from terrorism, major natural disasters, and other major emergencies. Public safety employer-employee cooperation is essential in meeting these needs and is, therefore, in the national interest.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA31AC5012F7A43729FD50F0C469C3AB5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Federal Government needs to encourage conciliation, mediation, and arbitration to aid and encourage employers and the representatives of their employees to reach and maintain agreements concerning rates of pay, hours, and working conditions, and to make all reasonable efforts through negotiations to settle their differences by mutual agreement reached through collective bargaining or by such methods as may be provided for in any applicable agreement for the settlement of disputes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8901962E8BB34E518FC1B3524EDEB41B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The absence of adequate cooperation between public safety employers and employees has implications for the security of employees and can affect interstate and intrastate commerce. The lack of such labor-management cooperation can detrimentally impact the upgrading of law enforcement, fire, and emergency medical services of local communities, the health and well-being of public safety officers, and the morale of law enforcement, fire, and EMS departments. Additionally, these factors could have significant commercial repercussions. Moreover, providing minimal standards for collective bargaining negotiations in the public safety sector can prevent industrial strife between labor and management that interferes with the normal flow of commerce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE11AFB844D02447B9FB73BCC5F8BA489"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Many States and localities already provide public safety officers with collective bargaining rights comparable to or greater than the rights and responsibilities set forth in this Act, and such State and local laws should be respected.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H9678EBD0A0D6432F9DFB43312DFD7CAE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H47421AF0FBD74FA7AC1F012B194E8ABD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The term <term>Authority</term> means the Federal Labor Relations Authority.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H051143E56C0048279027A4B21472B8B4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Confidential employee</header><text>The term <term>confidential employee</term> has the meaning given such term under applicable State law on the date of enactment of this Act. If no such State law is in effect, the term means an individual, employed by a public safety employer, who—</text><subparagraph id="HD93D76BAFD3D4C6EAF7231AA5FF0F7C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is designated as confidential; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H502003AB92E14DE3BFC34BC176195B03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is an individual who routinely assists, in a confidential capacity, supervisory employees and management employees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AD72E2E648149518C5CD21412297488"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Emergency medical services personnel</header><text>The term <term>emergency medical services personnel</term> means an individual who provides out-of-hospital emergency medical care, including an emergency medical technician, paramedic, or first responder.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5174FD42E11046068B0D3568036EBDEF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Employer; public safety agency; public safety employer</header><text>The terms <term>employer</term>, <quote>public safety agency</quote>, and <quote>public safety employer</quote> mean any State, or political subdivision of a State, that employs public safety officers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF5F6623D03D4FDC8D5677E8D4E068DF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Firefighter</header><text>The term <term>firefighter</term> has the meaning given the term <term>employee engaged in fire protection activities</term> in section 3(y) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203(y)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1B1C3AAD793452193A4E890E9FA02A3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Labor organization</header><text>The term <term>labor organization</term> means an organization of any kind, in which employees participate and which exists for the purpose, in whole or in part, of dealing with employers concerning grievances, conditions of employment, and related matters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2752D73BC9234D83BF1A0795C71FBA58"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Law enforcement officer</header><text>The term <term>law enforcement officer</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1204 of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10284">34 U.S.C. 10284(6)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF777C25EC9E646CB9B19633EC239E7C4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Management employee</header><text>The term <term>management employee</term> has the meaning given such term under applicable State law in effect on the date of enactment of this Act. If no such State law is in effect, the term means an individual employed by a public safety employer in a position that requires or authorizes the individual to formulate, determine, or influence the policies of the employer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H563DA057129D4E82B9663FF9625C6102"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means an individual or a labor organization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61F2FED3DADA4C29AA3ED90EF504152B"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Public safety officer</header><text>The term <term>public safety officer</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H22B01AFCD10F440B844F8BECDD0B9121"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an employee of a public safety agency who is a law enforcement officer, a firefighter, or an emergency medical services personnel;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58B839772B23475CBE0C9BDB61F10E54"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes an individual who is temporarily transferred to a supervisory or management position; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8754EFFB71D14667ADA062AF4717F634"><enum>(C)</enum><text>does not include a permanent supervisory, management, or confidential employee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H181781A9E1EE490ABF3E320562C4F168"><enum>(11)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, and any territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80F64DFD6E634FEAAD059DB4C77C23D8"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Substantially provides</header><text>The term <term>substantially provides</term>, when used with respect to the rights and responsibilities described in section 4(b), means comparable to or greater than each right and responsibility described in such section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A6677522E0740AA8A0C5E63DD731B59"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Supervisory employee</header><text>The term <term>supervisory employee</term> has the meaning given such term under applicable State law in effect on the date of enactment of this Act. If no such State law is in effect, the term means an individual, employed by a public safety employer, who—</text><subparagraph id="H6C172249C05D4FCE829078EA9F865312"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the authority in the interest of the employer to hire, direct, assign, promote, reward, transfer, furlough, lay off, recall, suspend, discipline, or remove public safety officers, to adjust their grievances, or to effectively recommend such action, if the exercise of the authority is not merely routine or clerical in nature but requires the consistent exercise of independent judgment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90741D8FCEC3425592394A0094EE9441"><enum>(B)</enum><text>devotes a majority of time at work to exercising such authority.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H37196E1F869C4C378C6224F466A4FDD6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Determination of rights and responsibilities</header><subsection id="H214ACABDE207482386E8CE934367DF85"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Determination</header><paragraph id="HF336435FA96A40BB8DAA1D4AED2941D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Authority shall make a determination as to whether a State substantially provides for the rights and responsibilities described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE062DAB8A3D74D87A58B06F441F7D21B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consideration of additional opinions</header><text>In making the determination described in paragraph (1), the Authority shall consider the opinions of affected employers and labor organizations. In the case where the Authority is notified by an affected employer and labor organization that both parties agree that the law applicable to such employer and labor organization substantially provides for the rights and responsibilities described in subsection (b), the Authority shall give such agreement weight to the maximum extent practicable in making the Authority’s determination under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B8CF0944B7B477D8CF4D4D9E8AE9711"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limited criteria</header><text>In making the determination described in paragraph (1), the Authority shall be limited to the application of the criteria described in subsection (b) and shall not require any additional criteria.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC091304106B6412B8AC3FBF13AF5B8AF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Subsequent determinations</header><subparagraph id="HA465F3CE77E54A258AA0CC342832DC2A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A determination made pursuant to paragraph (1) shall remain in effect unless and until the Authority issues a subsequent determination, in accordance with the procedures set forth in subparagraph (B) of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25C3621546C143E38D09807FA6AB3823"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Procedures for subsequent determinations</header><text>Upon establishing that a material change in State law or its interpretation has occurred, an employer or a labor organization may submit a written request for a subsequent determination. If satisfied that a material change in State law or its interpretation has occurred, the Authority shall issue a subsequent determination not later than 30 days after receipt of such request.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C9B2FEC782046E99B7CFA0C4D1E5556"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text>Any person or employer aggrieved by a determination of the Authority under this section may, during the 60-day period beginning on the date on which the determination was made, petition any United States Court of Appeals in the circuit in which the person or employer resides or transacts business or in the District of Columbia Circuit, for judicial review.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE81F05DFF3C440389D9D2BCCB572A71D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rights and responsibilities</header><text>In making a determination described in subsection (a), the Authority shall consider a State’s law to substantially provide the required rights and responsibilities unless such law fails to provide rights and responsibilities comparable to or greater than the following:</text><paragraph id="HB4657930BAFA45E581907425C84A9CE7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Granting public safety officers the right to form and join a labor organization, which may exclude management employees, supervisory employees, and confidential employees, that is, or seeks to be, recognized as the exclusive bargaining representative of such employees.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5471CECEC0EA46098F3EB1E0C4735A6B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Requiring public safety employers to recognize the employees’ labor organization (freely chosen by a majority of the employees), to agree to bargain with the labor organization, and to commit any agreements to writing in a contract or memorandum of understanding.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DCA7B62B8D143EFBF26C3F7F88C9650"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Providing for the right to bargain over hours, wages, and terms and conditions of employment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5269BEE082BD4C51AD31C65C866A2780"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Providing for binding interest arbitration as a mechanism to resolve an impasse in collective bargaining negotiations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39ACB484806D4C3E84B3B1BE436BB52F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Requiring enforcement of all rights, responsibilities, and protections enumerated in this section, and of any written contract or memorandum of understanding between a labor organization and a public safety employer, through—</text><subparagraph id="HE440BA45477B4B8393E5AAA213915310"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State administrative agency, if the State so chooses; and/or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D893DE98BC541CAAF59F1B900592581"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any court of competent jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H35D1556DC737456EAD1A3086C076A54C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compliance with requirements</header><text>If the Authority determines, acting pursuant to its authority under subsection (a), that a State substantially provides rights and responsibilities described in subsection (b), then this Act shall not preempt State law.</text></subsection><subsection id="H586BCA02ED064E4287AC4F39F1F36BBA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Failure To meet requirements</header><paragraph id="HE254DE430BE64BE4AE5CD7E6D15408D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Authority determines, acting pursuant to its authority under subsection (a), that a State does not substantially provide for the rights and responsibilities described in subsection (b), then such State shall be subject to the regulations and procedures described in section 5 beginning on the later of—</text><subparagraph id="H0FF4B62D60BC4AB88B413AA142539722"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H687140477DDF40C3B235FD5FC74C9F8C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date that is the last day of the first regular session of the legislature of the State that begins after the date the Authority makes a determination under subsection (a)(1); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE95E402B1350454AA146AAA1BD5E9F00"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of a State receiving a subsequent determination under subsection (a)(4), the date that is the last day of the first regular session of the legislature of the State that begins after the date the Authority made the determination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0D0DF967ECC43F4AE78D1623F161FE8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Partial failure</header><text>If the Authority makes a determination that a State does not substantially provide for the rights and responsibilities described in subsection (b) solely because the State law substantially provides for such rights and responsibilities for certain categories of public safety officers covered by the Act but not others, the Authority shall identify those categories of public safety officers that shall be subject to the regulations and procedures described in section 5, pursuant to section 8(b)(3) and beginning on the appropriate date described in paragraph (1), and those categories of public safety officers that shall remain solely subject to State law with respect to the rights and responsibilities described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB6D167D27A7B4A3A97390E7B2AB1D5A5"><enum>5.</enum><header>Role of Federal Labor Relations Authority</header><subsection id="H18534C0620FD42A2B8A9B0A7F186B57D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Authority shall issue regulations, in accordance with the rights and responsibilities described in section 4(b), establishing collective bargaining procedures for employers and public safety officers in States where the Authority has determined, acting pursuant to section 4(a), do not substantially provide for such rights and responsibilities.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF60A940788AF412186A6D72BA0103978"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Role of the Federal Labor Relations Authority</header><text>The Authority, to the extent provided in this Act and in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Authority, shall—</text><paragraph id="HAA31A43033444365AAC349101602687F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determine the appropriateness of units for labor organization representation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFBECEA14F024EE6B8AFD64EC87CD6EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supervise or conduct elections to determine whether a labor organization has been selected as an exclusive representative by a voting majority of the employees in an appropriate unit;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H688E6109327B47638D93B76B27E6D8B1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>resolve issues relating to the duty to bargain in good faith;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55F018CC309E484C837D86CEC57C6E9E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>conduct hearings and resolve complaints of unfair labor practices;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8534A24752F84380A7B27AF22C39373A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>resolve exceptions to the awards of arbitrators;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E0BFB86493C41178A02BCF1F42991D9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>protect the right of each employee to form, join, or assist any labor organization, or to refrain from any such activity, freely and without fear of penalty or reprisal, and protect each employee in the exercise of such right; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7420716DA61244AC98D07E8DE274CC94"><enum>(7)</enum><text>take such other actions as are necessary and appropriate to effectively administer this Act, including issuing subpoenas requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of documentary or other evidence from any place in the United States, and administering oaths, taking or ordering the taking of depositions, ordering responses to written interrogatories, and receiving and examining witnesses.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC06548EB3CEC4A81B68CD0831C9D9EC8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="H09E88DA2F6BC40D38F47436D0B17D2AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority to petition court</header><text>The Authority may petition any United States Court of Appeals with jurisdiction over the parties, or the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit, to enforce any final orders under this section, and for appropriate temporary relief or a restraining order.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77375391E67342FCAF4373F92D3F6C84"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text>Unless the Authority has filed a petition for enforcement as provided in paragraph (1), any party has the right to file suit in any appropriate district court of the United States to enforce compliance with the regulations issued by the Authority pursuant to this section, or to enforce compliance with any order issued by the Authority pursuant to this section. The right provided by this subsection to bring a suit to enforce compliance with any order issued by the Authority pursuant to this section shall terminate upon the filing of a petition seeking the same relief by the Authority. Enforcement against a State shall be pursuant to section 8(b)(4).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H67598920A92D4911AC3BD47D905EF5A2"><enum>6.</enum><header>Strikes and lockouts prohibited</header><subsection id="H1F3B5131ADA4441A98B571CE55AB3A20"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsection (b), an employer, public safety officer, or labor organization may not engage in a lockout, sickout, work slowdown, strike, or any other organized job action that will measurably disrupt the delivery of emergency services and is designed to compel an employer, public safety officer, or labor organization to agree to the terms of a proposed contract.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2E46488117E748D69037BBCD01B88026"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No preemption</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to preempt any law of any State or political subdivision of any State with respect to strikes by public safety officers.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA48EA1EEF3FF42CAA3E77C65F39F4C10"><enum>7.</enum><header>Existing collective bargaining units and agreements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A certification, recognition, election-held, collective bargaining agreement, or memorandum of understanding that has been issued, approved, or ratified by any public employee relations board or commission or by any State or political subdivision or its agents and is in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act shall not be invalidated by the enactment of this Act.</text></section><section id="H588608B47F3B4D19A28FF860A10FD764"><enum>8.</enum><header>Construction and compliance</header><subsection id="H8E8F812DFBE940B6A40FA39762A9F854"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed—</text><paragraph id="HBDEC10EC9C0C4AB2A478FD5DACC99801"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to preempt or limit the remedies, rights, and procedures of any law of any State or political subdivision of any State that provides comparable or greater rights and responsibilities than the rights and responsibilities described in section 4(b);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C1B1860CD644CB9AFE285FF51113CE3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to prevent a State from enforcing a right-to-work law that prohibits employers and labor organizations from negotiating provisions in a labor agreement that require union membership or payment of union fees as a condition of employment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H224F6A8952614EDC8E43D3B93539EB95"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to preempt or limit any State law in effect on the date of enactment of this Act that provides for the rights and responsibilities described in section 4(b) solely because such State law permits an employee to appear on the employee’s own behalf with respect to the employee’s employment relations with the public safety agency involved;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF146DB8885C4493CAB55389785008D2C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to prohibit a State from exempting from coverage under this Act a political subdivision of the State that has a population of less than 5,000 or that employs less than 25 full-time employees, including each individual employed by the political subdivision, except any individual elected by popular vote or appointed to serve on a board or commission; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B0EF63C7FF34A958E402E674274EE79"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to preempt or limit the laws or ordinances of any State or political subdivision of a State that provide for the rights and responsibilities described in section 4(b) solely because such law or ordinance does not require bargaining with respect to pension, retirement, or health benefits.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7993F310BBA54A8DA8806FA44FD6EFC5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Compliance</header><paragraph id="H46CDB91242F14EF4B828B63E1281AC29"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Actions of states</header><text>Nothing in this Act or the regulations promulgated under this Act shall be construed to require a State to rescind or preempt the laws or ordinances of any of the State’s political subdivisions if such laws provide rights and responsibilities for public safety officers that are comparable to or greater than the rights and responsibilities described in section 4(b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC33F6DF1A3E54C038D32400A555D0248"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Actions of the authority</header><text>Nothing in this Act or the regulations promulgated under this Act shall be construed to preempt—</text><subparagraph id="H8AF718470E874D46A970B26C3FE0CF91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the laws or ordinances of any State or political subdivision of a State, if such laws provide collective bargaining rights for public safety officers that are comparable to or greater than the rights enumerated in section 4(b);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5CEC84C74FB49319E933C1C099FA37C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the laws or ordinances of any State or political subdivision of a State that provide for the rights and responsibilities described in section 4(b) with respect to certain categories of public safety officers covered by this Act solely because such rights and responsibilities have not been extended to other categories of public safety officers covered by this Act; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H269F3E9B75CA4A14A6B2251A3B690D82"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the laws or ordinances of any State or political subdivision of a State that provide for the rights and responsibilities described in section 4(b), solely because such laws or ordinances provide that a contract or memorandum of understanding between a public safety employer and a labor organization must be presented to a legislative body as part of the process for approving such contract or memorandum of understanding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H62D58A3BE8954062867954A8D2C0697A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limited enforcement power</header><text>In the case of a law described in paragraph (2)(B), the Authority shall only exercise the powers provided in section 5 with respect to those categories of public safety officers who have not been afforded the rights and responsibilities described in section 4(b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H365972BE5F07487DB3E5AFF1788C2A20"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exclusive enforcement provision</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of the Act, and in the absence of a waiver of a State’s sovereign immunity, the Authority shall have the exclusive power to enforce the provisions of this Act with respect to employees of a State.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7CDB1CB24B204D309CC62C547860518D"><enum>9.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

