<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8393F0DD0F6741C2A0A926BEEE2F219F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2404 IH: Remote Opioid Monitoring Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2404</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001306">Mr. Balderson</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for a study on the effects of remote monitoring on individuals who are prescribed opioids.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H92936A54BFEB46ED99DAA841540D6FEC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3969D2C3766146989D764A74D9A8FDA1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Remote Opioid Monitoring Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4F0FD060B92A44EC9891967E930DA77D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Providing for a study on the effects of remote monitoring on individuals who are prescribed opioids</header> <subsection id="H517902B260334F7AB12A659689EC0FBE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study and submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report on the use of remote monitoring with respect to individuals who are prescribed opioids.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3BED429BDA6B4818848B8ED64EC12EF1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The report described in subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HC5F9DFE9BEBE42AD81AF5282DAC59DDF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of scientific evidence related to the efficacy, individual outcomes, and potential cost savings associated with remote monitoring for individuals who are prescribed opioids compared to such individuals who are not so monitored;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9455323AB85F43828E1E1706B0C0BDD4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assessment of the current prevalence of remote monitoring for individuals who are prescribed opioids, including the use of such monitoring for such individuals in other countries; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC469EF2B7283424298F5DEA1191D08F1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations to improve availability, access, and coverage for remote monitoring for individuals who are prescribed opioids, including through changes to Federal health care programs (as defined in section 1128B of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320a-7b">42 U.S.C. 1320a–7b</external-xref>)) and, if determined appropriate by the Comptroller General, an identification of cohorts of individuals who stand to benefit the most from remote monitoring when prescribed opioids.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

