<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BUR25604-CFJ-FG-G2W"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2670 IS: Strengthening Targeting of Organized Predatory Scammers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2670</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250801">August 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of the Treasury to designate certain covered organizations as Foreign Financial Threat Organizations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HE6801882A9204982B72D8095ACA7E5D1"><section id="idac733e61d3f7417abb1db890f6ef137e" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Targeting of Organized Predatory Scammers Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STOP Scammers Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE8421AE47C3C43C19397976183D96ACB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation of Foreign Financial Threat Organizations</header><subsection id="H72BAB127D47B4342937DB89C1AFAF313"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall designate covered organizations as <quote>Foreign Financial Threat Organizations</quote>. The Secretary shall make the first of such designations not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H24585132A1F1458F8EFB56A95C48D0BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procedure</header><paragraph id="H5A1D63CCD5634927A9B4BC874FF3325A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before making a designation under this section, the Secretary shall notify, in writing, the Speaker and the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, the President pro tempore, the Majority Leader, and the Minority Leader of the Senate, and the members of the relevant committees of Congress of the intent to designate an organization under this section as a Foreign Financial Threat Organization and the factual basis for such designation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H306F3ED1AAF846D395ED355D658B11A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication in Federal Register</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall publish a designation made under this section in the Federal Register not later than 7 days after providing the notification under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B3FF2BEDD4E47B4AAA8CBA0E888D5A1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Freezing of assets</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon notification under paragraph (1), the Secretary may require United States financial institutions possessing or controlling any assets of a Foreign Financial Threat Organization to block all financial transactions involving those asset until further direction from the Secretary of the Treasury, an Act of Congress, or an order of a court.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D63702DCEFA4A05AFE54A68A7CFF441"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Effect of designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Foreign Financial Threat Organization shall be subject to the same penalties and procedures as an organization that has been designated as a specially designated global terrorist organization by the Secretary of State or the Secretary of the Treasury, as the case may be, pursuant to Executive Order 13224 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property and prohibiting transactions with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H73E329FC1F3C4219813BADA0BDDC332F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Government may take such actions as necessary against a Foreign Financial Threat Organization to protect the cybersecurity of the United States and limit the ability of the Foreign Financial Threat Organization to access internet or cellular services.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCA44B056A37447958659E5D0B908A7E7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on contact</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall take such actions as may be necessary to prevent a Foreign Financial Threat Organization from contacting United States citizens or aliens who are lawful permanent residents of the United States by phone, internet, or email.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC59BD604C592421DA9AB12C34CF31D3C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="H14771F70BAA44F8A9874A4C6CE2D9B25"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the implementation of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2807F85477840C198E65E94190463B1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A report required by paragraph (1) shall include, for the period covered by the report—</text><subparagraph id="H6362B6F162734B23B3EE4D6DC855705F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification of covered organizations that have been designated as Foreign Financial Threat Organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H935C77D780AE4811AAF9E7768FD84EC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of assets seized from such Foreign Financial Threat Organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77F06D0E17AC484081085F5154DFAA14"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the actions taken by the Secretary to identify such Foreign Financial Threat Organizations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82C5C5DBD55D49BB87169A89B6F280A8"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of funds the Secretary was able to return to victims of fraud by such Foreign Financial Threat Organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H48CDE9506472494BB3708D7A302D2BE8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make publicly available a version of each report required by paragraph (1) that does not include any sensitive information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida869558c98df4f7da36a9cb168cf1a4c"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75904232a8f34691ab7e50e3b610425f"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id36d0a13a790346449c9770859cee4f32"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5132F9DD589046179C4D2477E3AA9E08"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Covered organization defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>covered organization</term> means a foreign entity (as defined in section 800.220(a) of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations), including any subsidiary or affiliate of a foreign entity, that engages in fraudulent activity in an attempt to deceive United States citizens or aliens who are lawful permanent residents of the United States to provide cash or other assets to such foreign entity, as jointly determined by the Secretary of the Treasury and the Attorney General.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

