<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HE21487D042404EB4A46A95960339DE5B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3380 RH: Taking Account of Institutions with Low Operation Risk Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 104</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3380</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–135]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250514">May 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250604">June 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="D000634">Mr. Downing</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250604">June 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on May 14, 2025</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies to take risk profiles and business models of institutions into account when taking regulatory actions, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HBA00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H56E42DF46CDE4C4DBE2912BE8208A5FA"><section section-type="section-one" id="HE97EB278BA4240E298B8D0251FEA10CC"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Taking Account of Institutions with Low Operation Risk Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TAILOR Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4712FD68DECB4A1B8B05A2B86AA9F85B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Tailoring regulation to business model and risk</header><subsection id="HD7F441CA599C4206A99BB804F70E90D4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="H13992441B8ED4EB0AB39D3894A82006A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>Federal financial institutions regulatory agency</term> means the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the National Credit Union Administration, and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3C1277AA42A4C4BA14730A87D303B03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>regulatory action</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HB8C757E0CC9846CBB0EBFF26F0C23164"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any proposed, interim, or final rule or regulation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FED0A54332C406FB34A84FDB80826C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any action taken by a Federal financial institutions regulatory agency that is solely applicable to an individual institution, including an enforcement action or order.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H37FFF9B8C3DE45B68209A1FE96D1A88E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consideration and tailoring</header><text>For any regulatory action occurring after the date of enactment of this Act, each Federal financial institutions regulatory agency shall—</text><paragraph id="H492C4899BDF843E197D5C39BBAED2554"><enum>(1)</enum><text>take into consideration the risk profile and business models of each type of institution or class of institutions subject to the regulatory action; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66AD4E50094E4527B3A1E368BF7321C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>tailor the regulatory action applicable to an institution, or type of institution, in a manner that limits the regulatory impact, including cost, human resource allocation, and other burdens, on the institution or type of institution as is appropriate for the risk profile and business model involved.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA23BF08BA20746F09C98B57BE0DB5A70"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Factors to consider</header><text>In carrying out the requirements of subsection (b) with respect to a regulatory action, each Federal financial institutions regulatory agency shall consider—</text><paragraph id="HE6BC838EA5B04FA69CA529EF202EA97A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the aggregate effect of all applicable regulatory actions on the ability of institutions to flexibly serve customers of the institutions and local markets on and after the date of enactment of this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H73AD3C9C6E284D57A88D9CBB62267666"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the potential that efforts to implement the regulatory action and third-party service provider actions may work to undercut efforts to tailor the regulatory action, as described in subsection (b)(2); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADEB12586F3244DAB97B7D38484182F0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the statutory provision authorizing the regulatory action, the congressional intent with respect to the statutory provision, and the underlying policy objectives of the regulatory action.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAD842CFFB41D47F3A353A610E1DC94DD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice of proposed and final rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Federal financial institutions regulatory agency shall disclose and document in every notice of proposed rulemaking and in any final rulemaking for a regulatory action how the agency has applied subsections (b) and (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="H3C5622BD0032459289C5FFCF0DD848E8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, each Federal financial institutions regulatory agency shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a report on the specific actions taken to tailor the regulatory actions of the Federal financial institutions regulatory agency pursuant to the requirements of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC56728E2933945E89664CC69A0C25902"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limited look-back application</header><paragraph id="H86F0A47BA4254F56AD190CAF59F850CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each Federal financial institutions regulatory agency shall—</text><subparagraph id="H5DF39D111F8B4B7AA8C73BB0EB15D5C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct a review of all final regulations issued pursuant to statutes enacted during the period beginning on the date that is 15 years before the date on which this Act is introduced in the House of Representatives and ending on the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9745E0A46CC4F848578C91EE851BB79"><enum>(B)</enum><text>apply the requirements of this section to the regulations described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF25E4D77E704460789B9A09DEC43805D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Revision</header><text>Any regulation revised under paragraph (1) shall be revised not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC89D78CD916D4BD5B58D8C9F7B37A20E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Short-form call reports for all banks eligible for the community bank leverage ratio</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The appropriate Federal banking agencies, as defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>), shall promulgate regulations establishing a reduced reporting requirement for all banks eligible for the Community Bank Leverage Ratio, as defined in section 201(a) of the Economic Growth, Regulatory Relief, and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5371">12 U.S.C. 5371</external-xref> note), when making the first and third report of condition of a year as required by section 7(a) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1817">12 U.S.C. 1817(a)</external-xref>).</text></section><section id="HB43905D4B89B41E1B062B8337223C9C0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report to Congress on modernization of supervision</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the appropriate Federal banking agencies, as defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>), in consultation with State bank supervisors, shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a report on the modernization of bank supervision, including the following factors:</text><paragraph id="H93A9F5A2939B406AA250353F7AB75C24"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Changing bank business models.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF58DFE59638468CAC1EDB2567CAEDA9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Examiner workforce and training.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAD9253A127D4E15986029A2F36748AA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The structure of supervisory activities within banking agencies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H729AB80D73B2473BB4823752D1E11603"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Improving bank-supervisor communication and collaboration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18E59EC5D86345F19204C115A125C93B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The use of supervisory technology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8CBF0714E21F4BF5BF9A7666B70470A2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Supervisory factors uniquely applicable to community banks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA97E939A71194C7C840F492910C9AFF7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Changes in statutes necessary to achieve more effective supervision. </text></paragraph></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20250604">June 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

