<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EHF25613-0M6-R1-XJP"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>111 S1544 IS: Insurance Data Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1544</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250430">April 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S389">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit the Federal Insurance Office of the Department of the Treasury and other financial regulators from collecting data directly from an insurance company.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HA611D1ADEE6A45748684A461391930CE"><section section-type="section-one" id="H1172F871766E4B5C9D0810EA94A80A00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Insurance Data Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HAD38432D1E8F4F31B10AAFFA029A2926"><enum>2.</enum><header>Repeal of subpoena and enforcement authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 313(e) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by striking paragraph (6).</text></section><section id="H81E613E2BBD947D6883B50F1DADCDD92"><enum>3.</enum><header>Confidentiality by Federal Insurance Office</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 313(e)(5) of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H1179F4CA75F443729BFBF7717F064D4B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), by inserting after <quote>Office</quote> the following: <quote>, or the sharing of any nonpublicly available data and information with or by the Office among any other Federal agency, any State insurance regulator (or any agent of such a regulator), or any other entity,</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H588CB994DD0B4A6F8574AE14FA8974FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)(ii), by inserting <quote>any privilege described in subparagraph (A) or</quote> after <quote>including</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2311D9B1BA3C4D98968116C53098C3E7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (D), by inserting <quote>including the exceptions under that section,</quote> after <quote>United States Code,</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HE6BFDF15E1154C3C99B88081BFCB23FF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Limitation on subpoenas by the Office of Financial Research</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 153(f)(1) of the Financial Stability Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5343">12 U.S.C. 5343(f)(1)</external-xref>) is amended, in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting after <quote>financial company</quote> the following: <quote>(other than an insurance company, as defined in section 201(a))</quote>.</text></section><section id="H850B5AC3554449C7ADC38863F8027F1F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Confidentiality by financial regulators</header><subsection id="HD5C93FC92D06455CB83EE14E951C4CD7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Financial Stability Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5311">12 U.S.C. 5311 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H055D84F2C0A3447ABF5359410DF59B35"><subtitle id="H5AC78E85FD274484A08E1BBD2ED0FDA9"><enum>D</enum><header>Treatment of data collected from insurance companies</header><section id="HA02EE6F33AA544E9896404EC01043980"><enum>181.</enum><header>Treatment of data collected from insurance companies by financial regulators</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idff4627822e5b4145abd9b20ac7ab3072"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f8d094bada749ed84a8e54b9c08ea95"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>The term <term>covered entity</term> means a nonbank financial company that is an insurance company.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id60cff31bc0d0450293ccf1b874bb3c2b"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Financial regulator</header><text>The term <term>financial regulator</term> means the Commission, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, the Council, the Federal banking agencies, and the Office of Financial Research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id081300ea38a84a1cbcf22e3c947d6476"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Insurance company</header><text>The term <term>insurance company</term> has the meaning given the term in section 201(a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAF8712F4CB994750A85CEBD916E70401"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Advance coordination</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id370cda82c61e4719861887088fc762b0"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8774774afd344ac69356df4cdb45ff7d"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pre-collection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before collecting any data or information pursuant to this title or title II from a covered entity, a financial regulator shall coordinate with each relevant Federal agency, State insurance regulator, and other Federal or State regulatory agency, and with any publicly available source, to determine if the data or information to be collected is available from, and may be obtained in a timely manner by, that agency, regulator, or regulatory agency, individually or collectively, or that publicly available source.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide1e61152868546f0aacd4ceb4aa2b0cf"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determinations</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id821ea9b0d5554446a1358bcdd8778beb"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information available</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a financial regulator, under subparagraph (A), determines that the data or information described in that subparagraph is available, and may be obtained in a timely manner, from an agency, regulator, regulatory agency, or source described in that subparagraph, the financial regulator shall obtain the data or information from that agency, regulator, regulatory agency, or source.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id260fc946aba54cce954d85fe16895be1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Information unavailable</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a financial regulator, under subparagraph (A) determines that the data or information described in that subparagraph is not available, the financial regulatory may collect that data or information from the applicable covered entity only if the financial regulator complies with the requirements of subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <act-name>‘Paperwork Reduction Act</act-name>’), in collecting that data or information.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb06b4c69e982470dac0262fa527f7d9f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority to provide information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for the purposes of paragraph (1), each relevant Federal agency and State insurance regulator or other Federal or State regulatory agency may provide to a financial regulator data or information described in that paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H110AC906AD57411C88A21D1AACBB1F67"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><paragraph id="HEC68A40759C341A9B77EE9DB7F1BBC90"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Retention of privilege</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sharing by a covered entity of any nonpublicly available data or information with a financial regulator under this title or title II shall not constitute a waiver of, or otherwise affect, any privilege arising under Federal or State law (including the rules of any Federal or State court) to which the data or information is otherwise subject.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB33EBF636B13498CB36BDF2B634CEAEF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continued application of prior confidentiality agreements</header><text>Any requirement under Federal or State law to the extent otherwise applicable, or any requirement pursuant to a written agreement in effect between the original source of any nonpublicly available data or information and the source of that data or information to a financial regulator, regarding the privacy or confidentiality of any data or information in the possession of the source to a financial regulator, shall continue to apply to that data or information after the data or information has been provided under this section to the financial regulator.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CFAD8B7DB054030AE1385726D798250"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information-sharing agreement</header><text>Any data or information obtained by a financial regulator may be made available to State insurance regulators, individually or collectively, through an information-sharing agreement that—</text><subparagraph id="H4E26B4014D8E46E88B24F2308F3F6419"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall comply with applicable Federal law; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC67803F6C1C4E60A955E30104CF7023"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall not constitute a waiver of, or otherwise affect, any privilege under Federal or State law (including any privilege described in paragraph (1) and the rules of any Federal or State court) to which the data or information is otherwise subject.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H469FFB75C86B4A3AA5F32466828CBE3A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Agency disclosure requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 552 of title 5, United States Code, including the exceptions under that section, shall apply to any data or information submitted to a financial regulator by a covered entity under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></subtitle><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H86D34DE0041E4F0993645ED28E86B2B3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/203">Public Law 111–203</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 176 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7FDC0F576E8847259AD94E40177FA1CE"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="subtitle">Subtitle D—Treatment of data collected from insurance companies</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 181. Treatment of data collected from insurance companies by financial regulators.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

