<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H869BC3B5568F4B06B57484C8AFB13D4E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4877 IH: Central Coast Heritage Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4877</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250805">August 5, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To designate certain Federal land in the State of California as wilderness.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HA6316D2D120F42B89C6B62FE820D2399" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8A41B9C8E1054165940C40D837D80CC0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Central Coast Heritage Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9EE5B285755E4565ADA82F03644F6A25"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6790A47FAB5C4D829431CB61CBE49127"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Scenic area</header><text>The term <term>scenic area</term> means a scenic area designated by section 7(a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAE6E3D8BB3DC426284FCB66FF5C6E127"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA956D9B072874C0EBA7DA9E28BD65CCE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to land managed by the Bureau of Land Management, the Secretary of the Interior; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB8D82612DF1E4435B2251C417C7B1E6E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to land managed by the Forest Service, the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H55B902F716BA41A6ADFB987D1DF93F8C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of California.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F3CC8EB2C4947CDB0BDE0CF78042382"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Wilderness area</header><text>The term <term>wilderness area</term> means a wilderness area or wilderness addition designated by section 3(a).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HCB5DF5D1042849DAA76F9B10E2F46802"><enum>3.</enum><header>Designation of wilderness</header> 
<subsection id="H0AEB113B2D044BC68C6EE7B2A97D6264"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), the following areas in the State are designated as wilderness areas and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text> <paragraph id="HB9BF8734E6B54640A60CB5D7FC969F6C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain land in the Bakersfield Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 35,116 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Proposed Caliente Mountain Wilderness</quote> and dated February 2, 2022, which shall be known as the <quote>Caliente Mountain Wilderness</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD58AA6FD382A4972A6E513AD2B749FAB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Certain land in the Bakersfield Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 13,332 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Proposed Soda Lake Wilderness</quote> and dated June 25, 2019, which shall be known as the <quote>Soda Lake Wilderness</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF644E595A9C3457BB9A9A23A9D46C805"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Certain land in the Bakersfield Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 12,585 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Proposed Temblor Range Wilderness</quote> and dated June 25, 2019, which shall be known as the <quote>Temblor Range Wilderness</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9132B7EB558D4B6B8BB9A8491B11D317"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 23,670 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Chumash Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed</quote> and dated March 29, 2019, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the Chumash Wilderness as designated by the Los Padres Condor Range and River Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/301">Public Law 102–301</external-xref>; 106 Stat. 242).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3E801E5CE1754C7E9BD9B61461B9B64D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 54,036 acres, as generally depicted on the maps entitled <quote>Dick Smith Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed Map 1 of 2 (Bear Canyon and Cuyama Peak Units)</quote> and <quote>Dick Smith Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed Map 2 of 2 (Buckhorn and Mono Units)</quote> and dated November 14, 2019, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the Dick Smith Wilderness as designated by the California Wilderness Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/425">Public Law 98–425</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H623C5A0EAF404D0FBA336128204B5D56"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest and the Bakersfield Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 7,289 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Garcia Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed</quote> and dated March 29, 2019, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the Garcia Wilderness as designated by the Los Padres Condor Range and River Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/301">Public Law 102–301</external-xref>; 106 Stat. 242).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H787FE6C5FD5E4576B04959C16CF51D6B"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest and the Bakersfield Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 10,817 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Machesna Mountain Wilderness—Proposed Additions</quote> and dated October 30, 2019, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the Machesna Mountain Wilderness as designated by the California Wilderness Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/425">Public Law 98–425</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4EACF1F00B2643C88599AE5E40219FCE"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 30,184 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Matilija Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed</quote> and dated March 29, 2019, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the Matilija Wilderness as designated by the Los Padres Condor Range and River Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/301">Public Law 102–301</external-xref>; 106 Stat. 242).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H990163D5957D406A8A5C2D3BB77EE3F7"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 23,969 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>San Rafael Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed</quote> and dated November 14, 2023, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the San Rafael Wilderness as designated by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/90/271">Public Law 90–271</external-xref> (82 Stat. 51), the California Wilderness Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/425">Public Law 98–425</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note), and the Los Padres Condor Range and River Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/301">Public Law 102–301</external-xref>; 106 Stat. 242).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE1051E2D80E14F569AB00870EF4BA147"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 2,921 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Santa Lucia Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed</quote> and dated March 29, 2019, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the Santa Lucia Wilderness as designated by the Endangered American Wilderness Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/237">Public Law 95–237</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC5B216441C68475090189CFBB76B7FCE"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 14,313 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Sespe Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed</quote> and dated March 29, 2019, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the Sespe Wilderness as designated by the Los Padres Condor Range and River Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/301">Public Law 102–301</external-xref>; 106 Stat. 242).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H41E6C47FEFB242BE8861BE255E69D75A"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 17,870 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Diablo Caliente Wilderness Area—Proposed</quote> and dated March 29, 2019, which shall be known as the <quote>Diablo Caliente Wilderness</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBBEE766A85F544CE96B44ED7D106E146"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Maps and legal descriptions</header> <paragraph id="H12833FA03D3D4E168B07783572066716"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall file maps and legal descriptions of the wilderness areas with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE1E363AF605C43F8A025173F2CD03C26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D35ECFD8C8D4435999CFA04325F6A33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCC6E11AE87694D279358E7E7579D28C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions filed under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct any clerical and typographical errors in the maps and legal descriptions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1CE89F69DC7C4BDC98BE83951193A0BE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions filed under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H5123A6CF68BD4198884324C42B25AB92"><enum>4.</enum><header>Administration of wilderness</header> 
<subsection id="H6FD864A50C5F4F07901B0A16449772AA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the wilderness areas shall be administered by the Secretary in accordance with this Act and the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), except that—</text> <paragraph id="H2212EBFA53204126AF89D45CCE10B0F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any reference in the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>) to the effective date of that Act shall be considered to be a reference to the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE89BFC2D155644F18A1F98273C85B80F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any reference in the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>) to the Secretary of Agriculture shall be considered to be a reference to the Secretary that has jurisdiction over the wilderness area.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB5CB11C3F7D445CF8F99DD27F306A3B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fire management and related activities</header> <paragraph id="H05DC1D48263E4D70B00F3E92B1D065A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may take any measures in a wilderness area as are necessary for the control of fire, insects, and diseases in accordance with section 4(d)(1) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(1)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H550B715078E74CA4BD8FADA725979C7F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funding priorities</header><text>Nothing in this Act limits funding for fire and fuels management in the wilderness areas.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H37467E57DB984B2C80ABB4C2FE34A43F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Revision and development of local fire management plans</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall amend the local information in the Fire Management Reference System or individual operational plans that apply to the land designated as a wilderness area.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H94ADC59CCA044E6093D44C47853ADD12"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with paragraph (1) and any other applicable Federal law, to ensure a timely and efficient response to a fire emergency in the wilderness areas, the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HAE68B5AF56E84A0FACB95F7069BAA3EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, establish agency approval procedures (including appropriate delegations of authority to the Forest Supervisor, District Manager, and other applicable agency field office officials) for responding to fire emergencies; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2C72AC20367547C7B8B919D8FADF0267"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enter into agreements with appropriate State or local agencies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H661E1083E5514962841F03504271AACE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grazing</header><text>The grazing of livestock in the wilderness areas, if established before the date of enactment of this Act, shall be permitted to continue, subject to any reasonable regulations as the Secretary considers necessary in accordance with—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4307198268A445BBB64EE8702247C80E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 4(d)(4) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(4)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D3F718C0E9145A3AD612395A8CA6186"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the guidelines set forth in Appendix A of House Report 101–405, accompanying H.R. 2570 of the 101st Congress for land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC8C37E29A4194198955664A48CE0EE68"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the guidelines set forth in House Report 96–617, accompanying H.R. 5487 of the 96th Congress for land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2129F18CA59A4115BFA07486D2445706"><enum>(4)</enum><text>all other laws governing livestock grazing on Federal public land.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB017B7EAE94B49B49AEC174C9924A299"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Fish and wildlife</header> 
<paragraph id="HDCEC299B329346B6A9BEC0449749D251"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with section 4(d)(7) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(7)</external-xref>), nothing in this Act affects the jurisdiction or responsibilities of the State with respect to fish and wildlife on public land in the State.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5B25D45C9A59415199663469CD9EAE76"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management activities</header><text>In furtherance of the purposes and principles of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), the Secretary may conduct any management activities that are necessary to maintain or restore fish and wildlife populations and habitats in the wilderness areas, if the management activities are—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6549B692023947FCACDA1A0E9620EB91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consistent with relevant wilderness management plans;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2A62942A7F22414F9F1AA433CCEDE668"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conducted in accordance with appropriate policies, such as the policies established in Appendix B of House Report 101–405; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1101330787F74E859F5E1BC75EB387A5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in accordance with memoranda of understanding between the Federal agencies and the State Department of Fish and Wildlife.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H015B68803F124EC598BFB4542F7D488C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Buffer zones</header> <paragraph id="H310EF3C0B16A4A68A213087EAF2B78ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Congress does not intend for the designation of wilderness areas by this Act to lead to the creation of protective perimeters or buffer zones around each wilderness area.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H87504EFEAA854229B21802846F67619E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities or uses up to boundaries</header><text>The fact that nonwilderness activities or uses can be seen or heard from within a wilderness area shall not, of itself, preclude the activities or uses up to the boundary of the wilderness area.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5BD6C7341CC34BD2B7CC5028E0F5CD17"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Military activities</header><text>Nothing in this Act precludes—</text> 
<paragraph id="H37AC2EBCAE3042ECAF20CA3679E2A2FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>low-level overflights of military aircraft over the wilderness areas;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE1819D7FBB244A895FF697D464A2532"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the designation of new units of special airspace over the wilderness areas; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2D2DF446CF4B4BCEA41B6DC251BB9A84"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the use or establishment of military flight training routes over wilderness areas.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H297F1BF89E77468E988B6C2F3A014AED"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Horses</header><text>Nothing in this Act precludes horseback riding in, or the entry of recreational saddle or pack stock into, a wilderness area—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3E2B1E8774454F3E8BB6EF3E1AC81B3E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in accordance with section 4(d)(5) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(5)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94A3145DA7D74613B4880D1DE7DF02CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject to any terms and conditions determined to be necessary by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDF10BA9BE8E44F3FAF768F6F6A8EA859"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the wilderness areas are withdrawn from—</text> <paragraph id="HB0727E370EE542B5B9AC1CAB928E41B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H97A2BE4F3C0B4A188CE5D4857463493D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87E372C355174C80975DCDF940B0254E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC77D9FC4AF914DABAE8E7EEB6DA99889"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Incorporation of acquired land and interests</header><text>Any land within the boundary of a wilderness area that is acquired by the United States shall—</text> <paragraph id="H6F8A2A5B070F4E64A3A12B389D984004"><enum>(1)</enum><text>become part of the wilderness area in which the land is located; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC3026D05B85244CC97BCDB185D88727B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be managed in accordance with—</text> <subparagraph id="H00FDB1A7451E435E8422E9AEA45D19BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this section;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H947CB9CF8CA244F08B4AEA486DE72D70"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDDF3305564FA45ADB095ACBBB2454063"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other applicable law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6FD197523E4F44FC961F67C47B61010C"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Climatological data collection</header><text>In accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>) and subject to terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary may authorize the installation and maintenance of hydrologic, meteorologic, or climatological collection devices in the wilderness areas if the Secretary determines that the facilities and access to the facilities are essential to flood warning, flood control, or water reservoir operation activities.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H8C7BD3D13C6B4A04BD30E94A241187EC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Designation of Wild and Scenic Rivers</header> <subsection id="H2AFC294635304D0683541BCE508631E6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Indian creek, mono creek, and matilija creek, california</header><text>Section 3(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HD00FF10814074C5398C6E8DFBFBC6E9F" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H48F8B935BB69433BB34676789EEFD910"><enum>(233)</enum><header>Indian creek, california</header><text>The following segments of Indian Creek in the State of California, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture:</text> <subparagraph id="H36C2639CB1764E97B480693C17274B99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 9.5-mile segment of Indian Creek from its source in sec. 19, T. 7 N., R. 26 W., to the Dick Smith Wilderness boundary, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4373AE3A5C73492BBCB5512D3BA287F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 1-mile segment of Indian Creek from the Dick Smith Wilderness boundary to 0.25 miles downstream of Road 6N24, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2E2CCB69CA14B5681CDDF731473F62F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The 3.9-mile segment of Indian Creek from 0.25 miles downstream of Road 6N24 to the southern boundary of sec. 32, T. 6 N., R. 26 W., as a wild river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB5C4B4FE511B4E4598BB0EEC5A337BD9"><enum>(234)</enum><header>Mono creek, california</header><text>The following segments of Mono Creek in the State of California, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture:</text> <subparagraph id="HE2FD154C79CA4D30BBD14748C9A9DD18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 4.2-mile segment of Mono Creek from its source in sec. 1, T. 7 N., R. 26 W., to 0.25 miles upstream of Don Victor Fire Road in sec. 28, T. 7 N., R. 25 W., as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H27DA452D39214D16B681F958155EAAEE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 2.1-mile segment of Mono Creek from 0.25 miles upstream of the Don Victor Fire Road in sec. 28, T. 7 N., R. 25 W., to 0.25 miles downstream of Don Victor Fire Road in sec. 34, T. 7 N., R. 25 W., as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE276C523211E41A68A10DF40709AF0ED"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The 14.7-mile segment of Mono Creek from 0.25 miles downstream of Don Victor Fire Road in sec. 34, T. 7 N., R. 25 W., to the Ogilvy Ranch private property boundary in sec. 22, T. 6 N., R. 26 W., as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H165F1A8581994F36B0D84DA90D851E1B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The 3.5-mile segment of Mono Creek from the Ogilvy Ranch private property boundary to the southern boundary of sec. 33, T. 6 N., R. 26 W., as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H239FCC66F0874702B0AC4A5F565C4FAE"><enum>(235)</enum><header>Matilija creek, california</header><text>The following segments of Matilija Creek in the State of California, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3AE11FC16D9F49BD9B16383D9382FF22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 7.2-mile segment of the Matilija Creek from its source in sec. 25, T. 6 N., R. 25 W., to the private property boundary in sec. 9, T. 5 N., R. 24 W., as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H49B7FCF97C1C46BFBE017379282811A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 7.25-mile segment of the Upper North Fork Matilija Creek from its source in sec. 36, T. 6 N., R. 24 W., to the Matilija Wilderness boundary, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE41E605345494550B31EB7B8EA691181"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sespe creek, california</header><text>Section 3(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (142) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H3B2CAD40117C4E6793C2D2CD6A934463" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H617DDDCD8DEF4957AED89D52A740856F"><enum>(142)</enum><header>Sespe creek, california</header><text>The following segments of Sespe Creek in the State of California, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE4133D22656246EC9BE55B13F0752EC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 2.7-mile segment of Sespe Creek from the private property boundary in sec. 10, T. 6 N., R. 24 W., to the Hartman Ranch private property boundary in sec. 14, T. 6 N., R. 24 W., as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8782D405732A4F64A7E7325E2131866C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 15-mile segment of Sespe Creek from the Hartman Ranch private property boundary in sec. 14, T. 6 N., R. 24 W., to the western boundary of sec. 6, T. 5 N., R. 22 W., as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H887B31CCFAE2438FB44D78C05FB93BA7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The 6.1-mile segment of Sespe Creek from the western boundary of sec. 6, T. 5 N., R. 22 W., to the confluence with Trout Creek, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5603837898DE41189707B0F48B7CA1B3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The 28.6-mile segment of Sespe Creek from the confluence with Trout Creek to the southern boundary of sec. 35, T. 5 N., R. 20 W., as a wild river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8E0157DF99614DC78F84E95A5C9DAEA9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sisquoc river, california</header><text>Section 3(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (143) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HAABCF365D1534DE294CC85E7BFFD71C0" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H24EB8EDE0809434BB6C6B5DD281F3D89"><enum>(143)</enum><header>Sisquoc river, california</header><text>The following segments of the Sisquoc River and its tributaries in the State of California, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H51BEF651623740A5AF937D1AE0EDBACF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 33-mile segment of the main stem of the Sisquoc River extending from its origin downstream to the Los Padres Forest boundary, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H27E0F8C547EB4721AAFD5735F77546E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 4.2-mile segment of the South Fork Sisquoc River from its source northeast of San Rafael Mountain in sec. 2, T. 7 N., R. 28 W., to its confluence with the Sisquoc River, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBF001CB3F27444209A1F22FFC894F40B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The 10.4-mile segment of Manzana Creek from its source west of San Rafael Peak in sec. 4, T. 7 N., R. 28 W., to the San Rafael Wilderness boundary upstream of Nira Campground, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3B60350C815B42BA93B2EC0773AC63DA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The 0.6-mile segment of Manzana Creek from the San Rafael Wilderness boundary upstream of the Nira Campground to the San Rafael Wilderness boundary downstream of the confluence of Davy Brown Creek, as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H704C3EA296494A4294F96707D2B5C0AC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The 5.8-mile segment of Manzana Creek from the San Rafael Wilderness boundary downstream of the confluence of Davy Brown Creek to the private property boundary in sec. 1, T. 8 N., R. 30 W., as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5902C1B5D2D7447593403B575463414D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The 3.8-mile segment of Manzana Creek from the private property boundary in sec. 1, T. 8 N., R. 30 W., to the confluence of the Sisquoc River, as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6C2671151D0E4C75A6BC266074BBEBB4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The 3.4-mile segment of Davy Brown Creek from its source west of Ranger Peak in sec. 32, T. 8 N., R. 29 W., to 300 feet upstream of its confluence with Munch Canyon, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB33D66C62A154ACEAD590654972024C8"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The 1.4-mile segment of Davy Brown Creek from 300 feet upstream of its confluence with Munch Canyon to its confluence with Manzana Creek, as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2D4BA81B714448D08BD4A4B0B8D34554"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The 2-mile segment of Munch Canyon from its source north of Ranger Peak in sec. 33, T. 8 N., R. 29 W., to 300 feet upstream of its confluence with Sunset Valley Creek, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB523CBAD2A9A45A9A955461FAD8372E8"><enum>(J)</enum><text>The 0.5-mile segment of Munch Canyon from 300 feet upstream of its confluence with Sunset Valley Creek to its confluence with Davy Brown Creek, as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA771A417D3FF4DF083A5FD9922AD7C14"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The 2.6-mile segment of Fish Creek from 500 feet downstream of Sunset Valley Road to its confluence with Manzana Creek, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC328A2DFB9C54921B8899AE3BCB64599"><enum>(L)</enum><text>The 1.5-mile segment of East Fork Fish Creek from its source in sec. 26, T. 8 N., R. 29 W., to its confluence with Fish Creek, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB500552E310D4410A79807FFC2EEEDE2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Piru creek, california</header><text>Section 3(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (199) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H595268251BAC43CA8B7FC882A33FC6F1" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H4C59BA453ED64B8AAECC5EFBE130CE27"><enum>(199)</enum><header>Piru creek, california</header><text>The following segments of Piru Creek in the State of California, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA4E7F6CE69E0484BA7BDC21ACCB395E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 9.1-mile segment of Piru Creek from its source in sec. 3, T. 6 N., R. 22 W., to the private property boundary in sec. 4, T. 6 N., R. 21 W., as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H34D972155A424CA4973C0DD0DC882758"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 17.2-mile segment of Piru Creek from the private property boundary in sec. 4, T. 6 N., R. 21 W., to 0.25 miles downstream of the Gold Hill Road, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC9F94B5AB1394675B76EAF3542FA4EFA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The 4.1-mile segment of Piru Creek from 0.25 miles downstream of Gold Hill Road to the confluence with Trail Canyon, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H935784C325324A71B779576FA0EFEE8C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The 7.25-mile segment of Piru Creek from the confluence with Trail Canyon to the confluence with Buck Creek, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5EEF87F1C81B4CE6B41FF2DC2066941E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The 3-mile segment of Piru Creek from 0.5 miles downstream of Pyramid Dam at the first bridge crossing to the boundary of the Sespe Wilderness, as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB5C9301BC1B04EDDB80BCE56FAAB546A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The 13-mile segment of Piru Creek from the boundary of the Sespe Wilderness to the boundary of the Sespe Wilderness, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H62145E2B2D33423B8948FC33EA477EC1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The 2.2-mile segment of Piru Creek from the boundary of the Sespe Wilderness to the upper limit of Piru Reservoir, as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H18236CC9F2814A9690808733DD60E987"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>The designation of additional miles of Piru Creek under subsection (d) shall not affect valid water rights in existence on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE567F0ACE9BC4699967211598C2DCE33"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Motorized use of trails</header><text>Nothing in this section (including the amendments made by this section) affects the motorized use of trails designated by the Forest Service for motorized use that are located adjacent to and crossing upper Piru Creek, if the use is consistent with the protection and enhancement of river values under the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1271">16 U.S.C. 1271 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H3525CDD5B16D445C95229EA2B37CDDD1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Fox Mountain Special Management Area</header> <subsection id="HD9A3602F7E0B4DA4ADA0DD24583FBB51"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of special management area</header> <paragraph id="H741D18271F9943C0BB0A8734D64F52B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Fox mountain special management area</header> <subparagraph id="HBC1A4D2E2832442DA53906DC6E889D84"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, there is established the Fox Mountain Special Management Area, comprising approximately 41,082 acres of Federal land in the Los Padres National Forest, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Fox Mountain Special Management Area</quote> and dated November 14, 2023.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFB68B742E61F4E18B0F241324876E688"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the Fox Mountain Special Management Area are to conserve, protect, and enhance for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations—</text> <clause id="H7E22620B5863459A92A9DF3DA00C0104"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the ecological, scenic, wildlife, recreational, roadless, cultural, historical, natural, educational, and scientific resources of the area; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H38BB9E300D4749F0A572A53933B115D5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cultural and historical resources and values of the area.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8CBB3DC26BF8471EB29871A299D347EC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Management plan</header> <paragraph id="HE68614B1EFE34592B9D5DAE916DE7008"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act and in accordance with paragraph (2), the Secretary of Agriculture shall develop a comprehensive plan for the long-term management of the special management area established by subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD80DFC5F3E134C009C39C2C48CFEBD34"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing the management plan required under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Agriculture shall consult with—</text> <subparagraph id="HEB45E9F2CD804D2E92019F5B907D8767"><enum>(A)</enum><text>appropriate State, Tribal, and local governmental entities; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H280B1EA84C6B45CCAFDEAF2D6F0BAB2B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>members of the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H81E5E83DE85F44D6ACB3BD487CC03458"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional requirement</header><text>The management plan required under paragraph (1) shall ensure that recreational use within the special management area established by subsection (a) (referred to in this section as a <quote>special management area</quote>) does not cause significant adverse impacts on the plants and wildlife of the special management area.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2CC9194F018F42DF87F6903309A27747"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Management</header> 
<paragraph id="HB4CE83B08426435D9AE73EF2E7D38AD4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall manage the special management area—</text> <subparagraph id="H0531D64D4ACD4D01B3B677FA724FCADA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in furtherance of the purpose described in subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H90A6515ABEAB4D0C8515987C4D85B716"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in accordance with—</text> <clause id="H90A4168DAAC9494AB7BD2375851E6BD2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the laws (including regulations) generally applicable to the National Forest System;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H02E05328FB544DF8A88CF03B7A110473"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>this section; and</text></clause> <clause id="H71EC7728E7E0424DB332BAF00A9728DB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other applicable law (including regulations).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H20200D8D367F48A29B89F2F9FBF91A1F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Uses</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall only allow uses of the special management area that the Secretary determines would further the purposes of the special management area described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H48582D7AC96A4D0A8BE8D8F6229F650E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recreation</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall continue to authorize, maintain, and enhance the recreational use of the special management area, including hunting, camping, hiking, sightseeing, nature study, horseback riding, mountain bicycling, and other recreational activities, if the recreational use is consistent with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H30A33EE0881244C8AD2583B26050248D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the purpose of the special management area;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE4D1182756D4640ADE51612A88D1C5C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>this section;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9763A3C127E644F68EE57669C950AEC4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other applicable law (including regulations); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8C5580910BE94AC7B513096DF7E473E6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any applicable management plans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H080346D6C142491C8268300085690ACB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Motorized vehicles</header> 
<subparagraph id="H4F88E509853B41E2834030CCEE247ABD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (C), the use of motorized vehicles in the special management area shall be permitted only on existing roads, trails, and areas designated for use by such vehicles as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD78C6D2F8DD3440E90A93FFCC40B0556"><enum>(B)</enum><header>New or temporary roads</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (C), no new or temporary roads shall be constructed within the special management area.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H878664401F8244A6B833D6952FDF1E58"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Nothing in subparagraph (A) or (B) prevents the Secretary of Agriculture from—</text> <clause id="H65DAA998A0E24957AA60125C4894B24B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>rerouting or closing an existing road or trail to protect natural resources from degradation, or to protect public safety, as determined to be appropriate by the Secretary;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5AD0371BC673488FA5506925DFD4CFE7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>designating routes of travel on land acquired by the Secretary and incorporated into the special management area if the designations are—</text> <subclause id="H8380E17C2BB844C1A5989FE55C46FF64"><enum>(I)</enum><text>consistent with the purposes of the special management area described in subsection (a); and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H0854A51ADE6D4291BC848D5C24147580"><enum>(II)</enum><text>completed, to the maximum extent practicable, not later than 3 years after the date of acquisition;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H6627CC3EB9944045ACD575FC70C727AD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>constructing a temporary road on which motorized vehicles are permitted as part of a vegetation management project carried out in accordance with subparagraph (D);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H021190257B3D495D983101647EC7158F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>authorizing the use of motorized vehicles for administrative purposes; or</text></clause> <clause id="H49BC68739AA54B8C81937334B036DB39"><enum>(v)</enum><text>responding to an emergency.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0E65E1DD3B9F41D4B245C372E77DC93D"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Decommissioning of temporary roads</header> 
<clause id="H51D2815AC6BC41F49D5AFF172C706902"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definition of decommission</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>decommission</term> means, with respect to a road—</text> <subclause id="HA0D9B5A7793A44AFAEC1DF25D9CB0043"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to reestablish vegetation on the road; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H51F69691775744D29A1B105660C584BB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to restore any natural drainage, watershed function, or other ecological processes that are disrupted or adversely impacted by the road by removing or hydrologically disconnecting the road prism.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H0D9C4170B89848008FC2CA702FBAD5E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date on which the applicable vegetation management project is completed, the Secretary of Agriculture shall decommission any temporary road constructed under subparagraph (C)(iii).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB387494708B24186937DE5B11553B943"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grazing</header><text>The grazing of livestock in the special management area, where established before the date of enactment of this Act, shall be permitted to continue—</text> <paragraph id="H86301C90FB274655AAC7ED0BEF8E0ED8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>subject to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H01510628C06A422D863448BCEF786563"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such reasonable regulations, policies, and practices as the Secretary of Agriculture considers necessary; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA69ED931962443F8A7D1CFF2871382A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>applicable law (including regulations); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5FBDDB97EE1C4D21A2C69132D3A8E23A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in a manner consistent with the purposes of the special management area described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF3AD3565BAF44B6E8704026BBB4F9670"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Wildfire, insect, and disease</header><text>Consistent with this section, the Secretary of Agriculture may carry out any activities within the special management area that the Secretary determines to be necessary to control fire, insects, or diseases, including the coordination of those activities with a State or local agency.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAF31F6C3187C4B96A855F374D34758B7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Acquisition and incorporation of land and interests in land</header> 
<paragraph id="H8A679AB6EF2243A0A59C01245BB3DDB1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Acquisition authority</header><text>In accordance with applicable laws (including regulations), the Secretary of Agriculture may acquire any land or interest in land within or adjacent to the boundaries of the special management area by purchase from a willing seller, donation, or exchange.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0141BCE45257423894E454A413BF08D2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Incorporation</header><text>Any land or interest in land acquired by the Secretary of Agriculture under paragraph (1) shall be—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBD7A5770212F43F1A603BCA332EAE056"><enum>(A)</enum><text>incorporated into, and administered as part of, the special management area; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H67A471F895B645DFA5397EFBD87765A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>withdrawn in accordance with subsection (i).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC6B863E5C740428EADE9F6099D37F965"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Tribal agreements and partnerships</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable and in accordance with applicable laws, on request of an affected federally recognized Indian Tribe, the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, shall enter into agreements, contracts, and other cooperative and collaborative partnerships with the federally recognized Indian Tribe regarding management of the special management area under relevant Federal authority, including—</text> <paragraph id="H81490BCA171546AF8AA1974BBCF28972"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5301">25 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBDAF27C1261C4850914C874E3EFA5442"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H526BD76ABE024642BAC147FDDE26E451"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Tribal Self-Governance Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5361">25 U.S.C. 5361 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA6EA3F1EF52845458F7529AB2487D815"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Tribal Forest Protection Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/3115a">25 U.S.C. 3115a et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF119376A6619484593AFDCD7A90AAABD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the good neighbor authority under section 8206 of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2113a">16 U.S.C. 2113a</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7AAF87C91B7E41D0A8ECCF31EC1C99C0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Executive Order 13175 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5301">25 U.S.C. 5301</external-xref> note; relating to consultation and coordination with Indian Tribal governments);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4DD166A4E04047F8ABD1C3722B1CF957"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Secretarial Order 3342, issued by the Secretary of the Interior on October 21, 2016 (relating to identifying opportunities for cooperative and collaborative partnerships with federally recognized Indian Tribes in the management of Federal lands and resources); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8D706AEDA3B42288539E4B5692D38C2"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Joint Secretarial Order 3403, issued by the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture on November 15, 2021 (relating to fulfilling the trust responsibility to Indian Tribes in the stewardship of Federal lands and waters).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0BE911183E664926A1642FF6C7B4EF56"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, all Federal land located in the special management area is withdrawn from—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC7382573E3C7452B823B2B201904BBAC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3539061B60AF454785901386C5C6D3B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patenting under the mining laws; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1D928D76C3914CB6BD6F6F5BDA849A8B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H3BCF83873EBE46EB9E808FFCA26789A0"><enum>7.</enum><header>Designation of scenic areas</header> <subsection id="HBB3E5A3296AF459189C2BAAACC9B6CAB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, there are established the following scenic areas:</text> 
<paragraph id="H60FE9150641046F58186AC12C2A136C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Condor ridge scenic area</header><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 18,666 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Condor Ridge Scenic Area—Proposed</quote> and dated March 29, 2019, which shall be known as the <quote>Condor Ridge Scenic Area</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9DD414A2602E49ABB25266A8BF30DB20"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Black mountain scenic area</header><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest and the Bakersfield Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 16,216 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Black Mountain Scenic Area—Proposed</quote> and dated March 29, 2019, which shall be known as the <quote>Black Mountain Scenic Area</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBA4EBA76BDC9482EA0B948698A2D66EB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Maps and legal descriptions</header> 
<paragraph id="HDB0AC51A50C243708A37B546DD0A700A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior shall file a map and legal description of the Condor Ridge Scenic Area and Black Mountain Scenic Area with—</text> <subparagraph id="H9395A30382CF4C5296A5DB42CC9567BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7565CE0DACB34673A9F135EFB49666A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D98455F5C284DE9853186407504DB40"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions filed under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary of Agriculture may correct any clerical and typographical errors in the maps and legal descriptions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F24CAC565A548E28FA25C1EE9EB27A1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions filed under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE29CD76FE90F4C8AA11F87CD54DD3C44"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the scenic areas is to conserve, protect, and enhance for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations the ecological, scenic, wildlife, recreational, cultural, historical, natural, educational, and scientific resources of the scenic areas.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H46977C5517304C4D99B4D03DE9BB46EB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Management</header> 
<paragraph id="H583EBCB6B42C4B3CAB81B181E9017A99"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall administer the scenic areas—</text> <subparagraph id="HA01258BFECF7413E874B42AF90692343"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in a manner that conserves, protects, and enhances the resources of the scenic areas, and in particular the scenic character attributes of the scenic areas; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD2E1AF1B7BCE4CE3B3562955ACAB3944"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in accordance with—</text> <clause id="H7E69E9AC17784B5BA17188BD7DCB685D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>this section;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC65E8051620E48FFA263A9EE5273B4D4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Federal Land Policy and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) for land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior;</text></clause> <clause id="HCA47078E0F1D48F3B0DB8122074D2015"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any laws (including regulations) relating to the National Forest System, for land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFB3BE319435D49C1BAA1455102D84A44"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any other applicable law (including regulations).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5473D34A1A1F4DD8BCEB28185DB966B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Uses</header><text>The Secretary shall only allow those uses of the scenic areas that the Secretary determines would further the purposes described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE6C551CC1809478FA432458F8A95B245"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Federal land in the scenic areas is withdrawn from all forms of—</text> <paragraph id="HF46E81C1CA0B4DA2803AED6AF676AB65"><enum>(1)</enum><text>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC4454DA602854A1AB2EC5C9C87C443C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEFADD26F9A424424B1C6F8E63386FE47"><enum>(3)</enum><text>disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAAC6DD87268A416C8F953355613E2341"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Prohibited uses</header><text>The following shall be prohibited on the Federal land within the scenic areas:</text> <paragraph id="HC8F2C864C2C74E08B4F7496A9BB9CBB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Permanent roads.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4224F155A67643578902E1F28F4C6CC0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Permanent structures.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H68C9D4CBA27A4450B1766B3AC68EAECC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Timber harvesting except when necessary for the purposes described in subsection (g).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H29CB0DC19BD84214B638B029CFF98002"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Transmission lines.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H04677E574C4B45069E3D91958B7990CE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Except as necessary to meet the minimum requirements for the administration of the scenic areas and to protect public health and safety—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H634466BD51B54C0B88A99A2468E726F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the use of motorized vehicles; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD5F342286AD8445FBE87B271A4247B8A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the establishment of temporary roads.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD1580E051A9D4BF4956C89442D1E4276"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Commercial enterprises, except as necessary for realizing the purposes of the scenic areas.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEAF59A0F717B42A585A7FE1AF6EDC097"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Wildfire, insect, and disease management</header><text>Consistent with this section, the Secretary may take any measures in the scenic areas that the Secretary determines to be necessary to control fire, insects, and diseases, including, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, the coordination of those activities with the State or a local agency.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD7F42962500C46A581394509DE3F5A85"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Adjacent management</header><text>The fact that an otherwise authorized activity or use can be seen or heard within a scenic area shall not preclude the activity or use outside the boundary of the scenic area.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H2ADD5CBEE556493A8D6D77FC6853FA2E"><enum>8.</enum><header>Condor National Scenic Trail study</header> <subsection id="HA632CE09C88C46F6BBB3D5D4FD3F0F6A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall conduct a study that addresses the feasibility of, and alternatives for, connecting the northern and southern portions of the Los Padres National Forest by establishing a trail across the applicable portions of the northern and southern Santa Lucia Mountains of the southern California Coastal Range by designating the Condor National Scenic Trail as a component of the National Trails System.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE6099618CF1D46C6B60EBB2EE34F5C35"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In carrying out the study required under subsection (a), the Secretary of Agriculture shall—</text> <paragraph id="HE669EE252D33489DA7131134D5CF7762"><enum>(1)</enum><text>comply with the requirements for studies for a national scenic trail described in section 5(b) of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1244">16 U.S.C. 1244(b)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6D86DBA3873F421186859B0B6F559F69"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide for a continual hiking route through and connecting the southern and northern sections of the Los Padres National Forest;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C9FA34BD47E4700B74BFA842269CA45"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promote recreational, scenic, wilderness, and cultural values;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H72DB3768601C48CD84D86462CEFCB173"><enum>(4)</enum><text>enhance connectivity with the overall system of National Forest System trails;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA43405EA2A6D45DF97A7A743A3CA6509"><enum>(5)</enum><text>consider new connectors and realignment of existing trails;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8A8A7FAF2FA64E1DA686F055A93F66D4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>emphasize safe and continuous public access, dispersal from high-use areas, and suitable water sources; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E06E32D47A5422E9010EC8ABF265CFB"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, provide all-year use.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5DE75E3E5B974734A27D04579B2D65BC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional requirement</header><text>In completing the study required under subsection (a), the Secretary of Agriculture shall consult with—</text> <paragraph id="H19E6FF247F7A41538A76641538C62632"><enum>(1)</enum><text>appropriate Federal, State, Tribal, regional, and local agencies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HECA94C0B7BEE42CB8763DFA060B7E959"><enum>(2)</enum><text>private landowners;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06E8BDBA06F84DC1A0B1DEE410E351FA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>nongovernmental organizations; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA909C57A3BB24F01AF7D519C5BE4AA85"><enum>(4)</enum><text>members of the public.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBA4F5739D9F44FD784B4B30376E01625"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall submit the study required under subsection (a) to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8DA9B18EA60C43E088A5BC58B1158F97"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H03E7341EB7464EF8893CE042A83BE842"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HFAA036CD42714185BABD479DE17E9469"><enum>9.</enum><header>Forest service study</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture (acting through the Chief of the Forest Service) shall study the feasibility of opening a new trail, for vehicles measuring 50 inches or less, connecting Forest Service Highway 95 to the existing off-highway vehicle trail system in the Ballinger Canyon off-highway vehicle area.</text></section> <section id="HD2775BC039A44A17B26DCB55D471CB3B"><enum>10.</enum><header>Nonmotorized recreation opportunities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with interested parties, shall conduct a study to improve nonmotorized recreation trail opportunities (including mountain bicycling) on land not designated as wilderness within the Santa Barbara, Ojai, and Mt. Pinos ranger districts.</text></section> 
<section id="H65F77CE7DA224EAF8D70F7BBBF62D653"><enum>11.</enum><header>Use by members of Tribes</header> 
<subsection id="HAA5BABE51FA3407D9668919C764108DC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Access</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that Tribes have access, in accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), to the wilderness areas, scenic areas, and potential wilderness areas designated by this Act for traditional cultural and religious purposes.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7AB066B16309459480AA4532F6ED37D1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Temporary closures</header> <paragraph id="H51E8794649E549D8B05C841AE31287C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary, on request of a Tribe, may temporarily close to the general public one or more specific portions of a wilderness area, scenic area, or potential wilderness area designated by this Act to protect the privacy of the members of the Tribe in the conduct of traditional cultural and religious activities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1590B0CAFE694EB29D9C7E8106538B0B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Any closure under paragraph (1) shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="H71603A4708FE459AB8A9B9CD1D916795"><enum>(A)</enum><text>made in such a manner as to affect the smallest practicable area for the minimum period of time necessary for the activity to be carried out; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC363E7961F8D4A37BF303AB80C488255"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be consistent with the purpose and intent of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/341">Public Law 95–341</external-xref> (commonly known as the American Indian Religious Freedom Act) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1996">42 U.S.C. 1996</external-xref>) and the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

