<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL25667-YF2-T0-H0L">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2053 IS: To ensure that Write Your Own companies can sell private flood insurance products that compete with National Flood Insurance Program products.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2053</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> introduced the
                following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban
                    Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To ensure that Write Your Own companies can sell private flood insurance
            products that compete with National Flood Insurance Program products.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="H57A9B8315CD443EC9BFDC0322F678D24">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Prohibition on non-compete requirement for Write Your Own companies under the
                National Flood Insurance Program</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1345 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4081">42 U.S.C. 4081</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
            <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9DF5D858C6143F6A582009E3D77F08C">
                <subsection id="HC5E5333A1D2947FFB57A168894322FFF">
                    <enum>(f)</enum>
                    <header>Authority To provide other flood coverage</header>
                    <paragraph id="id823DF556BBE94F389B499BF09E34F09A">
                        <enum>(1)</enum>
                        <header>Write Your Own Program defined</header>
 <text>In this subsection, the term <term>Write Your Own Program</term> means the program under which the Federal Emergency Management Agency enters into a standard arrangement with private property insurance companies to—</text>
                        <subparagraph id="id09ABCC90E7454399A6F595D616821F62">
                            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>sell contracts for flood insurance coverage under this title under their own business lines of insurance; and</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="id5E44C28DA12D4391A8EB247FF924DDA9">
                            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>adjust and pay claims arising under the contracts described in subparagraph (A).</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="H88F58886A3E04E9D958052FE43F3610B">
                        <enum>(2)</enum>
                        <header>Prohibition on non-compete clause</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may not, as a condition of participating in the Write Your Own Program or in otherwise participating in the utilization by the Administrator of the facilities and services of insurance companies, insurers, insurance agents and brokers, and insurance adjustment organizations pursuant to the authority in this section, nor as a condition of eligibility to engage in any other activities under the National Flood Insurance Program under this title, restrict any such company, insurer, agent, broker, or organization from offering and selling private flood insurance (as that term is defined in section 102(b) of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4012a">42 U.S.C. 4012a(b)</external-xref>)).</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="H4182DE1D9B424CCAA1B495DFE2743F48">
                        <enum>(3)</enum>
                        <header>Financial assistance/subsidy arrangement</header>
 <text>After the date of enactment of this subsection, the Administrator may not include in any agreement entered into with any insurer for participation in the Write Your Own Program any provision establishing a condition prohibited under paragraph (2).</text>
                    </paragraph>
                </subsection>
                <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

