<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-CAN25611-M4M-7P-KP5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2080 IS: FLRAA Production Acceleration Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2080</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the Secretary of the Army to accelerate the procurement of the future long range assault aircraft by initiating early production of not more than 24 such aircraft, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H8BC531E679514557B7EA823C2B0681DF"><section section-type="section-one" id="H6D4DD7132DAF410E80FA55F6BAF2E743"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>FLRAA Production Acceleration Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD76C5AECE5914B0488432CED582B0079"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization to initiate early production of future long range assault aircraft</header><subsection id="HE231E04F60D148F8ADBDD02754D3E8DF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>The Secretary of the Army may enter into contracts, in advance of full-rate production, for the procurement of not more than 24 future long range assault aircraft as part of an accelerated low-rate early production effort.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE09CB2016CFC4C2CB892A99EF1DD95B3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text>In carrying out the early production effort described in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Army shall pursue the following objectives:</text><paragraph id="H400F428A11944B398168287EB0C044B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To expedite delivery of future long range assault aircraft operational capability to the warfighter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8EA5FCFBC5145848628524319FBFE3C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To maintain momentum and learning continuity between test article completion and full production ramp-up.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A73679DAF7C46B6A91462826525B18F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To stabilize and retain the specialized workforce and industrial base supporting future long range assault aircraft, including critical suppliers and production facilities in Texas, Kansas, and other States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59BD0082134B4E3789FEAFDFC6004511"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To mitigate cost escalation risks and improve program affordability across the life cycle.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB56F8AD5D7E343799A6263555AAA3B02"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In executing the authority provided by subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H0E643EE3DC2D4B6ABBDC77CFCED6A7D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prioritize program continuity, cost-efficiency, and workforce retention across the supply chain for tiltrotor aircraft;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A80508180524E769E19793AA778C15B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that aircraft procured as part of the early production effort described in subsection (a) incorporate lessons learned from test article evaluations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDA9A6B4E7CF491191FF8C39AB69EB1B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>maintain flexibility in design to accommodate future upgrades through the modular open systems architecture and digital backbone.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3E030C9C13164ADAA6929E8130675919"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Army shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report detailing—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAD6E68AA2F6F4DE49CC7266619113FDA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the implementation plan and timeline for the procurement and early production effort described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7715AED1552144F7985CD13D02B7F7E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the status of industrial base readiness and supply chain coordination; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5984B09257794102A6766125D9197A79"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">estimated long-term cost savings and operational benefits derived from such early production effort.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

