<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MUR25375-D3L-K1-4S7">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1920 IS: Continuous Skilled Nursing Quality Improvement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 1920</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250522">May 22, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr.
                    Sullivan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez
                Masto</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred
                to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on
                Finance</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to develop national quality
            standards for continuous skilled nursing services provided through Medicaid, and for
            other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="S1">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Continuous Skilled Nursing Quality Improvement Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcfa9fe954d0249f780adb7418a39876f">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc0b45688b8c14d048f9f5b367470e553"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Full-benefit dual eligible individual</header> <text>The term <term>full-benefit dual eligible individual</term> means an individual who is entitled to, or enrolled for, benefits under part A of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>), or enrolled for benefits under part B of title XVIII of such Act, and is eligible for medical assistance under the Medicaid program for full benefits under section 1902(a)(10)(A) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(10)(A)</external-xref>) or 1902(a)(10)(C) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(10)(C)</external-xref>), by reason of section 1902(f) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(f)</external-xref>), or under any other category of eligibility for medical assistance for full benefits, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idf8de07b280bb44a6b140e46009731b50">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Medicaid beneficiary</header>
 <text>The term <term>Medicaid beneficiary</term> means an individual who is eligible for, and enrolled in, a State Medicaid program.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id7de5b8a1e9cb4e34b0b1027db7204583">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Medicaid program</header>
 <text>The term <term>Medicaid program</term> means, with respect to a State, the State program under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) (including any waiver or demonstration under such title or under section 1115 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315">42 U.S.C. 1315</external-xref>) relating to such title).</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide0ab23fa0cbb4dc1b0f16b5643420f73">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Private duty nursing services</header>
 <text>The term <term>private duty nursing services</term> has the meaning given that term for purposes of section 1905(a)(8) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(a)(8)</external-xref>) (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id793011a2b90d419bbccdeefca44ed421">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Secretary</header>
 <text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida49fda0256f747fbaf4c14c60a850a05">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <header>State</header>
 <text>The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1101(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1301">42 U.S.C. 1301(a)</external-xref>) for purposes of title XIX of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="id176192daccfc49b59e7cc1064aca7331">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Redefining private duty nursing services provided through Medicaid</header>
            <subsection id="id285a9469cebe4f0da5d67c800e64696d">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Definition of medical assistance</header>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0e0a499525f94349bbce7bfc8b9d1f0d">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1905(a)(8) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S. 1396d(a)(8)) is amended by striking <quote>private duty nursing services;</quote> and inserting <quote>continuous skilled nursing services;</quote>.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfe3dc61c889946e3bbcbae39ef9a4fd6">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Effective date</header>
 <text>The amendment made by paragraph (1) takes effect on the date that is 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id152273cba8b74a24a8795989b89729bf">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Definition of continuous skilled nursing services</header>
 <text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, through notice and comment rulemaking, shall—</text>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida029addcd11e49588e709561ac4c925f">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">revise the definition of <quote>private duty nursing services</quote> in section 440.80 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations, to be <quote>continuous skilled nursing services</quote>; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e2472bc11a041d9847588c3b8938bc8">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require that such services under the Medicaid program provided to complex-care patients who require multiple hours of continuous nursing services per day, as determined by the State, are provided by a licensed nurse, including a registered nurse or a licensed practical nurse.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77f6a73671b8488a95d60a04d66f789b">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>Development of national quality standards for continuous skilled nursing
                services provided through Medicaid</header>
            <subsection id="id1bf894ad32e04262b263f6dac7bbe790">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall convene a working group that includes representatives of independent and national providers of private duty nursing services under the Medicaid program, other private duty nursing agencies, associations representing providers of continuous skilled nursing services, full-benefit dual eligible individuals, Medicaid beneficiaries, patient advocacy groups, officials of State Medicaid programs, private duty nursing accrediting bodies, and other relevant stakeholders, to develop and establish national quality standards for the purposes of improving the standard of care for private duty nursing services provided by States under the Medicaid program.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idb6a86fc0b0f545978bafee1edc9db7ae">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Ensuring clinically appropriate standards</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall issue a letter to State Medicaid Directors stating that providers of private duty nursing services under the Medicaid program are not required to adhere to conditions of participation for home health agencies under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="ideb7041da6139483d90319012b8fbe81f">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Publication of national standards</header>
 <text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the working group described in subsection (a) is first convened, the Secretary, after providing a period of public notice and opportunity for comment, shall publish the national quality standards developed by the working group for use by State Medicaid programs, managed care entities that enter into contracts with such programs, and providers of items and services under such programs.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="id22a0c414f00b4bcd90ab8c38b0a64f81">
            <enum>5.</enum>
            <header>Maintaining up-to-date continuous skilled nursing standards</header>
            <subsection id="id2fadf5c1caeb41b497bb8f86962849f9">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Updating home and community-Based waiver services</header>
 <text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, through notice and comment rulemaking, shall revise the list of services that are included as <quote>home and community-based waiver services</quote> under section 440.180(b) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations, to include continuous skilled nursing care services, as defined for purposes of section 1905(a)(8) of the Social Security Act (as amended by section 3(a)) under section 440.80 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (as revised after the application of section 3(b)).</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idf461310dd47342ec85d1c4e753b2c225">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Updating the home and community-Based services quality measure set</header>
                <paragraph id="id99ec8289495948d294250d5deda169fa">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall update and publish the HCBS Quality Measure Set, described in the State Medicaid Director Letter #22–003 issued on July 21, 2022, to include core and supplemental quality measures for continuous skilled nursing services for use by State Medicaid programs, managed care entities that enter into contracts with such programs, and providers of items and services under such programs.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id7ca7042851ca4d9da52a36cdf884e205">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Regular reviews and updates</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall review and update the core set and supplemental set of continuous skilled nursing services quality measures published under paragraph (1) not less frequently than every 8 years. Any such update shall include a period of public notice and opportunity for comment.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

