<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25027-HWH-WH-NFD"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S53 IS: Preventing the Recycling of Immigrants is Necessary for Trafficking Suspension Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 53</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250109">January 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to fingerprint noncitizen minors entering the United States who are suspected of being victims of human trafficking, to require the Secretary to publicly disclose the number of such minors who are fingerprinted by U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) officials and the number of child traffickers who are apprehended by CBP, to impose criminal penalties on noncitizen adults who use unrelated minors to gain entry into the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="idee832e86a81a4485afe7367d4fa1742c" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short titles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing the Recycling of Immigrants is Necessary for Trafficking Suspension Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PRINTS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3887a9e57dab404984989727fb92ecd5"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Authorization of fingerprinting of noncitizen children entering the United States to reduce child trafficking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 262(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1302">8 U.S.C. 1302(c)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7BE2F20AA34743E2BF0B08916F34178A"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a26471553c442fe9dd9843e5da637f7"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security, working through U.S. Customs and Border Protection, in order to reduce the number of children who are trafficked into the United States, shall obtain a set of fingerprints from any alien younger than 14 years of age who is entering the United States if a U.S. Customs and Border Protection officer suspects that such child is a victim of human trafficking, in accordance with the standards established pursuant to the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/7101">34 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H8FF278AF776040D89FA139ABE40BF0A3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Criminalizing recycling of minors</header><subsection id="HCA34E3C7B493427293D0113019364272"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/69">Chapter 69</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F3C65074AA44251B64A8B7425C6A898"><section id="HA5AAD93A2DE744038AA94C23A62282CA"><enum>1430.</enum><header>Recycling of minors</header><subsection id="HE005BF484CEE4E7E9ABAC0B2318766C4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person 18 years of age or older who knowingly uses, for the purpose of gaining entry into the United States, a minor to whom the individual is not a relative or guardian, shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4C7E810F9C5E4E90AEA85D072F275564"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relative</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>relative</term> means an individual related by consanguinity within the second degree, as determined by common law.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H4B12EB3A413D43398ECCD811BAED1803"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/69">chapter 69</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA99E47918D4A41F2A150BE48EF6EAAB6"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">1430. Recycling of minors.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id21b512a35cab4ab699c3f4f8ca5cadaf"><enum>4.</enum><header>Information sharing</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">With respect to any unaccompanied alien child (as defined in section 462(g) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/279">6 U.S.C. 279(g)</external-xref>)) who is transferred from the custody of the Secretary of Homeland Security to the custody of the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall, on request, share with the Secretary of Health and Human Services the fingerprints collected under section 262(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by section 2. </text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9bc39080ba9644eb81cca1311e31856b"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reports</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id797ee4061fa94ec1929a215e7fd47875"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Annual report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit an annual report to Congress that identifies the number of minors who were fingerprinted during the most recently completed fiscal year pursuant to the authority granted under section 262(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by section 2.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id78ec61906eba4f3a889c7918e4195979"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Online publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall post, on a monthly basis on a publicly accessible U.S. Customs and Border Protection website, the number of apprehensions during the previous month involving child traffickers who falsely claimed that a child accompanying them into the United States was a close relative.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

