<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H19DADC3B02CC46CAAE67EE383000614B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3721 IH: Indo-Pacific Treaty Organization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3721</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250604">June 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a Task Force on the Indo-Pacific Treaty Organization, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H701FCBAB98084AEBA5166564275919AD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCEDD1FE9EF4049A5939A4F604564BA16" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Indo-Pacific Treaty Organization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6F9AA4B6ABA44BE89C7ED6CC67230C54"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H03514A89307843079B53E03CC4870128"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For years, the People’s Republic of China (<quote>China</quote>), has repeatedly exhibited aggressive and irresponsible behavior towards the United States and its allies and partners in the Indo-Pacific. This includes establishing overseas military bases in the South China Sea, deploying ships and planes near Japan’s Senkaku Islands, invading Taiwan’s air space, and sending a high-altitude surveillance balloon over the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7150D343F55B47A888572FF65392EC38"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For years, the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (<quote>North Korea</quote>) has repeatedly exhibited aggressive and erratic behavior towards the United States and its allies and partners in the Indo-Pacific. This includes conducting missile tests dangerously close to South Korea and Japan as well as deepening ties with the Chinese Communist Party and other hostile regimes.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF5CBB4771C81432CBF33356F066752E5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Both China and North Korea pose significant risks to regional security in the Indo-Pacific, to United States security, and to international security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9266E062F374066B889796E599F8434"><enum>(4)</enum><text>It is critical that the United States work with allies and partners to proactively deter further aggression from China and North Korea to preserve peace, ensure prosperity, and advance democracy.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HCCC590919D994E648BE3F1E5159E0B5F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Task force</header>
<subsection id="H2B016E88881A4DD88462A7A313D5CB98"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall establish a task force, to be known as the <quote>Task Force on the Indo-Pacific Treaty Organization</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Task Force</quote>) to—</text> <paragraph id="HDD2F503D627748EB95796A7C2EEA1DB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>analyze the conduct of China and North Korea, as well as the security situation in the Indo-Pacific; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB8EBBC018E9B4B0FAFBFE0996326C316"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determine whether a collective security agreement between the United States and Indo-Pacific allies and partners could serve as an effective deterrent to further aggression.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8D9EE406FC25487ABC6B4DDF2CF5B2A8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allies and partners</header><text>The Indo-Pacific allies and partners described in subsection (a)(2) may include Japan, South Korea, the Philippines, Australia, Thailand, New Zealand, India, and any other country in the Indo-Pacific region the Task Force determines appropriate.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H17BEF81954CA4762B098D05133488D49"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Task Force established pursuant to subsection (a) shall be—</text> <paragraph id="H9530CACF6A364176B780718715FE9027"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">chaired by the Secretary of State; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H896F53F91C304C1CA181031C312A2055"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consist of the Secretary of Defense, Secretary of the Treasury, Secretary of Commerce, the Director of National Intelligence, the Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs, and the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Indo-Pacific Security Affairs.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H59747EADA957495482967E8F0F6BE9FE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the establishment of the Task Force, the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate a report that contains the results of the analysis described in subsection (a) and any recommendations of the Task Force with respect to the terms of such a collective security agreement.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

