<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-HLA25745-PX1-4J-0MW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 385 IS: Recognizing suicide as a serious public health problem and expressing support for the designation of September as “National Suicide Prevention Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 385</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250911">September 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing suicide as a serious public health problem and expressing support for the designation of September as <quote>National Suicide Prevention Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas suicide is the 11th leading cause of death in the United States and the second leading cause of death among individuals between 10 and 34 years of age;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>CDC</quote>), 1 individual in the United States dies by suicide every 11 minutes, resulting in around 49,000 deaths each year in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Department of Veterans Affairs, more than 6,400 veterans die by suicide annually, the equivalent of nearly 18 veteran suicides per day;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, between 1999 and 2022, the suicide rate in the United States increased by 36 percent from 10.5 suicides for every 100,000 individuals to 14.2 suicides for every 100,000 individuals;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is estimated that there are approximately 1,500,000 suicide attempts each year in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than half of individuals who die by suicide did not have a known mental health condition;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the CDC, many factors contribute to suicide among individuals with and without known mental health conditions, including challenges related to relationships, substance use, physical health, and stress regarding work, money, legal problems, or housing;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the CDC, suicide results in an estimated $70,000,000,000 each year in combined medical and work-loss costs in the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the stigma associated with mental health conditions and suicidality hinders suicide prevention by discouraging at-risk individuals from seeking life-saving help and can further traumatize survivors of suicide loss and individuals with lived experience of suicide: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id245c4909ddd64a7aa3619943d29b3087"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes suicide as a serious and preventable public health problem of the United States and each State;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idba68cbbe565048a88c2c894f398b4de5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the designation of September as <quote>National Suicide Prevention Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id00250f133351426f958c5f9b0726d741"><enum>(3)</enum><text>declares suicide prevention as a priority;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id958c89390f7042739ea41861bc3e3dbc"><enum>(4)</enum><text>acknowledges that no single suicide prevention program or effort will be appropriate for all populations or communities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id90fbd077170a4ebba27f9b186dbc43b9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>promotes awareness that there is no single cause of suicide; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id41662e4ce108469e8a0d00be9c644c38"><enum>(6)</enum><text>supports strategies to increase access to high-quality mental health and suicide prevention services and substance-use disorder treatments.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

