<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0F8D5E962810485C80F66A2D2CF1DB95" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 465 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Congress should enact the Older Americans Bill of Rights to establish that older Americans should have the right to live with dignity and with independence.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 465</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250603">June 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Congress should enact the Older Americans Bill of Rights to establish that older Americans should have the right to live with dignity and with independence.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the percentage of the United States population that is 65 years of age and older, including the percentage of aging veterans, is rapidly expanding, with 10,000 Americans turning age 65 every day;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Federal policies are needed that promote economic well-being and quality of life for older Americans across many different communities, recognizing race and ethnicity, sexual orientation, gender identity, cultural diversity, and the growing inequality between poor and wealthy families;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Social Security, Medicare, Medicaid, and the Older Americans Act of 1965 provide critical resources to aging Americans and their families but should be expanded and improved to meet growing needs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas prescription drug prices in the United States are more than 4 times higher on average than in other peer nations, a burden that disproportionately falls on older Americans, as almost 90 percent of adults 65 or older take a prescription drug;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas aging Americans deserve a dignified, secure, and independent retirement, but nearly half of all Americans 55 and older have no retirement benefits or savings;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas aging women (the majority of those over 65) live longer on average, are more likely to live in poverty, earn lower Social Security benefits, and are less likely to have pensions because of paycheck disparities, time spent out of the workforce for family caregiving responsibilities, and a greater chance of having worked low-wage jobs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas older Americans in rural, low-income, minority, Indian country, and other underserved communities may be especially vulnerable because of a lack of access to needed and affordable services that allow them to remain in their communities, including adequate transportation, functioning technology, and protected voting rights;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 5,900,00 older Americans lived in poverty in 2022; 6,900,000 seniors aged 60 and older Americans were food insecure in 2022; 138,000 older Americans over the age of 55 experienced homelessness in 2023, and more than 1 in 3 Americans between 50–80 years are socially isolated;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many older Americans are living longer, working longer, and enjoying healthier, more active lifestyles than past generations, while others are facing shorter lifespans and increased physical, mental, and psychological challenges;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas age-friendly movements are gaining momentum across the country in communities, health systems, and public health initiatives but are not yet fully aligned and coordinated to ensure maximum results;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 70 percent of those reaching age 65 will require long-term services and supports and will need to rely on family, friends, or paid caregivers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas by 2035 it is estimated that 1 in 3 households will be headed by someone aged 65 or older, but many older Americans face challenges in obtaining or keeping affordable, safe, and accessible housing;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nearly 6,000,000 children live in grandparent-headed households, and almost 3,000,000 are being raised by their grandparents;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas approximately 75 percent of Medicare beneficiaries who need a hearing aid do not have one; 70 percent of beneficiaries who have trouble eating because of their teeth did not go to the dentist in the past year; and 43 percent of beneficiaries who have trouble seeing did not have an eye exam in the past year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas older Americans are increasingly the victims of fraud, scams, exploitation, identity theft, and even physical and financial abuse, that threaten their dignity, security, and health; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the COVID–19 pandemic disproportionately burdened older Americans, resulting in over 850,000 deaths as of May 2023, millions of cases, and increased distress in adults aged 65 and older, especially those in congregate living facilities: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H9F2EB257DD80425B90C5EB1E8D59E6F3"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HB1516BF052BC4F40AEFCD774BB97545E"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that the Congress should enact the Older Americans Bill of Rights to establish that older Americans should have the right to live with dignity and with independence, including the right to—</text><paragraph id="HEC5D2E6282014A29A76589B16DD40976"><enum>(1)</enum><text>high-quality and affordable health care and long-term services and supports through—</text><subparagraph id="HA0CD71FCC32740E8A0E08E20242CA68C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>guaranteed access to equitable, comprehensive, geographically available, timely, safe, and dignified health care;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17E2E327C02C4BC6A7029201DB688257"><enum>(B)</enum><text>preserved, improved, and expanded Medicare and Medicaid benefits;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDC9264662C447E9AA752BCBEBDEA568"><enum>(C)</enum><text>lower prescription drug prices and increased drug price transparency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4571929621342179872BD0E36571AAB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>mechanisms to allow aging in place, including support for family and nonfamily caregivers, and expansion of the direct care workforce;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60CA804A40C8478CA0D31F7F81FA1237"><enum>(E)</enum><text>protection against neglect, abandonment, and domestic abuse;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FD8349151D74657AD99B645A187461F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>culturally and linguistically competent health care and social services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE178C104E6324B65A6C82D897D1ACD43"><enum>(G)</enum><text>health-promoting public health policies and programs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E9F7C06F3DA4AC28DFE34F4E5C093F6"><enum>(H)</enum><text>higher standards for skilled nursing facilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8404FB9B52A448208246622FA935654E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>increased access to palliative care; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA48CCFEBBDBD43F5BD7A7E9C30100844"><enum>(J)</enum><text>increased access to nutritional service;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA58E29083E2B4710B8DF4B614C5DE899"><enum>(2)</enum><text>financial and retirement security for themselves and their families, through—</text><subparagraph id="H0B2ED035FC8C4580B68F7292149C7C2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>preserved, improved, and expanded Social Security benefits;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD330F7F62311462C8DA57440E6F6BF46"><enum>(B)</enum><text>protection for pensions as earned benefits;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H145779F195934F2082D2F92B3F5CE15C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assistance in establishing retirement savings;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79E0705B1A7749A188723D7ADD3FAE75"><enum>(D)</enum><text>protection against financial exploitation, abuse, scams, and digital identity theft; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73E7681677B44B16A4C04533BB4351B7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>job training, volunteer opportunities, and enforcement of age discrimination in employment prohibitions;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H740B3AC816D44DCB8365FC9E06E3F271"><enum>(3)</enum><text>full participation in and contribution to their communities, through—</text><subparagraph id="HF6A30DDFA3C3466EBE39C2AEE4BDC5CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>accessible and affordable housing and transportation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B473ADBBEB44CED99E462C37AC499E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>equitable access to technology, including expanded broadband speed, affordability, and accessibility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB81EB7004EC427C8B1E568ABF0B0E5B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>social networking and other opportunities for digital engagement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58412BDB296C41C98EEE59FD34FF8EBB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the right to vote and improved polling location accessibility; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4650E477833D47888D1E690954EDA2A2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>culturally and linguistically competent and comprehensive home and community-based services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

