<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDDDE9636BBB44E95B005309C3299A5AC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 756 IH: 287(g) Program Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 756</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250128">January 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend section 287(g) of the Immigration and Nationality Act to clarify congressional intent with respect to agreements under such section, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBEF4B28DFD8A4957B53F06D1811E62B1" style="OLC"><section id="H6095EC45F08D41CC9C1160D95629A0CA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>287(g) Program Protection Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H3BBB13FF7F0E4BC7B9217BF32DC3DF96"><enum>2.</enum><header>Clarification of congressional intent</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 287(g) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1357">8 U.S.C. 1357(g)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H56B8E61D0B7946E3999BCC9211C13C75"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>the Attorney General may enter</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting the following: <quote>the Secretary of Homeland Security shall enter into a written agreement with a State, or any political subdivision of a State, upon request of the State or political subdivision, pursuant to which law enforcement officers of the State or subdivision, who are determined by the Secretary to be qualified to perform a function of an immigration officer in relation to the investigation, apprehension, or detention of aliens in the United States (including the transportation of such aliens across State lines to detention centers), may carry out such function at the expense of the State or political subdivision. No request from a bona fide State or political subdivision or bona fide law enforcement agency shall be denied absent a compelling reason, and the Secretary shall notify the Congress and publish in the Federal Register an explanation for those reasons at least 180 days in advance of making final the denial. No limit on the number of agreements under this subsection may be imposed. The Secretary shall process requests for such agreements with all due haste, and in no case shall more than 90 days elapse from the date the request is made until the agreement is consummated. For purposes of this subsection, any reference to a political subdivision shall be construed to include any law enforcement or corrections agency of the political subdivision.</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53A48E03099645B19553F6E0DFDDADB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>Secretary</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD65642F6DB44DFC9591523692AD2028"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) through (10) as paragraphs (5) through (13), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91135358FF744B3385A06BF1B4C88CC4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H1FE7E34D39844C32B0CCC4C629270A5F" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HB53A18D744D1493FB70101EB9D4C0843"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An agreement under this subsection shall accommodate a requesting State or political subdivision with respect to the enforcement model or combination of models, and shall accommodate a patrol model, task force model, jail model, any combination thereof, or any other reasonable model the State or political subdivision believes is best suited to the immigration enforcement needs of its jurisdiction.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H166E3BC47FBD45C4B7B337CE098ECB09"><enum>(3)</enum><text>No Federal program or technology directed broadly at identifying inadmissible or deportable aliens shall substitute for such agreements, including those establishing a jail model, and shall operate in addition to any agreement under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBA803191400418FAE78F4DB8B1AE4BD"><enum>(4)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3516C28866444061B9E74F668EECEFE1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No agreement under this subsection may be terminated absent a compelling reason.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B94D7AE863C4440AFBAA97E9650BF16" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA13FF1F542144B15A1BADD8784BC4EDA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Secretary shall provide a State or political subdivision written notice of intent to terminate at least 180 days prior to date of intended termination, and the notice shall fully explain the grounds for termination, along with providing evidence substantiating the Secretary’s allegations.</text></clause><clause id="HA6EB6C276FF24AA1B25DD21E2B7ADAA0" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to determine whether the requirements of this paragraph have been satisfied, the State or political subdivision shall have the right—</text><subclause id="H1F23D53A86B548D9B9A09DF44A7AEB01"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to appeal the decision of the Secretary to an administrative law judge for a hearing and decision; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H68F673766F4849218E8B29CCC0338E88"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to bring a civil action in an appropriate court of jurisdiction.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AE11B5D7A5B4FB7B6E0AF33A90A6C10" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The agreement shall remain in full effect during the course of any and all legal proceedings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9B1A67A858F430BBC28C00EE8EF4CC8"><enum>(5)</enum><text> in paragraph (6) (as redesignated), by adding at the end the following: <quote>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall implement uniform training requirements for law enforcement officers who are, or will be, performing a function of an immigration officer under this subsection. The training requirements shall align with Federal Law Enforcement Training Center standards for training under this subsection (as in effect of the date of the enactment of this sentence).</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC20052185EE04D63B6B5EA0431DE138E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 286(r) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1356">8 U.S.C. 1356(r)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB3473D1BB74240DB8519947862DD012C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Breached Bond/Detention Fund</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Breached Bond/Detention/287<enum-in-header>(g)</enum-in-header> Fund</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEED957C1C7CE43D9AA9E9AC15E09AC22"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>Secretary of Homeland Security</quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3985C19B7C54B309D556FEF22E77F0A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>Breached Bond/Detention</quote> and inserting <quote>Breached Bond/Detention/287(g)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94B61377911342E184F79870357D42D8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>Department of Justice</quote> and inserting <quote>Department of Homeland Security</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB58DA83B93824AD1ACCF3CB18ECB816A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text><subparagraph id="HD11528EB3315431A811900450007327F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>, and</quote> at the end and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59267D49B9974E1EA6521503D4B215A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE323BC0A1F294EB19CE71224CC47B7FF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H20B7CBABE3E943BC8FB75638446DD2C6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="HF50309F125DA43DF8464C75DDFF28653" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for expenses associated with administering section 287(g).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HF691E7C185C34BB7BB841D65AA4FDF3D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Requirements on Secretary</header><subsection id="H9C49347A07244F5EB56375B766F9C5EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual performance report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31 of the first fiscal year that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not later than December 31 of each year thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall publish an annual performance report on the program under section 287(g) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1357">8 U.S.C. 1357(g)</external-xref>) that includes at least the following information:</text><paragraph id="H7ED1A19E8D5F4429BD28FE5C7D6B9B61"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of aliens apprehended and screened by law enforcement through the program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1546E6F4AA8440AF8729A52320AC77CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of aliens removed from the United States as a result of the program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FEB4CF032DD4F81A6F35A8E4545EB72"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of aliens described in paragraph (1) who were not removed and an explanation for why they were not removed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC8294A5613E441C9B22716D6A47A0BC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The methods being used to conduct oversight of each law enforcement agency participating under the program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EADFEC7123F46A8B7DBA9156C2409D2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The number of law enforcement agencies in compliance with the program’s training requirements.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8450D2C1D1394D6C80029F7475A4EA8C"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of complaints filed against law enforcement agencies claiming they did not comply their written agreement entered into under such section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D6BC56686DC4E63960F0E661CB4561A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The number of law enforcement agencies that had such written agreement terminated.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF116A70B04584DDFBF186C5A656C72BE"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The reasons for such termination.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC1748C62A6D546BC8F666DEBB2B64186"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual recruitment plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31 of the first fiscal year that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not later than December 31 of each year thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall publish an annual recruitment plan with respect to the program under section 287(g) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1357">8 U.S.C. 1357(g)</external-xref>) that includes at least the following information:</text><paragraph id="H269FA5FE9EB04E6681895ECE9764AFA4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Annual goals for the next five years for recruitment of new States and political subdivisions of States to participate in the program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H999B58FC91964917A183FF653A8EE0DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of new States and political subdivisions of States participating in the program each year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1BCE6B80C5546C99E75EDFB31643588"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the outreach to States and political subdivisions of States conducted for the program and the other methods used to achieve recruitment goals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6A1D0537DF9430E87083D9FE84ABAC2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The number of requests for agreements received, approved, denied, and pending approval.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H903EC2B1AAF644EAA83B30996CA39CB5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall publish a notice of rulemaking with respect to the training requirements under section 287(g)(6) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1357">8 U.S.C. 1357(g)(6)</external-xref>), as added by section 2(5).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

