<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H1BAF57858CF3431CBC21727FF8077E08"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1170 IH: Congressional Access to Military Posts Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1170</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250210">February 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000388">Mr. Kelly of Mississippi</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for expedited access to certain military installations of the Department of Defense for Members of Congress and certain Congressional employees.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H482F3095AD86450FA98D95D97BC151E3"><section id="H90EA4845E1654893BF7A18C4294D49AC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Congressional Access to Military Posts Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8FABAB0C4A7146B89DED49D991086CE4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expedited access to certain military installations of the department of defense for members of congress and certain congressional employees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/159">Chapter 159</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="HD2D50B732A39449EB912124886D65D43" style="USC"><section id="H06551DFF04444ACD970224F8A68F966E"><enum>2698.</enum><header>Expedited access to military installations for Members of Congress and certain Congressional employees</header><subsection id="H3B4D08FFC00A4F8593181EB5450F085D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), the Secretary shall establish procedures to ensure that—</text><paragraph id="H07A15DBE736D41A4B0D83D2DE4B72B11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a Member of Congress seeking access to a covered installation is granted such access if such Member presents a covered identification card; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50BD45D28C3540DAA7E59D3AE5076E9B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any Congressional employees accompanying a Member of Congress granted access under paragraph (1) are granted the same access.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD137EB296B34495E9D07EAA95BE33A60"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibited procedures</header><text>Under such procedures, the Secretary may not require a Member of Congress to schedule a grant of access to a covered installation under subsection (a) prior to the arrival of such Member and accompanying Congressional employees, if applicable, at such covered installation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2DD754F096BF453DB96448649DE30155"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H7C827DB8EC1B4CB7A3DC53E4D758CA71"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>Congressional employee</quote> has the meaning given such term in paragraph (5) of section 2107 of title 5.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H92DF9041DC1547BCAC7FA1AF18ECAB24"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered identification card</quote> means a valid identification badge issued by the appropriate office of the House of Representatives or the Senate, as the case may be, which identifies the individual to which such identification badge was issued as a current Member of Congress.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91C2BF97162A4FD4BFFCF563133119B1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered installation</quote> means a military installation located in the United States or Guam at which the presentation of an issued Department of Defense common access card is the sole requirement for a member of the Armed Forces to be granted access to such military installation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD20E04D383DF4308A0E3927EA7F95632"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <quote>Member of Congress</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H5A792F3E24DA462B89F1F1E708CD3119"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Senator; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8604D16F6BEE4CF1BD05DF52897E5C9A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, Congress.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

