<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6F47EBD4E25140D49C3E5777A65CC431" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1200 IH: Freight Rail Assets Investment to Launch Commercial Activity Revitalization Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1200</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250211">February 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000585">Mr. LaHood</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001082">Mr. Hern of Oklahoma</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001126">Mr. Carey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001224">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. S&#225;nchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000601">Mr. Goldman of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000600">Mr. Diaz-Balart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000480">Mr. Fong</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a tax credit to encourage the replacement or modernization of inefficient, outdated freight railcars, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H198738BBF47346D38606B299A46E6B98" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE7FF7228983242FF87B743CC045192CE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Freight Rail Assets Investment to Launch Commercial Activity Revitalization Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Freight RAILCAR Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAF8374B033744686B679FA116D86B122"><enum>2.</enum><header>Freight railcar modernization credit</header> <subsection id="HCF3B5077D3324AD3B605A168FED1FF0B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H1D271B4586F6481CADC01500644080A8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H78DB2584FD674C6EA319789BD666D122"><enum>45BB.</enum><header>Freight railcar modernization credit</header> 
<subsection id="H26CBEEEEBFC64921BDA707061A3CF824"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of section 38, the freight railcar modernization credit determined under this section for the taxable year is an amount equal to 10 percent of the taxpayer’s freight railcar fleet modernization expenses.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0E7D00A4303C469E89AFFDDF2D4F721E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>No more than 1,000 qualified freight railcars per taxpayer may be taken into account for purposes of determining the credit under subsection (a) with respect to a taxable year. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4948F1A113CF45CF8A3AAA1B59212BB9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="HBF554E78750E4C7BA450EA88175B7A42"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Freight railcar fleet modernization expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>freight railcar fleet modernization expenses</quote> means the sum of the qualifying railcar replacement and modernization amount.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC0B9A079B255496F83DDA0A059319E37"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifying railcar replacement and modernization amount</header><text>The term <quote>qualifying railcar replacement and modernization amount</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HCF55C27790274D63B7F0C6DA87810ADD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the basis of any qualified newly built replacement railcar placed in service by the taxpayer during the taxable year, plus</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2191A6B369EB44F7BF6089BCF102F2C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the qualified railcar modernization expenditures of the taxpayer for the taxable year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5C940F23456E4975BC92A33E217AF5A1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified newly built replacement railcar</header><text>The term <quote>qualified newly built replacement railcar</quote> means a qualified freight railcar which—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF862B65524C14287B0BBD92A864D1AB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is built after the date of the enactment of this section,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H40C9D25AB474408C936D08DFF9540950"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is ordered or originally placed in service before the date that is three years after the date of the enactment of this section, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE084FBC54CA54D2CBC14E29B9C31D4D9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>replaces two freight railcars owned by the taxpayer that—</text> <clause id="H3090DA6102354126BDFA2FC5B71FFCC9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>were in service within the 48 months preceding the beginning of the taxable year, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H874A5B805FD54E1FAB97752029EBEEAF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which were both scrapped and permanently removed from the AAR Umler System master file during such taxable year.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9317BEDD76784BC18FB0DEE4888FEF51"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualified freight railcar</header> <subparagraph id="HD135B52ABB3E47DF8CBC341B10ACD189"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>qualified freight railcar</quote> means a freight railcar that—</text> 
<clause id="H350EC81323AF4516867E5F1DC90FA5ED"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is either acquired or modernized by the taxpayer after the date of the enactment of this section,</text></clause> <clause id="H66D16D62EB88442DA11103F0338997E8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meets the significant improvement requirements for capacity, fuel efficiency, or performance of subparagraph (B),</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF3FF75195DBD4C01B20A0DCC062EF1FB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>was built in a qualified facility, and</text></clause> <clause id="H486A6C8A90DF49E79E76870B890C6CD3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>with respect to which no credit under this section was previously claimed by any taxpayer.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8B981BD77D4F4523AC32B9C37C42D80E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Significant improvement</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, an improvement in capacity or fuel efficiency and performance with respect to a modernized freight railcar is a significant improvement if—</text> <clause id="H3A3F79033A07452AB048BA883E3AF863" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such capacity or fuel efficiency, as the case may be, is increased by at least 8 percent, or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4F4DFA76A4404176B98AC0D94EB2BF6A" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of performance, the qualified freight railcar meets the requirements of the Association of American Railroads Standard S–286 or is modernized to meet the design standards set forth in final rule HM–251 of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration (as amended by HM–251C).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE3A4F8E2DD2046729DB73692899BBF78"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Modernized</header><text>The term <quote>modernized</quote> means modified, retrofitted, converted or rebuilt for the purpose of meeting the significant improvement criteria of subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC1349708275740B1A25A0B995905DE09"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Qualified railcar modernization expenditure</header><text>The term <quote>qualified railcar modernization expenditure</quote> means any amount paid or incurred—</text> <subparagraph id="HEF27D96F94B045F09F7C5A05FA81ED40"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in connection with the modernization of a freight railcar resulting in such railcar being designated a qualified freight railcar, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H22F55C69CCF848DFB7D2FC26A2D3BAB8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which is properly chargeable to a capital account with respect to such freight railcar.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B5838781A8E4263B37AB9BDBA9813DA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Qualified facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>qualified facility</quote> means a facility that is not owned or leased by an entity that would be ineligible for an award of a contract or subcontract under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/5323">49 U.S.C. 5323(u)</external-xref>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAD0AEB889EC1489689250E9488087073"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Special rules</header> 
<paragraph id="HF701BC17E8FF4569958BCEC8A39A47FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No credit shall be allowed under subsection (a) for any expense for which a deduction or credit is allowed under any other provision of this chapter.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H988B011AEBCE468B9918FDBF0CA761DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Basis adjustment</header><text>For purposes of this subtitle, if a credit is allowed under subsection (a) with respect to any qualified freight railcar, the basis of such railcar shall be reduced by the amount of the credit so allowed.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4FBED52EBB984381B2B605D066716F7F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sale-leaseback</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), if any qualified freight railcar is—</text> <subparagraph id="H78F54C1CACAB4C9E9A7651E7C5973CC2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>originally placed in service by a person after the date of the enactment of this section, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC6A8382B78A1407DB17F0C2705BDF4D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sold and leased back by such person within 3 months after such railcar is originally placed in service (or, in the case of more than one railcar subject to the same lease, within 3 months after the date the final railcar is placed in service, so long as the period between the time the first railcar is placed in service and the time the last railcar is placed in service does not exceed 24 months), such railcar shall be treated as originally placed in service not earlier than the date on which such railcar is used under the leaseback referred to in this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB92A5CCE1E614144ABE9DFEEB8D53AE8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Syndication</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBE30659813E94E879D23684B0DFA9FBD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any qualified freight railcar is originally placed in service after the date of enactment of this section by the lessor of such railcar,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C1CF1D2670240C787028FBAFB02264C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such railcar is sold by such lessor or any subsequent purchaser within 3 months after the date such railcar was originally placed in service (or, in the case of more than one railcar subject to the same lease, within 3 months after the date the final railcar is placed in service and the time the last railcar is placed in service does not exceed 12 months), and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBB9B3625C0AB4B5291F575C6E1A4110C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the user of such railcar after the last sale during such 3-month period remains the same as when such railcar was originally placed in service, such railcars shall be treated as originally placed in service not earlier than the date of such last sale.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H44FA1D2E162B437B89E0CD41EA59C063"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Entities owned or controlled by state-owned enterprises ineligible</header><text>No credit under subsection (a) shall be allowed to any taxpayer that would be ineligible for an award of a contract or subcontract under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/5323">49 U.S.C. 5323(u)</external-xref>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H683C00A7B41E4B8E9DB817305E665564"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall not apply to any qualifying railcar replacement and modernization amount after the date that is three years after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HB21192661529424CB946EABE99331103"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit allowed as business credit</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/38">Section 38(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to current year business credit) is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (40), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (41) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote> and by inserting at the end thereof the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H579E509CB1E94D5AA34B51606DCA90E9" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H439EB4E825FF49CF9AD6007D125A773D"><enum>(42)</enum><text>the freight railcar modernization credit determined under section 45BB.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H03B70273E5C3413D8EBE2EBADC83C2CD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination with section 55</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/38">Section 38(c)(4)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating clauses (x), (xi), and (xii) as clauses (xi), (xii), and (xiii), respectively, and by inserting after clause (ix) the following new clause:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H91A50EDFADFC4280A18D25E2D36BEE5A" style="OLC"> 
<clause id="HCF568AD6FFC54584BEACF0544BC7E564"><enum>(x)</enum><text>the freight railcar modernization credit determined under section 45BB,</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HAC4EE6945296436BB35028A6C94BAD0A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 45AA the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HF85382E9CCFD4EA8B06A8136653EE018" style="OLC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 45BB. Freight railcar modernization credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF20C38F3126D42069299EAE29821AE0B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to property placed in service, and amounts paid or incurred, after December 31, 2024.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H11A29CFEE3994AF8ADC5C4558B9864B6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on the freight railcar modernization credit</header> <subsection id="H2C9BB0CF3B264F9BB398A6E3DFCDD624"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate), shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report on activity with respect to the qualified freight railcar credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45BB">section 45BB</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H339F433EF6904837856AD23AA7E2DB16"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report contents</header><text>The report submitted under subsection (a) shall contain information with respect to the following:</text> <paragraph id="H94B51F430BFB442CA26349BD96E77434"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of times the credit was claimed.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF4B7648E14F4EF1B30D3321C9F79534"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of railcars scrapped as a result of the credit.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBBC29A21B7D64773ACC584DD19EAE2E6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of new railcars entered into contract as a result of the credit.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4FF3A017C3AA4B538A7E39FD5D26FA67"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The number of new railcars built as a result of the credit.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

