<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD820DAA160A248F0B5564095D3025567" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2635 IH: Uyghur Policy Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2635</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250403">April 3, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To support the human rights of Uyghurs and members of other minority groups residing primarily in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region and safeguard their distinct identity, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H3461773828344D2398EF43B1A0770599" style="OLC">
<section id="H81E1A1C2C4C04005B518A2B186DFCFD2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Uyghur Policy Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA0E93C57EE314B07B1C6D559A8E94D0B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HBE9A63D129314E8FBF96CB6B15CD91A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The People’s Republic of China (PRC) continues to repress the distinct Islamic, Turkic identity of Uyghurs and members of other ethnic and religious minority groups in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region (XUAR) in northwestern China and other areas of their habitual residence.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H495C5C08E20549CE814A8F25312819AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Uyghurs, and other predominantly Muslim ethnic minorities historically making up the majority of the XUAR population, have maintained throughout their history a distinct religious and cultural identity.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H87009EE995AE432EBD76AB8919CC0B24"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Human rights, including freedom of religion or belief, and respect for the Uyghurs’ unique Muslim identity are legitimate interests of the international community.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D139BB75E8D4CB493D93EF733F5633D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The PRC has ratified the International Covenant on Economic, Social, and Cultural Rights, and is thereby bound by its provisions. The PRC has also signed the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA2B0A9FC8985475391BA46FEB5D35444"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An official campaign to encourage Han Chinese migration into the XUAR has placed immense pressure on those who seek to preserve the ethnic, cultural, religious, and linguistic traditions of the Uyghurs and other ethnic and religious minority groups.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H70E77A76169C4BF291BD063E230E76AB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>PRC authorities have supported an influx of Han Chinese economic immigrants into the XUAR, implemented discrimination against Uyghurs and other minorities in hiring practices, and provided unequal access to healthcare services.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF74B7F5A61B94A06A7C7B683AF8193F3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>PRC authorities have manipulated the strategic objectives of the international war on terror to mask their increasing cultural and religious oppression of the Muslim population residing in the XUAR.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB4799A714A1B4EDDA6E292CFBCEFBEB6"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Following unrest in the region, in 2014, Chinese authorities launched their <quote>Strike Hard against Violent Extremism</quote> campaign, in which dubious allegations of widespread extremist activity were used as justification for gross human rights violations committed against Uyghurs and members of other minority communities in the XUAR.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFB5D686A98674F2E899E71BBF1CA4AD8"><enum>(9)</enum><text>PRC authorities have made use of the legal system as a tool of repression, including for the imposition of arbitrary detentions and for torture against members of the Uyghur community and other minority populations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0EB609E1E1C548E8803BC81967EE3271"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Uyghurs and Kazakhs who have secured citizenship or permanent residency outside of the PRC have attested to repeated threats, harassment, and surveillance by PRC officials.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7A92DFDBF6A94590B5B498659EB5E41E"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Reporting from international news organizations has found that over the past decade, family members of Uyghurs and other minority groups living outside of the PRC have gone missing or been detained to force Uyghur expatriates to return to the PRC or silence their dissent.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D42C439A21742ED876D09CA185259B1"><enum>(12)</enum><text>In 2017, Radio Free Asia’s Uyghur Service was the first media organization to report on the PRC’s vast, mass arbitrary-detention program in the XUAR in 2017.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H298E12CC19A946C28CB4C8D6394A05A5"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Credible evidence from human rights organizations, think tanks, and journalists confirms that more than 1,000,000 Uyghurs and members of other ethnic minority groups have been imprisoned in extrajudicial <quote>political reeducation</quote> centers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF1701D49D96A4954950493B574F1E137"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Independent accounts from former detainees of <quote>political reeducation</quote> centers describe inhumane conditions and treatment including forced political indoctrination, torture, beatings, rape, forced sterilization, and food deprivation.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7968C7702D34421198C133BFDED0B9FA"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Former detainees also confirmed that they were told by guards that the only way to secure release was to demonstrate sufficient political loyalty to the PRC Government.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF973B568C894AEBAE09176BCC0C8DAA"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Popular discourse surrounding the ongoing atrocities in the XUAR and advocacy efforts to assist Uyghurs remains muted in most Muslim majority nations around the world.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H88AD1AE12BC140DABCF0EB2E95A68123"><enum>(17)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Former Secretary of States Antony Blinken and Michael Pompeo and Secretary of State Marco Rubio confirmed that the PRC Government has committed genocide and crimes against humanity against Uyghurs and other ethnic and religious minorities in the XUAR.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87676AA1EF634FCC832141E06CEB13B7"><enum>(18)</enum><text>Government bodies of multiple nations have also declared that PRC Government’s atrocities against such populations in the XUAR constitute genocide, including the parliaments of the United Kingdom, Belgium, Czechia, Lithuania, the Netherlands, and Canada.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HE93B84D8611C43A8A21344AB107DA85D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the Sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HEAB5362E01704D43888F22481AD85562"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Government of the People’s Republic of China should immediately open the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region (XUAR) to regular, transparent, and unmanipulated visits by members of the press, international organizations including the Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights, academic and human rights research institutions, as well as foreign delegations including from the United States Congress;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H29766C701ADB4A059D6C916E9558AC96"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Government of the People’s Republic of China should recognize, and take tangible steps to protect and preserve, the distinct ethnic, cultural, religious, and linguistic identity of Uyghurs and members of other ethnic and religious minority groups in the XUAR;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA34F739663014A68953A5392F41B7FC8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Government of the People’s Republic of China should cease all government-sponsored crackdowns, imprisonments, and detentions of people throughout the XUAR aimed at repressing their ethnic, cultural, political, or religious identities;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6D78818B54644BD2A9F94C15A4FB9B44"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Government of the People’s Republic of China should cease all government-sponsored transnational repression of Uyghurs, including the detainment, harassment, intimidation, and surveillance of the family members of exiled Uyghurs and Uyghur activists;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H12B5881777DD4E1DA37546887CB0281C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>it is commendable for countries to provide shelter and hospitality to Uyghurs and other minority group members in exile, as Turkey, Albania, and Germany have done;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0A1CE00577834D72899B8693A9A5F152"><enum>(6)</enum><text>urges all countries, especially fellow democracies and those with sizeable Muslim populations, to condemn and address the plight of Uyghurs and other minority communities in the XUAR;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H09E4416D19084F42AE033E5C079D9C31"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Government of the People’s Republic of China should immediately and unconditionally release all prisoners that have been detained for their ethnic, cultural, religious, and linguistic identities, for expressing their political or religious beliefs in the XUAR, or for being related to members of the Uyghur diaspora or activist community including—</text>
<subparagraph id="H919ED1EBB98E45D58852E3D0C9CFB5D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Ekper Asat, who participated in the Department of State’s International Visitors Leadership Program in 2016, was incarcerated after returning to the XUAR, and is now serving a 15 year prison sentence on charges of <quote>inciting ethnic hatred and ethnic discrimination</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEE4AC28D2864455685FCC8F1D504D519"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Dr. Gulshan Abbas, a retired medical doctor and Uyghur, who was wrongfully detained in the XUAR on September 11, 2018, and unjustly sentenced to 20 years in prison in retaliation for her sister’s advocacy for Uyghur human rights issues; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDAC9D827761F4679A732ED72F41A66A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Kamile Wayit, a university student and Uyghur, who was wrongfully detained on December 12, 2022, after returning to the XUAR while on break from studying during the winter holiday;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA8F146513DD04CC59C4EDDC1C0E200B6"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Government of the People’s Republic of China should facilitate access for international humanitarian organizations, including the International Federation of Red Cross and Red Crescent Societies, to the <quote>political reeducation</quote> centers in the XUAR to ensure prisoners are not being mistreated and are receiving necessary medical care; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF563C4BD925A41A89A152131C166D0AF"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the Department of State should continue to facilitate the unhindered dissemination of information to the international community on issues regarding the human rights, religious freedom, and transnational repression of Uyghurs and members of other minority groups in the XUAR.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HF023E135A5D145EC8733E708EA80830D"><enum>4.</enum><header>United States strengthening of coordination on Uyghur issues</header> <subsection id="H0202BBBE71544D4AAD04E1B98C3661E4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State, as appropriate, shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H758C1E8206B64094A87D0B3B157B8432"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prioritize policies, programs, and projects to support the Uyghurs and members of other ethnic and religious minority groups in the XUAR;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE07EA82A839D4A9EBBA08E61F2CDC29E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>vigorously promote the policy of seeking to protect the distinct ethnic, religious, cultural, and linguistic identity of the Uyghurs and other minority groups and seek improved protection of human rights in the XUAR;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5BC1D6EC9EF94028902078F85B7798A9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>direct the State Department to maintain close contact with Uyghur religious, cultural, and political leaders, including seeking regular travel to the XUAR and to Uyghur populations in Central Asia, Turkey, Albania, Germany, and other parts of Europe;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF70A25A4F63A41FE99AE1C01F08CD42E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>lead coordination efforts for the release of political prisoners in the XUAR who are being detained for exercising their human rights or being relatives of exiled Uyghurs;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4F74BE838F674CA7B30471244F71B214"><enum>(5)</enum><text>consult with the United States Congress on policies relevant to the XUAR and the Uyghurs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H244E308EDC0E4A1EB6ABA1679369DE55"><enum>(6)</enum><text>coordinate with relevant Federal agencies to administer aid to Uyghur rights advocates; </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0B05ABE565204B5BA9A2ABEE05B61B95"><enum>(7)</enum><text>make efforts to establish contacts with foreign ministries of other countries, especially in Europe, Central Asia, and members of the Organisation of Islamic Cooperation, to pursue a policy of promoting greater respect for human rights and religious freedom for Uyghurs and other ethnic and religious minority groups from the XUAR;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF214A978AF44FE8AD3E58D4F2EE33E0"><enum>(8)</enum><text>utilize the Organisation of Islamic Cooperation and United States Strategic Dialogue to address Uyghur rights, working with the Organisation of Islamic Cooperation individual member states to develop and implement joint initiatives and programs aimed at promoting awareness of Uyghur rights, and support Uyghur victims of detainment, harassment, and transnational repression;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD3C174ED78CE44B3B1CEB9515D7D69AD"><enum>(9)</enum><text>support independent media authorized under PL 111/202 22 U.S.C. 6208 of the 111th Congress that conduct reporting and investigative journalism focused on the XUAR, including in local languages, to ensure that further PRC human rights abuses are reported on;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA2AE9344FB942229027CA79E00AE884"><enum>(10)</enum><text>work with international partners to raise awareness concerning acts of transnational repression against Uyghur Americans or Uyghurs exiled in the United States;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB05A4A7FEBDC4DDE859A3C7C931C9CAA"><enum>(11)</enum><text>develop and implement strategies to prevent and respond to the transnational repression of Uyghur Americans and Uyghurs exiled in the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HACCEA520D7D644CFB6CBE46AFC142DAC"><enum>(12)</enum><text>establish a reporting mechanism for individuals to report incidents of transnational repression; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA7D34F177B6F462EB6F85B41D47C0EFD"><enum>(13)</enum><text>submit an annual report, including a classified annex if necessary, to Congress on actions taken by the United States to address and prevent transnational repression against Uyghurs in the United States, and recommendations for further legislative or policy measures.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5A95926A512D45459A86B5B4E271A6D7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Support</header><text>The Secretary of State shall ensure the Department of State has adequate resources, staff, and administrative support to carry out this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HE5D386880630478FA02F1D37E6E82DAA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>This section shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HB85F4C7298F040B0A24454D260852BBB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Funding for human rights advocates to conduct public diplomacy in the Islamic world on the Uyghur situation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated for the United States Speaker Program of the Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs of the Department of State, $250,000 for each of fiscal years 2025, 2026, and 2027 is authorized to be made available to support human rights advocates working on behalf of the Uyghurs and members of other ethnic and religious minority groups from the XUAR that are persecuted in the PRC, whose names may be provided by the Department of State in consultation with representatives of the global Uyghur community, to speak at global public diplomacy forums, particularly those in which Organisation of Islamic Cooperation countries and other Muslim-majority countries are present, on issues regarding the human rights and religious freedom of Uyghurs and members of other ethnic and religious minority groups persecuted in the PRC.</text></section>
<section id="H17D33E7CC90B4F57BA07FF37DA1549C7"><enum>6.</enum><header>No additional funds authorized</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to carry out the requirements of this Act. Such requirements shall be carried out using amounts otherwise authorized.</text></section> <section id="H5DFAC938DD154DD884E133B07BDB2498"><enum>7.</enum><header>Access to detention facilities and prisons and the release of prisoners</header> <subsection id="HE34F4B8D2321409C843368F56985C54E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy on political reeducation and detention facilities</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, develop a strategy to cooperate with like-minded partners to pressure the People’s Republic of China to—</text>
<paragraph id="HC370037BD4C84D538899B96A2ACA76A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>close all detention facilities and <quote>political reeducation</quote> camps housing Uyghurs and members of other ethnic minority groups in the XUAR;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE54D0B0EF5AE44699C44C79887919F99"><enum>(2)</enum><text>allow unhindered access to detention facilities and <quote>political reeducation</quote> camps in the XUAR by independent media, researchers, international organizations and the Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights for a comprehensive assessment of the human rights situation; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB92D30AF64774307A0F4B35A108DC8A6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>protect human rights and preserve the distinct religious and cultural identity of the Uyghurs and the other religious and ethnic minority communities in the XUAR.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3B396B5C00024DBF9F93E789A20F8B2E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on strategy and implementation</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report, including a classified annex if necessary, that includes—</text>
<paragraph id="H1BE80DAD6F724DB4BB1FF31403CCC49D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the strategy developed pursuant to subsection (a); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1FBFA3B32C84B219CA3DF97463CDE93"><enum>(2)</enum><text>all the steps taken to implement such strategy pursuant to the objectives described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HABA384A693794C8897DC34FBBB4664DD"><enum>8.</enum><header>Requirement for Uyghur language training</header>
<subsection id="H7022521ECA9248D08D6DF5370411CE29"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Uyghur language training and staffing</header><text>The Secretary of State shall take such steps as may be necessary to ensure that—</text> <paragraph id="H35AAC4F8A99F49B1805DB158102FC831"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Uyghur language training is available to Foreign Service officers as appropriate; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF94502EAEF6340D2AF040C4F92754FAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>every effort is made to ensure that at least 1 Uyghur-speaking member of the Foreign Service (as such term is defined by section 103 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3903">22 U.S.C. 3903</external-xref>)) is assigned to each United States diplomatic or consular post in China.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBDC3B50238B64DB2BD0102510815C680"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>No later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 2 years, the Foreign Service Institute shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report that outlines all the steps taken to implement subsection (a).</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HF57E7C6B7BC84B2F989885D8384F2084"><enum>9.</enum><header>Uyghur considerations at the United Nations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President should direct the United States Permanent Representative to the United Nations to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States to—</text> <paragraph id="H41917B0A638241E2871CB9B05CD1B5A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>oppose any efforts to prevent consideration of the gross violation of internationally recognized human rights in the XUAR in any body of the United Nations;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H57F7C13C4B9A4812A448DBCB04AB4324"><enum>(2)</enum><text>oppose any efforts to prevent the participation of any Uyghur human rights advocates in nongovernmental fora hosted by or otherwise organized under the auspices of any body of the United Nations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H508B3F394FDE4F3C8A4766F3EB4F89A2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support the appointment of a special rapporteur or working group for the XUAR for the purposes of monitoring human rights violations and abuses in the XUAR, and for making reports available to the High Commissioner for Refugees, the High Commissioner for Human Rights, the Human Rights Commission, the General Assembly, and other United Nations bodies.</text></paragraph></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


