<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H25A1F5DCC96340BDBD0E177B79039B2B" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 427 IH: Recognizing “National Public Works Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 427</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250519">May 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing <quote>National Public Works Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas public works professionals and first responders work around the clock to ensure that vital infrastructure, facilities, and services are delivered to communities in a way that is dependable, sustainable, and resilient, promotes public health, and well-being throughout the United States, and advances the quality of life for all;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas such infrastructure, facilities, and services could not provide, operate, and protect communities without the dedicated efforts of public works professionals, or the engineers and managers who work for Federal, State, and local governments and private sector, and who are responsible for rebuilding, improving, and protecting the Nation’s transportation, water supply, water treatment and solid waste systems, public buildings, and other structures and facilities essential for public life;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas public works professionals are first responders and are often first to arrive and last to leave a natural disaster area or incident scene;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas it is in the public interest for everyone living in the United States to understand the importance of public works and public works programs in their communities; and</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the week of May 18 through May 24, 2025, marks the 65th annual <quote>National Public Works Week</quote> and its theme, <quote>People, Purpose, Presence</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H2AB3559C34C7480282F29C050E4F147B"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H3F196B21A556425D8BD388E8F19198E9"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="HBCFB7160C8F6459C9595876378F84F19"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports <quote>National Public Works Week</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H442AA4795D4E4BF2B427D8AA32C1DED9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to pay tribute to public works professionals, public works first responders, and those serving in support roles within the public works industry, to recognize the substantial contributions they make in protecting the country’s health, safety, and quality of life.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

