<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEL25576-8MD-CF-1S5">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2356 IS: Accelerating the Development of Advanced Psychology Trainees Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2356</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on
                    Finance</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To expand psychological mental and behavioral health services to Medicare,
            Medicaid, and CHIP beneficiaries by permitting reimbursement of psychological services
            provided by certain supervised psychology trainees, and facilitating the reimbursement
            of those services.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HC9FBDCAD407E4F94B6AB5685CF814D90">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="S1">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Accelerating the Development of Advanced Psychology Trainees Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ADAPT Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id9D25E61B32E64A67A3C8B051505FC6DE">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Coverage and coding for qualified psychologist services furnished by advanced
                psychology trainees under the Medicare program</header>
            <subsection id="id39CA3717F9AD4301BF3660646270705D">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Coverage</header>
                <paragraph id="id0181FEA69E8A40DA9DFD5DD8C41121B2">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1861(ii) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(ii)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="idEB4903E1E90545A9B974A9250083452A">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>(1)</quote> after <quote>(ii)</quote>;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idF0C7CC4AFA064471B1052DDAAF4ECD4D">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), as added by subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>(or furnished by an advanced psychology trainee under the general supervision of a clinical psychologist (as so defined) and billed by the supervising psychologist)</quote> after <quote>(as defined by the Secretary)</quote>; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id1C3D38E0FF9C46ADBEFA5E4C92603F73">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC95EE71A579D40C2A7364E1332796C5D"> <paragraph id="id79C252FEA4294CF7A835BD962698AA84" indent="up1"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>In this subsection:</text>
                                <subparagraph id="idA110334C98854B758161828DBB83CB15">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>The term <term>advanced psychology trainee</term> means—</text>
                                    <clause id="id1FE44DEB1D004EC59877B9B8B1EB430A">
                                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>a doctoral intern who is completing a required period of supervised experiential training through a program accredited by the American Psychological Association, not less than one year in duration, before being awarded a doctoral degree; or</text>
                                    </clause>
                                    <clause id="idAB82A85D3AC448DDBEAFE0AACD3C92D2">
                                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>a postdoctoral resident who has obtained a doctoral degree in psychology, is seeking a license to practice psychology, and is engaged in a 1- or 2-year period of additional supervised experiential training to acquire the skills or hours required for licensure through a program accredited by the American Psychological Association or a member of the Association of Psychology Postdoctoral and Internship Centers.</text>
                                    </clause>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="idE181C048E13B4B04A88FEA29A420BD66">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>The term <term>general supervision</term> means, with respect to a service, that the service is furnished under the overall direction and control of a clinical psychologist (as defined for purposes of paragraph (1)), but the supervising psychologist's presence is not required during the furnishing of the service.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                        </quoted-block>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id4B52E25503FF460E9D23B68CE3A2A12B">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Effective date</header>
 <text>The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to services furnished on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id190068EF9FF54C98BF7F17AD40D43DC8">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Development of GC modifier code</header>
 <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall develop a <quote>GC</quote> modifier code to identify and accurately bill for services furnished by an advanced psychology trainee pursuant to the amendments made by subsection (a).</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="id72EE382D7A5942779F888FDCD4242EFB">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Guidance to States on coverage of services provided by advanced psychology
                trainees under Medicaid and CHIP</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue and disseminate guidance to States on strategies to overcome existing barriers to coverage of services furnished by advanced psychology trainees (as defined under section 1861(ii)(2) of the Social Security Act, as added by section 2(a), through the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Children’s Health Insurance Program under title XXI of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397aa">42 U.S.C. 1397aa et seq.</external-xref>)). Such guidance shall include technical assistance and best practices regarding each of the following:</text>
            <paragraph id="idc7224d35072843f1855eb025a5a2150e">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>Recommended legal mechanisms for activating coverage of services furnished by advanced psychology trainees under such programs.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id1808834b453c4ef1859d50d071f79845">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Recommended billing codes and code modifiers for services furnished by advanced psychology trainees.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id67feafeb3f5a4742aef972aa39fada6f">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>Examples of States that have used waivers under the Medicaid program or Children's Health Insurance Program to enable coverage of services furnished by advanced psychology trainees under such programs.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

