<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H85E6A0DD0288409E82460B30B5B9FA69" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3329 IH: Wildlife Corridors and USDA Conservation Programs Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3329</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250513">May 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the conservation and designation of habitat connectivity areas, with support from the voluntary conservation programs administered by the Secretary of Agriculture, as American wildlife corridors, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAB965C8462364BD38E70C668A5405181" style="OLC"><section id="H3FAE6B2065E549AF9C59FAA6C9935B24" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wildlife Corridors and USDA Conservation Programs Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H37A06CC41ED6464A9BB1387D0D148103"><enum>2.</enum><header>Habitat connectivity area designation</header><subsection id="H84CFC106C67C415F983CE87F45262267" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="HBB820FAA53574D47BECBC33AD8048BC4" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>American wildlife corridor</header><text>The term <term>American wildlife corridor</term> means a habitat connectivity area, including any adjacent lands to such habitat connectivity area that is designated under subsection (c)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC729C20D294D47A19A30483623F1CF10" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Directors</header><text>The term <term>Directors</term> means the Secretary of the Interior acting through—</text><subparagraph id="HA19ED2CBF3254D44BD203004DE55078B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Director of the United States Geological Survey; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5BAF5DF0CBA41D998D0A2D010B14794" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H611FAB79CC8044F69695FB72B4C1C072" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Habitat connectivity</header><text>The term <term>habitat connectivity</term> means the degree to which landscapes, waterscapes, and seascapes allow species to move freely, including during seasonal migration and in response to changing environmental conditions, and ecological processes to function unimpeded.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3ECF956EFAF24390A599F7BE09A7F9FE" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Habitat connectivity area</header><text>The term <term>habitat connectivity area</term> means an area of intact habitat or a distinct component of the landscape, waterscape, or seascape the designation of which, under subsection (c)(2), may provide habitat connectivity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE5DBBDF17EC479DB1265484F43B1F81" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB6D7B7137D7840498E42061CB42F49D0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Identification of habitat connectivity areas</header><paragraph id="H71CB7B9ABBD74C5DB8C1754CF0FE9942" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Identification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and periodically thereafter, the Secretary, in collaboration with the Directors, shall identify habitat connectivity areas, including any lands adjacent to such identified habitat connectivity areas, that may improve habitat connectivity in such areas.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56B68657EA4E41CFAC68E7BCD537976E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maps</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to section 1244(b) of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3844">16 U.S.C. 3844(b)</external-xref>), as amended by section 3 of this Act, and section 1619 of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008, upon identifying habitat connectivity areas under paragraph (1), the Secretary, in collaboration with the Directors, shall—</text><subparagraph id="H932FC6D801D44ED5A98547A706433286" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop maps of the identified habitat connectivity areas, including any adjacent lands described in paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H057AB7E027E543C6BACB10541417F034"><enum>(B)</enum><text>expand and build upon any existing efforts by the Department of Agriculture in developing such maps.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E79D441743E4EB2AEE6AACCDCF24E7D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary identifies habitat connectivity areas, including any adjacent lands, under paragraph (1), and periodically thereafter upon any new identifications under such paragraph, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that—</text><subparagraph id="H1DBA74C8D2EA4804A9D04C95155BA177"><enum>(A)</enum><text>includes a description of habitat connectivity areas identified under paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F0063A65EE64916BB62FFB4BFD55CB8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a review of any associated data or surveys relating to activities carried out under paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02D5CAEAE4494CD98FE08DE91B8AF766"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes the maps developed under paragraph (2) in aggregate form; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7D26B8202D449A4A968E1A1F8C8C662"><enum>(D)</enum><text>identifies gaps in information with respect to carrying out paragraphs (1) and (2), including—</text><clause id="HE6A3024F41E44D69980D7B1C15858D91"><enum>(i)</enum><text>information relating to whether the identified habitat connectivity areas are being used as a wildlife corridor;</text></clause><clause id="H2EABF78676244E2FBC467CF63E19064A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>additional information required to identify additional habitat connectivity areas; and</text></clause><clause id="H49BBC2256B714587B0BD3B65BF0D57BA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other information the Secretary, in collaboration with the Directors, determines necessary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0C2E8B07C56B42B39E1A5AFA3C37E15B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Designation of American wildlife corridors</header><paragraph id="H7056389B578845218B3DEE55F73A20AB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue regulations to establish criteria, for the purpose of designating habitat connectivity areas under paragraph (2), that—</text><subparagraph id="H57B85AEA75B74F2AB104B8090936B5CA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>considers whether a designation is in concert with existing land and resource management plans; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C7F96BE204F46338EFA10079E9F6037"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determines, using the best-available science, whether a habitat connectivity area identified under subsection (b)(1), including any adjacent lands as described in that subsection—</text><clause id="H6F1F2FFA3FE04387BBA839B6739100F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>supports the persistence, resilience, adaptability, and movement of fish and wildlife;</text></clause><clause id="H2905AE328DF244F281F517C8C1AE3C91"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has the potential to benefit more than 1 species of fish and wildlife; or</text></clause><clause id="HD85EC2E609E145E79BE5D809B4CC2977"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has the potential to benefit fish or wildlife species that are listed as threatened or endangered under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H65F88E35BE254B14A4BFCE528B19F549"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date on which the Secretary establishes criteria pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary shall designate habitat connectivity areas identified under subsection (b)(1), including any adjacent lands that may provide additional habitat connectivity, using the criteria established pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, as an American wildlife corridor for the purposes of encouraging the long-term maintenance and conservation of the American wildlife corridor.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB1934902A77042CA8F5ACFB2B7B480CD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conservation of American wildlife corridors</header><paragraph id="H4C8609CA5B944F1C9292A4EAAF6166CC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><subparagraph id="HC1471DE4E1E7478289AA9C3E50F8A449"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in collaboration with the Directors, shall develop and establish technical standards and requirements, including best practices for the long-term conservation of an American wildlife corridor, to provide technical assistance, outreach, and education with respect to the conservation of the applicable American wildlife corridor.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE853D64BE1184154AD1B63EE3E59B100"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorized actions of Secretary</header><text>In providing technical assistance under paragraph (1)(B), the Secretary may encourage producers to—</text><clause id="H4D18568D41D84F74A1AFAE9C3D4F3D64"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implement strategies and activities that will promote sustainable production and conservation of wildlife habitats concurrently;</text></clause><clause id="H202A2DCF7E704A1194CFC667E2C56C2A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>maintain or improve habitats and habitat connectivity in American wildlife corridors;</text></clause><clause id="H9375AD8DA4F94ADFBCE261693A984259"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>establish wildlife monitoring plans; and</text></clause><clause id="HF6D64A81FE15406BBF386187CAB68452"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>implement strategies and activities that enhance the ability of fish and wildlife to respond to changing environmental conditions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5177C81757D456EBEDD34D9FD3C6D3D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contract modification</header><text>In furthering the purposes of an American wildlife corridor designation under subsection (c)(2), the Secretary may—</text><subparagraph id="H0A1211FC32B3473982B704180DEC4BFB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>give priority for enrollment or reenrollment in a conservation program administered by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B12889365FB4366AD8E47A9A73B1E3D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>terminate or modify an existing contract entered into with the Secretary under such a conservation program if—</text><clause id="HC6F18EF701D849358D178AFFD0EAD83D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the producer agrees to the termination or modification of such contract; and</text></clause><clause id="H711E0E1A346B44238B87FF91B97DF14D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>land subject to such contract will be enrolled in—</text><subclause id="H9B28F9B1850C4561BC140D564C61CCB1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the agricultural conservation easement program under subtitle H of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3865">16 U.S.C. 3865 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subclause><subclause id="HF3AA515588264BA69E05CDBD7E04F38F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the healthy forests reserve program under title V of the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6571">16 U.S.C. 6571 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFFFFED2E74F74AE2AACF73E56689D337"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><text>To carry out this section, the Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with—</text><paragraph id="H28E42E6A48C64D998AA7EB5B9D3E1588"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Federal agencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43BCA85BD9CA468BB0DCC2814F1E816C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>State, Tribal, and local governments;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7AA64DE711B4618A756F35BEA382413"><enum>(3)</enum><text>nongovernmental organizations; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0DDD95DC01D41D9A9D5A1EC74619CED"><enum>(4)</enum><text>institutions of higher education.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8321CCB135144EB3AC1BDF7D8327438D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Administrative requirements</header><subsection id="H07623418821145BC833A37136242BC2E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Privacy of personal information relating to Natural Resources Conservation Programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1244(b)(1)(B)(i) of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3844">16 U.S.C. 3844(b)(1)(B)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, including the <short-title>Wildlife Corridors and USDA Conservation Programs Act of 2025</short-title></quote> after <quote>Farm Service Agency</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD1F7AE47BDE24FB68D9E2C437AC3D33A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulatory certainty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1244(p) of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3844">16 U.S.C. 3844(p)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H51E4C130B10F4EA8861A8B3B35F83193"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(B), by inserting <quote>, or an American wildlife corridor (as such term is defined by section 2(a) of the <short-title>Wildlife Corridors and USDA Conservation Programs Act of 2025</short-title>),</quote> after <quote>wildlife resource concern</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B577F54D10B42EE81AD442AA58AF1BF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)(A), by inserting <quote>, or an American wildlife corridor,</quote> after <quote>wildlife resource concern</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

