<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25C01-YC1-2X-GKM">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2119 IS: Abducted Ukrainian Children Recovery and Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2119</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250618">June 18, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which
                was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee
                    on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To enhance United States support for identifying and recovering Ukrainian
            children who were abducted by the Russian Federation, and to hold accountable those who
            are responsible for such abductions.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Abducted Ukrainian Children Recovery and Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="idc1655b2356f84b14973434f913d512aa">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Findings</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="id5cdbec6c93e7404388c200c9ec83714e"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>According to a White House press release, dated March 25, 2025, <quote>The United States and Ukraine agreed that the United States remains committed to helping achieve the exchange of prisoners of war, the release of civilian detainees, and the return of forcibly transferred Ukrainian children.</quote>.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id4209537e56044835aa37b1edd6edac63">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>To implement the commitment referred to in paragraph (1), the United States Government requires an organized and resourced policy approach to assist Ukraine with—</text>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8fe156eb73694b0e8e67f2b8224fd1ce">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">investigations of Russia’s abduction of Ukrainian children;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1db3791aaa5e4d198b3ce2d6a752b1a1">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the rehabilitation and reintegration of children returned to Ukraine; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1fd09f4a578540fcb97a2e32c313404f">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">justice and accountability for perpetrators of the abductions.</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="idaa7c7e7b80ee4741b2b3e257d765f2b0">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Investigation support</header>
            <subsection id="id9e8eded0cee3498e91dc266bac876a31">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Authorization of technical assistance and advisory support</header>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id09553524a7cc4f72ab3dca4195627c28">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Justice, the Department of State, and the Department of Homeland Security are authorized—</text>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id58093a2f55a741cf9b0174a50ef35d19">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide technical assistance, training, capacity building, and advisory support to the Government of Ukraine in support of the commitment described in section 2(1); and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id17c50461eaec43ecac36c3ef450c4370">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to advance the objectives described in section 2(2).</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8751560ac4fb462eaf64ff1d80b2a905">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Type of assistance</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The technical assistance authorized under paragraph (1)(A) may include—</text>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb6abe4ae3187447a875351f52d5224e1">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">training regarding the utilization of biometric identification technologies in abduction and trafficking investigations;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id29f8e9ce15ec481780f8e41269ac60d5">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>assistance with respect to collecting and analyzing open source intelligence information;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id8b1a5ff2cc934e68bbc73a979c5f98a5">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>assistance in the development and use of secure communications technologies; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id3c8ce23f1bf647329f090b9c2f4b3bd3">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>assistance with respect to managing and securing relevant databases.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id685a224a06764e2fb73ae5d86f9b978a">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Coordination</header>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1bb7690785cc415da5676cd32f87eb4d">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nongovernmental
                        organizations</header>
 <text>The Department of Justice, the Department of State, and the Department of Homeland Security shall coordinate with, and may provide grants to, nongovernmental organizations to carry out the assistance authorized under subsection (a).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idc22ecf8607ba4b5a86d673079d0435b6">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Federal agencies</header>
 <text>The National Security Council shall convene meetings with appropriate representatives from the Department of Justice, the Department of State, the Department of Homeland Security, and the intelligence community (as defined in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>)) to carry out the assistance authorized under subsection (a).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id29de4becc3aa4c209a4c255662682e01">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Notification requirement</header>
 <text>The National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency may not suspend or terminate the Government of Ukraine’s access to the Global Enhanced GEOINT Delivery Program unless the Director of such agency, not later than 30 days before the date of such suspension or termination, submits a notification to Congress that includes—</text>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ce7ddf9e9de4839b42b066e6f785ffc">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a justification for such suspension or termination; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida649c6f16d654a0784ab772ea3ced714">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan describing an alternate method by which the Government of Ukraine may access satellite imagery collected by the United States Government.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="id862590ed58894917ba99e97c11a2f46e">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>Rehabilitation and reintegration</header>
            <subsection id="id5c0c165ee98d49cdb2fe4f7667a5d92c">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Authorization of assistance</header>
 <text>The Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development are authorized to provide support to the Government of Ukraine and to nongovernmental organizations and local civil society groups in Ukraine for the purpose of providing Ukrainian children who have been abducted by the Russian Federation with—</text>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc68b060592144310b816a7bf31183e18">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">medical and psychological rehabilitation services;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbab64da5bd1241bea1f891c8932e6523">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">family support services; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idff38c35cd14c4e9f9d5c2eaabf1473cd"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">services in support of the reintegration of such children into Ukrainian society, including legal aid and educational screening and placement.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id044883b951704750aee0faf6c483667f">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Report</header>
 <text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that describes all current or planned foreign assistance programs that will provide the assistance authorized under subsection (a).</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="ided88448901824fa18d0937962395f14a">
            <enum>5.</enum>
            <header>Justice and accountability</header>
            <subsection id="id5b03a9a3200a41119994565fad7cb623">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Atrocity Crimes Advisory Group for Ukraine</header>
 <text>The Department of State, under the direction of the Ambassador at Large for Global Criminal Justice, is authorized to support the Atrocity Crimes Advisory Group for Ukraine by providing technical assistance, capacity building, and advisory support to the Government of Ukraine’s Office of the Prosecutor General, and other relevant components of the Government of Ukraine, for the purpose of investigating and prosecuting cases involving abducted children, and other war crimes.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id2376ba5322fd44ccb23557ff8c3633d1">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Department of Justice</header>
 <text>The Department of Justice is authorized to provide technical assistance, capacity building, and advisory support to the Government of Ukraine through its Office of Overseas Prosecutorial Development, Assistance, and Training, which shall be coordinated by the Resident Legal Adviser at the United States Embassy in Kyiv, for the purpose of investigating and prosecuting cases involving abducted children, and other atrocity crimes.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id12c45af26e984d54b33e86caf169fc04">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Reports</header>
 <text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e0b85cc261544c3b8e551ce4f996ec4"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Attorney General, shall submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that describes current and planned United States Government support for the Government of Ukraine’s work to investigate and prosecute war crimes; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id00e981d044be42519918f1212266da38">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that outlines—</text>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide4d7eba5c5a740c393cd1128a4281d53">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any discrepancies between the sanctions regimes of the United States, the United Kingdom, and the European Union with respect to those responsible for the abduction of Ukrainian children; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id87a01f8f82d940e89652b52f77333680">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts made by the United States Government to better align such sanction regimes.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="idc5eb9eeb5ad242708347144acac9e0fe">
            <enum>6.</enum>
            <header>Use of seized Russian sovereign assets</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President may utilize any Russian sovereign assets held within the United States for the purposes described in this Act and in accordance with the Rebuilding Economic Prosperity and Opportunity for Ukrainians Act (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/50">Public Law 118–50</external-xref>).</text>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

