<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF16391D5E5994290B28C11B259AAA013" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1920 IH: Foreign Agricultural Restrictions to Maintain Local Agriculture and National Defense Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1920</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250306">March 6, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000446">Mr. Feenstra</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001237">Ms. McDonald Rivet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000490">Mr. Taylor</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000622">Mr. Riley of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 to strengthen oversight over foreign investment in the United States agricultural industry, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H287916045E0C496E982E97E485A8C572" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H6E908E444EAC41689E20D917F7B42479"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Foreign Agricultural Restrictions to Maintain Local Agriculture and National Defense Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FARMLAND Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF5752DE5A1B048E0B2546F10DCB72278"><enum>2.</enum><header>Agricultural foreign investment</header> <subsection id="HFC8A01C9D4454EFBA809B808CB2E2693"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD81A32FD4A934686AA6AED15B048DFB9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>agriculture is vital for the national security and economic prosperity of the United States and is a key element of United States national power;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H014B04E2A0D9495EAC97CC871D85899A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>agriculture of the United States feeds the people of the United States and the world, and has been a key contributor to advancements in technology and medicine;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H15D7FFE632AF4481BCB8589120646FF2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>strategic competitors of the United States have hegemonic goals to dominate the global agriculture industry and undermine the United States agriculture sector through intellectual property theft of seeds and other patented agriculture-related technologies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H80B6EFE2F4D64385912ACDF28AE4BE5A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>China in particular has increased agricultural investments tenfold over the past decade and continues to make investments in United States agriculture, agribusiness, and animal processing industries, including by acquiring ownership of farmland in the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C63E8BE2C554E1C8D07BE955515D78C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the United States must prevent agricultural espionage and theft of intellectual property conducted by China and other foreign entities of concern (as defined in section 9 of the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3508">7 U.S.C. 3508</external-xref>));</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA2CB905900674DD184D8241833063102"><enum>(6)</enum><text>agricultural intellectual property theft may enable global competitors to undercut United States producers in international seed markets;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H572DD822054642C7A3DC987941AD2014"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Federal Government does not fully exercise its authorized oversight over investment transactions within the agricultural industry, causing—</text> <subparagraph id="H8D28515F48A14076BCAEB39CC357043B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>United States farmland to be under foreign acquisition; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H23B670C8449A4C388927960BF70349FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the influence of foreign adversaries on agriculture in the United States to be an unknown risk factor; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA40049063ED34A9BBA6BD134E5CA116D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the Federal Government must enforce and modernize existing laws to monitor and prevent malign actions of foreign entities of concern (as defined in section 9 of the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3508">7 U.S.C. 3508</external-xref>)) on the farms and land of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6113F313C0354F4D95D77699A58B4613"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil penalties</header><text>Section 3 of the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3502">7 U.S.C. 3502</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1272F5D7808C4D11A8606F872E57FA1D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (b) as subsection (d);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFAEEFA17552A4910988D8CC76353210C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>(a) If the</quote> and all that follows through <quote>Any such civil penalty</quote> in the third sentence and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C1F0B4BE9CA47BA8BD0D7138882647C"> <subsection id="H485B8E61ED5948D5905106B80278DB02"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person shall be subject to a civil penalty imposed by the Secretary if the Secretary determines that the person—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7E2F3530E6264B41AF1B3AFF3BBFF57B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has failed to submit a report in accordance with the provisions of section 2; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7EE0BCEFAEEB4CAC95952720D9AE16EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has knowingly submitted a report under section 2 that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2C0209783E58417A9325BC8BB1318C12"><enum>(A)</enum><text>does not contain all the information required to be in such report; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF3F06F910DD841FC8A64AC677A3E0851"><enum>(B)</enum><text>contains information that is misleading or false. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4CFEE03F0B40465ABABD44731D01ADDB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability of funds from civil penalties</header><text>A civil penalty collected under subsection (a) shall be available to the Secretary without appropriation and remain available until expended for the purpose of enforcing this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H34556999997F441FA211605535A2FE8E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil action</header><text>Any civil penalty imposed by the Secretary under subsection (a)</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB750C0FEF2E64014A09B396319E84AA7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d) (as so redesignated)—</text> <subparagraph id="HEF148A592B974F49AD818191A7705B31"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking the subsection designation and all that follows through <quote>The amount</quote> and inserting the following: </text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28B61B21CE9846BE9ECC94418A3F1969"> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H67516B9FFF6F4BAA8930839F9FE0B0A7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Amount of penalty</header><text>The amount</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFBB49123EC974D8D8B02651BB1878549"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of this section</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC075DA8872B940028036FC85498608F9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>shall not exceed 25 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>shall be not less than 5 percent, but not more than 25 percent,</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H426BE34C0CF146629CA5777D0E4B83BF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public disclosure of noncompliant persons</header><text>Section 3 of the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3502">7 U.S.C. 3502</external-xref>) (as amended by subsection (b)) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C5D8F3872374466BA9FC30433D88E62"> 
<subsection id="HAF44F553E71F4A7EA0827B4A39C2554B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Public disclosure of noncompliant persons</header><text>The Secretary shall publicly disclose the name of each person who paid to the Secretary a civil penalty imposed under subsection (a), including, if applicable, after the completion of an appeal of a civil penalty.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H70FF3BEB62C747E2BB90C267E4DB7380"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Publication of reporting requirements</header><text>Section 3 of the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3502">7 U.S.C. 3502</external-xref>) (as amended by subsection (c)) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD6B0994E4BA8474D98AE44E160E213AE"> 
<subsection id="H4A702FD16CEA49C79AEDA49335FB4E51"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text>Using existing resources and efforts to the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall carry out a nationwide outreach program directed primarily towards landlords, owners, operators, persons, producers, and tenants (as those terms are defined in section 718.2 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Foreign Agricultural Restrictions to Maintain Local Agriculture and National Defense Act of 2025</short-title>)) of agricultural land and county property appraiser offices, land appraisal companies, and real estate auction companies to increase public awareness and provide education regarding the reporting requirements under this section. </text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H5450E07017DE4769802E83257D4E845D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Due diligence requirements</header><text>The Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 is amended by inserting after section 4 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3503">7 U.S.C. 3503</external-xref>) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF63871E1E1C549209BEDA3D6F482FDB1"> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC918527A3D345D9B8A1CB6CD23D82F4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Due diligence requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any entity (including a buyer, seller, real estate agent, broker, and title company) involved in the purchase or transfer of agricultural land in the United States shall—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H78D635C55BCD4A9B8E7DE4F844016E73"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct due diligence relating to the agriculture land being purchased or transferred; and </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H401F1ADDA738494982291B884D2DFC75"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certify to the Secretary that, to the best of the knowledge and belief of the entity, the entity is in compliance with all applicable provisions of this Act.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="HC890CAB4792C402EB8FAB6179CAF0F21"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on agricultural land purchasing activities in the United States by countries designated as state sponsors of terrorism and certain other countries</header> <subsection id="H9AC955AD0B554F058F3BFC373AD83480"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H28A3F6F7AC6D476993B0E45EB0BF0463"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agricultural land</header><text>The term <term>agricultural land</term> has the meaning given the term in section 9 of the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3508">7 U.S.C. 3508</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3AE6826C4EA44D8281B39FEA1940E016"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9CBFA14C8976426AADC94E0EFD00D274"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA13FD9C737E2487186F477A84C48BDFF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEA8B6E9DB2B74B0CB207E82736DC49B7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H95CC4E791EB14D099B2D9F3800D9B379"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H866BD30E07D344E7A3EED3B38F7BF8B9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H28E8A2F56818474F85FA6098D694836B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H022EFF2389634DCBA21B7B15B3A41DAD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered foreign country</header><text>The term <term>covered foreign country</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H331228582B3542D5B915D8ED787C4E8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the People’s Republic of China;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB238516F75F94017A93BF7FF8768EDFE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Russian Federation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H885286168AC845B3A9C47EEE3F51D4B5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a state sponsor of terrorism; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H56C9A7FA73BB48E9B3580512FFC16453"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other country identified by the Secretary of Homeland Security or the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6B018D41A164DB1A77D9CBDD09D8E3D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered foreign person</header><text>The term <term>covered foreign person</term> means a foreign person (as defined in section 9 of the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3508">7 U.S.C. 3508</external-xref>)) that is a citizen of, or headquartered in, as applicable, a covered foreign country.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9BB42B9179864FB3B26A5F4C2B94A942"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given the term in section 9 of the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3508">7 U.S.C. 3508</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBBCA4D0448244BAEBAA2736307DD3DA6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State sponsor of terrorism</header><text>The term <term>state sponsor of terrorism</term> means a country the government of which the Secretary of State has determined has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism, for purposes of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE1C3A8A98DAE4C66B4B28F594C2B0059"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 1754(c)(1)(A)(i) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4813">50 U.S.C. 4813(c)(1)(A)(i)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9A4BC9DCB7E14515A37684DF651AA024"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2371">22 U.S.C. 2371</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9A892BC665814D5D80C66996E6F3ED99"><enum>(C)</enum><text>section 40(d) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2780">22 U.S.C. 2780(d)</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE92ADC2AE8A2495DAE17E579FC4AA663"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other provision of law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H77819682AD1E442CAC9EED2FAB5D2C21"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<paragraph id="H988B709C384C4B74A2D25FF3EED0D42D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Agriculture, with support from the Secretary of Homeland Security and the head of any other appropriate Federal agency, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report describing the national security risks of the purchase and management of agricultural land by covered foreign persons.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H21E5F8AB24844C5B8972B2E5758C931D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following with respect to the year covered by the report:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF598A0386A2B405FA22D35619FDA7DD8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of—</text> <clause id="HA76C8AB1C6BC4C939236E2E8DE1C9BF2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of acres of agricultural land owned or managed by covered foreign persons, organized by State; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H17C2D3AD94764BC6B17B8DDEC11E0835"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for each State, the percentage of land owned or managed by covered foreign persons compared to the total acreage of the State.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0086B08D56874779B87DC4D2BF9F7FB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An analysis of the possible threat to food security, food safety, biosecurity, or environmental protection due to the ownership of agricultural land by each covered foreign country through covered foreign persons.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE88403346C4B4A35B0BB02BA9884A0BB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An analysis of the annual and total cost of support for agricultural land owned by covered foreign persons through farm programs administered by the Farm Service Agency.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF356CCE642164E66862119717A708745"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An analysis of the use of agricultural land for industrial espionage or intellectual property transfer by covered foreign persons.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD5179E430D5C4FA8B9D8545342E1579E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An analysis of the potential use by covered foreign persons of agricultural land in close proximity to manufacturing facilities, water sources, and other critical infrastructure to monitor, interrupt, or disrupt activities critical to the national and economic security of the United States.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7FA93AA0F53F4172B56C2901C0738F9D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>An analysis of other threats to the agricultural industry or national security of the United States due to the ownership of agricultural land by covered foreign persons.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H193531046090497B8D98FAAB5D81CB9E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Unclassified form</header><text>A report submitted under this subsection shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H3549E6C6C63D4FE3971AF48AA4E09E27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2EF00B9B0BBD486EAA075AB7944A7EC7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be consistent with the protection of intelligence sources and methods.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H211A934D6F14458790942A74AD38760A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Investigative actions</header> <subsection id="H2BB9D9EBFB394CE8803D269966422A7F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Investigative actions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4 of the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3503">7 U.S.C. 3503</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDD74A8AFBB93412BB43678A224DB4B1A"> 
<section id="H949B76195B8A4AE094F702A72E3B4AD4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Investigative actions</header> 
<subsection id="H56217CD73D1142B6AA01E0A8FD41591C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall appoint an employee in the Senior Executive Service (as described in section 3131 of title 5, United States Code) of the Department of Agriculture to serve as Chief of Operations of Investigative Actions (referred to in this section as the <quote>Chief of Operations</quote>), who shall hire, appoint, and maintain additional employees to monitor compliance with the provisions of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H015E159C45154B0C916DB1E09E20DBCD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Chief of operations</header><text>The Chief of Operations may serve in such position simultaneously with a concurrent position within the Department of Agriculture.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6868583AB48A4221A2AB5B2980F996E2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Security</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H312257CAAB464D739AEDC62FFBCB384A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide classified storage, meeting, and other spaces, as necessary, for personnel; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58EB623FC3A64F1C920B45BF187153F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assist personnel in obtaining security clearances.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEADB9D171DEE409698E2F429AB1AFB90"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Chief of Operations shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAD28A9DE44584CA38355FD80D1EEA027"><enum>(1)</enum><text>monitor compliance with this Act;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5361E521E746409DBCB28B30F9DB7997"><enum>(2)</enum><text>refer noncompliance with this Act to the Secretary, the Farm Service Agency, and any other appropriate authority;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFB7B14F85F8742BB80863919FE1709CE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conduct investigations, in coordination with the Department of Justice, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of the Treasury, the National Security Council, and State and local law enforcement agencies, on malign efforts—</text> <subparagraph id="H235B1AE17F354D019CB6569F16F71F93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to steal agricultural knowledge and technology; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE8D13BF63D5C43B6BA7AB5A72D286134"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to disrupt the United States agricultural base;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H35BA6B80A4CF485B83AC331F3A026AF1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>conduct an annual audit of the database developed under section 6(b) of the <short-title>Foreign Agricultural Restrictions to Maintain Local Agriculture and National Defense Act of 2025</short-title>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD742FAEBB88045CD84A011305DCBE704"><enum>(5)</enum><text>seek to enter into memoranda of agreement and memoranda of understanding with the Federal agencies described in paragraph (3)—</text> <subparagraph id="HD781C30739A84BC1B98E0A540F0DC83F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to ensure compliance with this Act; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBDE3C412181C4E3BA31C6702812A3748"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to prevent the malign efforts described in that paragraph;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E2482591B9F4794B4D6252B3DDF8C14"><enum>(6)</enum><text>refer to the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States transactions that—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H266F0777D7814E108B4421C1EF4B9A2E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">raise potential national security concerns; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9906DB7CCBD3451A862AD1E8C387CC5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">result in agricultural land acquisition by a foreign person that is a citizen of, or headquartered in, as applicable, a foreign entity of concern; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H075EC17441A64DDD9DBDF165F5B6C6CA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>publish annual reports that summarize the information contained in every report received by the Secretary under section 2 during the period covered by the report.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB481BA45AD13497E8B3815C075B99369"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Chief of Operations shall report to—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFDE6D4F4147444F19F97C89ED38653D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7CD67B12D4F04F169CE527086FB70BC7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if delegated by the Secretary, to—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEFADC1F37DCC47C1B18B9940E113A1B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Administrator of the Farm Service Agency; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE9070B4A3271427B999F7E3F29BAF5ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Director of the Department of Agriculture Office of Homeland Security.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H31FE57299A7243258696CEA4B18B6F2E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of foreign entity of concern</header><text>Section 9 of the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3508">7 U.S.C. 3508</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H46C56A21A69A466AAFB61FF70A0C35DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>For purposes of this Act—</quote> and inserting <quote>In this Act:</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4B49CAFF26B34D3B8D9FC4BF27D09431"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in each of paragraphs (1) through (6)—</text> <subparagraph id="HA1CF2053E7234EEA9AB3727B88B17CAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the term</quote> and inserting <quote>The term</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBA6CD246F3194AD3AF8E53DD1E8FC677"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting a paragraph heading, the text of which comprises the term defined in that paragraph;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDBF77A8795844F20BBD8804D0F91BDDA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) through (6) as paragraphs (3), (4), (6), (7), and (8), respectively;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H60257AE76B344BEB97A47AC4899658D2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9EEBEDE68FB245ADAC072FE844307F62"> <paragraph id="H949EDA604C1E4365BC5B2DC542C0F808"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign entity of concern</header><text>The term <term>foreign entity of concern</term> has the meaning given the term in section 9901 of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/4651">15 U.S.C. 4651</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H57F1E5F2C7E34392B5DCC9C9AA1061D8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) (as so redesignated) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H44D4577A92944F64BFE52E035A807021"> <paragraph id="HD352DBCDF81D441892511F187828D2DF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Malign effort</header><text>The term <term>malign effort</term> means any hostile effort undertaken by, at the direction of, on behalf of, or with the substantial support of the government of a foreign entity of concern.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6615901AE0384999BC05E3E5386FB810"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>The Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3501">7 U.S.C. 3501 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE2A70095FDCB402CB049D26DA4EE2FA8"> <section id="H11DD36FDD34644E49D9EC40506DB833B"><enum>11.</enum><header>Reports</header> <subsection id="HB45DD66302AA455BBC71A8B300303FF1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that describes the progress of the Secretary in implementing the amendments made by the <short-title>Foreign Agricultural Restrictions to Maintain Local Agriculture and National Defense Act of 2025</short-title>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBCD588B16589464FB1E159D3E6AB356C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on tracking covered transactions</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the feasibility of—</text> <paragraph id="H5B4E5CD0C2B841B2A514AFADD7858098"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establishing a mechanism for quantifying the threats posed by foreign entities of concern to United States food security, biosecurity, food safety, environmental protection, and national defense; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2B32DA68589A4E908BB8DA1E984EEF21"><enum>(2)</enum><text>building, and submitting to the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States for further review, a rigorous discovery and review process to review transactions described in section 721(a)(4)(B)(vi) of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4565">50 U.S.C. 4565(a)(4)(B)(vi)</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC1E6944B6DC348A685E17651979E006E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Yearly report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, and annually thereafter for the following 10 years, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the activities of the Secretary pursuant to this Act during the year covered by the report.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="H18B5427BEC894F0D878BFC4B29E7F7F0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authority of Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States to review certain real estate purchases by foreign entities of concern</header> 
<subsection id="HF46109B13EE2487F83BA82DAD8456177"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 721(a)(4) of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4565">50 U.S.C. 4565(a)(4)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA9CC3896FD6A409FBF1E5467D5D7B95D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7DCBF35EDFC94D23843C810F01407739"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD583A47D2E8C4F03BE095EF590E9C04A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0A9C290240AB47C8A995563E03DE4D07"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8B5A8EBE37A34FC4914B954B8391CFD6"> <clause id="HD85C838BCE524E55A26159A44B148D53"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any transaction described in subparagraph (B)(vi) proposed or pending on or after the date of enactment of this clause.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H05CBC5D885E5453E937AD12AFE5CB912"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C4DFA9FE7404CC09B264313D0A2696A"> <clause id="H7161BDFB989F422D8DDB2D8225104428"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Subject to subparagraph (C), the purchase or lease by, or a concession to, a foreign entity of concern of private or public real estate in the United States if—</text> 
<subclause id="HBE13099892604B619C6CB9B339900EC7"><enum>(I)</enum> 
<item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFA9FF1F506E94DA3BCC0F56EE3567700"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the value of the purchase, lease, or concession—</text> <subitem id="HB7EDF681C41A42D0BB476F7518CA92D5" indent="up1"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>exceeds $5,000,000; or</text></subitem> 
<subitem id="HC72114E17298446BAA0A34FB19B1E893" indent="up1"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>in combination with the value of other such purchases or leases by, or concessions to, the same entity during the preceding 3 years, exceeds $5,000,000; or</text></subitem></item> <item id="H452EFA0EAC9D46999D755B802F278B6D" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the real estate—</text> 
<subitem id="H5FF09F11F65A4EEFA80C2BECD0D1467B"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>exceeds 320 acres; or</text></subitem> <subitem id="H2F32CAC0EA824ED2B28DAB0BFB251F93"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>in combination with other private or public real estate in the United States purchased or leased by, or for which a concession is provided to, the same entity during the preceding 3 years, exceeds 320 acres; and</text></subitem></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H4ED7EFA536AD44A4BD21D55171C2F633"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the real estate is primarily used for—</text> <item id="H606BA94959014DEA9C5DBFE291AC5B9C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>agriculture, including raising of livestock and forestry;</text></item> 
<item id="H9A7B598410424C33BC91C4E3FCDB1124"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>extraction of fossil fuels, natural gas, purchases or leases of renewable energy sources; or</text></item> <item id="HF867BE56F08541FABDF077C034D763CC"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>extraction of critical precursor materials for biological technology industries, information technology components, or national defense technologies.</text></item></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H27D9EF4171BA4881B4C6A6D3B8AD678A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Foreign entities of concern</header><text>Section 721(a) of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4565">50 U.S.C. 4565(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE9D4F4386A844098B1E90542DB264A83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (7) through (13) as paragraphs (8) through (14), respectively; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H70360E26FF2F4B50AC5CA4880F820B27"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (6) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2895D57895934ADEA076D25A54E1105A"> <paragraph id="HEA8943E8AB0941C8B006BB32ED0B33EC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Foreign entity of concern</header><text>The term <term>foreign entity of concern</term> has the meaning given that term in section 9901 of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/4651">15 U.S.C. 4651</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H614A6ED0FA5D4D5788A0C3389ECE1588"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Factors To Be considered</header><text>Section 721(f) of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4565">50 U.S.C. 4565(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA6BABDAFF1D644A5A82584511B081AD6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (8) through (11) as paragraphs (9) through (12), respectively; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB5921B740996420996C361C5EA8020D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (7) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H98FA13FA71414E6399AF1F92E158C8A3"> <paragraph id="H4929B95285394DDF937F8DFCFFA748CB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the potential follow-on national security effects of the risks posed by the proposed or pending transaction to United States food security, food safety, biosecurity, environmental protection, or national defense;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H49E1285E005A459784EA5C097045AF51"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Inclusion of Secretary of Agriculture and the Commissioner of Food And Drugs on Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States</header><text>Section 721(k)(2) of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4565">50 U.S.C. 4565(k)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H380C0698C6B24EB2AAD08859A399E110"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (H), (I), and (J) as subparagraphs (J), (K), and (L), respectively; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H27164E37B92B4E4CA2D48A4489643E2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (G) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8524E64EE34747BAA7CDF7BBFF88167C"> <subparagraph id="H81257686C7C9482FBD892969C3343B64"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The Secretary of Agriculture.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H90B45C61B055441995E0F524927C31A9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Commissioner of Food and Drugs.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2654DC2683D246E8A34AEC1C2DCEB5C1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Section 721(m) of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4565">50 U.S.C. 4565(m)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE1453C22878C45F2AEC104AC613C2A92"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (5); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB84CA69A5D04FF895921A19099F7198"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7DEA497553104B73B33B5ACDBAE9671A"> 
<paragraph id="HED7B181E8D4E4699ADD88B185649E19E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>List of real estate owned by foreign entities of concern</header><text>The President and such agencies as the President shall designate shall include in the annual report submitted under paragraph (1) a list of all real estate in the United States owned by a foreign entity of concern or a person closely associated with such an entity.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD3EF5E788CE4407CA9080AD83133C7E5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury, in coordination with Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="H434263F4995A4089A62B7AC4CAD81D82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of the feasibility of requiring retroactive divestment of real estate owned by foreign entities of concern (as defined in section 721(a) of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended by this section); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H938966EC1D93403BB89D1126D5A2A5AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the process used by the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States to review the national security implications of any connections between—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H30F7F6EAEA6F4B5B9FED14126DF82F90"><enum>(A)</enum><text>foreign investment in the United States made by the Government of the People’s Republic of China or entities controlled by or acting on behalf of that Government; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4715BEA00A5B4EE0910EEDFD3C9D93B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Chinese Communist Party.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H66A1D5AF6C9B4032BB1F51A66106F97B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and apply with respect to any covered transaction the review or investigation of which is initiated under section 721 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 on or after such date of enactment.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HCA60A8416E3C4F998D333D8AFC3BECE2"><enum>6.</enum><header>Digitization and consolidation of foreign land ownership data</header> <subsection id="HA15BD1D5DE194A3BA4086B40500EE947"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBA7CDD8031B6475B952FB2C36D5E9229"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agricultural land</header><text>The term <term>agricultural land</term> has the meaning given the term in section 781.2 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAFFDB0986F4E492A8BCC5A10AD290EEB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3(a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD9AC44E689324C6DA97C58E0659728E2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Database</header><text>The term <term>database</term> means the database developed under subsection (b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H722C22589EEE46D58E765437F6A4841E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> has the meaning given the term in section 9 of the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3508">7 U.S.C. 3508</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H579678BA16C1472E8A848FB53720C565"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretaries</header><text>The term <term>Secretaries</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H497A0C8927FE46B096289DADF9D00946"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC9E3CB3FA7844C6D8ACA14489E43D904"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H77D7E22804B44B7C8C3BF9E4CCA06EC0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Database</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretaries, acting jointly, shall develop a database of agricultural land owned by foreign persons, using data that are—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB3F9A658681344DC9E87B6FC8DC00A64"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collected—</text> <subparagraph id="H0F9170186FF842598AFEA0067DFA5332"><enum>(A)</enum><text>pursuant to the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3501">7 U.S.C. 3501 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDECCE58460214522B4A8D1D2E5E08450"><enum>(B)</enum><text>from FSA–153 forms submitted to the Farm Service Agency; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H876FD7C3CE324D97A1B90F0888684F04"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publicly available.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8478847F95414A2DAB109D2B4BF8BCCA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each entry in the database for each registration or updated registration of agricultural land owned by a foreign person shall include information in the applicable FSA–153 form.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H433739F2893C4FCDBC2CA2FF92D25387"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Audit</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the database is made publicly available, and annually thereafter, the Chief of Operations for Investigative Actions appointed under section 4 of the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4338EA53759546AF85AE03DE8D2CE1AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct an audit of the database; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H64ACA527B6CB4BD3A75D6C8BEC513257"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H772F1C66F1244E7BAFAAAF2077B39FB7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluating the accuracy of the database; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4A8D14B1D1E6434D9F569E9D8906BE4F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describing recommendations for improving compliance with the reporting required under the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3501">7 U.S.C. 3501 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H03C76B28684042B4B04D66F472A0D329"><enum>7.</enum><header>Prohibition of participation in Farm Service Agency programs by foreign persons</header> 
<subsection id="HCD54102EF0DB49A5B216912F70D0B91A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H1559812F87CA47B2A8E1D2ED680C9881"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3(a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9CE4B8F68D8543ABA534127CC2DE090F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> has the meaning given the term in section 9 of the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3508">7 U.S.C. 3508</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC67ADAE7794249DDBEC2196399D5BAE7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Operator</header><text>The term <term>operator</term> has the meaning given the term in section 718.2 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F61309991AC42FCAC9150F3F48C084F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Owner</header><text>The term <term>owner</term> has the meaning given the term in section 718.2 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H23BA46EABBF840E8A45D585D02022067"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Participant</header><text>The term <term>participant</term> has the meaning given the term in section 718.2 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H06B2803BA38F4EA092CE0E05BF455FAB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9EF163805D2C4EC2941E29E7BC40CB61"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation for foreign-Owned or operated land</header><text>No operator or owner who is a foreign person may be a participant.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H612E562FBDE4462591CF98F1F8603C19"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compliance</header> 
<paragraph id="H19AD4D03239544BF8093F21CA916FE35"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may take such actions as the Secretary considers necessary to monitor compliance with subsection (b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E62219EB5CD452B9A7CCB2C7B8D1F9E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ownership certification</header><text>The Secretary shall require any owner or operator applying to be a participant to certify in the application that the owner or operator is not a foreign person. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90FCC3DF918F4BFCB94FCD2F4CF2F281"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header> 
<subparagraph id="H7086EF515FAA4359B7963E13C9B579B6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A foreign person shall be subject to a civil penalty imposed by the Secretary if the Secretary determines that the foreign person—</text> <clause id="HB635C8992C594DD9988A63BCA5DAE9E1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has received benefits prohibited under subsection (b); or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3E6204ADA7174C5D9A419B3CD62A5E9F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has knowingly submitted a request for those benefits that contains information that is misleading or false.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H670205CC7A36403194757897DBA5B52D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Civil action</header><text>A civil penalty imposed by the Secretary under subparagraph (A) shall be recoverable in a civil action brought by the Attorney General in an appropriate district court of the United States.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H80DC4C8CA24A4CE189AFFC620709645B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The amount of a civil penalty imposed by the Secretary under subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="H802C8915C09E4283BDA474709F3ECEB0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be such amount as the Secretary determines to be appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section; but</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEBFC1C9F986641489693B28DE49B0977"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall not exceed 125 percent of the monetary benefits provided to the foreign person in participating in the 1 or more programs of the Farm Service Agency in which participation is prohibited under subsection (b).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4377A5B93DA4018B7DE68017EFA361D"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Use of civil penalties</header><text>Penalties collected under this paragraph shall be available to the Secretary, without further appropriation and until expended, for the purpose of enforcing this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H155AB3FCE11F4134A73D7A01D231AC7D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of information</header><text>For the purpose of monitoring compliance under this subsection, the Secretary shall use information—</text> <subparagraph id="H62DA8887DA064E43B5998987F87C2AAB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collected by the Secretary under the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3501">7 U.S.C. 3501 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF6A16A92BA4F4BC0BB64BEF67C5638AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>from the FSA–153 form submitted to the Farm Service Agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDCFA1C854552404598FB1B75550F7AD6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress, on an annual basis, a report containing the following information:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA155C32C7BFC4FC08BBCF8AEBAB23552"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of violations of subsection (b) during the year covered by the report.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD364C11AB2404D8CA8F1904C995CC631"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An itemized list of savings for each program administered by the Farm Service Agency during the year covered by the report as a result of subsection (b).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H199AAAA6DB5C4CC8BE1461C874477579"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of compliance actions taken by the Secretary under subsection (c) during the year covered by the report.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAFE1D17A3381481A971FED855D3CCDC0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An itemized list of civil penalties imposed on foreign persons under subsection (c)(3) during the year covered by the report.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD3262DF90682426CACBD995C8F47C167"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Such other information on enforcement under this section, compliance with this section, and the benefits of this section as the Secretary determines to be necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC372B588BEEE486690E582D87272EED5"><enum>8.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A370AFACB554CFC858DDB9BE61154CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$35,000,000 for fiscal year 2026, to remain available until expended, for secure workspace buildout under the amendments made by section 4 and database system development under section 6; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCA0D6B34F8924B98A33E67817EC7D63E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$9,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030 for all other activities.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 


