<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-WAL25434-JL5-YS-SDD">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 244 IS: Affirming that the underlying purpose of the Foreign Emoluments Clause renders the acceptance and transfer of a plane from the Government of Qatar, without the explicit consent of Congress, an illegal emolument, withholding the consent of the Senate to the acceptance and transfer of plane from the Government of Qatar, and demanding the transfer of any plane received by President Donald J. Trump or entities under his control from the Government of Qatar to the permanent control of the United States Government.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>III</distribution-code>
        <congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. RES. 244</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action display="yes">
            <action-date date="20250521">May 21, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> submitted the following
                resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental
                Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
        <official-title display="yes">Affirming that the underlying purpose of the Foreign
            Emoluments Clause renders the acceptance and transfer of a plane from the Government of
            Qatar, without the explicit consent of Congress, an illegal emolument, withholding the
            consent of the Senate to the acceptance and transfer of plane from the Government of
            Qatar, and demanding the transfer of any plane received by President Donald J. Trump or
            entities under his control from the Government of Qatar to the permanent control of the
            United States Government.</official-title>
    </form>
    <preamble>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas President Donald J. Trump reportedly plans to—</text> <paragraph id="id64a00bf745fb4e10acc09531ae26ad61"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>accept a Boeing 747–8 jumbo jet from the Government of Qatar for United States Government use as Air Force One during the Trump Administration; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id3434476381ed415da458f62f9b4d3811">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>transfer that plane nominally to the Donald J. Trump Presidential Library shortly before the expiration of the term of office of President Trump but continue personal use of the plane after the Presidency of President Trump;</text>
            </paragraph>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the estimated value of the plane is $400,000,000, making the plane one of the biggest gifts to the United States from a foreign government, if accepted;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas Air Force One is equipped with advanced, specialized communications technologies, so that Air Force One may transmit highly classified national security information and serve as a mobile command center in the event of an attack on the United States;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas accepting a plane from a foreign government poses counterintelligence and other national security concerns, such as the insertion of listening devices on the plane;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas ensuring the plane is free from all security risks, including listening devices, could require stripping the plane down to its parts;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas retrofitting the Qatari plane to serve as Air Force One also requires the installation of multiple top-secret systems that enable secure Government communications, midair refueling, and missile defense and that protect against electronic jamming and electromagnetic pulse attacks;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas such a process could cost taxpayers more than $1,000,000,000 and take years to complete;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the only means of speeding up such work requires relaxing current Air Force One security rules;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, even if such work is sped up, the Qatari plane may only be ready near the end of the term of office of President Trump, at which time the plane will be turned over to the Donald J. Trump Presidential Library;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas all fees related to the transfer of the plane to the Donald J. Trump Presidential Library reportedly will be paid by the United States Air Force, rather than by President Trump himself;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the acceptance of a substantial gift from a foreign government could unduly influence the foreign policies of the United States;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the Foreign Emoluments Clause contained in clause 8 of section 9 of article I of the Constitution of the United States provides that no present, emolument, office, or title, of any kind, may be accepted by the President of the United States from a king, prince, or foreign state without the consent of Congress;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the Founders included the Foreign Emoluments Clause in the Constitution of the United States, by unanimous agreement of the State delegations, to ensure the President would remain loyal to the Nation and the public interest;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the Foreign Emoluments Clause has long been understood to be <quote><quote>directed against every kind of influence by foreign governments upon officers of the United States,</quote> in the absence of consent by Congress</quote>;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the President of the United States has a constitutional and statutory obligation to uphold the public trust; and</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the violation of the Foreign Emoluments Clause of the Constitution of the United States undermines public trust and the integrity of public office in the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text>
        </whereas>
    </preamble>
    <resolution-body>
        <section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section">
 <text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="id842167fbea99402aa7b3086a71880fc0"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>affirms that the underlying purpose of the Foreign Emoluments Clause of the Constitution of the United States renders the acceptance and transfer of a plane from the Government of Qatar, without the explicit consent of Congress, an illegal emolument, regardless of the legal technicalities of ownership;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id2cc7d165d7054e588fe9d6ff5a30eb7e">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>withholds the consent of the Senate to the acceptance and transfer of any plane from the Government of Qatar, as such acceptance and transfer poses unacceptable potential costs to taxpayers in the United States as well as grave risks to national security and of foreign corruption; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id372dcedcb4574d128c451ff104b8668f">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>demands the transfer of any plane received by President Donald J. Trump or entities under the control of President Trump from the Government of Qatar, in violation of the Foreign Emoluments Clause contained in clause 8 of section 9 of article I of the Constitution of the United States, to the permanent control of the United States Government.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
    </resolution-body>
</resolution>

