<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H982A1AE5EB724BB18586D667B555C030" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4839 IH: Merchant Marine Allies Partnership Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4839</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250801">August 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To allow the Secretary of Transportation to authorize vessels documented in allied foreign countries, owned by nationals of allied foreign countries, or crewed by allied foreign countries to engage in certain coastwise trade, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H45F9ABBDCF7943BDBE234369B890795E" style="OLC"><section id="H72386BC0BEBA45E79425771F182F1093" commented="no" section-type="section-one" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Merchant Marine Allies Partnership Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H00C5A810391541178DCED0530C33A8BB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Participation in coastwise trade of citizens and vessels of allied foreign countries</header><subsection id="H370B0DA279FA4DFF8FEE26D5F6B69806"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Endorsement eligibility for vessels built in foreign allied countries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 12112(a)(2)(B) of title 46, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H98C99A7B56534DD8A90DA94B3CA9D5BA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (ii) by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE93DB8114578469BBE2C5A8B9DAA9322"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (iii) by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8515F3A8C83441969A53EE4E58EEBA6C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HADF1B327B47944A99FB52A60064300F8"><clause id="H0B6FEB4DC2234777AECCE3B1921F45BD" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was built in a country listed on the Foreign Ally Shipping Registry under section 55124(d) as of the date of issuance of the coastwise endorsement; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H51BC7293959A41018F81D207808E68BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Loss of coastwise trade privileges</header><text>Section 12132 of title 46, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H1DE25B3FCF81497FAF8C4661BACB7089"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b) by striking <quote>outside the United States</quote> and inserting <quote>in a country other than the United States that is not listed on the Foreign Ally Shipping Registry under section 55124(d)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA80CBD8A867546EBA9EC06DF0B8A9B81"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HC4E2F1D46963408A8B67DC7BF5C265D0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H7B5609AB60DF48C98120973C653B9921"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Built or rebuilt in country removed from Foreign Ally Shipping Registry</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in law, a vessel built or rebuilt in a country other than the United States that is eligible to engage in coastwise trade may not engage in coastwise trade for any period during which such country is not listed on the Foreign Ally Shipping Registry, beginning on the effective date of the removal of such country from the Registry.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF8F92F7517D54F12A44A9F3BA671C5E8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment of foreign allied countries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/551">Chapter 551</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HF9D77A4659D140589124E6000D8D53F3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H405C89F265254B9B90D58500D8FEF7A2"><enum>55124.</enum><header>Transportation of merchandise by vessels, owners, and crews of foreign allied nations.</header><subsection id="H6087CBAF120948129A861E2AF99D1EB6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Qualified vessel described</header><text>For purposes of this section, a qualified vessel is a vessel—</text><paragraph id="HD64F713F95F9494B919138873FF5773B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>wholly owned for purposes of engaging in coastwise trade by—</text><subparagraph id="HFB3066175474464EBF5BF97BBE1EA50E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">one or more nationals of a country listed on the Foreign Ally Shipping Registry;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93211B142CD54F1AA4E1611BE9CC6A4F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the government of a country listed on the Foreign Ally Shipping Registry; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA5A9FF11B364680B287A301A747EB0D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a combination of the entities described in clauses (i) or (ii) and a national of the United States; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D038419E00E4AFB8BA68AC1CE59CAC9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">flagged in the United States or a country listed on the Foreign Ally Shipping Registry.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C834EF0C7FA4D689497CCF91DA9C1B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization To engage in certain trade</header><paragraph id="H0829BC65280A45F8BB8564F9FC0E2F40"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Transportation may authorize, for a period not to exceed 5 years, a qualified vessel to transport merchandise by water, or by land and water, between points in the United States to which the coastwise laws apply, either directly or via a foreign port.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AEFF26D50D048449EE3F731116FD23F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Renewal</header><text>The Secretary may renew an authorization under paragraph (1) for subsequent periods not to exceed 5 years each.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2935FCA47BB44BE8B002A19B92D6F98D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Revocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, at any time during the period that an authorization issued under this subsection applies, the vessel subject to such authorization ceases to be a qualified vessel under this section, the Secretary shall revoke the authorization—</text><subparagraph id="HA78744320D1A4EBCAB218AF13390AC2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>except as provided in subparagraph (B), not later than 30 days after the date on which such vessel ceases to be a qualified vessel; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E64FE31C26D4598B4C91D42C77EE428"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a vessel that ceases to be a qualified vessel due to the removal of a country from the Foreign Ally Shipping Registry pursuant to subsection (d)(2), on the effective date of such removal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H87679A17E172431B84898D19FA09361A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notice of change in information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The owner of a vessel subject to an authorization under this subsection shall notify the Secretary of each change in information on which the authorization is based (including information indicative of if the vessel is a qualified vessel) not later than 30 days after such change.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA5E57151226C4C66936A59C11FC4CB7A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Non-Applicability of crewing requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may not enforce citizenship requirements under section 8103 of title 46, United States Code, or the credentialing requirements under section 8701 of title 46, United States Code, with respect to an individual who is—</text><paragraph id="H46E1E9348B844F4081A0A894A76ADF53"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a national of the United States or a country listed on the Foreign Ally Shipping Registry; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF3692C8232C4ECAB08A3A6F4CA1F32F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>employed on a qualified vessel engaged in trade pursuant to an authorization under subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H608A6D9D5A9841DC9FB2D9158A015D67"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Foreign Allied Country Registry</header><paragraph id="HE377D738E723498ABF09F8BDFABB76A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Registry</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of authorizing transportation of merchandise by a vessel under subsection (b), the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Commandant of the Coast Guard, shall maintain a registry to be known as the <quote>Foreign Ally Shipping Registry</quote> that contains a list of each country determined by the Secretary to be an ally of the United States for purposes of carrying out coastwise trade under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0928E89B36304D608DDF24AEDB6A8388"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Removal Procedures</header><subparagraph id="HDD7D87BA6CFA4241BEE2B90B55EF0235"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Commandant, may remove from the Foreign Ally Shipping Registry any country determined by the Secretary to no longer be an ally for purposes of carrying out coastwise trade under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H713B41ECFF16491EB1D69782FCAA75B2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Congressional notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as is practicable within the 30-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary determines that a country is no longer an ally under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Foreign Affairs and Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Foreign Relations and Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a notice of such determination.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82A4CAACD28045479A26FB1156747E63" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effective date of removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Removal of a country from the Foreign Ally Shipping Registry under subparagraph (A) shall take effect on the date that is 30 days after the date on which the Secretary submits a notice under subparagraph (B) with respect to the country.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B4E288C49ED4FA3A2D5AA298473E89E"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Immediately removal resulting from declaration of war</header><text>Effective immediately upon a declaration of war by Congress on any country on the Foreign Ally Shipping Registry—</text><clause id="HEEB8906230BA4BF6872ACBF71A10F213"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such country is removed from the Registry; and</text></clause><clause id="H28DFF805CD624C9D8693358810EAED55"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Secretary may not add such country to the Registry during the period of such war.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F5F2C04CC114953924BF3884F443718"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment of NATO member countries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Foreign Ally Shipping Registry shall include each member country of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, unless and until the date on which such country—</text><subparagraph id="HE0D513F659B944EFB58A13855690AC9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is no longer a member country of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F51C4A49FC44484B3EBFBB01AF5899D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is otherwise removed from the Foreign Ally Shipping Registry pursuant to paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HDC51469E935B47B3840C13E12DC9F036"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/551">chapter 551</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, is amended by adding after the item relating to section 55123 the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H273855469154476F89CE7CCCF50A4BC9"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">55124. Exception for transportation of merchandise by vessels, owners, and crews of foreign allied nations.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H8CDE141966A8447CBA906BFEC489240F" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exemption from duty on repairs of documented vessels in allied foreign countries</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 466(h) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1466">19 U.S.C. 1466(h)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H25FEEC7E084F48A584400EF4595E8FE3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66582E559E3B49D48736DEA966C45925"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35442EFD80184FCD8FAE55E19D4A9125"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H764979848F3F4B9787DCE8C0841D54CD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HB17432CC12B94E8398339DF869CF8EE6"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the cost of repairs made in a shipyard located in a country listed on the Foreign Ally Shipping Registry pursuant to section 55124(d) of title 46, United States Code, with respect to documented vessels (as such term is defined in section 106 of such title). </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

