<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7011721E3CBA4B6EA07872B6185BDC21" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 571 IH: A resolution solemnly marking the one-year anniversary of the attempted assassination of President Donald J. Trump, condemning the multiple attempts against the President’s life, condemning those who incite violence against political officials, and honoring the victims of the shooting.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 571</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250710">July 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001098">Mr. Hamadeh of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001306">Mr. Balderson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001327">Mr. Bresnahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001230">Mr. Mackenzie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000474">Mr. Flood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000235">Mr. Ezell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000490">Mr. Taylor</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000388">Mr. Kelly of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000619">Mr. Rulli</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001188">Mr. Stutzman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001235">Mr. Moore of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001093">Mrs. Houchin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000622">Mr. Patronis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001148">Mr. Simpson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000610">Mr. Reschenthaler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">A resolution solemnly marking the one-year anniversary of the attempted assassination of President Donald J. Trump, condemning the multiple attempts against the President’s life, condemning those who incite violence against political officials, and honoring the victims of the shooting.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on July 13, 2024, an attempt was made on the life of President Donald J. Trump in Butler, Pennsylvania;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Corey D. Comperatore tragically died while shielding his family from the gunfire in Butler, Pennsylvania;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas David Dutch and James Copenhaver were critically injured in the attack and hospitalized in Butler, Pennsylvania;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, during these attacks, law enforcement, first responders, and medical personnel performed their duties with professionalism and heroism;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on December 10, 2024, the Task Force on the Attempted Assassination of Donald J. Trump released their Final Report of Findings and Recommendations; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas continued calls for violence against the President of the United States, violent acts carried out against elected officials like those perpetrated on Governor of Pennsylvania Josh Shapiro, Minnesota State House Speaker Emerita Melissa Hortman, and Minnesota State Senator John Hoffman, and continued divisive rhetoric targeting elected officials are contradictory to the United States tradition and risk undermining the democratic process and endangering the lives of public servants: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H0C0BD4A3028246779B4874D989BDC1AB"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HBFE6AA5471DD4C11A574BB0FC20BE904"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H826AB4C7CCB747B69231273DDD4E0BDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns the assassination attempts against President Donald J. Trump on July 13, 2024, in Butler, Pennsylvania, and on September 15, 2024, in West Palm Beach, Florida;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H60D3007432E0496B86DD3A400A9772B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors Corey D. Comperatore, who died while protecting his family from the gunfire at the rally for President Trump;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF788C83FF348456691331844E607FB94"><enum>(3)</enum><text>honors David Dutch and James Copenhaver, who were critically injured in the gunfire at the rally for President Trump and hospitalized;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB791EF9FD8B1448B86811F6161E2BA76"><enum>(4)</enum><text>expresses gratitude to the law enforcement officers, first responders, and medical personnel who responded to the attacks, conducted investigations, and provided aid to the victims;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H272BD57569D9462685958EF8AD7EBFF5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>affirms that the United States Secret Service is the agency responsible for protecting the country’s highest elected officials and is therefore central to upholding the Nation’s constitutional values; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB7558CE18C844427BE85C2904E73CF81"><enum>(6)</enum><text>calls on all United States citizens to unite against political violence and condemns those who incite violence against political officials.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

