<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-HLA25152-G8L-DJ-R4L"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 119 IS: Memorializing those lost to the COVID–19 pandemic.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 119</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250306">March 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Memorializing those lost to the COVID–19 pandemic.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the first Monday in March is recognized as <quote>COVID–19 Victims Memorial Day</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas SARS–CoV–2 is a coronavirus that causes COVID–19 disease;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in late 2019, COVID–19 emerged and began to spread throughout the world, creating a pandemic that has had a catastrophic impact on human life, communities, and the economy of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in March 2020, communities in the United States began to experience increased death due to the COVID–19 pandemic, and families lost parents, siblings, children, friends, and neighbors to the virus;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, beginning in 2020, many across the United States were, and continue to be, personally impacted by the COVID–19 pandemic, including mourning their loved ones or suffering from the unknown long-term health implications of the virus;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, by the end of February 2025, there had been more than 103,000,000 known cases of COVID–19 in the United States, and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention estimates that more than 1,220,000 individuals tragically lost their lives due to illness related to COVID–19;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention estimate that between October 1, 2024 and February 15, 2025, there were 6,400,000 to 11,500,000 known cases of COVID–19 in the United States; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the COVID–19 pandemic has had a disproportionate impact on low-income communities and communities of color, individuals with disabilities, individuals with weakened immune systems, individuals with other risk factors, such as physical or mental comorbidities, and individuals living in congregate settings, such as long-term care facilities and prisons;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas frontline and essential workers and health care and public health professionals have taken selfless actions to protect their neighbors and communities, support struggling local economies, and find innovative ways to provide services;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas local, State, Tribal, and Federal Government entities have provided critical support to businesses, communities, and the people of the United States in need; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas each life lost to the COVID–19 pandemic and each sacrifice made shall never be forgotten: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idb9247294967b4fb781dd4da990f6ab0a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>will memorialize those lost to the COVID–19 pandemic;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7b5d2436656048ff96067fb71b3445a0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the suffering of those who contracted the SARS–CoV–2 virus and those who continue to struggle with the ongoing impacts of the COVID–19 pandemic; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0564bed18cec408db77f026f70f15452"><enum>(3)</enum><text>expresses support for the annual designation of the first Monday in March as <quote>COVID–19 Victims Memorial Day</quote>. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

