<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H00054942B3314D2C99F4AB6AFD86E665" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 783 IH: Reaffirming German-American friendship and supporting continued cooperation between the United States and Germany.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 783</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250930">September 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Reaffirming German-American friendship and supporting continued cooperation between the United States and Germany.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States and Germany have a close bond and friendship based on heritage, common values, and shared interests that must be maintained and strengthened;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 2018, Germany and the United States launched Wunderbar Together, with the goal of promoting the robust relationship between Germans and Americans and showcasing the close links between our countries;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas more than 40,000,000 Americans of German origin live in the United States, many of whom have provided valuable contributions to the growth and development of the United States and to the maintenance of strong ties to Germany and the German people;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas today the United States and Germany are close political allies, partners, and friends working together for a peaceful world order based on the rule of law;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Germany is an important trading partner of the United States in the European Union, and, in 2021, German companies represented the third-largest foreign employer in the United States, accounting for about 885,000 jobs, and between 2020 and 2022, Germans have invested more than $1,180,000,000,000 in the United States, the third-largest European source of foreign direct investment in the United States, and, during the same period, Americans invested more than $517,000,000,000 in Germany;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States played a leading role in the reconstruction of Germany after World War II through political and financial means, laying the groundwork for the establishment of a peaceful, democratic postwar West Germany and paving the way for close United States-West Germany bilateral relations;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States played a crucial role in the unification of Germany after the fall of the Berlin Wall, which took place 36 years ago this November;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on October 3, 2025, Germany celebrated its 35th annual Day of German Unity commemorating German reunification in 1990;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 2025 marks the 42d anniversary of the Congress-Bundestag Youth Exchange Program, which has strengthened ties between almost 28,000 American and German youth, improved their career skills through formal study and work experience, and expanded their perspectives and awareness of each other’s culture, society, history, and politics;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States and Germany stand united in their support for Ukraine and the Ukrainian people as they defend democracy and freedom against illegal Russian aggression;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States and Germany stand resolutely against antisemitism and stand in firm and unwavering solidarity with Israel in the aftermath of barbaric terror attacks;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on October 6, 2023, President Biden issued a proclamation on German-American Day urging Americans to <quote>celebrate the rich and varied history of German Americans and remember the many contributions they have made to our Nation</quote>; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Germany and the United States maintain strong bilateral ties and cooperate closely on the global stage and through international organizations where both countries work to promote shared values, including human rights, democracy, and the rule of law: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HFB33A37568C04C439B9C3D9B63FC1389"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H24247FF13A40498DB8EB1E7160D29D95"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="H767821A75EDE4B6982B21180AE11326C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes and highlights the importance of the alliance between the United States and Germany in—</text> <subparagraph id="H59F709C9243A4D2C9CFB4C0A85BDE995"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an enduring shared commitment to our free and democratic societies;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA8CA64D734004842A0DBD24D3251903A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>expanding and deepening economic prosperity for the United States and Europe; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H71814E2A7F2B46EDBE9E628D2EB06494"><enum>(C)</enum><text>protecting and defending our security, freedom, and common values;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA0860758DB9D43D3946EE4E0B35342A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the strong personal, cultural, and historical ties between our populations and governments, and the importance of our common set of fundamental values as guiding principles for tackling the growing global challenges of the 21st century; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H17E90B574B014929B4DE137A4C69BDE3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirms the deep and historical friendship between the Government and people of the United States and the Government and people of Germany.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

