<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KAT25094-1TH-7C-8V3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S412 IS: Plum Island Preservation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 412</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250205">February 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prescribe requirements relating to the management of the consolidated Federal asset commonly known as Plum Island, New York, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section id="id1db7adeb-ea66-41be-95c2-2f7fbea06f2a" section-type="section-one" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Plum Island Preservation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8b78ab9b-e432-456a-9622-3bd221750c35" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Permanent preservation of Plum Island, New York</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3a6ef04d-158e-4252-9b5c-dfe0f4062fae" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The consolidated Federal asset commonly known as Plum Island, New York, and all associated real and personal properties, including the Orient Point, New York, terminal and facilities (referred to in this section as <term>Plum Island</term>), shall be protected in perpetuity for the purposes of—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id63dbd805694444ff848aece49586683c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ecological conservation; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4dfd19461fec44fe8f255b54c400eec3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">discovery and celebration of the historical and cultural heritage of Plum Island; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd7d6b65d5474eb890d0f8fd6e349030" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>maintaining access to Plum Island.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1ca27be4-9fb4-4401-9896-47db865dad2d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of General Services (referred to in this section as the <term>Administrator</term>), in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of the Interior, relevant Federal and State agencies, Tribal governments, and other stakeholders, shall initiate a process to commence formal visioning sessions that may form the basis for a future ecological management plan for Plum Island in accordance with subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="id760c1d5a-ed0c-44fd-9cec-0ff2311f3781" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date on which the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of the Interior, relevant Federal and State agencies, Tribal governments, and other stakeholders, initiates the process required under subsection (b), and each year thereafter until the date that is 1 year after the date on which the visioning sessions required under that subsection are completed, the Administrator shall submit to the Committees on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committees on Energy and Commerce, Natural Resources, and Oversight and Accountability of the House of Representatives a report that describes—</text><paragraph id="id4d31a9ae-bb03-4792-a1aa-7be6afd57f57" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Federal and State agencies, Tribal governments, and other stakeholders consulted during those visioning sessions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id40b34421-ff78-423b-9bad-307efaef703d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the items discussed or reviewed during that process for the period covered by the applicable report;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8104378c-5d2f-41d7-bf22-c4bcf1d40361" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the outcomes of that process, or expected outcomes if the process is ongoing;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id129f342c-a004-42cb-a647-b60eea2e70c9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>if that process is not completed, the estimated timeline for completion; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3c73b295-f0c2-4c03-b24f-6113013b55f4" changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><text>if that process is completed, the recommendations from those visioning sessions that may form the basis for a future ecological management plan for Plum Island. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

