<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCBFB483BCCA747FBBD1DA687E3374BB5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3480 IH: Health Coverage for Inclusive and Valued Families Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3480</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250519">May 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to include fertility treatment and care as an essential health benefit.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H49B2A2063AAE41F3A9BB22D4B9A4A103" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAC37B27FEBB14830B0E1FAA81E7D6FD2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Health Coverage for Inclusive and Valued Families Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Health Coverage for IVF Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H96208B0E08964C83AF733C80A88C33E8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Including fertility treatment and care as an essential health benefit</header> 
<subsection id="HC277ADAC20914521891BA2C556B0F492"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1302(b) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18022">42 U.S.C. 18022(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2BFCF962A96F403D804CF7A0F0696F24"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H517968A0D5304762AE9DF8B3A538F5B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>paragraph (2)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (2) and (6)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6C3CB2C89DB54CC4BA2115B3F09B3DBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE16EC38F71C445269A4A4B6B18956DA7" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H696732D8CF71473EA2B5F81D836AB316"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Fertility treatment and care.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HABC070E3EED7431891B47E83E6CC1802"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H95B986C39D2845C7B70C4576052F0EC6" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H1E5D19B632C34535A0087FC0DDDE7916"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Fertility treatment and care defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1)(K), the term <quote>fertility treatment and care</quote> means the following medically appropriate items and services furnished to an individual:</text> <subparagraph id="HE0C719282CAE4EE39C0D439F32703F0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Preservation of human oocytes, sperm, or embryos for later reproductive use.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD283594D6F6A4BA1A8EF53DBAD19B0A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Artificial insemination, including intravaginal insemination, intracervical insemination, and intrauterine insemination.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFACDC9965DF742B4A041F7B86DD0D856"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Assisted reproductive technology, including in vitro fertilization and other treatments or procedures in which reproductive genetic material, such as oocytes, sperm, fertilized eggs, and embryos, are handled, when clinically appropriate, and including at least 3 complete oocyte retrievals and an unlimited number of embryo transfers from such retrievals (regardless of whether such retrieval was performed on, before, or after the date of the enactment of this paragraph) in accordance with the guidelines of the American Society for Reproductive Medicine and using single embryo transfer when recommended and medically appropriate.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H855B2F04309B4163ADBDC3DAE86AEA0A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Genetic testing of embryos.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2FDB71716ADE4E75A1B326D47C6D25F7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Medications prescribed, as indicated for fertility.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H306409E83F3A4C80BADAEE31754D19A0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Gamete donation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H50F583753AEB46E3A39BD649F8B03814"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Such other information, referrals, treatments, procedures, medications, laboratory testing, technologies, and services relating to fertility as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC42C7DD431ED48348D35031605804357"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text>Subpart II of part A of title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-11">42 U.S.C. 300gg–11 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA2EA499E11524EDD9BCED8D46682D612" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H426F8D0C879D40F5BD9447BF5795520F"><enum>2730.</enum><header>Requirements relating to fertility treatment and care</header> <subsection id="HCBB8728EF1DB4C43B5757700486DDD91"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of health insurance coverage offered in the individual or small group market that provides both medical and surgical benefits and benefits for fertility treatment and care (as defined in section 1302(b) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act), such coverage shall ensure that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0828462FDDCB4DEE9E47EA01938BF027"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the financial requirements applicable to such fertility treatment and care benefits are no more restrictive than the predominant financial requirements applied to substantially all medical and surgical benefits covered by the coverage, and there are no separate cost sharing requirements that are applicable only with respect to fertility treatment and care benefits; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H977B2F49CFBA466A9BE173EB6DD20C96"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the treatment limitations applicable to such fertility treatment and care benefits are no more restrictive than the predominant treatment limitations applied to substantially all medical and surgical benefits covered by the coverage and there are no separate treatment limitations that are applicable only with respect to fertility treatment and care benefits.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H210560C293C54E2BA777E42795647459"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on denial of care</header><text>A health insurance issuer offering health insurance coverage in the individual or small group market may not deny benefits for fertility treatment and care for individual on the basis that such individual lacks a diagnosis of infertility.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H17D84892FE29437B99E1D1DCFA401A3C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Utilization management tools</header> <paragraph id="H10B72C8DE19E441DA19C48565C2B22F2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A health insurance issuer offering health insurance coverage in the individual or small group market that imposes any utilization management tool with respect to fertility treatment and care shall, for each of the first 5 plan years beginning on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act (and, upon request of the Secretary or the Comptroller General of the United States, for any subsequent plan year), conduct an analysis of the application of any such tool to such treatment and care and submit such analysis to the Secretary and to the Comptroller General of the United States. Such analysis shall contain the following information:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE04604D8A0164F559A4B433EF1B252D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The specific coverage terms or other relevant terms regarding the application of such tools to such benefits and a description of all such benefits.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE416B8D5EB7D493283934DE8F72F06DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The factors used to determine when utilization management tools apply to such benefits.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6088410F78834EB2BA135FE7F2F28B18"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The evidentiary standards used in designing the application of such tools with respect to such benefits and any other source or evidence used to determine the application of such tools to such benefits.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H52FAAD5D10A0455F97999C1F37215BF9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Information demonstrating how application of such tools to such benefits are consistent with clinical guidelines for fertility treatment and care.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCA3F22B8DC194955AE9F5BF384871305"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any findings by the issuer that such coverage is not in compliance with this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA1138D2DBEFE4EC1ACB70A682AC3D53D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress and make publicly available a report that contains the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H18867068F0E6452088E686FEFE627616"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A summary of the analyses submitted under paragraph (1) with respect to such plan year.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2F7F03466D674D87BCB54CA9845DE41A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An identification of each health insurance issuer that failed to submit an analysis under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD4771064185F46CF834AC0F9F24C4AB9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>With respect to each health insurance issuer that did submit such an analysis, a specification as to whether such issuer submitted information sufficient to determine whether such issuer was in compliance with such requirements.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFB9ED3EB932343D6B613C049FDD9A8DD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>For each health insurance issuer that did submit information sufficient to determine such compliance, a finding of whether such issuer was in compliance with such requirements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H93F87A2EF2084853BD7839339531909D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>The terms <quote>financial requirement</quote>, <quote>predominant</quote>, and <quote>treatment limitation</quote> have the meaning given such terms in section 2726(a)(3).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HFBE4D30252C243AABCF1DBE4351EE2FF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to plan years beginning on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

