<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-joint" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-DAV25308-09W-W7-CC8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SJ 34 IS: Providing for congressional disapproval of the proposed foreign military sale to the Government of Israel of certain defense articles and services.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. J. RES. 34</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250310">March 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</sponsor> introduced the following joint resolution; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing for congressional disapproval of the proposed foreign military sale to the Government of Israel of certain defense articles and services.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H9C2E52D41B6B4895AF900093904886AC"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H989ECF5139D54D76ADB5C1A2622B7489"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the following proposed foreign military sale to the Government of Israel is prohibited:</text><paragraph id="H3097CF3D5718499F8467A0E4F8AB6418"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The sale of the following defense articles and services described in Transmittal No. 25–26, submitted to Congress pursuant to section 36(b)(1) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2776">22 U.S.C. 2776(b)(1)</external-xref>), and published in the Congressional Record on March 3, 2025: The following Major Defense Equipment (MDE): Two hundred one (201) MK 83 MOD 4/MOD 5 General Purpose 1,000-pound bomb bodies. Four thousand seven hundred ninety-nine (4,799) BLU–110A/B General Purpose 1,000-pound bomb bodies. One thousand five hundred (1,500) KMU–559C/B Joint Direct Attack Munition (JDAM) guidance kits for the MK 83 bomb body. Three thousand five hundred (3,500) KMU–559J/B JDAM guidance kits for the MK 83 bomb body. The following non-MDE items will also be included: U.S. Government and contractor engineering, logistics, and technical support services; and other related elements of logistics and program support. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

