<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4A584377F4144D0D9956A6D9A8F7FBB3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1787 IH: Roberto Clemente Commemorative Coin Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1787</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250303">March 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint commemorative coins in recognition of the life and legacy of Roberto Clemente.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3C681A4E7F4346AE9E7CBEBED5831E15" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF87F5A6D1AD643438307C2B19B6D6A48" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Roberto Clemente Commemorative Coin Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7789FCD445A3478E8FD53A352647D6CE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H7E8D947263FC40D1A335C4043F0C6E7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Roberto Clemente Walker was born on August 18, 1934, to Don Melchor Clemente and Luisa Walker in Barrio San Antón, Carolina, Puerto Rico, as the youngest of 7 children.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E939D9AC0A74430BA7B61BBE54EF2F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Clemente excelled in athletics as a youngster and, at the age of 17, was playing for the Santurce Cangrejeros <quote>Crabbers</quote> of the Puerto Rican Baseball League.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB7BA17F526AD4D32ACA5E9B9378A9CC1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 1954, the Pittsburgh Pirates selected Clemente in the first round of the Major League Baseball Rule 5 draft.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28B06AB6FF3D40BBADA56CFA2589E04F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Pirates center fielder Earl Smith wore jersey number 21 until he parted ways with the team in April 1955, and Clemente wore number 13 until then.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1340E5F7E422499788F679F5B79F6AA3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In 1955, Clemente made his Major League debut as he went on to play for the Pittsburgh Pirates, starting as a right fielder.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5535C93DD5424709A777C255ED3551D3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>When the team traveled to Richmond, Virginia, for games or Florida for spring training, Clemente encountered Jim Crow laws for the first time when the Black players had to stay at a separate, inferior hotel and were refused the option to dine with their White counterparts.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H978EAEBCEDA04418AD5E936BBEF33639"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Clemente was known for being a proud Afro-Latino and protested the discrimination that Latin and Black ball players encountered.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8CC138EB427B4204A4B480B330EAEDB2"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Clemente was known for defending the rights of Black and Brown people, both on the field and in the streets.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC50618FA087C4F3DA117B2469735F116"><enum>(9)</enum><text>After the assassination of Martin Luther King, Jr., in 1968, Clemente and his teammates refused to play until after the funerals and even wrote a public statement showing their respect for Dr. King.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE0635F0409D74408BA72EAEF16D0602B"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Clemente became a union leader in the incipient Major League Baseball Players Association and defended players’ rights to demand better working conditions and benefits.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2DCAA41C935F45B49F6F0A3B84A82E69"><enum>(11)</enum><text>In every city where the Pirates played, Clemente visited sick children in hospitals.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDD2D8067343E45D8A413FB45F40B5912"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Clemente established training clinics, providing baseball lessons and fun for boys and girls in Pittsburgh, his home island of Puerto Rico, and throughout Latin America.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDBD58EA7F89244DDA27D38CFE3BB5D17"><enum>(13)</enum><text>In 1958, Clemente enlisted in the United States Marine Corps Reserve after the 1958 season and spent 6 months on active duty at Parris Island, South Carolina, and Camp LeJeune, North Carolina.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF619872D89347C983CB05127647A121"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Clemente served until 1964 and was inducted into the Marine Corps Sports Hall of Fame in 2003.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H591006270E1C43BE954AC54A1246EF25"><enum>(15)</enum><text>By the end of his career, Clemente had joined the exclusive 3,000-hit club, was selected to 15 All-Star teams, and won 12 Gold Gloves, 2 World Series, and a National League MVP award.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H604B08A92EBD4198B001C12786F6E70A"><enum>(16)</enum><text>In Clemente’s 18 seasons with Pittsburgh he won 4 batting titles, hit 240 home runs, and posted a lifetime .317 batting average.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H42E509B66EEE4E87B4A51D13B3CC1AB4"><enum>(17)</enum><text>In late 1972, a 6.3 magnitude earthquake ravaged Managua, Nicaragua, and killed 5,000 people.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0CC5CA74EADC45D6A5E80BA18448BB48"><enum>(18)</enum><text>In his philanthropic spirit, Clemente sent shipments of humanitarian aid to the country.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H982375F42AC64CCEB9A118819DA1E09B"><enum>(19)</enum><text>After learning that 3 previous shipments had been diverted by corrupt Somoza Government officials, Clemente decided to accompany one of the aid shipments.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H395FCA9B83CB4C1890C0B9A01435B5A2"><enum>(20)</enum><text>The four-engine DC–7 plane Clemente chartered for a flight on New Year’s Eve crashed in the Atlantic Ocean immediately after takeoff from the coast of Isla Verde, Puerto Rico.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H362935A53D914E418D014107EBA75EF8"><enum>(21)</enum><text>On December 31, 1972, Clemente died in the plane crash at the age of 38 years young.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D8D54C4B1734F299AC083B5D516A081"><enum>(22)</enum><text>Since 1973, Major League Baseball gives out the Roberto Clemente Award to one player in the league who <quote>best exemplifies the game of baseball, sportsmanship, community involvement and the individual’s contribution to his team</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7FC49638490C401B9E43A9BF0BFF6AA4"><enum>(23)</enum><text>In 2002, Major League Baseball declared the first annual Roberto Clemente Day.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H81172A5777884051A046D51F3DD539F7"><enum>(24)</enum><text>In 2021, Major League Baseball announced September 15 would be the permanent date of Roberto Clemente Day to coincide with the beginning of Hispanic Heritage month.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC19643CAE27F4FD6B21C94F94FAB2E9A"><enum>(25)</enum><text>Clemente was the first Latino player to accomplish many feats in Major League Baseball.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7FF6834FD101410DBC07C9733C1DE758"><enum>(26)</enum><text>Clemente was the first Puerto Rican, and first person of Latino heritage, to win a World Series as a starter, be named league MVP, be named World Series MVP, and be elected to the Hall of Fame.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFE5ECE88CDA94CDE89755E3D497671A3"><enum>(27)</enum><text>Clemente was posthumously elected to the National Baseball Hall of Fame in 1973, being the first National League baseball player to receive the mandatory 5-year waiting period waiver.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H302ACC6FCA414E8181ED64A54897B753"><enum>(28)</enum><text>Clemente was a legend in life and death, a baseball star, a humanitarian activist, and a symbol of Latin American pride;</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H8522D63290204D1D8F5C0E2E00DE911F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Coin specifications</header>
<subsection id="H78755963A18C42199A2234DA5B8F461C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Denominations</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall mint and issue the following coin:</text> <paragraph id="HE9BC12ED91C2495B99309D67988B48A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>$5 gold coins</header><text>Not more than 50,000 $5 coins, which shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="HBE69AFED71E8463AB19E57AADEA6C8B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>weigh 8.359 grams;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9CC35EC175AE434CACA408C9399ADE6B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have a diameter of 0.850 inches; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA4D2880A124D4A4897CC45F8AEDB1ABF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>contain not less than 90 percent gold.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H983FEC01FA944E828C1554D788A69A87"><enum>(2)</enum><header>$1 silver coins</header><text>Not more than 400,000 $1 coins, which shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="HD4F67502727B443EBC7EBBFF2D792854"><enum>(A)</enum><text>weigh 26.73 grams;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D79B7CC7FA8495E949A429F0E6CA50B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have a diameter of 1.500 inches; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB551DBC1222E43CF84BC4F5CAEA3F224"><enum>(C)</enum><text>contain not less than 90 percent silver.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2138A4328C1840EAB0FD5213FF96C01F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Half-dollar clad coins</header><text>Not more than 750,000 half-dollar coins which shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1E85E03D4D044C96B799767B70603CC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>weigh 11.34 grams;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H670C473936AB4FA2A2C29695999F1993"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have a diameter of 1.205 inches; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFAEE9864508F412683979A99D30A6109"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be minted to the specifications for half-dollar coins contained in section 5112(b) of title 31, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H49CA39084D5D42769EB0512C2298B5D9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Legal tender</header><text>The coins minted under this Act shall be legal tender, as provided in section 5103 of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HC1FB40EF10254D288BCCDE4412C59593"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all coins minted under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H7C721C317A74428982D04E8B514E721F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Design of coins</header> <subsection id="HB521BBAAFA244EE6A219EA65D0EB9B34"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Design requirements</header> <paragraph id="H1C0834DB3204409DAC47D6ACA4BF6DAB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The designs of the coins minted under this Act shall be emblematic of the life of Roberto Clemente including his human rights activism and baseball stardom legacy. At least one obverse design shall bear the image of Roberto Clemente.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HED864E94A9A04D998169449B0C1A76B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation and inscriptions</header><text>On each coin minted under this Act, there shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="HA477E6E424164D9195908FD27766EBF5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an inscription of Roberto Clemente;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6C39597B1D06412DAC66B5A74BBA61FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a designation of the denomination of the coin;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4B9E0A5C314D4A2FBF80DFB9BEC3B9A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an inscription of the year <quote>2027</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDDC60513F94946E2B54CF265D1C27AD8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>inscriptions of the words <quote>Liberty</quote>, <quote>In God We Trust</quote>, <quote>United States of America</quote>, and <quote>E Pluribus Unum</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H78FB51DBD08C486E998F7628D5CEA7E8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The designs for the coins minted under this Act shall be—</text>
<paragraph id="H7DFDD77DF1464E8D8BED694AE6E0DB9F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>selected by the Secretary after consultation with the Roberto Clemente Foundation, Roberto Clemente’s living family members, and the Commission of the Fine Arts; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7264CC9B626C4638BA66EC1EBAE1E2E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reviewed by the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HE585D48C295E463A9819F0C4B6DA42DD"><enum>5.</enum><header>Issuance of coins</header>
<subsection id="H6786172999BE44F3907BABD1E02980B3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Quality of coins</header><text>Coins minted under this Act shall be issued in uncirculated and proof qualities.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H64E5CA8E2DEC4913B94BF73B623444F7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Period for issuance</header><text>The Secretary may issue coins under this Act only during the calendar year beginning on January 1, 2027.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H185DA1B0DC1449AABFE0D705BF0F11EF"><enum>6.</enum><header>Sale of coins</header>
<subsection id="H27577B03975D42E0BB78FDE49B2AD3F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sale price</header><text>The coins issued under this Act shall be sold by the Secretary at a price equal to the sum of—</text> <paragraph id="HD2973C5660B549A0A1C47C35627BDA84"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the face value of the coins;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE9F3166A6B48499ABB82D05C383AAC0F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the surcharge provided in section 7(a) with respect to such coins; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H649DCA06436E4248BFDC0D5010B4AEE9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the cost of designing and issuing the coins (including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, overhead expenses, marketing, and shipping).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H8AD9D53FBC4D48A590AF72252219E449"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Bulk sales</header><text>The Secretary shall make bulk sales of the coins issued under this Act at a reasonable discount.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF9140B54CA2D4771A2C3C11FEBA08691"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prepaid orders</header> <paragraph id="H78FC78817B8947D28D1F6F9521BF7BED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall accept prepaid orders for the coins minted under this Act before the issuance of such coins.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA3034A125854494ABA061204A0534CF0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Discount</header><text>Sale prices with respect to prepaid orders under paragraph (1) shall be at a reasonable discount.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H56881073AD994FDE92877900AFE7F41D"><enum>7.</enum><header>Surcharges</header> <subsection id="H8CD468B1A17D48668CD33F3CCCA0DE9B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All sales of coins issued under this Act shall include a surcharge of—</text>
<paragraph id="H6EF2E0D1DBB54A0C8ECD256B113C7D07"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$35 per coin for the $5 coin;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA093E0290F524EDE88B50767E0E684EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$10 per coin for the $1 coin; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H72A2C9E1C00B47F6B8066FF3D56A9F8C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$5 per coin for the half-dollar coin.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H55FF39D089BD4449AC49F3850C940794"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>Subject to section 5134(f) of title 31, United States Code, all surcharges received by the Secretary from the sale of coins issued under this Act shall be paid to the Roberto Clemente Foundation for application to general expenses associated with the fulfillment of the mission of the Roberto Clemente Foundation including for costs associated with educational, youth sports, and disaster relief historic preservation—</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H35D5A27D59AB4117BC6BB849D679C3B7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Audits</header><text>The Roberto Clemente Foundation, shall be subject to the audit requirements of section 5134(f)(2) of title 31, United States Code, with regard to the amounts received under subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8CADFF3705784FC1A83F555FAFDCF3D0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), no surcharge may be included with respect to the issuance under this Act of any coin during a calendar year if, as of the time of such issuance, the issuance of such coin would result in the number of commemorative coin programs issued during such year to exceed the annual 2 commemorative coin program issuance limitation under section 5112(m)(1) of title 31, United States Code (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act). The Secretary may issue guidance to carry out this subsection.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HBEFAAB1B359845049C63BCC523E2DDE0"><enum>8.</enum><header>Financial assurances</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall take such actions as may be necessary to ensure that—</text> <paragraph id="H6AFB3330722840B7ADE271E5AD149489"><enum>(1)</enum><text>minting and issuing coins under this Act will not result in any net cost to the United States Government; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBAE69E49D90448A0A3D60C010FB2669B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>no funds, including applicable surcharges, shall be disbursed to any recipient designated in section 7 until the total cost of designing and issuing all of the coins authorized by this Act (including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, overhead expenses, marketing, and shipping) is recovered by the United States Treasury, consistent with sections 5112(m) and 5134(f) of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

