<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25A55-C7J-HM-2G3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1888 IS: United States Foundation for International Food Security Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1888</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250522">May 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish the United States Foundation for International Food Security to
            leverage private sector investments in order to improve and scale economically viable
            agricultural production, build food systems to mitigate food shock, reduce malnutrition,
 and drive economic growth, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c457168ba3c419994ce361e890fc136"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States Foundation for International Food Security Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4f64430c484a4c34b975343dacc55898"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="S1">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idc6a0c0f4630b486da0fbd1a192536565">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id1e9c9709774d4ba08e660a98c9729722">Sec. 3. United States Foundation for International Food Security.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idacb1ec39240f443e85aa5523114de8c8">Sec. 4. Governance of the Foundation.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id0be01df8e8c24be7b836605bc9afe654">Sec. 5. Corporate powers and obligations of the Foundation.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id810653c31e66412eb13bf5a46c9dbc8a">Sec. 6. Outcome-based funding, safeguards, and accountability.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idf2e9167306ae446a8035e3e223b1e2dd">Sec. 7. Ventures, financing, and grants.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idf8a82382e2524a929c268f901a76e0fa">Sec. 8. Prohibition of support in countries that support terrorism or violate human rights and of support for sanctioned persons.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id8fce3f84f3394edeb20e4ce84cbfce4b">Sec. 9. Annual report.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idcc28f1ac21fb4609a70481adecfa0c8b">Sec. 10. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="idc6a0c0f4630b486da0fbd1a192536565"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="idc245e01cc5e14f4fa826f1313408d4fc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4d716a4b9c024652b673957aef5b7df3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate;</committee-name></text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1548ae3c5c2d483282962039e2e065d7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc486f1bf839442868adeda19d66447fc"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9aacf9dc47884de286cf593e6b2a8a88"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id86ac18950f0e453386387250fb226925"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id1e9c9709774d4ba08e660a98c9729722"><enum>3.</enum><header>United States Foundation for International Food Security</header><subsection id="idd592634f31a2454091ae16931a88d39d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph id="id818c8548d11e4584aa8cfd3c2600ba78"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Finding</header><text>Congress finds that there has been established, in the District of Columbia, a private, nonprofit corporation, which is known as the United States Foundation for International Food Security (referred to in this Act as the “Foundation”), which is not an agency or establishment of the United States Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id632d4addecec4f23ab9871c5b66eef6b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed as—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0fed0f0a366c4589b61740043157babe"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">making the Foundation an agency or establishment of the United States Government; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa12d805e28e42e1b519d5a78bf2023b"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">making any member of the Board of Directors of the Foundation or any officer or employee of the Foundation an employee of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70705b8f41714548bd7bae3a23eed84b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transfers or consolidation require act of congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Neither the Foundation nor any of its functions, powers, or duties may be transferred to, or consolidated with, any department, agency, or entity of the Federal Government absent an Act of Congress to such effect.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id170d9425ec464306859d0aedf2385a10"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Tax-exempt status</header><text>The Board shall take all necessary and appropriate steps to ensure that the Foundation is established as an organization described in subsection (c) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, which exempts the organization from taxation under subsection (a) of such section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id73b6bab1cae947f5be0b233869fc2262"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the Foundation are—</text><paragraph id="idf7f5ee4f643847b89a060d3f0041d8e3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to accelerate enduring, primarily locally led agriculture investments that foster food security and resilience in the crop, poultry, aquaculture, and livestock industries, that focus on building economically resilient food systems by investing in—</text><subparagraph id="id96d0f904e55d450d99611f31439c73c6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>financing for, distribution of, and training around key inputs required for increasing crop and animal productivity, distribution, and profits;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7ef0f961518b463e97c8294f55cf6c80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>infrastructure, such as irrigation, warehousing, storage, and food processing, to improve food production and market access through better product quality and the prevention of food loss;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4602f94e95a146d9aed2c324f2b833b4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>applied agricultural research; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8694fc8e04d9416b91c81f6f8b021c90"><enum>(D)</enum><text>economically viable technology deployment that reduces hunger and increases agriculture production or distribution methods;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id45c09c4959704358898984c2c442cbe3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to prevent unnecessary or inefficient vetting processes, due diligence, project financing, or evaluation reviews by seeking out partnerships and contracting with existing government and nongovernmental entities that have proven track records;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaa1fe80b0f634033932b9b5e6dd4707b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to deploy and scale technology and innovation to accelerate food security and agricultural-led economic growth that reduces global hunger and malnutrition;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4fa62067181e4848a10a63171cabfa37"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to coordinate with the United States Foundation for International Conservation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9c3e9cd8d04e4b449fde5e3f04a3743f"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to advance the national security interests of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7bc8c0a850eb4eb59f64fbeb49d2ecce"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to complement international and government investment and technical assistance mechanisms, such as those employed or managed by the United States International Development Finance Corporation, and United States Government food security programs, to jointly catalyze private and public sector engagement, spur agricultural-led economic growth, and strengthen local food and nutrition systems; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc5693d61dd2f4ea7bc7e9b4410ef5fbc"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to ensure the effective use of United States taxpayer dollars and the prioritization of United States foreign policy interests.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idacb1ec39240f443e85aa5523114de8c8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Governance of the Foundation</header><subsection id="id5bc5949c38af453ea890ee5e3a70679b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Board of Directors</header><paragraph id="id97be975034fc4dd7ba3147effc7d9351"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Governance</header><text>The Foundation shall be governed by a voting Board of Directors (referred to in this section as the <quote>Board</quote>) that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf77aec81d7604d519d85c21053a4bbaa"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not exceed 15 members; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id693dd45ef41f404493e7632227ba9b3e"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may consult with a nonvoting Board of Advisors when making decisions related to the Foundation’s work.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idF7991E14CEF54B0C805547D90A4FEA9F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>Individuals appointed to the Board shall include individuals who are knowledgeable and experienced in matters relating to—</text><subparagraph id="id4F1A79A6EA06457EAFAF7D698A809352"><enum>(A)</enum><text>agricultural production, livestock, land management, or forestry;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id55aabc4765db4f3a942a533326d9b3d6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>agricultural economics, business development, technology deployment, market access, agribusinesses (including food companies), market access, supply chains, infrastructure, or commodities groups;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idac023ecd316646698aaa258f6ee4f0b7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>international finance and multilateral governance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6780b74a80744b9d8f358fbbba13e6e9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>outcome-based and impact funding concepts, including the role of impact evaluations and data collection, to measure the progress of ventures, and innovative grantee or investee selection and funding structures;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfafbd2a1dbd844bda7cf4de67f8c40ac"><enum>(E)</enum><text>agricultural research and development; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3000f463439b453881e52076bf716462"><enum>(F)</enum><text>national security.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id785e6feb41aa4772980ffe4ae697f5db"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on political affiliation</header><text>The Directors of the Board shall include members of both major political parties in a relatively equal number.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb9b934ac76d94ab8ad6af97ac3c2fdbe"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>A quorum of the voting Directors of the Board shall elect a Chairperson, who shall serve in such position for a 4-year term.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id14000f69018e48c29918568e8a169c2c"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Voting</header><text>All voting Directors of the Board shall have equal voting rights.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf3506475d1ca45f68b0ed9f43e93190d"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Terms; vacancies</header><subparagraph id="id20f348acf9a544e69b25e96a52c76f4c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>The term of service of each Director may not exceed 5 years and is renewable for not more than 1 additional 5-year term.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddb5f738864ef482aafbbd3ad9a6c9328"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>Any vacancy in the membership of the appointed Directors of the Board—</text><clause id="id62ddbdf5037d461dbf12504eda72c135"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be filled in accordance with the bylaws of the Foundation;</text></clause><clause id="id4848b2459720459da13f7c884d98b10f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not affect the power of the remaining appointed Directors to execute the duties of the Board; and</text></clause><clause id="ida7d22597b89b473f94bd9f135e14437e"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>shall be filled by an individual selected in accordance with the bylaws of the Board.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1563ab94931d4f71936e9a3b8d35c8d9"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the current membership of the Board shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of Foundation business.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id43e7a155caad471fbbbb8b46823beacd"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Meetings</header><subparagraph id="ide5f3d79a806449ed9f2ab3399e10af4b"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board shall meet not less frequently than twice per year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id42fe98d34f7f4477afe82a5357da2c46"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Board shall maintain full control and decision-making authority of the Foundation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0026a09dc4bd42e6b56b2ff29831f591"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Removal</header><text>Any Director may be removed from the Board if—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddb079f3f5e4846fba7f0055149dd5f0f"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Director is absent from 2 consecutive regularly scheduled meetings without reasonable cause; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23bd842dff814004a6d1b03520e85cea"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Board, by a majority vote of the other Board members, determines that such Director should be removed from the Board.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9109d060929e4d558e5cacf9396743ad"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Reimbursement of expenses</header><text>Directors of the Board shall serve without pay, but may be reimbursed for the actual and necessary traveling and subsistence expenses incurred by such members in the performance of their duties on behalf of the Foundation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc97f457da1744607a714157f6cc41fe1"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Not Federal employees</header><text>Appointment as a Director of the Board shall not constitute employment by, or the holding of an office of, the United States Government for purposes of any Federal law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idefeb015b6c8f4ffdbe2d06db14ad2dac"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Board shall—</text><subparagraph id="idb082a76fdc0e439390269f7db4228846"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish bylaws for the Foundation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd9af94f16c5349d39f2cd744d7cba092"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide overall direction for the activities of the Foundation and establish priority activities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb624174f8a5849c38744f4d7c5d28ec4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>carry out any other necessary activities of the Foundation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id087415856beb4600812457c6c0281094"><enum>(D)</enum><text>hire and evaluate the performance of the Executive Director of the Foundation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id309b0f8340dc407eaea31f7f461abf5f"><enum>(E)</enum><text>take steps to limit the Foundation’s administrative expenses to the extent practicable and in accordance with industry standards.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idca8fdc43b465477ab4260961234f4f33"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Bylaws</header><text>The bylaws of the Foundation shall require the Board to establish—</text><subparagraph id="id80f46ad04ec04982bb780513aa5e1c6f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>policies for the selection of Directors of the Board, Members of the Board of Advisors, and officers, employees, agents, and contractors of the Foundation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id78da5b2ba7d34ef3b07a5aea0ea46672"><enum>(B)</enum><text>policies, including ethical standards, for—</text><clause id="idce0540f99b724112975ba5c4dd9b29ac"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the acceptance, solicitation, and disposition of donations and grants to the Foundation; and</text></clause><clause id="idebbcbd86dd0b42388c065a07a424febd"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the use and disposition of the assets of the Foundation;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ided442e57849c44e79a850d82b34cb895"><enum>(C)</enum><text>policies that subject all employees, fellows, trainees, and other agents of the Foundation (including all of the Directors of the Board and all of the Members of the Board of Advisors) to prevailing conflict of interest standards for the industry;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id72a1aa754cf84ec695e6556311585366"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the specific duties of the Executive Director of the Foundation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida23ab36634c4488ca848a7c8e47de012"><enum>(E)</enum><text>policies for winding down the activities of the Foundation upon termination, including a plan—</text><clause id="id5f886534763d47b294a750f38f3742f3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to return unobligated appropriations to the Department of the Treasury; and</text></clause><clause id="idf8e1b4a9925a477784f4a01b896ddeb6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to donate unspent private and philanthropic contributions to projects that align with the goals and requirements described in this Act; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc041b0bec52240a0bc6709f41d5b7ec8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>specific policies and requirements governing project criteria, measurable outcomes, impact evaluations, and country eligibility requirements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9422376c30f7498c9637b9c4ff9441b4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Board of Advisors composition</header><paragraph id="idba257fa301634016a33433aacb1293f9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The nonvoting Board of Advisors may be composed of, at a minimum—</text><subparagraph id="id9ef838fa2846494aa2c8b6ca5ede0a32"><enum>(A)</enum><text>members of the executive branch of the Federal Government from departments and agencies with expertise that would benefit the Foundation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1b555aa1a77d4ec2b83b20c498f08bd3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of State, or the Secretary's designee;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide225fc14981d4ff99465eaf9e08c4e8a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Chief Executive Officer of the United States International Development Finance Corporation, or his or her designee; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide0cec5c61c1c4527bf328fba9d0c0613"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 deans or other designated faculty members of United States land-grant colleges or universities that have an international agriculture program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4a5aaef657054ee1a4e278e86a1eb0dd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Board of Advisors shall provide advice and consultation to the Board in accordance with the bylaws of the Foundation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide3ce53f275834d6e9ff55c021b08c25d"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Removal</header><text>The Board of Directors may remove an Advisor from the Board of Advisors by majority vote.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76646270f4e7466fb2f8c72ba7742515"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Procedures</header><paragraph id="idae84cc961d6848c9ae23bfada082f278"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>The Board shall hold its initial meeting not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida03943e2c3ff431497be8673bf91f70e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Organizing principles; appointment of executive director</header><text>The Directors of the Board shall name an Executive Director of the Foundation not later than 120 days after the date of the initial meeting of the Board.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9a8e4491f3a54ff999e6687b0ddedfa3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Executive Director; staff</header><paragraph id="id8a95962ea21a4774805dddf2ca449361"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Executive director</header><text>The Board shall hire a qualified individual to serve, at the pleasure of the Board, as the Executive Director of the Foundation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id590a7d835e484e44875c11e8b9018464"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foundation staff</header><text>Officers and employees of the Foundation—</text><subparagraph id="idcc6dac4659be409ca4ad4d8c16d9f070"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may not be employees of, or hold any office in, the United States Government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id81d477c0aae14a90b85217c8aa992bc4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be appointed without regard to the provisions of—</text><clause id="id1d139f8f8b434b4291ff1fd4a359636c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service; and</text></clause><clause id="id68b5177263f64924a9746a357f34ea1d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title, relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id012fe32f1f0b43f7a510dcc6f77c8d7f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall receive a salary that is commensurate with the salaries of similar positions in similar foundations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id81ba030a7c9f4a4bb9287b2b52162b79"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitation; conflicts of interests</header><paragraph id="id518e62cd8bc741f68f0f3c13be8a2681"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Political participation</header><text>The Foundation may not participate or intervene in any political activities on behalf of any candidate for public office in any country.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc12585c3018a40e38890b7046035c33a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Financial interests</header><text>All Directors of the Board, Advisors, officers, and employees of the Foundation are subject to industry standard conflicts of interest protocols set forth in the Foundation bylaws.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id0be01df8e8c24be7b836605bc9afe654"><enum>5.</enum><header>Corporate powers and obligations of the Foundation</header><subsection id="id49f84faa685f4735b2717ca053a4acc7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General authorities</header><text>The Foundation—</text><paragraph id="id63e5ef07507d4b2c9215c1a5b55a7567"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may conduct business throughout the States, territories, and possessions of the United States and in foreign countries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd53e5dbf0be0455bb291df4cee3ba010"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall have its principal offices in the Washington, DC, metropolitan area; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id495a8cf3f06c42b0a051598179895d7b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall continuously maintain a designated agent in Washington, DC, who is authorized to accept notice or service of process on behalf of the Foundation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbc4b7fb9ec2445338005950e67c40b29"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorities</header><text>In addition to powers explicitly authorized under this Act, the Foundation, in order to carry out the purposes described in section 3(b), shall have the usual powers of a corporation headquartered in Washington, DC, including the authority—</text><paragraph id="id57d62e6f2c664ae98361cc1015eb6433"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to accept, receive, solicit, hold, administer, and use any gift, devise, or bequest, either absolutely or in trust, or real or personal property or any income derived from such gift or property, or other interest in such gift or property;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6b07aeb5e7a34f748bd1560d859d50e0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to acquire by donation, gift, devise, purchase, or exchange any real or personal property or interest in such property;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcad71551f1e74108950359c191e9e152"><enum>(3)</enum><text>unless otherwise required by the instrument of transfer, to sell, donate, lease, invest, reinvest, retain, or otherwise dispose of any property or income derived from such property;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida5eb0f60384541e099d68b2bb949ec72"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to complain and defend itself in any court of competent jurisdiction (except that the Directors of the Board shall not be personally liable, except for gross negligence);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6aad9c16d9df4e2396c90e0d4753093d"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to enter into legal arrangements with public agencies, private organizations, and persons and to make such payments as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of such contracts or arrangements; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf76a7efcf8d9403dad2cf12acf0f850b"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to engage in funding activities, which may include structured or project financing, grants, equity (provided that returns flow back to the Foundation), and concessional lending, for eligible projects, in accordance with section 7.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id966d897765bb476b940807a0a0e3d0bd"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal funds</header><paragraph id="idb0be1ac137d34616af43084544da697c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Foundation may—</text><subparagraph id="idcc908ae10d4a47d09ad8df68728fb1ce"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hold Federal funds made available, but not immediately disbursed; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4436d5759b934bb78eeddd74d092b379"><enum>(B)</enum><text>use any interest or other investment income earned on such Federal funds to carry out the purposes of the Foundation under this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbab39f15d7884764aa10a71f106e1829"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Investments by the Foundation made with Federal funds may only be made in—</text><subparagraph id="ide6daec5ec8b1426fb5e0708211fbe6bc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>interest-bearing obligations of the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5fe690e543a6479690bf8217c0e225aa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9abde18178ea4834ab1719249b8870c9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation of public liability</header><text>The United States shall not be liable for any debts, defaults, acts, or omissions of the Foundation. The Federal Government shall be held harmless from any damages or awards ordered by a court against the Foundation.</text></subsection></section><section id="id810653c31e66412eb13bf5a46c9dbc8a"><enum>6.</enum><header>Outcome-based funding, safeguards, and accountability</header><subsection id="id4e2bb12ec8fb435d93ca58d0a2957548"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Outcome-Based funding</header><paragraph id="idcd82085c5f544fa197aab49c97414ab1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Foundation shall establish a funding strategy that sets targets based on measurable outcomes to be improved in populations served through its investments, including—</text><subparagraph id="ideda6ac22f44a401f828660f6b1414317"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifying and regularly reviewing any such outcomes that advance the purposes described in section 3(b), such as increased crop and animal productivity, increased profit to farmers, or decreased hunger rates; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf12e381f558347948a9aed94f9cca897"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a portfolio, multi-year, approach to Foundation investments in which the failure of any specific program to achieve target outcomes is acceptable if the overall portfolio of projects meets target outcomes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4a7b6b6ce64c424a8cf9aaf446e7e3a1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Financing and evaluation process</header><text>The Foundation shall establish an efficient and streamlined financing and evaluation process that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf121bf0e072a462684e9ff26741c62b6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prioritizes the achievement of defined outcomes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf1fc30b1292346d99c3c76ab18afb391"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assesses risk of corruption and employs a strategy to counter corruption;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idadf07cde0d3b4b69ae8ada58a79120ec"><enum>(C)</enum><text>prioritizes funding ventures with partners that are primarily locally based or locally run organizations, entities, and businesses that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc0b3a21eb5ef4a65901309cbb71a20cc"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">achieve such outcomes; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd6d1c32579144fd9b65621817e881f9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrate an ability to sustain the financed project; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id818af6c4bdef412aa2853fd3b0ce8679"><enum>(D)</enum><text>focuses venture evaluations on assessing such outcomes and minimizing unnecessary reporting on project activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6574520e9dd7485bbee989c14db30640"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Accountability</header><paragraph id="idef07ec6e1c7c4951888b4500799ad4a5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Impact evaluations</header><text>The achievement of venture outcomes shall be determined through impact evaluations that include a comparison group to determine any measured improvements that are attributable to the funded venture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6cb35de15a644cf0b65c4e9aca41c73a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Methodology assessments</header><text>Foundation staff may assess the methodology used by grantees or investees that are already running impact evaluations to increase efficiency, and such evaluations may be accepted in place of additional evaluations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id89280447a85f4f70a1c877c89140a51e"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Dedicated funding</header><text>Any grantee or investee that lacks impact evaluation capacity may receive dedicated funding to support in-house evaluations or to contract with independent, external evaluators.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0a0aa010095d49348e6ebdf3461b1ab4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Third-party evaluations</header><text>The Foundation may pay for third-party evaluations of any grantee's project to verify the results derived from an in-house evaluation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddfaac466dc7b428a94f21e7035c3ff83"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Safeguards</header><text>The Foundation shall develop, and incorporate into any agreement for support provided by the Foundation, appropriate safeguards, policies, and guidelines, consistent with internationally recognized best practices.</text></subsection><subsection id="idf3516473cc404f3aace4f5e6f04fabd5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Independent accountability mechanism</header><text>The Foundation shall establish or contract for a transparent and independent accountability mechanism, consistent with best practices, which shall provide—</text><paragraph id="id3cbf5b8f16dc4c4594b52c7d648f5266"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a compliance review function that assesses whether Foundation-supported ventures adhere to the requirements developed pursuant to subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1144c77d927548368115605270e1078c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a dispute resolution function for resolving and remedying concerns between venture implementers regarding the impacts of specific Foundation-supported ventures with respect to such standards; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idecc9930250cc4e098e7a614c7d4ad2ca"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an advisory function that reports to the Board regarding ventures, policies, and practices.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idf2e9167306ae446a8035e3e223b1e2dd"><enum>7.</enum><header>Ventures, financing, and grants</header><subsection id="idedef27aff7a640fc8e9fb54a7fbbc3c6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Venture funding requirements</header><paragraph id="id152740dda9a94267b6ba3f63e4156c40"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Foundation shall award funding, which may include project financing, credit risk insurance, grants, concessional lending, or credit, in accordance with this section, for eligible projects described in paragraph (2) that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98cf9b1c0eda499bbf80d2c6a6b0401f"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase agricultural productivity and incomes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id77bbe9caecd2468cae7516d6f6debab0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure food security is achieved and sustained, while supporting farmers moving beyond subsistence agriculture to growing higher value crops that can be sold for profit.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd6cd4f29a7d94f6cbe42df02d50c60a1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible ventures</header><text>A venture qualifies as an eligible venture if the venture seeks—</text><subparagraph id="id4bfd19d6b2204f459d814176d8fba887"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to have cost matching from sources other than the United States Government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id510bb09564114ef5b4f0673277d3cd1a"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to incorporate a set of key independently verified outcomes, which shall be measured by rigorous impact evaluations, such as measuring attributable increases in agricultural yields, infrastructure, or any other eligible use;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddb0f85b831504d5ca46576f61331c9ad"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to not substantially duplicate the work of other funders or institutions or displace current profit-making ventures;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide5b5f8097e5f4a319c0ae7a001b9f017"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to leverage existing infrastructure and community-led development to allow for the immediate launch of ventures;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5de3e415546d4cc7ac07b90d7c55e14e"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to advance the national security interests of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3cc2afa45e2b460cab01e5f7d5983278"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to demonstrate—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2bdcbbfde46b42a9be23bdcc2c1075fe"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the ability to financially and operationally maintain and build on the outcomes or mission of the venture after the Foundation funding has ended; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id12505e89e8e04930a19f2855320fe0ae"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan to strengthen the capacity of, and transfer skills and technologic tools to, local enterprises, organizations, or institutions to manage projects and other funded entities after the Foundation funding has been expended; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id19691778b5a64512af902ecde736e689"><enum>(G)</enum><text>to consider projects that meet the highest needs of food insecure populations based on food security, agriculture, and malnutrition assessments.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9b263cd151784b0b90f054d385f9cb52"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible countries for ventures</header><text>Before entering into any venture agreement pursuant to this section, the Board shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8cece29f114041c287167fda0214dd06"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish criteria to determine whether a country is eligible to receive funding for such a venture; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb30f03bb964e4722bca051f844b95e64"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify ventures to receive support that—</text><subparagraph id="id497b9a5553234084999ffbb83736d028"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advance the national security priorities of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a35783fad9f498c9d2615e5e39c0529"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have demonstrated leadership to modernize the country's agricultural food systems, in partnership with the private sector; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id408cf7499c54479a8da9ebe8a248ac17"><enum>(C)</enum><text>are committed—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1429669a38a141ed8be62f15d815ab6c"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to making policy reforms to help transform, scale, and build enduring food systems;</text></clause><clause id="ideb8ef6da2f284fc49715488890e1298d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to cofinancing and sustaining long-term projects implemented by the Foundation; and</text></clause><clause id="id61898ad047094019aecc66e5cd7b4820"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to collaborating with stakeholders—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc5031deae2124905818a04ead6940143"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to increase agricultural production and crop yields;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id43cbc8b7aeb64af895cbf2648dca589d"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to scale resilient food systems; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id38ff6705dc7b45a69cf22dfe3292b97d"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to improve food safety, processing, logistics, and supply chain processes for input and output markets.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd2ace2e613f041a990bfb01cf4d20de3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding authorized</header><paragraph id="id2d30d82a1a0c43f18e31f882b522828a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order to maximize the impact of the funding authorized under this section, the Foundation should—</text><subparagraph id="id4be234e3b48d47bdbc968182a99c69d0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coordinate with other international public and private donors or investors and local organizations active in food security to the extent possible; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb8c770a0acd64c4096ed1f7c776cdb15"><enum>(B)</enum><text>seek additional financial and nonfinancial contributions and commitments for its projects from host governments and other organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9abb794726744fc6a8eab774c580e2ea"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funding criteria</header><text>Funding awarded pursuant to this section—</text><subparagraph id="ide37d08ce850b4ffcb47d161e2df68529"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be provided to ventures that demonstrate progress, during the funding period, in achieving clearly identified performance indicators and outcomes defined in the project agreement, which may include—</text><clause id="id67a6865968894ed3a840a75c0c7d6167"><enum>(i)</enum><text>increasing agricultural or food production through agriculture research and the competitive delivery of market-based financing, distribution and extension services, and supporting technology commercialization and adoption through such services;</text></clause><clause id="ide474cca628b6490fbe8bf1dd8d3e0666"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improving the nutritional status of intended beneficiaries by—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id266b81900c904af1b09b568e979b67c1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increasing the production, availability, and access of nutritious foods domestically;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide7eb5ad23d7f49b3a41aad5fb589e646"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promoting highly nutritious foods, diet diversification, and nutritional behaviors that improve maternal and child health; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idcaaa81291fa14aac93845558974758d3"><enum>(III)</enum><text>supporting the expansion of producer market opportunities;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id207e2c9107dc4315b7e0d8ce6914be4f"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>building resilient food systems to help mitigate against future food shocks among vulnerable populations and households; and</text></clause><clause id="id2c93c5cf2adf4672bd43fba7eea59a88"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>identifying additional revenue sources or financing mechanisms to meet the recurring costs of ventures by serving as a conduit between institutional investors and the agribusiness sector; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id49541799d8634ed4ad557bca1931dbbc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be terminated if the Board determines that the country receiving such funding—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9b0e2bf5cbeb41d89eff03c6d1ba9aac"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not meeting applicable requirements under this Act;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0e3b5179dc05437cab7023d7ac024643"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not making progress in achieving the key performance indicators described in the project agreement; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id74502cb532984541a2eec84f41798c25"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is not advancing United States national security priorities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idf8a82382e2524a929c268f901a76e0fa"><enum>8.</enum><header>Prohibition of support in countries that support terrorism or violate human
 rights and of support for sanctioned persons</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1d432c230f5b4871841bf93bec18add1"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Foundation may not provide support for any government, or any entity owned or controlled by a government, if the Secretary of State determines that such government—</text><paragraph id="id0deceda44a9e48718ee86e26e0556bdc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism, as determined under—</text><subparagraph id="id6a54609f39c04df88035306f597c01b0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 1754(c)(1)(A)(i) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4813">50 U.S.C. 4813(c)(1)(A)(i)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7859bea0c93e445da5596fda25c75f9a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 620A(a) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2371">22 U.S.C. 2371(a)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9b24c912d7464d0cbd0b45de2f4ad7b0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>section 40(d) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2780">22 U.S.C. 2780(d)</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbf8e829b5b9c41cf9a93ad4c59642c48"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other relevant provision of law;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id181e1f9147154c668c9a330f50109275"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has repeatedly engaged with any organizations designated as foreign terrorist organizations by the Secretary in accordance with section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddc719c0c82054a07a35028db1e031a1c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has engaged in a consistent pattern of gross violations of human rights, as determined under section 116(a) or 502B(a)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151n">22 U.S.C. 2151n(a)</external-xref> and 2304(a)(2)) or any other relevant provision of law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id229fb143336840988f2cd51ee4d00056"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition of support for sanctioned persons</header><text>The Foundation may not engage in any dealing prohibited under United States sanctions laws or regulations, including dealings with persons on the list of specially designated persons and blocked persons maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury, except to the extent otherwise authorized by the Secretary of State or the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></subsection><subsection id="id468e0f10912c4c3aba888685566185ea"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of subsections (a) and (b) with respect to any government, or any entity owned or controlled by a government, by notifying the appropriate congressional committees of the intention to exercise such waiver not later than 45 days before the waiver is scheduled to take effect.</text></subsection></section><section id="id8fce3f84f3394edeb20e4ce84cbfce4b"><enum>9.</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter by March 31st of any year during which the Foundation is operational, the Executive Director of the Foundation shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7ddc410842ce44d6befd9ed022a94302"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been approved by the Board of Directors;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbbff797b582d46499e9b36c0e0157b32"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contains the expectations of the year ahead; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2c6e75b75aca4beca10e42115c600be4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes—</text><subparagraph id="id8d1543866a7c475aae14fd8bf79f6e89"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the goals of the Foundation for the upcoming year, including areas to increase operational efficiency and further advance United States policy objectives and national security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3751b34a4d0d4f64b7bea34869dbb61e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>lessons learned and best practices developed through projects funded by the Foundation during the prior fiscal year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9b8f121ded334a3f87b5ed05572822f3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a project-specific and a portfolio-level report describing—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9eee27dfec04470da247861e7fc67d2d"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the progress achieved against key performance indicators and the outcomes described in section 6, and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76b67cf901254dbfb562295d2f20ca3b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how such progress will benefit the American taxpayer;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8822721048ec4c67b256a2087cadb3a2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an assessment of—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id63ff3b2a16e94c6c9df276ed6c6f741e"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the grant making and financing processes are effective and expeditious;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida3bf9017cbb64fd7997324b24c8cd573"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how any necessary additional efficiencies can be built into future project selection; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida63d5b4e24514286b256481944b2f71d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether project evaluations are successfully measuring outcomes;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id794a8eecb87c452ba58fa4d60b120b81"><enum>(E)</enum><text>how the funding and selected projects authorized under this Act were publicized in the selected country to expand recognition for the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfaf29454cad7455ba20ba9112f43de1f"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an annual financial report from an independent auditor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="idcc28f1ac21fb4609a70481adecfa0c8b"><enum>10.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subsection id="id4fef32d453a64c1e9af7a4a31dd8e4b8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Using funds appropriated to the Department of State to carry out chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2346">22 U.S.C. 2346 et seq.</external-xref>), the Secretary of State is authorized to award an annual grant to the Foundation to enable the Foundation to carry out the purposes specified in section 3(b).</text></subsection><subsection id="id20237aef7c3c4153b1107cf99e0adcd9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cost matching requirement</header><text>Amounts authorized to be appropriated pursuant to subsection (a) shall be made available, on a cost matching basis, to the maximum extent practicable, from sources other than the United States Government.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3052710b5ced4db8b01ec4c2263a965a"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consultation requirement</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State and the Executive Director of the Foundation shall consult with the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name> regarding the implementation of this Act and the proposed activities of the Foundation.</text></subsection><subsection id="idd36d21861c8847bf8ccf891e58a00a63"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition of use of grants for lobbying expenses</header><text>No grant funds provided by the Foundation pursuant to section 7 may be used for any activity intended to influence legislation pending before Congress.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


