<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEN25066-6YM-2C-XKH"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S454 IS: Gambling Addiction Recovery, Investment, and Treatment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 454</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250206" legis-day="20250205">February 6 (legislative day, February 5), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use to award formula grants to the States to address gambling addiction, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HDE54F3CCB2DD484CA30AD26C3A4934E9"><section section-type="section-one" id="HC77C5C8775FE4825AC5C00E4AB03D81E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gambling Addiction Recovery, Investment, and Treatment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7D3B4BA943494637B9BA173779D5F5F0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants to address gambling addiction</header><subsection id="HAC25BAFB085741BCBE2CF4E2A75160AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration</header><paragraph id="HD8A6E439CCEE4D4BA464C339E05E0255"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use shall award grants to the States to address gambling addiction in amounts determined in accordance with paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11F16927107141A5B930E53529ABF4A7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of amount</header><text>The Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use shall—</text><subparagraph id="H8779F882900A4AD591DBCFC0F6DEACCB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>allocate the total amount of funds awarded as grants under paragraph (1) among the States for a fiscal year in the same ratios as the Assistant Secretary allocates the total amount of block grants for prevention and treatment of substance abuse under subpart II of part B of title XIX of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-21">42 U.S.C. 300x–21 et seq.</external-xref>) among the States for such fiscal year; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41AA624F17434D96B64CF8513B79E188"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if any State fails to apply for a grant under this subsection for such fiscal year, reallocate the amount that would otherwise be awarded to such State among the States that do so apply in proportion to the amounts allocated to such States under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H76FE215307B84BA3857A05937F1BDA68"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>State</term> has the meaning given to that term in section 1954 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-64">42 U.S.C. 300x–64</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDC72F0AF10E24402AB8203EFC17E1DE3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National Institute on Drug Abuse</header><text>The Director of the National Institute on Drug Abuse may award grants to support research on gambling addiction.</text></subsection><subsection id="H68BE9B193E6F4E519ED17945458561D9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit a report to the Congress on the effectiveness of the programs and activities carried out pursuant to subsections (a) and (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD6472A108F0C4B628FF71A5F3AC738D2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2034—</text><paragraph id="H66C774D87E874D688F4EF1A4250B99E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to carry out subsection (a), the amount that is 37.5 percent of the amount estimated by the Secretary of the Treasury as being equal to the amount of taxes received under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4401">section 4401(a)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 during the preceding fiscal year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8949FC0610B84FC49F7A949BB0B28431"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to carry out subsection (b), the amount that is 12.5 percent of such amount estimated by the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

