<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HED6C59F7F6514517936B472636E347FD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4508 IH: Bringing Unfair Reporting Duties to Electeds Now Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4508</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require Members of Congress to certify they meet work requirements applicable to beneficiaries under Medicaid and the supplemental nutrition assistance program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0E2668EE5CC34DB89FF3109F26CFC3D1" style="OLC"><section id="H40813C36F3C34D64BCFA774951B7290C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bringing Unfair Reporting Duties to Electeds Now Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BURDEN Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2728040680DD4E9795AA7C9B699CED9F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Certification by Members of Congress on meeting Medicaid and SNAP work requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A Member of Congress (as that term is defined in section 2106 of title 5, United States Code) may not enroll in any health benefits plan offered under the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code) unless the Member submits to the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, for each month beginning on or after the date of the enactment of this Act—</text><paragraph id="HA0820D56DFA745CB883D17C1186F774C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a written certification that the Member has demonstrated community engagement for the month in the manner described in section 1902(xx)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(xx)(2)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BFDD453F0164251A4138374E45933CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a written certification that the Member complied with each work requirement applicable under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2011">7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>) as if the Member is a member of a household participating in the supplemental nutrition assistance program under such Act.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

