<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA479BD8C02F34C40BE4C053C6391B2C2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4998 IH: Safeguarding the Use of the National Guard Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4998</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250819">August 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000607">Mr. Liccardo</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001234">Ms. Morrison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001094">Ms. Hoyle of Oregon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000620">Ms. Rivas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000635">Ms. Dexter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for congressional oversight of domestic use of the reserve components of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBA1A1DDFC5094E50AF641A3E6B7F8B3F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H51F05F94EDBC480C896C0E17EABD2EEC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safeguarding the Use of the National Guard Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SUN Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HF2FA7828D20D4694A72DAF760F532B5C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional oversight of domestic use of the reserve components of the Armed Forces</header> 
<subsection id="HEE4A548867A04115AF7EFD6A33E0C247"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), not later than 15 days after the date on which the President deploys or otherwise uses members of a reserve component of the Armed Forces at a location in the United States pursuant to chapter 13 or 15 of title 10, United States Code, or any other law or authority—</text> <paragraph id="HA8F3B1A88CA1460086AED27C1AF67084"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the President shall submit to Congress a report on the use or deployment that includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE9C34B12CE254425BC7DC30B03622292"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the precise legal basis and goals of the President for the deployment or other use, including any evidence substantiating the assessment of the President;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4A2FD2D3EBB640E192ECC770DBA72F1B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the effect of such deployment or use on any situation identified in such justification, including any specific reports of any interactions between members of the Armed Forces and civilians engaged in violence or threats of violence;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H91D45EFD82CE43729AEDAF0B6ADF0C86"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reports from local and State law enforcement agencies describing any such interactions, including the extent of actual violence or threat of violence, and the assessment of such agencies of the propriety of deployment or other use of members of the Armed Forces;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFC2C28BEED724F7CB86545CBA3C06893"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification of the total cost to the Federal Government of such deployment or use, including any indirect costs borne by the Department of Defense and civilians called up to serve in the National Guard; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA328CB13177C4039A18A2DB5C879D993"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a certification that such deployment or use of the members of the reserve component will not interfere with the ability of the Armed Forces to respond in the event of a disaster that could be covered by a presidential declaration under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE411BBD0D15F4A3D83F9AFB575B94571"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Chief of the National Guard Bureau shall provide to Congress a briefing on whether the deployment or use of the reserve components resulted in a reduction of violence and met the stated goals identified by the President under paragraph (1)(A).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDE5F232465F0499382196FB3F7E0CAEB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to the use or deployment of members of the Armed Forces at a location in the United States pursuant to a presidential declaration under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>) in response to a natural disaster or other weather-related event.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

