<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HEN25998-04D-WM-WLW"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 377 IS: Authorizing the en bloc consideration in Executive Session of certain nominations on the Executive Calendar.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code> 
<calendar>Executive Calendar No. 1</calendar> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>S. RES. 377</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20250908">September 8, 2025</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was ordered to lie over, under the rule</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>EXECUTIVE RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Authorizing the en bloc consideration in Executive Session of certain nominations on the Executive Calendar.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body id="HCC32CEB7763548F4A31D8BC99610F807"> 
<section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That it shall be in order to move to proceed to the en bloc consideration of the following nominations on the Executive Calendar:</text> <paragraph id="idd3a8d2ef95d143198c99db942a0fe6c4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Calendar Number 89: Jessica Kramer, of Wisconsin, to be an Assistant Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id3133e4e593b24d84b3076a5c71b75914"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Calendar Number 105: Dario Gil, of New York, to be Under Secretary for Science, Department of Energy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idd4e2e9b35d184219bbcc998e70ba5c6e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Calendar Number 107: Brandon Williams, of New York, to be Under Secretary for Nuclear Security.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id78019860ec2444068e1a5e0360e831bb"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Calendar Number 121: Tristan Abbey, of Florida, to be Administrator of the Energy Information Administration.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id977c5a9a4f454ee8bbf977ff90500fd4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Calendar Number 122: Leslie Beyer, of Texas, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id203c99e4bafe4431ae8c76d3cfc9fd52"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Calendar Number 123: Theodore J. Garrish, of Maryland, to be an Assistant Secretary of Energy (Nuclear Energy).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id4646081dc0e947ea9e9831b9f87c5daf"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Calendar Number 124: Andrea Travnicek, of North Dakota, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idf227a38f9a594c6285760746a2deb75e"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Calendar Number 132: Justin Overbaugh, of Florida, to be a Deputy Under Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id31c9cb4667364488874d8b472cfac366"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Calendar Number 133: Scott Pappano, of Pennsylvania, to be Principal Deputy Administrator, National Nuclear Security Administration.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id51173ba2f144414685e6bb1ffb290f50"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Calendar Number 135: Michael Cadenazzi, of Rhode Island, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idb557ca1813014168a0e9777229f242c2"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Calendar Number 136: Sean O'Keefe, of Virginia, to be a Deputy Under Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="iddce0ffc0c1c54fc2ae0afc85b9e94dfb"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Calendar Number 137: Michael Obadal, of Virginia, to be Under Secretary of the Army.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id8550aa4d16ef408c814236ac31c52b0c"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Calendar Number 139: Katherine Sutton, of Illinois, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idc419a39241854e708c276aa643d83020"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Calendar Number 141: William L. Doffermyre, of Texas, to be Solicitor of the Department of the Interior.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idccfc16cac17a4bae8be76c794afb3be4"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Calendar Number 142: Kyle Haustveit, of Oklahoma, to be an Assistant Secretary of Energy (Fossil Energy).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id26bd8a9cfafa41c1a5c5ea30a5fc7b9f"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Calendar Number 152: Matthew Napoli, of Virginia, to be Deputy Administrator for Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation, National Nuclear Security Administration.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idfb63c6ca19984707bf077558c2070265"><enum>(17)</enum><text>Calendar Number 153: Richard Anderson, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Air Force.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idd46ef4d03c684615b27daa179cca1f42"><enum>(18)</enum><text>Calendar Number 154: Conner Prochaska, of Texas, to be Director of the Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy, Department of Energy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id5ca416ff98094be1a1ef8476cd9d4138"><enum>(19)</enum><text>Calendar Number 156: Tina Pierce, of Idaho, to be Chief Financial Officer, Department of Energy.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id9e19830bd0634300a8de65c14bd6703a"><enum>(20)</enum><text>Calendar Number 157: Jonathan Brightbill, of Virginia, to be General Counsel of the Department of Energy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idf1ce1cb705164e1fa92e8c1066bfcff0"><enum>(21)</enum><text>Calendar Number 161: Robert Gleason, of Pennsylvania, to be Director of the Amtrak Board of Directors for a term of 5 years.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idb1749bf758b64d4c913c753aadbe18e6"><enum>(22)</enum><text>Calendar Number 177: Sean McMaster, of Virginia, to be Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id79a2360a8c07409090e9275dbbf33bf8"><enum>(23)</enum><text>Calendar Number 180: Donald Bergin III, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Congressional and Legislative Affairs).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id9bdd9fa7a62e45a59b0ee048e8e977f9"><enum>(24)</enum><text>Calendar Number 185: John Squires, of Florida, to be Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id2d890c5243c042bcb3cc157a260f94ff"><enum>(25)</enum><text>Calendar Number 251: Daniel Aronowitz, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id277874b768314e169ac2d19dd277e4f0"><enum>(26)</enum><text>Calendar Number 276: Michael Dodd, of Indiana, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense (New Position).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idcc3be503c0fb43b8898f4c1598389922"><enum>(27)</enum><text>Calendar Number 277: William Gillis, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Army.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id155da81457d5487ab4e7b83b15a61bb9"><enum>(28)</enum><text>Calendar Number 278: Jules Hurst III, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Army.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id6efa9bf2beb54aaf847ba54e69bfa0eb"><enum>(29)</enum><text>Calendar Number 279: Brent Ingraham, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Army.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idd2fc0c9f6d4749939cb914c866191bc4"><enum>(30)</enum><text>Calendar Number 283: George Wesley Street, of Virginia, to be Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id9ef016b1128c4347b880bb88476fd4ec"><enum>(31)</enum><text>Calendar Number 285: Peter Thomson, of Louisiana, to be Inspector General, Central Intelligence Agency.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id0158a55506d34174b55aa539fd626fe1"><enum>(32)</enum><text>Calendar Number 289: Jeffrey Bartos, of Pennsylvania, to be Representative of the United States of America to the United Nations for U.N. Management and Reform, with the Rank of Ambassador, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as an Alternate Representative of the United States of America to the Sessions of the General Assembly of the United Nations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idf85f1a5586de4492b9c13b82df06857c"><enum>(33)</enum><text>Calendar Number 290: Jennifer Locetta, of Florida, to be Alternate Representative of the United States of America for Special Political Affairs in the United Nations, with the rank of Ambassador, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as an Alternate Representative of the United States of America to the Sessions of the General Assembly of the United Nations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id48c14f2129ca4ff78ae4f35c18979590"><enum>(34)</enum><text>Calendar Number 297: Dudley Hoskins, of the District of Columbia, to be Under Secretary of Agriculture for Marketing and Regulatory Programs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id6063719d95844a03aea947b610d25518"><enum>(35)</enum><text>Calendar Number 298: Scott Hutchins, of Indiana, to be Under Secretary of Agriculture for Research, Education, and Economics.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idfd1307b090bf4e2a9d94f2e404269ab3"><enum>(36)</enum><text>Calendar Number 303: Benjamin DeMarzo, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idfc7ac2206ddf4d61bb562414fba2b716"><enum>(37)</enum><text>Calendar Number 305: Jovan Jovanovic, of Pennsylvania, to be President of the Export-Import Bank of the United States for a term expiring January 20, 2029.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id4a18f12fc77f425e900a7d05aad3cb01"><enum>(38)</enum><text>Calendar Number 324: Richard Fordyce, of Missouri, to be Under Secretary of Agriculture for Farm Production and Conservation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idd1895862a422483e896c7a6992fba6c3"><enum>(39)</enum><text>Calendar Number 344: Paul Roberti, of Rhode Island, to be Administrator of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration, Department of Transportation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id47e362509e584cb6adf5af42b59a7ee7"><enum>(40)</enum><text>Calendar Number 346: Jonathan Morrison, of California, to be Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id5867bf032b774a7b9987f90ea9b14a31"><enum>(41)</enum><text>Calendar Number 352: Jason Evans, of Texas, to be an Under Secretary of State (Management).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id1d15518ab4394a96871b3c7552876919"><enum>(42)</enum><text>Calendar Number 356: Edward Aloysius O'Connell, of the District of Columbia, to be an Associate Judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for the term of 15 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id1302f9f16458478fbb86c9e88b7cdb77"><enum>(43)</enum><text>Calendar Number 362: Katherine Scarlett, of Ohio, to be a Member of the Council on Environmental Quality.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id70c86735e8f24e83b1a3b29ee3c9cba9"><enum>(44)</enum><text>Calendar Number 365: Bryan Switzer, of Virginia, to be a Deputy United States Trade Representative (Asia, Textiles, Investment, Services, and Intellectual Property), with the rank of Ambassador.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id6c8e3a910aff431aad261810e2691903"><enum>(45)</enum><text>Calendar Number 149: Callista Gingrich, of Florida, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Swiss Confederation, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Principality of Liechtenstein.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id481dc24ee64d4c1b8cfaa2d1b1c15321"><enum>(46)</enum><text>Calendar Number 286: Kimberly Guilfoyle, of Florida, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to Greece.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id45bee87001d246f9b9152ff02e322e70"><enum>(47)</enum><text>Calendar Number 302: Christine Toretti, of Pennsylvania, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Kingdom of Sweden.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id717408077c5d47659f183dc51b2a99f3"><enum>(48)</enum><text>Calendar Number 350: Peter Lamelas, of Florida, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Argentine Republic.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body> </resolution> 

