<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1411FD3A407C4195A4F04599230053FC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4913 IH: Countering Harassment and Applying Legal Liability to Effectively Nurture Government Election Stability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4913</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250805">August 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to protect individuals who are lawfully registered to vote in elections for Federal office from bad faith challenges to their registration status, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB050402D132F40B79902020269D94D99" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF8D44053D057416D8BF09BC461BE3B2B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Countering Harassment and Applying Legal Liability to Effectively Nurture Government Election Stability Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CHALLENGES Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H875591AC4D494E599D9133E1F16F61F3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Protections against bad faith challenges to voter registration status</header> 
<subsection id="H4ECFCC0776464B38912841EE241A9BD0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Protections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20501">52 U.S.C. 20501 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 8 the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H838978FFB02F416DA6E76E839BE88827" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H3C7DDB9DA20744ABBEB939849CB3CDAB"><enum>8A.</enum><header>Protections against bad-faith challenges to registration status</header> <subsection id="HE08092F2EC73462C872073564768D26F"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Protections against bad-Faith challenges</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person, other than a State or local election official, may submit to a State or local election official a formal challenge to the voter registration status of an individual who is registered to vote in elections for Federal office held in the State unless the person—</text>
              <paragraph id="H7EFC87F12D7449F196C06F724793CA83">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides the official with clear and convincing evidence generated by an inquiry into the specific individual’s voter registration status that offers proof that the individual is not eligible to be registered to vote in elections for Federal office in the State and is not generated by a mass computerized data matching process;</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H613FFF55F86B4EEE92B5D122FBD17448">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>presents the official with an oath or attestation of such person under penalty of perjury that the person has personal knowledge that the individual is not eligible to be registered to vote in elections for Federal office in the State; and</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H6D2DA0AF7E6D4E4CBFCC2B6DBBD67665">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>if the person is an individual, is registered to vote in the same registrar’s jurisdiction as the individual who is the subject of the challenge.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H113BCB6D66FA46A6A7B4FC3193875FB6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements for online portals accepting challenges</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or local election official who operates an online portal through which a person may submit a formal challenge to the voter registration status of an individual who is registered to vote in elections for Federal office held in the State—</text> <paragraph id="HB1D5F2251EA3481FBA23399558318236"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall reject a challenge submitted on the portal by a person who does not include the person’s name on the material the person submits for the challenge; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9707AA815A5946EBA8FDBB8AF2CC5CB4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall include on the portal information on the prohibition under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H6699530217A842F09AC982B92BDE58EC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <paragraph id="HB17B26CD5C3B47E498B287225E7E6B9A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 11(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20510">52 U.S.C. 20510(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="traditional" id="HD5F41CD2068148668F3C3FF25E08B62B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H5084078153C54BF0841BFA592609F407" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In the case of a violation of section 8A—</text> <subparagraph id="H774E1B61BA0743B2822C32DE5EDF29E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the aggrieved person need not provide notice to the chief election official of the State under paragraph (1) before bringing a civil action under paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2341DBF08478425BABDBC75BC5957EFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in addition to declaratory and injunctive relief, the civil action may be for compensatory damages equal to the amount incurred by the aggrieved person due to the violation, together with punitive damages in an amount not to exceed $1,000 for each such violation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD16F9054480640B1A7EA6C35FE918B35"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criminal penalties</header><text>Section 12 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20511">52 U.S.C. 20511</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3293B0BC72BC4B38927C3D82B51FFE7C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A person</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">In general</header-in-text>.—A person</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3CFAF8EBD6494446919F356D460204ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2A96A3925CDD4520AD27D80EDF88E323" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HBA77F9F9B77744668BF290EFC9B3E38F">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Knowing and negligent false challenge to eligibility To register To
                  vote</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to any other penalty under this Act, if—</text>
                <paragraph id="H2DE265B333134FE7A389465F1522EF66">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>a person submits to a State or local election official a formal challenge to the voter registration status of an individual who is registered to vote in elections for Federal office held in the State knowing and negligently disregarding that the individual is eligible to be registered to vote in elections for Federal office in the State; or</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HD768AC99115D40D2916624D34BF21CF8">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>a person provides another person with information alleging that an individual is not eligible to be registered to vote in elections for Federal office held in a State knowing that the information is false and with the reasonable expectation that the person to whom the information is provided will use the information to submit to a State or local election official a formal challenge to the voter registration status of the individual,</text>
                </paragraph>
                <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">the person shall be fined in
                  accordance with title 18, United States Code, imprisoned not more than 6 months,
                  or both, except that if the person is not an individual, the amount of the fine
                  shall be equal to $10,000 for each violation under this
                  subsection.</continuation-text>
              </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFAB79DE0AD9C4CC7955D20210F42BAA3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to a challenge to the voter registration status of an individual who is registered to vote in elections for Federal office in a State which is made after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

