<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCG25524-3W7-WX-T5T"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1505 IS: To ensure that Social Security beneficiaries receive regular statements from the Social Security Administration, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1505</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250429">April 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To ensure that Social Security beneficiaries receive regular statements from the Social Security Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HAEDF127FC6234275B965A7EEAC9B8A61"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id16090BB45CA647C4895F7DC9D01386D7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Ensuring beneficiaries receive regular social security statements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2027, the Commissioner of Social Security shall ensure that—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9F1363E2BFD446C2AB8003557019D065"><enum>(1)</enum><text>individuals with social security account numbers are mailed a paper social security statement whenever they enter the workforce or start a new job; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6FB06893DC92480E90BF067094E8068C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a paper social security statement is mailed to each individual with a social security account number not less frequently than—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD2C4B770BA744FBFA4C249CCAD108FCE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>once every 5 years beginning with the year in which the individual achieves age 25; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id66299B6661B54105AB2C0D8F215FCBBB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>once every 2 years beginning with the year in which the individual achieves age 55; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6EF3E19179C54DD89DEA28B66B1235C7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>annually beginning with the year in which the individual achieves age 60;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida88d3aefa427467dbd657f116ab9be57"><enum>(3)</enum><text>individuals with social security account numbers are mailed paper social security statements regardless of whether they have created an online <quote>my Social Security</quote> account with the Social Security Administration; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85CC152841044CF6AE7B3A2D50AE786A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>individuals are able to opt out from receiving paper social security statements (including statements otherwise required under this section). </text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id685EE34123C649FA92C75A29AE0F8B38"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on administrative expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Commissioner of Social Security for the Social Security Administration's Limitation on Administrative Expenses for each fiscal year beginning with 2026 such sums as are necessary to carry out this Act. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

