<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF9A17F89E006481A9ACC10B13C475844" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 821 IH: Expressing support for the recognition of October 2025 as “National Dyslexia Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 821</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251017">October 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001314">Mr. Bean of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001093">Mrs. Houchin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the recognition of October 2025 as <quote>National Dyslexia Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas dyslexia is—</text> <paragraph id="ide5f5c7d9a71e44f68b6402def29789ae"><enum>(1)</enum><text>defined as an unexpected difficulty in reading for an individual who has the intelligence to be a much better reader; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idf08d10942beb427897d618c8ae730272"><enum>(2)</enum><text>most commonly caused by a difficulty in phonological processing (the appreciation of the individual sounds of spoken language), which affects the ability of an individual to speak, read, and spell;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the First Step Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/391">Public Law 115–391</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 5194) included a definition of dyslexia as part of the requirement of the Act to screen inmates for dyslexia upon intake in Federal prisons;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the definition of dyslexia in section 3635 of title 18, United States Code, as added by section 101(a) of the First Step Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/391">Public Law 115–391</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 5195), is the first and only definition of dyslexia in a Federal statute;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas dyslexia is the most common learning disability and affects 80 to 90 percent of all individuals with a learning disability;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas dyslexia is persistent and highly prevalent, affecting as many as 1 out of every 5 individuals;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas dyslexia is a paradox, in that an individual with dyslexia may have both—</text>
<paragraph id="id9557a69d6f794464b3143dc87acd0670"><enum>(1)</enum><text>weaknesses in decoding that result in difficulties in accurate or fluent word recognition; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id58d1d032bb7d4a588a062bc85e6211bb"><enum>(2)</enum><text>strengths in higher level cognitive functions, such as reasoning, critical thinking, concept formation, and problem solving;</text></paragraph></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas great progress has been made in understanding dyslexia on a scientific level, including the epidemiology and cognitive and neurobiological bases of dyslexia;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the achievement gap between typical readers and dyslexic readers occurs as early as first grade;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas early screening for, and early diagnosis of, dyslexia are critical for ensuring that individuals with dyslexia receive focused, evidence-based intervention that leads to fluent reading, the promotion of self-awareness and self-empowerment, and the provision of necessary accommodations that ensure success in school and in life; and</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas October 2025 is an appropriate month to designate as <quote>National Dyslexia Awareness Month</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="HEEE955048A454873A727A6FC47B51D59"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H6301BBD518B442F1AAFB6F62992536A7"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H7764E7F3A79F4378925F8236F5D49C8B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>calls on Congress, schools, and State and local educational agencies to recognize that dyslexia has significant educational implications that must be addressed; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H30D30D9FDD6047098AEC119192B55AE2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National Dyslexia Awareness Month</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

