<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE364D185658C4E62AD9E34954C4163F2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 600 IH: WHO is Accountable Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 600</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250122">January 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000375">Mr. Arrington</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000298">Mr. Estes</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the use of funds to seek membership in the World Health Organization or to provide assessed or voluntary contributions to the World Health Organization.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H38D3B7B03B3B43CF97307AB92E175148" style="OLC"><section id="H10C160C81DF54CE9901EDD6890BD00B0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>WHO is Accountable Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H346399490616499797A9668FDA2DB76C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds to seek membership in the World Health Organization or to provide assessed or voluntary contributions to the World Health Organization</header><subsection id="H0C353E9C5FED450996A50A1CA1BF1503"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no funds available to any Federal department or agency may be used to seek membership by the United States in the World Health Organization or to provide assessed or voluntary contributions to the World Health Organization until such time as the Secretary of State certifies to Congress that the World Health Organization meets the conditions described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="HAEE652C44C754A589B80BADC57CF143A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conditions described</header><text>The conditions described in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="H2CDC8EBC25AA4869A6312ED0147148CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The World Health Organization has adopted meaningful reforms to ensure that humanitarian assistance is not politicized and is to be provided to those with the most need.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07B03D05007F468E86E0C8C7E5527B61"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The World Health Organization is not under the control or significant malign influence of the Chinese Communist Party.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FA737D5D9B344D5BC14A4A785E9A33E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The World Health Organization is not involved in a coverup of the Chinese Communist Party’s response to the COVID–19 pandemic.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H232CB1C1E95D4B5786D00B841DAB7543"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The World Health Organization grants observer status to Taiwan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78CBB1A96A084D8C94F84B104506D90E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The World Health Organization does not divert humanitarian or medical supplies to Iran, North Korea, or Syria.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACD5924F3B2343AA89450943A77444B8"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The World Health Organization has put in place mechanisms to increase transparency and accountability in its operations and eliminate waste, fraud, and abuse.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FFBDEA07F854619B3FBF3562E0C0010"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The World Health Organization has ceased all funding for, engagement in, and messaging with respect to certain controversial and politically charged issues that are non-germane to the World Health Organization’s directive, including—</text><subparagraph id="H7E20E381CD2C4767AFB644182DBEF804"><enum>(A)</enum><text>so-called <quote>gender identity</quote> and harmful rhetoric relating to <quote>gender affirming care</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H999FF4159F1A4B44A8D6ECEA41A248E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>climate change; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1568E0E770F04805BD62C22D1538836A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>access to abortion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA18ABCC253CE489686E65EBE753693C9" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The World Health Organization has agreed that as a condition of membership by the United States in the World Health Organization, no directive issued by the World Health Organization may be considered to be legally binding on any United States citizen or individual State. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

