<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE60CB4D67D0B4543B99B942B2A895C10" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-joint" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HJ 125 IH: Providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Office of the Secretary of the Department of Health and Human Services relating to “Policy on Adhering to the Text of the Administrative Procedure Act”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 125</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250918">September 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</sponsor> submitted the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing for congressional disapproval under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/8">chapter 8</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Office of the Secretary of the Department of Health and Human Services relating to <quote>Policy on Adhering to the Text of the Administrative Procedure Act</quote>.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HD1CC59725F5B476896065666C910761D"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HB59409F407464D888A3376646CFD2FA3"><enum/><text>That Congress disapproves the rule submitted by the Office of the Secretary of the Department of Health and Human Services relating to <quote>Policy on Adhering to the Text of the Administrative Procedure Act</quote> (published on March 3, 2025, and a letter of opinion from the Government Accountability Office dated August 27, 2025, printed in the Congressional Record on September 3, 2025, on pages S6003–S6005, concluding that such Policy Statement is a rule under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/8">chapter 8</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code), and such rule shall have no force or effect.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

