<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7C8A665C80D343F3A2EC94680F977090" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 537 IH: Incentivizing New Conversions to Residential Entities to Accelerate Supply and Expand Housing Affordability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 537</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250116">January 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide tax credits for the conversion of commercial buildings to residential units, to provide support and technical assistance to State and local housing agencies to identify and advance housing conversion opportunities for underutilized commercial buildings, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H653FA650A1704B8589F6F07313CF7195" style="OLC"><section id="H06584C0856FC4F01B5698A97E5F1F94C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Incentivizing New Conversions to Residential Entities to Accelerate Supply and Expand Housing Affordability Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>INCREASE Housing Affordability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H527A2A68ACC047C995DEA019760EDD46" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Commercial-to-residential credit</header><subsection id="H27920E1864BA4CCC82BCC406BAD4A537" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/46">Section 46</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating paragraph (7) as paragraph (8), by redesignating the paragraph (6) relating to the advanced manufacturing investment credits as paragraph (7), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (7) (as so redesignated), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (8) (as so redesignated) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA2F37A8270A451C8187E4E9CB90666B"><paragraph id="HF5A28F3CBB094479B844C0651B2E10EF" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the commercial-to-residential credit.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H3A46F5000CB54D60BDB65C53C42DAD8E" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amount of credit</header><text>Subpart E of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 48E the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAECFCEFEEACE4B8DAE7796B3E09DAEB9"><section id="H4138509773AF4992A5BC468ED271C567" commented="no"><enum>48F.</enum><header>Commercial-to-residential credit</header><subsection id="H752F724060BC411D8448F3FF172AF293" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of section 46, the commercial-to-residential credit for any taxable year is equal to 15 percent of the qualified conversion expenditures with respect to a qualified converted building.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6652A85BA5FA4656A9A08797C0582676" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on credit amount</header><text>The credit determined under subsection (a) may not exceed—</text><paragraph id="H25D400A1E190453E9577C8D19474B135"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$200,000 per new residential housing unit, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD940D88460914708B60B86E635E20FE4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$10,000,000 per qualified converted building.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD1A615B3B5C14DBCA45E50855308BCC7" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>When expenditures taken into account</header><paragraph id="H1F15788C8BE9475A836CE514D504DE56" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Qualified conversion expenditures with respect to any qualified converted building shall be taken into account for the taxable year in which such qualified converted building is placed in service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60F39A2C12B34A6FA2C3F26655F2D39E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination with subsection <enum-in-header>(e)</enum-in-header></header><text>The amount which would (but for this subparagraph) be taken into account under subparagraph (A) with respect to any qualified converted building shall be reduced (but not below zero) by any amount of qualified conversion expenditures taken into account under subsection (e) by the taxpayer or a predecessor of the taxpayer (or, in the case of a sale and leaseback described in section 50(a)(2)(C), by the lessee), to the extent any amount so taken into account has not been required to be recaptured under section 50(a). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7ED72B058E62453DA48810423859450D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Bonus credits</header><paragraph id="H0C879037537D4C4DB6352A2EA8FB62CA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affordable housing bonus credit</header><subparagraph id="H4B220B9BB7AE4C6FA2EEAA499C91AAC7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a qualified converted building which has been converted to a majority rental residential use and which satisfies the requirements under subparagraph (B), the amount of the credit determined under subsection (a) (determined without regard to this subsection) and the limitation on credit amount described in subsection (b) (determined without regard to this subsection) with respect to such building shall each be increased by an amount equal to—</text><clause id="H0F57927D59524B54B7F7FAF088B42D92"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a qualified converted building 25 percent or more of the residential units of which are both rent-restricted and occupied by individuals whose income does not exceed 100 percent of area median income, 10 percent of such amounts,</text></clause><clause id="HDE1FD138916343A6993ABDFA42B7201E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a qualified converted building 25 percent or more of the residential units of which are both rent-restricted and occupied by individuals whose income does not exceed 80 percent of area median income, 15 percent of such amounts, and</text></clause><clause id="HD3980C16E71446F6BD651228BD82A37E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of a qualified converted building 25 percent or more of the residential units of which are both rent-restricted and occupied by individuals whose income does not exceed 60 percent of area median income, 20 percent of such amounts.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3629B8516DA741419936E39C230605FE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rent and income limitation</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), rules similar to the rules of section 42(g) shall apply to determine whether a unit is rent-restricted, treatment of units occupied by individuals whose incomes rise above the limit, and treatment of units where Federal rental assistance is reduced as tenant’s income increases.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H329B7C04F1864CDEB32A7D2231C02B3B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prevailing wage bonus credit</header><subparagraph id="H5B27FAC64A2648889C100F8B129CCE7F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any qualified converted building with respect to which the taxpayer certifies to the Secretary that the taxpayer satisfied the requirement of subparagraph (B) with respect to the conversion process, the amount of the credit determined under subsection (a) (determined without regard to this subsection) and the limitation on the credit amount described in subsection (b) (determined without regard to this subsection) with respect to such building shall each be increased by an amount equal to 15 percent of such amounts.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0839634AD6C14D05965EB3E70553D390"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prevailing wage requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement described in this subparagraph is satisfied with respect to any conversion if all laborers or mechanics employed by the taxpayer or any contractor or subcontractor of the taxpayer to carry out the conversion were paid wages at rates not less than the prevailing rates for construction, alteration, or repair of a similar character in the locality in which such project is located as most recently determined by the Secretary of Labor, in accordance with subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8769215F210045339E29D13EB77B70BC" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><paragraph id="H909DF833782140549E03F5BD5E03991A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified converted building</header><subparagraph id="H2F700BC0A600407A905391FD098A7C5C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified converted building</term> means any building (and its structural components) if—</text><clause id="H1CBBBD829EAA479F9A049200F4E346C6" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>prior to conversion, such building was nonresidential real property (as defined in section 168) which was leased, or available for lease, to office tenants,</text></clause><clause id="H051946D7CEB24E189BB246D6D874D5B4" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such building has been substantially converted from an office use to a residential or residential-retail mixed use,</text></clause><clause id="H35B77567782E4576B7DC405AC842C9F9" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>such building was initially placed in service at least 15 years before the beginning of the conversion, and</text></clause><clause id="HC8892A4562BE4BA1819680624C4E230D" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>depreciation (or amortization in lieu of depreciation) is allowable with respect to such building.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD7108766E3047B9978887BCD738E94F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Substantially converted defined</header><clause id="H1F31F99BC4EF459F892F2508A46767E9" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)(A)(ii), a building shall be treated as having been substantially converted only if the qualified conversion expenditures during the 24-month period selected by the taxpayer (at the time and in the manner prescribed by regulation) and ending with or within the taxable year exceed the greater of—</text><subclause id="HB4DD2DE8854D4B1FB2E82DE7F5B44A4B" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the adjusted basis of such building (and its structural components), or</text></subclause><subclause id="H8B33B84E948246749E16CE255910C2F7" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>$15,000.</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause" commented="no">The adjusted basis of the building (and its structural components) shall be determined as of the beginning of the 1st day of such 24-month period, or of the holding period of the building, whichever is later. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the determination of the beginning of the holding period shall be made without regard to any reconstruction by the taxpayer in connection with the conversion. </continuation-text></clause><clause id="HE769091002734656B15BC2A199E412FD" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Special rule for phased conversion</header><text>In the case of any conversion which may reasonably be expected to be completed in phases set forth in architectural plans and specifications completed before the conversion begins, clause (i) shall be applied by substituting <quote>60-month period</quote> for <quote>24-month period</quote>.</text></clause><clause id="HBF13385F3B454DBB81C9FD72EDE2FD5B" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Lessees</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe by regulation rules for applying this subparagraph to lessees.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04070E57C6F549E9A83BDE5CE5B78644" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Reconstruction</header><text>Conversion includes reconstruction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC25AC6222964F21940801613D4A9979" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified conversion expenditures defined</header><subparagraph id="HEA5C0CE13B364B50AA67C76170050A08" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the term <term>qualified conversion expenditures</term> means any amount properly chargeable to capital account—</text><clause id="H95414E3E4A1D4451AFC427CDC987B885" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for property for which depreciation is allowable under section 168 and which is—</text><subclause id="H9A2283C19417461DA46520411D6BAB19" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>nonresidential real property (as defined in section 168),</text></subclause><subclause id="HC6E6A8F8C23844A3A31FF29131F91C8A" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>residential rental property (as defined in section 168), or</text></subclause><subclause id="HD7082EA693C8479C94D581F95C74D9A9" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an addition or improvement to property described in clause (i) or (ii), and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H92E3C8BEEF594FA3BBB6ABBEB01854A7" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in connection with the conversion of a qualified converted building.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD279BD2A016E4EF58D3C8C02BA9CA182" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certain expenditures not included</header><text>The term <term>qualified conversion expenditures</term> does not include—</text><clause id="H9D8909EBC64B4BF5A1B95BFF4FE7F882" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Straight line depreciation must be used</header><text>Any expenditure with respect to which the taxpayer does not use the straight line method over a recovery period determined under subsection (c) or (g) of section 168. The preceding sentence shall not apply to any expenditure to the extent the alternative depreciation system of section 168(g) applies to such expenditure by reason of subparagraph (B) or (C) of section 168(g)(1).</text></clause><clause id="HC8E6F4292D0943A6AF21A058193A812C" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Cost of acquisition</header><text>The cost of acquiring any building or interest therein.</text></clause><clause id="H2F329E9A31424920A76F33B4E4620F74" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Enlargements</header><text>Any expenditure attributable to the enlargement of an existing building.</text></clause><clause id="HD32DF98CCCC140D29A9B935C92BC2293" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Tax-exempt use property</header><text>Any expenditure in connection with the conversion of a building which is allocable to the portion of such property which is (or may reasonably be expected to be) tax-exempt use property (within the meaning of section 168(h)), except that—</text><subclause id="H16D2CB6604AF403C8898851076B75B04" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text><quote>50 percent</quote> shall be substituted for <quote>35 percent</quote> in paragraph (1)(B)(iii) thereof, and</text></subclause><subclause id="H9F7CF824AA4049A8A871FA1F81174E60" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an eligible educational institution (as defined in section 529(e)(5)) shall not be treated as a tax-exempt entity.</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause" commented="no">This clause shall not apply for purposes of determining whether a building has been substantially converted. </continuation-text></clause><clause id="HAE9DEAB38B2545BEB89988ACFBC8013E" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Expenditures of lessee</header><text>Any expenditure of a lessee of a building if, on the date the conversion is completed, the remaining term of the lease (determined without regard to any renewal periods) is less than the recovery period determined under section 168(c).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H44C32DBF381044F4BB4AE11C804424C6" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Progress expenditures</header><paragraph id="HB896977B7E6D43DBA01A8732B0E04F6C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any building to which this subsection applies, except as provided in paragraph (3)—</text><subparagraph id="HB4E7CAEDA91F448EABB8C692725376EC" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if such building is self-converted property, any qualified conversion expenditure with respect to such building shall be taken into account for the taxable year for which such expenditure is properly chargeable to capital account with respect to such building, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B981F6C613840858E7DF87BC8FB12FF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if such building is not self-converted property, any qualified conversion expenditure with respect to such building shall be taken into account for the taxable year in which paid.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBD73CAD0A3C4E6389439FB5AC244DB0" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Property to which subsection applies</header><subparagraph id="HD69670802C7E4253839238A330D09A56" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This subsection shall apply to any building which is being converted by or for the taxpayer if—</text><clause id="HF2CDC310F461416382C6416351C61278" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the normal conversion period for such building is 2 years or more, and</text></clause><clause id="H5D7F06F0EC9F44CEB05ECEA96359747C" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>it is reasonable to expect that such building will be a qualified converted building in the hands of the taxpayer when it is placed in service.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph" commented="no">Clauses (i) and (ii) shall be applied on the basis of facts known as of the close of the taxable year of the taxpayer in which the conversion begins (or, if later, at the close of the first taxable year to which an election under this subsection applies). </continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF508763BDA7D42A5838FF5AA44AEA0C3" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Normal conversion period</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <term>normal conversion period</term> means the period reasonably expected to be required for the conversion of the building—</text><clause id="H681575C7E7BA4C3B8556F4FDC2CF6E17" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>beginning with the date on which physical work on the conversion begins (or, if later, the first day of the first taxable year to which an election under this subsection applies), and</text></clause><clause id="HF7F902AE44DA4ED2B1C1E032D4A9DE28" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ending on the date on which it is expected that the property will be available for placing in service.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DF6A6E097484387B03A41B9649A707A" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rules for applying paragraph (1)</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H83C2DD2927A747B7BE6EC008AD1DB7DD" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Component parts, etc</header><text>Property which is to be a component part of, or is otherwise to be included in, any building to which this subsection applies shall be taken into account—</text><clause id="H5A80C747B2D3410AA5EA67B63DA3B1D3" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at a time not earlier than the time at which it becomes irrevocably devoted to use in the building, and</text></clause><clause id="H56221126EBF44362818462230E5BC8BF" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as if (at the time referred to in clause (i)) the taxpayer had expended an amount equal to that portion of the cost to the taxpayer of such component or other property which, for purposes of this subpart, is properly chargeable (during such taxable year) to capital account with respect to such building.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BEF321AF689414FA60C1DE6A6C46D30" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certain borrowing disregarded</header><text>Any amount borrowed directly or indirectly by the taxpayer from the person converting the property for him shall not be treated as an amount expended for such conversion.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D6A84321C8544B78B69B5B067D1853D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation for buildings which are not self-converted</header><clause id="H4612395EF5244DA4BAB7AC879CB67912" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a building which is not self-converted, the amount taken into account under paragraph (1)(B) for any taxable year shall not exceed the amount which represents the portion of the overall cost to the taxpayer of the conversion which is properly attributable to the portion of the conversion which is completed during such taxable year.</text></clause><clause id="HAAB7B97DE29C442FA6E7AAC08ABA93B6" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Carryover of certain amounts</header><text>In the case of a building which is not a self-converted building, if for the taxable year—</text><subclause id="H6C8E3AF6693A4162979556F096B440CA" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the amount which (but for clause (i)) would have been taken into account under paragraph (1)(B) exceeds the limitation of clause (i), then the amount of such excess shall be taken into account under paragraph (1)(B) for the succeeding taxable year, or</text></subclause><subclause id="H8FEAF61AE1E742CDB49A9E05B946E5D0" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the limitation of clause (i) exceeds the amount taken into account under paragraph (1)(B), then the amount of such excess shall increase the limitation of clause (i) for the succeeding taxable year.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B38AA25CFE242CE8C5E5FB32353DAA4" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Determination of percentage of completion</header><text>The determination under subparagraph (C)(i) of the portion of the overall cost to the taxpayer of the conversion which is properly attributable to conversion completed during any taxable year shall be made, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, on the basis of engineering or architectural estimates or on the basis of cost accounting records. Unless the taxpayer establishes otherwise by clear and convincing evidence, the conversion shall be deemed to be completed not more rapidly than ratably over the normal conversion period.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB907360EE1904AB782D5C00F61404F1A" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><header>No progress expenditures for certain prior periods</header><text>No qualified conversion expenditures shall be taken into account under this subsection for any period before the first day of the first taxable year to which an election under this subsection applies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73B8599F25674A74BE68FE8FEBF7E93C" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><header>No progress expenditures for property for year it is placed in service, etc</header><text>In the case of any building, no qualified conversion expenditures shall be taken into account under this subsection for the earlier of—</text><clause id="H4B26C837FDFC40E3A75722C16DE04CAB" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the taxable year in which the building is placed in service, or</text></clause><clause id="H20BCCDAAC57342C28AB8CCAA25E4B844" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the first taxable year for which recapture is required under section 50(a)(2) with respect to such property,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph" commented="no">or for any taxable year thereafter. </continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H838975889CA042AD870D81E70233678A" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Self-converted building</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>self-converted building</term> means any building if it is reasonable to believe that more than half of the qualified conversion expenditures for such building will be made directly by the taxpayer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9AD2E87A4994371BD60649DC1CF8CD1" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Election</header><text>This subsection shall apply to any taxpayer only if such taxpayer has made an election under this paragraph. Such an election shall apply to the taxable year for which made and all subsequent taxable years. Such an election, once made, may be revoked only with the consent of the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H60FD3614F6D24D1C8F4E0667FB1D04F9" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text>A credit shall not be allowed under this section for any qualified conversion expenditure for which a credit is allowed under section 42 or 47.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HE2716ED336584970AD3CE8928F51A00D" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="HAAA218507AF24888AC13F48CC68D185F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/49">Section 49(a)(1)(C)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of clause (vii), by striking the period at the end of clause (viii) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by adding after clause (viii) the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H416903B88946458A8622614D6C85F23E"><clause id="H242E5E49E4904379BDE4041F0AAA3FA8" commented="no"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the portion of the basis of any qualified converted property attributable to qualified conversion expenditures under section 48F.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H9062B26A6BF144EA952F8440A6A7E67C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 50(a)(2)(E) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>or 48E(e)</quote> and inserting <quote>48E(e), or 48F(e)</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F25B6BB1EF94760A31234C0EA8532D7" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 50(b)(2) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (C), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (D) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>, and by adding after subparagraph (D) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H24BE689895BB41FA94B02C89C0A84861"><subparagraph id="H0DC33BEBF8FF409490E691AC65815CE4" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a qualified converted building to the extent of that portion of the basis which is attributable to qualified conversion expenditures.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H957A1476AF50475B9A2D81F9B38D104C" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Section 50(b)(3) is amended by inserting <quote>, or, solely with respect to the commercial-to-residential credit, an eligible educational institution (as defined in section 529(e)(5))</quote> after <quote>section 521</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53E12E36BFE4423EB3C81E634DA50FBA" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The table of sections for subpart E of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 48E the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEA9ACA3BF61B45FFBDDF1B6921EB25E2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="HAECFCEFEEACE4B8DAE7796B3E09DAEB9" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H4138509773AF4992A5BC468ED271C567" level="section">Sec. 48F. Commercial-to-residential credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA8F20DCC1C9B44A38C0F83C44DAF216B" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to qualified conversion expenditures incurred after the date of enactment in taxable years ending after such date. </text></subsection></section><section id="HD51E3DDE691D41CFBA1790D40252CDA8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Commercial to residential conversion advisory board</header><subsection id="H0CB1DBB527AF4FDA80465928079D3C69"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall establish an advisory board to carry out the duties described in subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="H1D3AE2ABFD294A30A9F160B4C8D27A24"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The advisory board shall be composed of not less than 20 members, appointed by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="H84CEBCC533594952B74B4656D5D24B79"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The advisory board shall provide logistical support, technical assistance, best practices, and training to State and local housing agencies with respect to—</text><paragraph id="HD9C8465E3E944016A1E54EFB12F8CB1A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifying the best candidates for commercial to residential conversions that are financially and logistically feasible and meet demonstrated housing demand in localities within the State or locality;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53D85A4C5F2F48258DB2E87DDA0B7B12"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conducting floor plan and feasibility analyses for prospective commercial to residential conversions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3037CF6C4241424A9CAB7EA75162DAD2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>expediting State or local regulatory processes and permitting processes to allow for faster approval and construction of commercial to residential conversions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H23C62AEF1E9645EE8FEE532BDDEAD3CF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reforming of local regulatory and zoning barriers to allow for more commercial to residential conversions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03681C88B8BE4F37A1867586228B1F9D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identifying Federal and State funding sources that can be used by localities to provide financial assistance on commercial to residential conversion projects.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B74157BB984442689ACF31CE6DE455D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

