<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELL25241-DF4-N7-W29"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1101 IS: States Handling Access to Reciprocity for Employment Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1101</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250325">March 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the use of Federal Bureau of Investigation criminal history record information for administration of certain licenses. </official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H2EAB3C42781E4CAE888D6FB0DB0704E4"><section section-type="section-one" id="H11BCF30B0A1A426FA1D19092883FBACD"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>States Handling Access to Reciprocity for Employment Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SHARE Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H9AB3C543C6CF4FE68E10C8EEBC535429"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sharing and use of criminal history record information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subtitle E of title VI of the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/41106">34 U.S.C. 41106 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBDF633528A6D4132ADFFE2326C032BFE"><section id="HDFA0F9D320F547A6B5EA917282D60CE9"><enum>6404.</enum><header>Sharing and use of criminal history record information</header><subsection id="H598C0E46FA114688BAAB536750083859"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H2A59ECC436C54693BDC16E981D7A6DF6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means a joint governmental entity, including an interstate compact commission, established by legislative enactment of an interstate compact.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8352FA0E15074E109241B8B77035F306"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criminal history record information</header><text>The term <term>criminal history record information</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id03ab5f6dfcee4709a04f23cd07825c35"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means information collected by criminal justice agencies on individuals consisting of identifiable descriptions and notations of arrests, detentions, indictments, information, or other formal criminal charges, and any disposition arising therefrom, including acquittal, sentencing, correctional supervision, and release; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ac871f335454df2b93b83ed7ebe6aab"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include identification information, such as fingerprint records, if such information does not indicate the individual’s involvement with the criminal justice system. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0169553E19EE4247A895FB0400D2F977"><enum>(3)</enum><header>License</header><text>The term <term>license</term> means a license, multistate license, certification, or other authorization by which a State licensing authority authorizes an individual to practice an occupation or profession in that State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC99B18A9B244B51B6F041E600A82FDE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Privilege</header><text>The term <term>privilege</term> means a grant of authority issued pursuant to an interstate compact to a license holder that permits the license holder to practice in a compact member State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE2FB76A7CC04E94AAD1A5359BB521FD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means any State, territory, or possession of the United States, and the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7943A1C3CA7A4EA0A05ACB2D38132990"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State identification bureau</header><text>The term <term>State identification bureau</term> has the meaning given such term in section 6402(c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA2E37740A304344BE42A3C61FA5B7B5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State licensing authority</header><text>The term <term>State licensing authority</term> means a State licensing board, agency, department, or other entity that is empowered under the law of that State to grant a license to practice an occupation or profession.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9992BCA01D184729834134B294A45706"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement for Federal Bureau of Investigation To provide certain criminal history record information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the restrictions in subsection (c), the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall furnish or otherwise make available to a State licensing authority, through an agreement with a State law enforcement agency or State identification bureau, criminal history record information to the extent required by an interstate compact, or the regulations duly promulgated thereunder, for the purpose of conducting a criminal history background check of any individual seeking a license or privilege to practice an occupation or profession in a compact member State. </text></subsection><subsection id="H912152B7130042EB92C5C8A6771741BD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State licensing authority use of criminal history record information</header><paragraph id="HB3CE191E05774310ABB64D83D8062F95"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>A State licensing authority that is a member of an interstate compact that requires completion of a criminal history background check for an individual for the purpose of acting upon a license or privilege of that individual to practice an occupation or profession in a State shall use such information solely for that purpose and may not share criminal history record information or any part thereof with the compact’s Commission, any other State entity or State Licensing Authority, or the public.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBBE96308A1141A5AAF57255BE7ED242"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sharing fact of completion of criminal history background check expressly permitted</header><text>A State licensing authority informing a compact Commission of the completion of the criminal history background check, including a binary determination of whether or not the criminal history background check of an applicant was satisfactory, is expressly permitted under this section and shall not constitute the sharing of criminal history record information under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

