<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-NEW25128-0C5-3G-8NL"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 97 ATS: Honoring the life of Nebraska community leader Howard L. Hawks.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 97</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250225">February 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the life of Nebraska community leader Howard L. Hawks.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1935, Howard L. Hawks (referred to in this preamble as <quote>Hawks</quote>) was born in Carleton, Nebraska;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1987, Hawks co-founded Tenaska Energy, where Hawks served as—</text><paragraph id="id7ca89a6a5e9c494bb1476a4f1f213043"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Chairman and CEO until 2010; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf4a63ff4a5ab4af7a7347d21cf1c9603"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Chairman until 2022;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Hawks grew Tenaska Energy from a small business out of Omaha, Nebraska, to 1 of the largest private companies in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Hawks remained active in Tenaska Energy even after transitioning to Chairman Emeritus in 2022;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, through his dedication to the community around him, Hawks served as—</text><paragraph id="id14e6a8b8145f4f749f8b3c14d0558682"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a Regent at the University of Nebraska for 18 years; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id117ef6ee4b694ec7a4d329c9a2a60878"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Board Member of Creighton University for 12 years;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, among his many philanthropic efforts, Hawks transformed the University of Nebraska-Lincoln in both athletics and academics and, in 2023, the University of Nebraska-Lincoln honored Hawks and his wife with the Regents Medal to recognize their contributions;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Hawks supported various efforts and projects across the University of Nebraska system, including—</text><paragraph id="id6812d07d654547c89e83c4d40adee229"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Howard L. Hawks Hall;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id803936257c8347a4a24c2bfbf3405c5e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a business ethics and leadership chair for the University of Nebraska-Lincoln College of Business;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a3a462eba874e42a31624aaba40bd30"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Kiewit Hall for the University of Nebraska-Lincoln College of Engineering;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6727fb5b5c2447ca8159b7fbb044d561"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Hawks Championship Center and Hawks Field at Haymarket Park for University of Nebraska-Lincoln athletics;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56e87ad0e1ad48f4b1d62315646d3134"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Baxter Arena and the baseball and softball complex for University of Nebraska-Omaha Athletics;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2ffdfc0059124529a731c28759acb370"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the renovation to the Durham Science Center for University of Nebraska-Omaha;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a702d764724493e8956f7135ddcd3b0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Tim Hawks Chair in Cancer Prevention and Population Science in the University of Nebraska Medical Center College of Public Health;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd8d9751a9f44991a71a06c8393e9ad6"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the Rhonda and Howard Hawks Movement Disorders Fellowship in the University of Nebraska Medical Center Department of Neurological Sciences;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6db21e824b1445518f661fa5734c5dca"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Sharing Clinic, a University of Nebraska Medical Center student-run clinic; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2dae16f82a2449089fd2b58666cd0344"><enum>(10)</enum><text>student scholarships;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Hawks served on the executive committee for <quote>Campaign for Nebraska: Unlimited Possibilities</quote>, a fundraising campaign conducted from 2005 to 2014 that raised $1,800,000,000 in private support for the University of Nebraska-Lincoln; and</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Hawks’ philanthropic commitment extended well beyond the University of Nebraska system, supporting initiatives addressing homelessness and mental health, and supporting education and the arts: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id5ade9b411fac456eb1679cd91a77bd4b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has heard with profound sorrow and deep regret the announcement of the death of Howard L. Hawks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddac2e333d612439da62d3c4d3f0ba6ed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the life and legacy of Howard L. Hawks for his unwavering dedication to Nebraska as a civic leader and philanthropist; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id983beb4dc8cf495780de2e9b6936525c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>respectfully requests that the Secretary of the Senate transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to the family of Howard L. Hawks. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

