<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H026E9A941FE54A60A151F99B020DCE84" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1412 IH: Know Your Rates Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1412</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250218">February 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to establish additional Federal standards that require electric and gas utilities to transmit to each of its consumers information regarding the consumption of electric energy or gas, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8DFC3186FB034FAC9C87354E59856D3A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7E4F48E7B2F543B895459E777FE9E8B9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Know Your Rates Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4D6D990FE635424DBF9F7FA7C6E2AC74"><enum>2.</enum><header>Additional information to electric consumers</header> <subsection id="H7C8B9B9326E440958EF4F4C688F1F3D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 113(b)(3) of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2623">16 U.S.C. 2623(b)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H77BF47B511214BB085DF393F96C89A40" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H7352D022D03540F0B3CF5F965E7F48CE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information to consumers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each electric utility shall transmit to each of its electric consumers information regarding rate schedules and consumption of electric energy in accordance with the requirements of section 115(f).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H7E3D4DE2D1BE492EBDC5971B17482621"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information to electric consumers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 115(f) of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2625">16 U.S.C. 2625</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7A493E90B02A444885C2204433731DF2" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H2AB7178F56BD4DB39395CF717BEADCA9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Additional information</header> 
<subparagraph id="H83B05E79F21F40AC87FD293BCF07E455"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of the standard for information to consumers established by section 113(b)(3), each covered electric utility shall establish a program under which such covered electric utility shall transmit information in accordance with this paragraph.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H15ED8CE63DE54035AFDE11AE268F046E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional billing information</header><text>Each covered electric utility shall include in each billing to an electric consumer of the covered electric utility—</text> 
<clause id="H6688721714024195B22BB1817695579C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the difference between the dollar amount charged in the billing and the dollar amount charged in the previous billing period; and</text></clause> <clause id="H193E853071AC475A80C08B29B59FBB6D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in dollars and in kilowatt hours, the average monthly consumption of electric energy by such electric consumer.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDC569A5DC51143B78C2157B6B185598D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Usage notices</header><text>A covered electric utility shall notify an electric consumer information relating to the average daily consumption of electric energy by such electric consumer in the following manner:</text> <clause id="H0646B83D91824509815F6BDE05BA02B6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>If within the first 9 days of a billing period the average daily consumption of electric energy by an electric consumer exceeds the average daily consumption of electric energy for the previous billing period, the relevant covered electric utility shall notify such electric consumer on the 10th day of the billing period of the excess consumption.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H95636A60138B45DAB6FAED1E9B652041"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>If within the first 19 days of a billing period, or within another date an electric consumer chooses, the average daily consumption of electric energy by such electric consumer exceeds the average daily consumption of electric energy for the previous billing period, the relevant covered electric utility shall notify such electric consumer on the 20th day, or the day after the date on which the electric consumer chooses, of the excess consumption.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5D68246584994BB8A2E0AA5FC986F10F"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Optional notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the program established pursuant to subparagraph (A), a covered electric utility shall provide an option to each electric consumer to be notified by the covered electric utility in the event the electric consumer, within an active billing period, reaches a dollar amount—</text>
<clause id="H42D518217B774F2DB75822186409897C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that is based on the rate charged by a covered electric utility for providing electric service;</text></clause> <clause id="H3082C947BA2D4412A6CDEAEF893E68DD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that reflects the amount of electric energy consumed within the active billing period; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H1461A956947F45499DC3A33FE2F7EDCE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>chosen by such electric consumer.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC0E8965A67084F98A1F6DAA333BBD199"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Covered electric utility defined</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>covered electric utility</term> means an electric utility that receives funding from Federal sources, as determined by the Commission.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="H748C852D99B7470991BF42AF3727A29E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Additional information to gas consumers</header> 
<subsection id="H8B33682D35AE4C619B58E0FF57DCD2CD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 303(b) of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3203">15 U.S.C. 3203(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0507BA08688747E0910C2B82475DD8CB" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H3DDBBC1E97FF4B3AA45EBDEADE1743A5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Information to consumers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each gas utility shall transmit to each of its gas consumers information relating to the consumption of gas in accordance with section 304(c).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFAD0A61AB69D4F029948075804AE75E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information to gas consumers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 304 of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3204">15 U.S.C. 3204</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC3CDBED32DDE480BA4221FEFEB2E8217" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HC7EF5CFA0A3A4971ABAD3E673FDBB624"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Information to consumers</header> <paragraph id="H3DF81CBA4AAB4BFAB4534A74BD69E40F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of the standard for information to consumers established by section 303(b)(c), each covered gas utility shall establish a program under which such covered gas utility shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H416F45253D1646CFA21C94735299EEC4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in each billing to a gas consumer of the covered gas utility, include—</text> <clause id="HE68CD913440C4D51A42ABA50D1FFC01F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the difference between the dollar amount charged in the billing and the dollar amount charged in the previous billing period; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF4FC32522C544B22A2DABF6ECD443168"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in dollars and therms, the average monthly consumption of gas by such gas consumer; and</text></clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H61AFBC17A93140D4BFB45FAAB2B351B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notify each such gas consumer information relating to the average daily consumption of gas by such gas consumer in the following manner:</text>
<clause id="H94372C70EB9847278A64ADB692367479"><enum>(i)</enum><text>If within the first 9 days of a billing period the average daily consumption of gas by a gas consumer exceeds the average daily consumption of gas for the previous billing period, the relevant covered gas utility shall notify such gas consumer on the 10th day of the billing period about such exceedance.</text></clause> <clause id="H6F7EC86BE09A485A8953527EB0CA6966"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>If within the first 19 days of a billing period, or within another date a gas consumer chooses, the average daily consumption of gas by such gas consumer exceeds the average daily consumption of gas for the previous billing period, the relevant covered gas utility shall notify such gas consumer on the 20th day, or the day after the date on which the gas consumer chooses, of the excess consumption.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H30C16424212B497887746555C0770663"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Optional notice</header><text>Under the program established pursuant to paragraph (1), a covered gas utility shall provide an option to each gas consumer to be notified by the covered electric utility in the event the gas consumer, within an active billing period, reaches a dollar amount—</text> <subparagraph id="H516B95394B0E48D185F7EA2684E2C6C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is based on the rate charged by a covered gas utility for providing gas service;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC0C553BF2C794D80B2F41DF8F9EB8030"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that reflects the amount of gas consumed within the active billing period; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE212C3D8D5744E3DBFCFC0F503459A50"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">chosen by such gas consumer.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD770291570A14CB78557212F61A1EB44"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered gas utility defined</header><text>The term <term>covered gas utility</term> means a gas utility that receives funding from Federal sources, as determined by the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

