<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR25814-F4X-SH-WWS"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2416 IS: Identifying Regulatory Barriers to Housing Supply Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2416</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require certain grantees under title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to submit a plan to track overly burdensome land use policies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H5E619CDA2F8C4969A703949AABBC09E6"><section section-type="section-one" id="HABDDE0989E634E5B837600EEDEA67532"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Identifying Regulatory Barriers to Housing Supply Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idc4e2f8a9e41f45b7998cf8daae27e207"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to discourage the use of overly burdensome land use policies and remove barriers to making housing more affordable in order to further the original intent of the Community Development Block Grant program.</text></section><section id="id4c34dddb7e574f9aa1068008d7961616"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id19e25ce38c5b41a4b51f6572277d2610"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States has a shortage of millions of homes, contributing to a record number of cost-burdened households across rural, urban, and suburban communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id74a4568e1ce24d54989a3bffe3c78f1c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The housing shortage is constraining the economy and costing the people of the United States about $2,000,000,000,000 per year in lost opportunities and lower productivity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id31951964ffe54dec94879b4a84e10cb7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Zoning and land use policy reforms are one part of the solution to addressing the rising cost of housing, alongside policies that invest in fair and affordable housing throughout the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8d3a712ea9eb4d0eb197d0df48449cb6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Department of Housing and Urban Development should maintain adequate staffing levels to implement this legislation, assist communities in overcoming zoning and land use challenges unduly constraining housing, and support quality and affordable housing programs serving the most vulnerable in the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idac1e9639e8c2444db75bac0f4c8d6149"><enum>4.</enum><header>Land use plan</header><subsection id="id7a101f9ac5e64b228d2368de2ab07adb"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 104 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5304">42 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd51ab13be4a4531995409d4afd89edd"><subsection id="idd6c49b72fcd34660bac6b299960d33a1"> <enum>(n)</enum> <header>Plan To track and reduce overly burdensome land use policies</header> <paragraph id="ideb8ace5222734045a9c9651a27ae7006"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>Prior to receipt in any fiscal year of a grant from the Secretary under subsection (b), (d)(1), or (d)(2)(B) of section 106, each recipient shall have prepared and submitted, not less frequently than once during the preceding 5-year period, in accordance with this subsection and in such standardized form as the Secretary shall, by regulation, prescribe, with respect to each land use policy described in paragraph (2) that is applicable to the jurisdiction served by the recipient, a description of—</text>
              <subparagraph id="id98adc59409884e6ab8c61c06b519c90f">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>whether the recipient has already adopted the policy in the jurisdiction served by the recipient within the preceding 5-year period;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="id6f883cbcece043a4b9e36546e7639d52">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the plan of the recipient to adopt and implement the policy in that jurisdiction; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="idee4501c2366d4a258fb6ee1677445588">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>the ways in which adopting the policy will benefit the jurisdiction.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="ide9b6838d40744e659758fc56cd4cddca"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Land use policies</header> <text>The policies described in this paragraph are as follows:</text>
              <subparagraph id="id91547df89bfe4a21ab6ec43de5f7fdf0">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>Expanding by-right multifamily zoned areas.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id266d71138cc44440852843cd9bd94a2c"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>Allowing duplexes, triplexes, or fourplexes in areas zoned primarily for single-family residential homes.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="id607e32649566480cb11c8daca9c7ea17">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>Allowing manufactured homes in areas zoned primarily for single-family residential homes.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="id9da003b9860f459d9ef02399399a2405">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>Allowing multifamily development in retail, office, and light manufacturing zones.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="ide992247292c64ca6910c7c5a1b093b2e">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>Allowing single-room occupancy development wherever multifamily housing is allowed.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="idd39b48589d104f06b4bab18b27e8d3ba">
                <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>Reducing minimum lot size.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id4e034b4275bb4d39a9cfca597d91d2f3"> <enum>(G)</enum> <text>Ensuring historic preservation requirements and other land use policies or requirements are coordinated to encourage creation of housing in historic buildings and historic districts.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="idaaf05d74a17740f194ba805877569f21">
                <enum>(H)</enum>
 <text>Increasing the allowable floor area ratio by allowing a higher ratio of total floor area in a building in comparison to its lot size.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="id8c2dc540e185424f88885fa710566d4d">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>Creating transit-oriented development zones.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id359ddac685724284b20caea5d70c319c"> <enum>(J)</enum> <text>Streamlining or shortening permitting processes and timelines, including through one-stop and parallel-process permitting.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="idf8b00f77c5634673994ab379e7cbea44">
                <enum>(K)</enum>
 <text>Eliminating or reducing off-street parking requirements.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idc69a5d99ff1346b5ad1121f03a11acdd"> <enum>(L)</enum> <text>Ensuring impact and utility investment fees accurately reflect required infrastructure needs and related impacts on housing affordability are otherwise mitigated.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="idf4c4c203764a4a148fa149ca78bcbcd6">
                <enum>(M)</enum>
 <text>Allowing off-site construction, including prefabricated construction.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id4b26a9da023c4d99a811c1698f528a20"> <enum>(N)</enum> <text>Reducing or eliminating minimum unit square footage requirements.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="id4ff5a436944043f5be333341afd1ae16">
                <enum>(O)</enum>
 <text>Allowing the conversion of office units to apartments.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idff3f1717c16346e783f90f4595e94208"> <enum>(P)</enum> <text>Allowing the subdivision of single-family homes into duplexes.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="id56439baad08e4fe6b014df039d908cef">
                <enum>(Q)</enum>
 <text>Allowing accessory dwelling units, including detached accessory dwelling units, on all lots with single-family homes.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="id71c7c5527fb6477d8a693713e6a17265">
                <enum>(R)</enum>
 <text>Establishing density bonuses.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idae16080331414a5d80ef97a01ea9fef2"> <enum>(S)</enum> <text>Eliminating or relaxing residential property height limitations.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="id25e30c3f208c4c50b3ec8fa47bfa863a">
                <enum>(T)</enum>
 <text>Using property tax abatements to enable higher density and mixed-income communities.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="idf2e512dc17044e19a9f9184438eb492f">
                <enum>(U)</enum>
 <text>Donating vacant land for affordable housing development.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id3659fc59984248d9a9918f4f34ef9689"> <enum>(V)</enum> <text>Enacting other relevant high-density single-family and multifamily zoning policies that the recipient chooses to report.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ide6d326cfdd4a4f44936d8b819df2971f">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <header>Effect of submission</header>
 <text>A submission under this subsection shall not be binding with respect to the use or distribution of amounts received under section 106.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id7db827004d1b476cb8032c0301bfe1e0">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <header>Acceptance or nonacceptance of plan</header>
 <text>The acceptance or nonacceptance of any plan submitted under this subsection in which the information required under this subsection is provided is not an endorsement or approval of the plan, policies, or methodologies, or lack thereof.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id4f1609457d6f4fa7b439ce8f086f7cd2">
              <enum>(5)</enum>
              <header>Prohibition on use of information for enforcement</header>
 <text>Information provided by a recipient to the Secretary under this subsection may not be used as the basis for any enforcement action.</text>
            </paragraph>
 </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id0511db7b6786466da755995cc916385d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The requirements under subsection (n) of section 104 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5304">42 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a), shall—</text><paragraph id="idbaef7d31e78b41fbbaa99f9e7273ebea"><enum>(1)</enum><text>take effect on the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddec797103194451bb9672ae07b17f1bd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>apply to recipients of a grant under subsection (b), (d)(1), or (d)(2)(B) of section 106 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5306">42 U.S.C. 5306</external-xref>) before, on, and after such date.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

