<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H24F3286805AC471BA69552D57DC1F4A1" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 441 IH: Expressing support for the designation of May 2025 as “Mental Health Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 441</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250521">May 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001123">Mr. Cisneros</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000136">Mr. Vasquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hernández</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001094">Ms. Hoyle of Oregon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of May 2025 as <quote>Mental Health Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Americans across the country continue to confront an ongoing mental health crisis;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Americans continue to see increasing reports of loneliness, stress, anxiety, depression, suicidal thoughts, and substance abuse;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 2023 National Survey on Drug Use and Health conducted by the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA) found that—</text><paragraph id="H64C02922A883427F83D07478FB8FE9DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of American adults living with a mental illness has risen from 51,400,000 in 2019 to 58,700,000 in 2023;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF4B3B25028F41A4AAB6C49C17072D0C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">23 percent of Americans over the age of 18 and 34 percent of Americans between the ages of 18 and 25 have lived with a mental illness during the past year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5101B959DA664EAAAFC4FC832CFAAA7F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">12,800,000 adults had serious thoughts of suicide during the past year;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas an October 2022 Kaiser Family Foundation/CNN Mental Health in America Survey found that—</text><paragraph id="H7830FB58E5BE437D8E079A47FD412ABE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">90 percent of the public think that there is a mental health crisis in the United States today;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28B84314344D4990A3DD6494DB6CF161"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">55 percent of the public think that mental health issues in children and teenagers in the United States today are a crisis;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4A053F6303D45CDBA84033F7AFA983B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">47 percent of parents say that the COVID–19 pandemic has had a negative impact on their child’s mental health; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B48D4FBC4A946F489B7E249DB98DB7E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">51 percent of all adults say they or a family member has experienced a severe mental health crisis;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Stress in America 2023 survey conducted by the American Psychological Association found that—</text><paragraph id="HC37E3B7F5A554938BD381D4D5815E67E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">26 percent of adults are so stressed that they struggle to function;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H715D7F50D5D14CFFAF7A144D6F0C3AB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">47 percent of adults struggle to go to work or attend school because of stress; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06D156E554C64411ADD152770EBAC710"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">58 percent of Americans between the ages of 18 and 34 feel completely overwhelmed by stress every day;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 2022 Access to Care Survey conducted by the National Council for Mental Wellbeing found that—</text><paragraph id="HCD880A3CC90246879EECD6074290283F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 in 5 Americans reported needing mental health care;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C3F8F382D6A41D698D4CB553D521965"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">43 percent of Americans who needed mental health care over the past 12 months did not receive it; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB924C8487BB1490AB799941106E87C2B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">two-thirds of Americans believe that it is harder to find a mental health care provider than it is to find a physical health care provider;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a February 2024 Household Pulse Survey found that 17.7 percent of adults reported symptoms of anxiety disorder;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), mental health disorders are chronic conditions, and without proper diagnosis and treatment children can face problems at home and in school which can interfere with their future development;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more resources should be dedicated in schools to the prevention, early detection, and treatment of mental health disorders in children;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas childhood depression is more likely to persist into adulthood if it is left untreated;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is important that the United States provide the necessary funding and resources to reach children and youth early on in life;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the October 10, 2024, CDC Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report found that adverse childhood experiences (ACEs) were common among adolescents, with approximately three in four students experiencing one or more ACEs and approximately one in five students experiencing four or more ACEs and that these experiences contribute substantially to numerous health conditions and risk behaviors in adolescence;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the May 12, 2023, CDC Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report found that between 2020 and 2023, the number of pediatric emergency department visits associated with mental health conditions increased and was most pronounced in girls between the ages of 12 and 17;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the COVID–19 pandemic has accelerated the use of digital technologies, such as any social media;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there has been a great concern about the impact of social media on the mental health of children and youth;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas social media does expose children to bullying, depression, anxiety, and self-harm;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there is a strong need to further understand and deter any negative impacts of social media on children and youth;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the CDC’s Youth Risk Behavior Survey Data Summary and Trends Report: 2013–2023, found that—</text><paragraph id="H3939A6F94A504822A3B08DF4196981AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">nearly 3 in 5 teenage girls in the United States felt persistently sad or hopeless in 2021, which is double that of boys and the highest level reported in decades;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H180D9389A80A4BE49EAA89827F90B3DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">30 percent of teenage girls in the United States seriously considered attempting suicide in the past year; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05CD31568FC440C989220D891E075979"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">youth experienced high and worsening levels of persistent sadness or hopelessness across all racial and ethnics groups; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3A5A119F46A45BE8D2FF805278685EB"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">40 percent of high school students felt so sad or hopeless almost every day for at least 2 weeks in a row that they stopped doing their usual activities;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the CDC’s Youth Risk Behavioral Survey Data Summary and Trends Report: 2013–2023, found that—</text><paragraph id="H91855C8B7B6B4219B69D9AFDA0966C52"><enum>(1)</enum><text>31 percent of heterosexual high school students and 65 percent of LGBTQ+ high school students felt persistent feelings of sadness or hopelessness during 2023;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65FAED79DA294D38ACD1BC4F31B2DF2D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>11 percent of heterosexual high school students and 32 percent of LGBTQ+ high school students made a suicide plan during the last 12 months; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3397312223F4F66A5A2FB9B6288B39D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>6 percent of heterosexual high school students and 20 percent of LGBTQ+ high school students actually attempted suicide during the last 12 months;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the 2023 National Survey on LGBTQ Youth Mental Health conducted by The Trevor Project, 50 percent of LGBTQ youth who wanted mental health care in the past year were not able to get it and 39 percent of LGBTQ youth seriously considered attempting suicide over this same time period;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas disparities remain in access to mental health treatment for communities of color, with Asian, Native American, Hispanic, and Black individuals less likely to receive mental health care than their White counterparts;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a July 2021 survey conducted by the National Council for Mental Wellbeing found that from July 2020 to July 2021—</text><paragraph id="H32F18D0ABEBC40DEB1CC68EAC6B747B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>46 percent of Black adults say they are experiencing more stress and mental health challenges, but just 21 percent say they have received treatment or care of any kind for their mental health;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA059A763C2D747668CEB64571FDD70DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>45 percent of Native American adults have experienced more stress and mental health challenges, but only 24 percent have received treatment for mental health;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A17719F35EA4BA0A145D4B331E3774B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">42 percent of Hispanic adults report experiencing more stress and mental health challenges, but just 26 percent say they have received treatment for mental health;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C7720F98E9E4C708E70F00A409E5515"><enum>(4)</enum><text>40 percent of Asian adults say they are experiencing more stress and mental health challenges, but just 11 percent say they have received treatment or care of any kind; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E4C3111555F48AB90311585E225FBEB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>almost half (47 percent) of all adults surveyed stated that the cost of help or treatment is an obstacle in seeking treatment for their mental health;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2021, the Kaiser Family Foundation found that over half of White, Hispanic, and Black adults say that the COVID–19 pandemic has had a negative impact on their mental health;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas suicide is a significant public health issue that can have an enduring impact on individuals and their communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas additional resources should be dedicated to the prevention of suicide in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the CDC, the overall suicide rate in the United States increased by 30 percent between 2000 and 2020;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the CDC, the total number of deaths by suicide in the United States increased by 2.6 percent between 2021 and 2022;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas provisional data published by the CDC in November 2023 found that—</text><paragraph id="HAEC84D2A9945454BBF8C1AB5DC5B9228"><enum>(1)</enum><text>suicide is one of the leading causes of death in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A07608C7880450BA600607C5931C656"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of suicides was 3 percent higher in 2022 than it was in 2021;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas veterans are more likely to experience mental health challenges than nonveterans;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is important that the United States provide additional funding and resources to support veterans with mental health needs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 2023 National Veteran Suicide Prevention Annual Report found that—</text><paragraph id="HEB73B1CAF2FA4050A3572AA571DFB39B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>6,392 veterans died by suicide in 2021, which is a daily average of 17.5;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D71A6B931B747B3AC197761CE68EB6D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the suicide rate for veterans was 71.8 percent greater than for nonveteran United States adults; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8013C11A28E4B2AB2901559894DBE4E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the suicide rate was highest among veterans between the ages of 18 and 34; and</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it would be appropriate to observe May 2025 as <quote>Mental Health Awareness Month</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HDC7DD4BC551B42F6A0C8A564273D9F88"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HC9A3B5C1A498420583DAFC33AF919C6A"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H2C0554A40B4045B1A4D0C9770A6CCAF9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>Mental Health Awareness Month</quote> to remove the stigma associated with mental illness and place emphasis on scientific findings regarding mental health recovery;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9390E33A40B04BC5A016EC39FB70B215"><enum>(2)</enum><text>declares mental health a national priority;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2FA990A192E49BD9E2B3DF9BAA8F914"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports the expansion of funding for mental health services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE352A47509F49CF85CC64AB67E6B91D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recognizes that mental well-being is equally as important as physical well-being for citizens, communities, schools, businesses, and the economy in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE70FF7999D7451F82194C6F440274A2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>applauds the coalescing of national, State, local, medical, and faith-based organizations in working to promote public awareness of mental health and providing critical information and supports to individuals and families affected by mental illness; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H74C20B3C7C6043159A0A78A26325D91E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>encourages all to draw on Mental Health Awareness Month as an opportunity to promote mental well-being and awareness, ensure access to appropriate coverage and services, and support an overall quality of life for those living with mental illness.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

