<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H22FFF8A1FE9C481F9733DDFE566BDAFB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2729 IH: Carnivals are Real Entertainment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2729</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide nonimmigrant status to mobile entertainment workers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H99A1A06DD9BE49E8A9B90F88067BBD58" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA5AA38B73B674F38B2B421B32DA6C87B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Carnivals are Real Entertainment Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HBF943E75007A4307B1381A9E52BFA231"><enum>2.</enum><header>Mobile entertainment workers</header> <subsection id="HB98888F392CE44D9A3FFC002D83C35F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mobile entertainment workers</header> <paragraph id="H9A3F075279234F5D8BDB81BA14F03B94"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subparagraph (P) of section 101(a)(15) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(P)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8710D6BB43A34F04A3CEA929E686C683"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (iii)(II), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HABFCA2071EE94304BEDDF6BE8126DE12"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (iv) as clause (v);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6629D7E5EDE44C838B4ED8CD43CB495D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in clause (v), as redesignated by subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>clause (i), (ii), or (iii)</quote> and inserting <quote>clause (i), (ii), (iii), or (iv)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA73AA031962B41739CD2CB40FFF43503"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (iii) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HFE5FEDDA0CB245AFBB047E5D9BA2202C" style="OLC"> 
<clause id="H5E1CBD5ECFCE4830B8C61C902F6BAC3A" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>seeks to enter the United States temporarily and solely for the purpose of performing functions that are integral and essential to the operation of a mobile entertainment provider (as set forth in section 214(c)(4)(I)(ii)); or</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F76480A47AA4C8C93907201BFBFBE71"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Admission of mobile entertainment workers</header><text>Paragraph (4) of section 214(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1184">8 U.S.C. 1184(c)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H444BCA93F2014CFCA5060C6BDAE4A88E" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H405A88DC85C543F2B5DCE0BCC5E0D61E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The following shall apply to the admission of any alien under section 101(a)(15)(P)(iv):</text> <clause id="HBCB516B167B9487A97EFEB4C9F53B623"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The mobile entertainment provider shall be subject to the same program requirements that govern the admission of non-immigrants pursuant to section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii)(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)</external-xref> (15)(H)(ii)(b)) as promulgated by the Department of Labor in section 655 of title 20 of the Code of Federal Regulations. </text></clause> 
<clause id="HF58C3071A3374A89B41308103DE25637"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>For purposes of section 101(a)(15)(P)(iv), functions that are integral and essential to the operation of a mobile entertainment provider include transporting, assembly, operation, disassembly, and maintenance of mobile entertainment attractions, structures, and equipment, including rides, games, novelties, and food or beverage concessions, as well as other functions that are common in the mobile entertainment industry and are necessary for the safe and efficient operation of the mobile entertainment provider.</text></clause> <clause id="H5FAC3BC54D0643948ABA1852E0F8AFBB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <quote>mobile entertainment provider</quote> means—</text> 
<subclause id="HD83B673F99BC4E7488FEC5FFB6CE23C5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a carnival or circus that travels around the United States on a temporary or seasonal basis; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA3D94521F0A24E269BC21F73D14E2AF4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a provider of services normally affiliated with a carnival or circus, such as food and game concessions, that travels around the United States on a seasonal or temporary basis to provide services to State, county, and local fairs and festivals, or support events sponsored by not-for-profit organizations for fundraising.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2288D823C029468581C02E9F8934C7CC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of Labor shall separately publish in the Federal Register proposed rules implementing the provisions of this section and the amendments made by this section, and shall finalize such rules not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

