<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCG25443-C42-S9-9VP"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1416 IS: Reduction of Excess Business Holding Accrual Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1416</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for purposes of the tax on private foundation excess business holdings to treat as outstanding any employee-owned stock purchased by a business enterprise pursuant to certain employee stock ownership retirement plans.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H4F254CFABFA54EE7A3F1DEDE5C22D0C9"><section section-type="section-one" id="H07546B1593D542F4BD7B166561BB8660"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reduction of Excess Business Holding Accrual Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HD6D8D72255E44658BC4C6A5A8FAA4D40"><enum>2.</enum><header>Certain purchases of employee-owned stock disregarded for purposes of foundation tax on excess business holdings</header><subsection id="HEE0ACA7F84C54DE4A099AA5BE5D30027"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4943">Section 4943(c)(4)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new clauses:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3EDF5A5BFF1B478BBE07688192DA5E97"><clause id="H19B304136FF441059D2C686077C47455" indent="up1"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (i), subparagraph (D), and paragraph (2), any voting stock which—</text><subclause id="HB8E4764D1A4640629F846AA5746610E1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is not readily tradable on an established securities market,</text></subclause><subclause id="H0F820CC5C0C94F05856536EE374B4DF3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is purchased by the business enterprise on or after January 1, 2020, from an employee stock ownership plan (as defined in section 4975(e)(7)) in which employees of such business enterprise participate, in connection with a distribution from such plan, and</text></subclause><subclause id="HC5D4287CD225492C8D15A725FB2F8F5F"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is held by the business enterprise as treasury stock, cancelled, or retired,</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause" indent="subparagraph">shall be treated as outstanding voting stock, but only to the extent so treating such stock would not result in permitted holdings exceeding 49 percent (determined without regard to this clause). The preceding sentence shall not apply with respect to the purchase of stock from a plan during the 10-year period beginning on the date the plan is established.</continuation-text></clause><clause id="H397AB240BCF54FDAA1C85A4F1C86D61E" indent="up1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Clause (ii) shall not apply with respect to any decrease in the percentage of holdings in a business enterprise by reason of the application of clause (v).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H683D7FBBD2034D0B86CA895FB0EF1FDF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to taxable years ending after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

