<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF6C37C806AB74049AFD011D0D73628FC" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 425 IH: Expressing support for designation of May 16, 2025, as the “National Day of Light”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 425</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250517">May 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for designation of May 16, 2025, as the <quote>National Day of Light</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the National Day of Light is aimed at raising awareness of the vital role of light in our daily lives and its importance to 21st-century technology and innovation;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas for centuries, light-based technologies have provided solutions to worldwide challenges in energy, agriculture, manufacturing, telecommunications, national security, and health;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas optics and photonics is the study of the fundamental properties of light and harnessing them for practical applications;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas light has revolutionized medicine through technologies such as x-ray imaging, laser surgery, and cancer treatments;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas light has transformed communication via the internet, a tool we cannot imagine living without today;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas light has helped us improve transportation safety with sensors in vehicles and advanced infrastructure monitoring;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas light has greatly enhanced the ability of the United States to gather intelligence, defend the Nation, and protect its troops in the field;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas most of what we have observed in the universe is known only through light-based technologies, first from the visible wavelengths observed by Galileo into x-ray, infrared, and radio waves, and even gravitational waves detected by lasers;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas advanced manufacturing is possible due to light-based technologies that can provide custom, precise, and high-added value through means such as additive manufacturing;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas quantum computing, sensing, and communication systems are largely enabled by light-based technologies;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas through the National Quantum Initiative Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/368">Public Law 115–368</external-xref>), the United States is accelerating our investment in quantum information science and the development of commercially available quantum-based technologies, thereby facilitating growth in the economy of the United States and protecting our national security;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas 2025 is the 40-year anniversary of the invention of chirped pulse amplification, a technique used to amplify ultrashort laser pulses that was recognized with the 2018 Nobel Prize in Physics and has become the basis of all modern high-power lasers, enabling revolutionary applications of ultraintense light including LASIK laser eye surgery, cancer treatment, commercial laser materials processing, fundamental physics research, and ultrafast imaging including attosecond science; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas May 16 is already recognized internationally as the Day of Light: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HF39A3219563F47AB9521472098B6B478"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HAE3FF5C603534BE3B5C7F744071C7B3D"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="H3CFD0717B28D4A6A9152D4B72B5D8CB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of a <quote>National Day of Light</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H990BB53828DD4C6692528C5322E66F8C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the continuing importance of the United States as the world leader in light-based science and technologies;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD8F3320437DA4078AABABB7F1A953AAC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of inspiring the next generation of scientists, researchers, innovators, technicians, and entrepreneurs; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E5E10167FCA4AD88D7AB1BED0A647C5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages schools, community colleges, and universities to observe the day with appropriate activities.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

