<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-AEG25209-C9K-WH-S5J"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1253 IS: College Admissions Accountability Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1253</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250402">April 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish the Office of the Special Inspector General for Unlawful Discrimination in Higher Education within the Department of Education.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H04AA35658F89433EB69CC4E475EFBF2D"><section section-type="section-one" id="H45DFDFE777674A73A5FB44D8215108B1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>College Admissions Accountability Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4156A3B134E6448AB090AB3F5FC74939"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="H8F2522921D064A2CB7818C69EE29AA61"><enum>(1)</enum><text>21st century elite college admissions functions as the Nation’s sorting machine for prestige and opportunity, allocating a limited number of valuable credentials.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA66468A7B2AD450B8912CA4E616DD4F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For decades United States colleges and universities adopted admissions and policies practices that rendered special preferences to applicants on the basis of race.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEED8BFCC09374E22AF74DF3BAA5B53A4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In Students for Fair Admissions, Inc. v. President and Fellows of Harvard College, 143 S. Ct. 2141 (2023), the Supreme Court of the United States found race-based admissions policies to be in violation of the Equal Protection Clause of the 14th Amendment to the Constitution of the United States. The Court further held that <quote>universities may not simply establish through application essays or other means the regime we hold unlawful today</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a8ae21312574987aaf202952c644771"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>) prohibits entities that receive Federal funding from discriminating based on race.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDCEEFBD9FAD4665B0486BADF4585C72"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Following the Court’s ruling in Students for Fair Admissions, Inc. v. President and Fellows of Harvard College, several United States colleges and universities issued statements or unveiled new policies at odds with the letter and spirit of that ruling.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4EBA447EAF3481EB9BD3087CF0F866C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Institutions of higher education, including their offices of admission, must comply with the Constitution and laws of the United States, as interpreted by the judiciary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36EF4709D4B24DD7944565F84FAD17DC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>It is the duty of the United States Government to protect the civil rights of its citizens and to enforce the Constitution and laws of the United States, as interpreted by the judiciary.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H6D0EC2AE219647AA8826EE3DD08FC681"><enum>3.</enum><header>Special Inspector General for Unlawful Discrimination in Higher Education</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFB93023CE297407CBDF2962B831A1638"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title II of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3411">20 U.S.C. 3411 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0F5FCE5CCC042A1AD942F04E5E5BFA6"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="HF55016B8D5854F94AC4E88CED50249BD"><enum>221.</enum><header>Special Inspector General for Unlawful Discrimination in Higher Education</header><subsection id="H625A08C022E949D2A767CF5A685BC698"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H5D321C7EDA784063AFD1F6F75E17BB8A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H568CDE5CBF0943CAB0EBAB70AA73D511"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD59406395BA4384B779D9795C075ED4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Subcommittee on Labor, Health and Human Services, Education, and Related Agencies of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A630B3D50BF45DAB650D3029D20705B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD465CDF370864E9D9EA46A37966FBF90"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Subcommittee on Labor, Health and Human Services, Education, and Related Agencies of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H189E96F493C34501800E43AC990CED0E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered individual</header><text>The term <term>covered individual</term> means any individual who—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C6002E6F3EA41978810267CBE6E73E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">files an application for admission as a student at a covered institution; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H020BA8F22BF24EF39E6FFD53C35961E0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is enrolled as a student at a covered institution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H22DA95AA7A5947F8A384223EF896B332"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered institution</header><text>The term <term>covered institution</term> means an institution of higher education that receives funds from Federal student assistance or Federal institutional aid under the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H110FB87590B64B7DA6D5494B327FC2C5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Office of Inspector General</header><text>There is hereby established within the Department the Office of the Special Inspector General for Unlawful Discrimination in Higher Education.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDA2EDFD7F89A460392ADD9CE30B98B96"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appointment of Inspector General; removal; basic pay</header><paragraph id="HDD352FCBC32A4B278E6F2BF9C3B38B2D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of the Office of the Special Inspector General for Unlawful Discrimination in Higher Education shall be the Special Inspector General for Unlawful Discrimination in Higher Education (referred to in this section as the <quote>Special Inspector General</quote>), who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H23EDF353A54C42A4A5C07478128B55DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nomination</header><text>The nomination of the Special Inspector General shall be made on the basis of integrity and demonstrated familiarity with higher education and admissions, in addition to expertise in auditing, civil rights, law, academic administration, education regulation, or investigations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA83AC882EF9C427F99406FA424231DE8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Removal</header><text>The Special Inspector General shall be removable from office in accordance with the provisions of section 403(b) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18B9C2C63B9141DE9893933726138C87"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Basic pay</header><text>The annual rate of basic pay of the Special Inspector General shall be the annual rate of basic pay for an Inspector General under section 403(e) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4164AF4AE2C8483D98A49824919FEDA6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header><paragraph id="H7E78709EEF4E4211A30EDFACF321FFEF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It shall be the duty of the Special Inspector General to, in accordance with section 404(b)(1) of title 5, United States Code—</text><subparagraph id="HE101E2292B8A4475B5AC9FCE4A04FF86"><enum>(A)</enum><text>receive, review, and investigate allegations from covered individuals or employees of covered institutions of admissions decisions, policies, or practices, or financial aid determinations or academic programs, that are in violation of—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4755872D2794F62B0F88772410EB89A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Equal Protection Clause of the 14th Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, pursuant to the holding in Students for Fair Admissions, Inc. v. President and Fellows of Harvard College, 143 S. Ct. 2141 (2023) (referred to in this subsection as the <term>Equal Protection Clause</term>); or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC826CCB5561948838A61F2D9746AEA1F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>) (referred to in this subsection as <term>title VI</term>); </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H094DE1C21623440598AD7C9D938E6AD0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review any Federal policies and programs that have the effect of incentivizing covered institutions to violate the Equal Protection Clause or title VI; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6E5B695188649D1AA382F5815903A8E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>make recommendations to the applicable covered institution, the Secretary, the Attorney General of the United States, and the appropriate committees of Congress regarding—</text><clause id="H1032DD7280A64397833699DE2FF7E374"><enum>(i)</enum><text>measures that the covered institution should take to remedy any violation described in subparagraph (A) through remedial or corrective action;</text></clause><clause id="H5EEE69321C45420B8B4F2F3F3732B5AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any employee of the covered institution that the Special Inspector General determines, after a review or investigation described in subparagraph (A), should face disciplinary action (including removal) as a result of a violation described in such subparagraph;</text></clause><clause id="H39BDD47D7D2942348DD36A0007AA3835"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>eligibility of the covered institution to receive funds from Federal student assistance or Federal institutional aid; </text></clause><clause id="H8000452AA0044DD59F69D4A9A33ECC85"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>further investigation into the covered institution’s compliance with the Constitution of the United States, title VI, and other laws of the United States; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10BF9E19A6394BF7B04A52DB44E8D107"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reforms to any Federal policies and programs that have the effect of incentivizing covered institutions to violate the Equal Protection Clause or title VI.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAECBEEC7252D419488D074FC813A2C5F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maintenance of systems</header><text>The Special Inspector General shall establish, maintain, and oversee such systems, procedures, and controls as the Special Inspector General considers appropriate to discharge the duties of the Special Inspector General under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H894F04248DA24D3E8FF74AC31F26E6D3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional duties and responsibilities</header><text>In addition to the duties described in paragraphs (1) and (2), the Special Inspector General shall also have the duties and responsibilities of inspectors general under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/4">chapter 4</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7D3D9F2670649A7A462DEC21EFE766C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Confidentiality of information</header><text>The Special Inspector General shall maintain the confidentiality of the identity of any person submitting information to the Special Inspector General for the purposes of carrying out the duties of the Special Inspector General under this section, including in any report submitted under subsection (g).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H93F51C80F74E469E8D2F587D695FB2EE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Powers and authorities</header><paragraph id="H51836BF4535144288142B252BD2311B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the duties of the Special Inspector General under subsection (d), the Special Inspector General shall have the authorities provided in section 406 of title 5, United States Code. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E6101AD93DF44CD811D4509F7BCC557"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of office</header><text>The Office of the Special Inspector General shall be considered to be an office described in section 406(f)(3) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6F10210469984625A800092DD033764D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Personnel, facilities, and other resources</header><paragraph id="HABBB0D619DAD43AFBCD57E6B964323B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointment of officers and employees</header><subparagraph id="H0FEF2DF7630D44AA8F4C344CECA4162B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Special Inspector General may select, appoint, and employ such officers and employees as may be necessary for carrying out the duties of the Special Inspector General.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D08EFCBC3E242058634B8F907D61B22"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Status</header><text>The positions to which officers and employees are appointed under subparagraph (A) shall be positions in schedule C of subpart C of part 213 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2C936C1486845B4945BCC79FE479813"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Experts and consultants</header><text>The Special Inspector General may obtain services as authorized under section 3109 of title 5, United States Code, at daily rates not to exceed the equivalent rate prescribed for grade GS–15 of the General Schedule by section 5332 of that title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H123453F9C0644C70A72103FF7C72D3FC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contracts</header><text>The Special Inspector General may enter into contracts and other arrangements for audits, studies, analyses, and other services with public agencies and with private persons, and make such payments as may be necessary to carry out the duties of the Special Inspector General.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E960663FC174E08BCEC27BD6B5CD21F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H7AA42A54883340AE8471F6D607802719"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Quarterly reports</header><subparagraph id="H280EFF09FD8940EBA4D98904564B1AC9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the Special Inspector General is confirmed, and once every calendar quarter thereafter, the Special Inspector General shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report summarizing the activities of the Special Inspector General during the 3-month period ending on the date on which the Special Inspector General submits the report.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD71C5AB304984E9E88E479869A94F103"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall include, for the period covered by the report, the following:</text><clause id="H239AC881BFA949C2A0B569C105626CFD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A general description of the allegations received and reviewed by the Special Inspector General under subsection (d)(1)(A).</text></clause><clause id="H27FA3A359D294A6AAFB1EDDDA00AADCF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Recommendations of the Special Inspector General regarding reforms that the Special Inspector General believes should be undertaken with respect to the authority of the Special Inspector General and matters within the authority of the Special Inspector General to review and investigate, including the authority described in subsection (d)(1)(B).</text></clause><clause id="HB193590E48EB4E19AE790B51B7AACE12"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>For a covered institution with respect to which an allegation submitted under this section applies, the steps that the covered institution has taken, and has yet to take, to remedy the issues outlined in the allegation.</text></clause><clause id="HC0F61FFB543141DEA74A25CADF449B8D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Data regarding the number of allegations received and reviewed by the Special Inspector General under this section that document any legitimate violation, as determined by the Special Inspector General, which shall—</text><subclause id="H3D8150AE6637493A9E77413209FBCE78"><enum>(I)</enum><text>be disaggregated by the number of violations committed by each covered institution; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HAD54262C345345AC9147BF9934BE96DD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>contain a separate provision listing the number of those acts that relate to racial bias, which shall be disaggregated as described in subclause (I).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HA5557982FF694ED0AB505F21330BBBB9"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Commentary by the Special Inspector General regarding the level of cooperation by each covered institution with respect to reviews and investigations performed by the Special Inspector General, including, with respect to each covered institution, whether the covered institution has implemented recommendations made by the Special Inspector General and whether the covered institution has provided information or access requested by the Special Inspector General.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H24D4463BB9054FF9A1BD2CE45CB4C4D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to authorize the public disclosure of information that is—</text><subparagraph id="H810601418164499BB89FE322906A0865"><enum>(A)</enum><text>specifically prohibited from disclosure by any other provision of law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5A768D5A6F54EF8A84EFB4F400036B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specifically required by Executive order to be protected from disclosure in the interest of national defense or national security or in the conduct of foreign affairs; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CA63338C3554DC8B78677198228E996"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a part of an ongoing criminal investigation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9EC5B7FCF55C472CA507BFEE9C47D8CA"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated $25,000,000 to carry out this section, which shall remain available until expended.</text></subsection><subsection id="H55F2E6D18EA14656A52B5C2A3873142C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency</header><text>The Special Inspector General shall be a member of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency established under section 424 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB8D697C24FDC46D78B431827A94293F6"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Corrective responses to audit problems</header><text>A covered institution shall—</text><paragraph id="HB123D4D0EC3E4468A3DCC1DA454F3B69"><enum>(1)</enum><text>take action to address deficiencies identified by a report or investigation of the Special Inspector General; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C030FBFBC434A7A9923E706378BBCF8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to a deficiency identified under paragraph (1), certify to the Special Inspector General and the appropriate committees of Congress that no action is necessary or appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H98755F8EF33F4C4AB6E9747EE157AFD8"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed as limiting the authority of the Inspector General of the Department.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE59A3C80BF9D4CEF9EACC1CC18EBB1FF"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office of the Special Inspector General for Unlawful Discrimination in Higher Education, established under this section, shall terminate on the date that is 12 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>College Admissions Accountability Act of 2025</short-title>.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A01F43DA76B4D6DB9FD092F7047C0BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents in section 1 of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3401">20 U.S.C. 3401</external-xref> note) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 220 the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFB04C27162BD4B95A9DBB6440C7AEB1A"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 221. Special Inspector General for Unlawful Discrimination in Higher Education.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H18A430839CF74797A3EE81E88C69F22B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Higher Education Act of 1965</header><text>Part B of title I of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1011">20 U.S.C. 1011 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C9514F48B184C5CA630A632C4DBF1B3"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7CE1D14317749DEB00B1075F61318BD"><enum>124.</enum><header>Ineligibility due to discrimination on the basis of race in violation of Equal Protection Clause or title VI</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no institution of higher education shall be eligible to receive funds from Federal student assistance or Federal institutional aid under this Act if the Secretary determines that the institution had an admissions decision, policy, or practice, or financial aid determination or academic program, that discriminated on the basis of race in violation of—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7B741D973BC4EB2A2707458AB161B50"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Equal Protection Clause of the 14th Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, pursuant to the holding in Students for Fair Admissions, Inc. v. President and Fellows of Harvard College, 143 S. Ct. 2141 (2023); or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6598A02820D94CAB9F65A2FC4354A616"><enum>(2)</enum><text>title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

