<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8F3B81B8A60E4D2290DED68E76C25512" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 67 IH: Modernizing Retrospective Regulatory Review</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 67</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250103">January 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve retrospective reviews of Federal regulations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3D98A09B1FD343898349CA07C1994BC9" style="OLC"><section id="H69B2480F279E4BA0A87CF16F55F327C4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Modernizing Retrospective Regulatory Review</short-title> Act</quote>.</text></section><section id="H4958721407B14041901FB756F32AB40F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improving retrospective reviews of existing Federal regulations</header><subsection id="HCAD9F2AA5F544AD6AC0F7185782FFE56"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report on availability of existing regulations in machine-Readable format</header><paragraph id="H8B81CC8075614400987E8C1608CA6E19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, acting through the Administrator and in consultation with the Director of GPO, the Archivist, and the Director of the Federal Register, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees, a report on the progress of the Federal Government in making regulations of agencies available in machine-readable format.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14AE30AF295640B1ABA32C201419EBA1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of report</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HB891909848C941B8A258DAB6CD2EA36F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of whether regulations of agencies have been made available in a machine-readable format to the public; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H663982FA0B80491C8E51D18F005A468F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information regarding the recognition by the Administrative Committee of the Federal Register of the eCFR maintained by the Director of the Federal Register and the Director of GPO as an official legal edition of the Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB92857017BD4420EBA708AF7758EBC02"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance on using technology To conduct retrospective reviews</header><paragraph id="HBAD9BCE5976B4CA6A4C1CE88310A3303"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, acting through the Administrator, shall issue guidance on how the head of the agency can—</text><subparagraph id="HFCCAF3FCB944400EAE9E69F5FE9E8C12"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify, procure, and use technology (including algorithmic tools and artificial intelligence) to more efficiently, cost-effectively, and accurately conduct any retrospective review of the existing regulations of the agency, including to more efficiently, cost-effectively, and accurately identify through any such review regulations of the agency that—</text><clause id="H44C72ADDC0A14CBCA084B0F187141630"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are obsolete, ineffective, insufficient, excessively burdensome, or redundant;</text></clause><clause id="H9AB54DDCAD0341F7B34635B58F1E2D08"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>should be improved;</text></clause><clause id="HCF843FF689114E9FA6A74EF6C5A99D94"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>contain typographic errors;</text></clause><clause id="H02E43F3169064882B12EA0D57D9A2D65"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>contain inaccurate cross-references; or</text></clause><clause id="HF93FAEE4DC534FD88AB2AC981A5C3403"><enum>(v)</enum><text>contradict or overlap with each other, or any standards of the agency; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5461605E1AB8487B9853B44A1CB7400C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>adequately train personnel of the agency on how to use such technology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H37803A98E23E42AFABBEDDDAEF325DBF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Development of guidance</header><text>In developing the guidance required pursuant to paragraph (1), the Administrator shall take into account any assessment or information included in the report required by subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H52769A22FB5E4E6ABCC9B1A6765603AF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Agency retrospective review plan</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of each agency shall submit to the Administrator and the appropriate congressional committees a plan that—</text><paragraph id="HA3BAD0ADCF38451C89F9ECD24F0544E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes a detailed strategy for implementing the guidance issued pursuant to subsection (b) with respect to the regulations of the agency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5687D4E27D494AF08B66D9A791BAF9F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies any regulation of the agency, or categories of regulations of the agency, that the head of the agency—</text><subparagraph id="HB23C73A98B0840E1B0CB9233700B1C26"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is required by law to review after the applicable regulation is issued; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC11E41A637C045679B6483E8C19183E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determines would benefit from being reviewed after the regulation is issued; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD37F4D4E46574E7BBB123A8DCAD45C46"><enum>(3)</enum><text>includes any additional information, data, or ex-post analysis determined necessary or useful by the head of the agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD37DE1F089864F4D9988E219D5531A4A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Agency implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the head of an agency submits the plan required by subsection (c), the head of the agency shall implement the strategy included in such plan with respect to any retrospective review of an existing regulation of the agency. </text></subsection><subsection id="H1CDF1002CE034468A1719E838665AFBF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H88FD3B8E0FED4E60A519BBD82643690A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrative Committee of the Federal Register</header><text>The term <term>Administrative Committee of the Federal Register</term> means the Committee established under section 1506 of title 44, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BC0CCFE07A04BE496D669C23404D5CB" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA4BDF494AA34B3BA67F3544CB9C5113"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3502 of title 44, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FE0389E6C494966BD48AD1C472AB491"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H4DD4FE0C2A4849988CC1A5A29FE0F848"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3A19F95D2A84E729C39E448E395643B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H46F2C3ABE30E49AFADBEDA7ECFDEB18E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Director of GPO</header><text>The term <term>Director of GPO</term> means the Director of the Government Publishing Office. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H161CA8BFF9E0471EAC87C19E1B3E2CD7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Machine-readable</header><text>The term <term>machine-readable</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3502 of title 44, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H640FF79328F44E708495130467FD59FB"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Retrospective review of an existing regulation of the agency</header><text>The term <term>retrospective review of an existing regulation of the agency</term> means a review of a regulation of the agency conducted after the regulation has been issued, including any such review required by law or determined appropriate by the head of the agency.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

