<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6C29A4C1A0AB4682ADA744CFEF545480" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4464 IH: Preventive Health Savings Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4464</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250716">July 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">Committee on the Budget</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 respecting the scoring of preventive health savings.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H65FFED21D3CB4261A49E5DF4595001AE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9D0FDE68B8D14A12836CB55BADDB3B15" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventive Health Savings Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H01F84B216498498491583A9A6CFD2F49"><enum>2.</enum><header>Scoring of preventive health savings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 202 of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/602">2 U.S.C. 602</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H09AFC4A315DD4546B0D424BA29394EE0" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H76693DA6606E4548B1ED31185B7F13D4"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Scoring of preventive health savings</header> 
<paragraph id="HD423A5E531014EC7AD75FAE69784D33B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination by the director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon a request by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on the Budget of the Senate and chairman and ranking minority member of the committee of primary jurisdiction of the Senate or by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives and the chairman and ranking minority member of the committee of primary jurisdiction of the House of Representatives, the Director shall determine if proposed legislation would result in net reductions in budget outlays in budgetary outyears through the use of preventive health care.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFDE047D93EA5464E9C0C34567B84D0AF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Projections</header><text>If the Director determines that proposed legislation would result in net reductions in budget outlays as described in paragraph (1), the Director—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H82B4CE5AC0E6418FB49AAA8066331434"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall include, in any projection prepared by the Director on such proposed legislation, a description and estimate of the reductions in budget outlays in the budgetary outyears and a description of the basis for such conclusions; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAE065EE1B973485B8CA346F7F91A7619"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may prepare a budget projection that includes some or all of the budgetary outyears, notwithstanding the time periods for projections described in subsection (e) and sections 308, 402, and 424.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCB7F81E607554B43ADD4AF4121E5C856"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any estimate provided by the Director pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be used as a supplementary estimate and may not be used to determine compliance with the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 or any other budgetary enforcement controls.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H970A031B022248FD8CF9CA08EB44CC73"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>As used in this subsection—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H49D2B17D7352477B9B8495161163F70A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>budgetary outyears</term> means the 2 consecutive 10-year periods beginning with the first fiscal year that is 10 years after the current fiscal year; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4780A9F173D343379657DB10D785D970"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>preventive health care</term> means an action that focuses on the health of the public, individuals, and defined populations in order to protect, promote, and maintain health and wellness and prevent disease, disability, and premature death, including through the promotion and use of effective, innovative health care interventions that are demonstrated by credible and publicly available evidence from epidemiological projection models, clinical trials, observational studies in humans, longitudinal studies, and meta-analysis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

