<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3C83F83273164764B98AA510B564BEA3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2324 IH: Unity through Service Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2324</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250325">March 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish an Interagency Council on Service to promote and strengthen opportunities for military service, national service, and public service for all people of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7FDFC79844E14CC7BCDE3FECDF950828" style="OLC"><section id="HA6DEE59ECAE24E0780467B074C9EC241" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Unity through Service Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1BCD421B25D64BDE9F468A048110228F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Interagency council on service</header><subsection id="H97961F78DE4F4856A12DFEB3AC1E7BF4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph id="H887AAF566BF7462DB163C6A3D7F3C1D1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established an Interagency Council on Service (in this section referred to as the <quote>Council</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8104AD7F3B34461A93D67E7A53949EC1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The Council shall—</text><subparagraph id="HF8F57BCFBD2C4DC8870973EC8AF81DD6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advise the President with respect to promoting, strengthening, and expanding opportunities for military service, national service, and public service for all people of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC150CC9342494808890804E354B267ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>review, assess, and coordinate holistic recruitment strategies and initiatives of the executive branch to foster an increased sense of service and civic responsibility among all people of the United States and to explore ways of enhancing connectivity of interested applicants to national service programs and opportunities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB17170775A1F4F4EA6004EDCA339E65A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Composition</header><paragraph id="HBC253F83B8994746A65626BFEB0FAB60"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Council shall be composed of members who are representatives of—</text><subparagraph id="HF5A1CEB44277490589D0F0716DF1C819"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AA0F79EE9134D30BB0C49D78A56DB03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Defense;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H110EB445BEA74C99AF9882579D8E2FAC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Attorney General;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1F6C2D6093F42239C7BA1D8E07C0152"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D96296945F74850847BAFB0CEA54EC6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Secretary of Commerce;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DF5E226B719413786C46AC133DB6646"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Secretary of Labor;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2348DA6B2BC24357BF177AF962BB99F7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Secretary of Health and Human Services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C17FAD22B4542019E5C50A9F76F3F08"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Secretary of Education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H172868CB118048D985307A6AD3E117D1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Secretary of Veterans Affairs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C358018C5A64207A047DE568FB05E16"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the Secretary of Homeland Security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0365F8A98CAF45689D87FA8ECBE2DFA2"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the Director of the Office of Management and Budget;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H950711DBD2A442F58380FE9EE0FF6FA3"><enum>(L)</enum><text>the Director of National Intelligence;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H523FA3C40EAD4CF6839D247E97B207AC"><enum>(M)</enum><text>the Director of the Office of Personnel Management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2332C5202E3B4145B4EB3BE7DC545652"><enum>(N)</enum><text>the Director of the Peace Corps;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8FAFF30DBC442D6BBA8CC9A1C9F82C3"><enum>(O)</enum><text>the Director of Selective Service System;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20A2B520995A495ABECF4DFC6DB20358"><enum>(P)</enum><text>the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3234A83146B24820B740A5A8EA20CC9A"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>such other officers as the President may designate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A53D1DCC04E42D9A31919F05FAE40FC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The President shall annually designate to serve as the Chair of the Council a member of the Council under paragraph (1), the appointment of whom as an officer or employee of the Federal Government was made by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB5472AAFA1B4B06BA82B71ED2410520"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Council shall meet on a quarterly basis or more frequently as the Chair of the Council may direct.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5222B3D8F29D4766881D18D23C99F8FE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibilities of the council</header><text>The Council shall—</text><paragraph id="H1490260E754F4D079F3E4D427F86B9D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assist and advise the President in the establishment of strategies, goals, objectives, and priorities to promote service and civic responsibility among all people of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C26E9505DD9422B9F8E76A1408C0B31"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop and recommend to the President common recruitment strategies and outreach opportunities for increasing the participation, and propensity of people of the United States to participate, in military service, national service, and public service in order to address national security and domestic investment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC07AD52852443E5AC8DA9ACFBF29DE4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>serve as a forum for Federal officials responsible for military service, national service, and public service programs to, as feasible and practicable—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD32247F2DDE5404DA313242F056F5475"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate and share best practices for service recruitment; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBCC36169D6C14B77825CBE769E0513AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop common interagency, cross-service initiatives and pilots for service recruitment;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA75D115C07EB404A926105242B55ED9E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>lead a strategic, interagency coordinated effort on behalf of the Federal Government to develop joint awareness and recruitment, retention, and marketing initiatives involving military service, national service, and public service;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF8A6A568D7F4D54B5791B5122243480"><enum>(5)</enum><text>consider approaches for assessing impacts of service on the needs of the United States and individuals participating in and benefitting from such service;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H374E13A116CA40D5981117B56BF8C5A5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>consult, as the Council considers advisable, with representatives of non-Federal entities, including State, local, and Tribal governments, State and local educational agencies, State Service Commissions, institutions of higher education, nonprofit organizations, faith-based organizations, philanthropic organizations, and the private sector, in order to promote and develop initiatives to foster and reward military service, national service, and public service;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06A816C068844F2EA52ED3399BBC864C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and quadrennially thereafter, prepare and submit to the President and Congress a Service Strategy, which shall set forth—</text><subparagraph id="HD736DE33DB3D4205A7AB19AD6E099133"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a review of programs and initiatives of the Federal Government relating to the mandate of the Council;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD512EDBC4E04D58B4430CFD6938CB57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a review of Federal Government online content relating to the mandate of the Council, including user experience with such content;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE70D929760D44C77AEB1DE0D3C659A91"><enum>(C)</enum><text>current and foreseeable trends for service to address the needs of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H903857A52C554550B1C72127310FA288"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommended service recruitment strategies and branding opportunities to address outreach and communication deficiencies identified by the Council; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H946AAD8645024D17AFF9E0EE487B29E3"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent practical, a joint service messaging strategy for military service, national service, and public service;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H911D996F7F084AA5B1DA08B514E82BFD"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify any notable initiatives by State, local, and Tribal governments and by public and nongovernmental entities to increase awareness of and participation in national service programs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H62387458481B42DBAAF603C2B8F5282A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>perform such other functions as the President may direct.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9B5A7B49CD8E4BF983ED450C538F9650"><enum>3.</enum><header>Joint market research to advance military and national service</header><subsection id="H6AAA8AA7C5014B538D40F185CCE9E0C2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service, and the Director of the Peace Corps may carry out a joint market research, market studies, recruiting, and advertising program to complement the existing programs of the military departments, the national service programs administered by the Corporation, and the Peace Corps.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD3E4CF79E6A249CEAA1FA5AFAFE4A0FB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information sharing permitted</header><text>Section 503 of title 10, United States Code, shall not be construed to prohibit sharing of information among, or joint marketing efforts of, the Department of Defense, the Corporation for National and Community Service, and the Peace Corps to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H869E884581C44E08B17DA1121BFB59E8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Transition opportunities for military servicemembers and national service participants</header><subsection id="HEAE89D8B26AB4E8EB2585A2B6ED887B1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Employment assistance</header><text>Section 1143(c)(1) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>the Corporation for National and Community Service,</quote> after <quote>State employment agencies,</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H765C099A35E842A4965B7498323F3D77"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Employment assistance, job training assistance, and other transitional services: Department of Labor</header><text>Section 1144 of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H0F3C146BA88A4F5A8017906DDD6A6271"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD019B88A2C89443EA8B0AF1418CB9E3E"><paragraph id="H5DDE97A69336442C97423E1547EF365E"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Provide information on public service opportunities, training on public service job recruiting, and the advantages of careers with the Federal Government.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C94AF75ED844AEE9302EF24E6ED0CA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (f)(1)(D)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE761D936248D418A8E5D406AA42B82CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating clause (v) as clause (vi); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9828DC454954AD589CFB96659F329E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (iv) the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H751D842B198F427C989A89D2F446F849" act-name=""><clause indent="up1" id="H2D81A1C840824601AA3CA1213CB811C0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>National and community service, taught in conjunction with the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB9543530C5C84005BA27476D6D4D9C83"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorities and duties of the chief executive officer</header><text>Section 193A(b) of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12651d">42 U.S.C. 12651d(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H67BE3337348A415C93EB8CAB8AB2AB0D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (24), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAECFEBEA475D4FE9BF7C9CF14BB85F03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (25), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D2F43935D1347208929A8F5E95D0113"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0CA1C071C7841DCB71DC0D4566A8ECB"><paragraph id="H4BA89920F9304CAC917C900B0E957748"><enum>(26)</enum><text>ensure that individuals completing a partial or full term of service in a program under subtitle C or E or part A of title I of the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4951">42 U.S.C. 4951 et seq.</external-xref>) receive information about military and public service opportunities for which they may qualify or in which they may be interested.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE8F832B035134D659B1470460D7C4761"><enum>5.</enum><header>Joint report to congress on initiatives to integrate military and national service</header><subsection id="HC5BA44FD27724D578A2BCF041CDE25A9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act and quadrennially thereafter, the Chair of the Interagency Council on Service, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service, and the Director of the Peace Corps, shall submit a joint report on cross-service marketing, research, and promotion, including recommendations for increasing joint advertising and recruitment initiatives for the Armed Forces, programs administered by the Corporation for National and Community Service, and the Peace Corps, to the following congressional committees:</text><paragraph id="H1CA3FA9683B04D45BFAD7C2B7D506B6F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2E5125E796F41D7A8D5AEE06D2E7D71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H602D7410A9654EF2A5D03602A5144782"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Committee on Oversight and Accountability of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0C8E6C9B67F43ACBD537C1CF828BC1D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H776291336B2945AC9F5783954DCAB5DF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7457EFA5D4F7463FA41CA8C88EC95997"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DF6CB1751B748918FA6C7B61B106162"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H044F65025F2046E1A2E2CC990A93C8B6"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04BA1306E792433DA76AFB1BB25490DB"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H42F2A18903784C519418890DEAEBBF20"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of report</header><text>Each report under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H13029ACA95314937A6E9A3EE7EF89DBB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of Peace Corps volunteers and participants in national service programs administered by the Corporation for National and Community Service, who previously served as a member of the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFC4622917334E1ABE8E20E2C7119B47"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of members of the Armed Forces who previously served in the Peace Corps or in a program administered by the Corporation for National and Community Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB8A203DA05241D7B16FC1FA0093DBB0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of existing (as of the date of the report submission) joint recruitment and advertising initiatives undertaken by the Department of Defense, the Peace Corps, or the Corporation for National and Community Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F7531A6529D49FF9A0B05C6E16D4C17"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of the feasibility and cost of expanding such existing initiatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9838DC1820E14BCEBAD2BD1414E499D8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An assessment of ways to improve the ability of the reporting agencies to recruit individuals from the other reporting agencies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97AE1AE23EDB4D40A160B9D3837A4A32"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A description of the information and data used to develop any initiative or campaign intended to advance military service or national service, including with respect to any activity carried out under section 3. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA5B4E0AAB8CC4C199E45037B89D938F6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Chair of the Interagency Council on Service, the Secretary of Defense, the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service, and the Director of the Peace Corps shall undertake studies of recruiting efforts that are necessary to carry out the provisions of this section. Such studies may be conducted using any funds appropriated to those entities under Federal law other than this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H7A8190B4B7CC47AA83DDDE661DE6F18C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reports to Congress on lessons learned regarding retention and recruitment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Chair of the Interagency Council on Service shall—</text><paragraph id="HBDB26C8EFA464C8D9E317E1246D794E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a study on—</text><subparagraph id="H398FAC17CE84413AA430008914EC5AB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effectiveness of past advertising campaigns for military service, national service, and public service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7539A5D828D74984A99023B4262828B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the role of vaccine requirements on the retention and recruitment of individuals for military service, national service, and public service; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H650319309038442C8CE1D97C03E9E6CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act, submit a report on the findings of and lessons learned from the study under paragraph (1) to—</text><subparagraph id="H3A66D9C8016E4578B4FB951C610D076F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23E8E9BC141E4DE886F9CCC38743F4E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HAC86BE32A54C472F991A46B76C499107"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HF06CE859EC6D431385BF14419C0F1751"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interagency Council on Service</header><text>The term <term>Interagency Council on Service</term> means the Interagency Council on Service established by section 2(a). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF75E46163CA04EA2ABF221B4DBE1B823"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Military department</header><text>The term <term>military department</term> means each of the military departments listed in section 102 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE87CA501F8B480094B3026072814850"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Military service</header><text>The term <term>military service</term> means active service (as defined in subsection (d)(3) of section 101 of title 10, United States Code) or active status (as defined in subsection (d)(4) of such section) in one of the Armed Forces (as defined in subsection (a)(4) of such section).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF38E067A601F49788ACB749673628E73"><enum>(4)</enum><header>National service</header><text>The term <term>national service</term> means participation, other than military service or public service, in a program that—</text><subparagraph id="H96AF06A0E904462BBFED8E485443C9D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is designed to enhance the common good and meet the needs of communities, the States, or the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80BB6750AB8C4FACA0647430A353F2EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is funded or facilitated by—</text><clause id="H6DF149B9A962499FB79F2853139BF5D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an institution of higher education as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>); or</text></clause><clause id="H7334D8A387A347C0BCBE81D7CA20DCEF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Federal Government or a State, Tribal, or local government; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBFB50989AC6461998F35D7EF1FE5DDA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is a program authorized in—</text><clause id="H62A712698EEF4819AA317EF5BFD46333"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2501">22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="HD6CB531BDF5746BD9B5E851DA7C4AE2F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>section 171 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3226">29 U.S.C. 3226</external-xref>) relating to the YouthBuild Program;</text></clause><clause id="HF4062328CCE8409B9B00E4391F9C9868"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4950">42 U.S.C. 4950 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></clause><clause id="H6539B430B74E45148798F31948797103"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12501">42 U.S.C. 12501 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H59B6DA17A6C04BD48466C6BED2723DB3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Public service</header><text>The term <term>public service</term> means civilian employment in the Federal Government or a State, Tribal, or local government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78D1B1A9C1D04E298A9BB56A9DB74043"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Service</header><text>The term <term>service</term> means a personal commitment of time, energy, and talent to a mission that contributes to the public good by protecting the Nation and the citizens of the United States, strengthening communities, States, or the United States, or promoting the general social welfare.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H622371D2460E446DB4F7FF47C56A4B0E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State service commission</header><text>The term <term>State Service Commission</term> means a State Commission on National and Community Service maintained by a State pursuant to section 178 of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12638">42 U.S.C. 12638</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></section><section id="HEBCA16EBB3F542BE8B638B7B34482EA5"><enum>8.</enum><header>No additional funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of carrying out this Act.</text></section><section id="H96D970EC08A1449E83B964CCCBE8519C"><enum>9.</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall report to Congress on the effectiveness of this Act and the amendments made by this Act. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

