<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA157AE5A4A64479E955E41D63B63BB0D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3102 IH: To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish an Office of Rural Health, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3102</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250430">April 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000600">Ms. Perez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish an Office of Rural Health, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H962D75BCA47E42B781AC790491A0C42D" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H00D7D36998394D5382E238285985595C"><enum>1.</enum><header>CDC Office of Rural Health</header>
<subsection id="H8B1B80526B0147698D891B836B381E4B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall establish within the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention an office to be known as the Office of Rural Health, to be headed by a director selected by the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H330DE8EBC6A548D7A99DA11EA44E53AA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties and authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The duties and authorities of the Director of the Office of Rural Health shall be limited to the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HA5DB682AFC23411C90343380A02FE6AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Serving as the primary point of contact in the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention on matters pertaining to rural health.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBDE7151F2A5446F8593103B941BB077"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assisting the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in conducting, coordinating, and promoting research regarding public health issues affecting rural populations, and in disseminating the results of such research.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HADECFD53476E4DBEBA081DF12A2AFE94"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Working with all personnel and offices of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to develop, refine, coordinate, and promulgate policies, best practices, lessons learned, and innovative, successful programs to improve care and services (including through telehealth) for rural populations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD18E9AF1A5BB4B918D4ECE7A70409835"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Coordinating and supporting rural health research, conducting and supporting educational outreach, and disseminating evidence-based interventions related to health outcomes, access to health care, and lifestyle challenges, to prevent death, disease, injury, and disability, and promote healthy behaviors in rural populations.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB5D2A0C8C640483082EAAEA3964D71E3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Improving the understanding of the health challenges faced by rural populations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H59A157896A3C40C38170E47122F1676C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Identifying disparities in the availability of health care and public health interventions for rural populations.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7D38332F05CA4FFB85D6A14610298F2D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Awarding and administering grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts to provide technical assistance and other activities as necessary to support activities related to improving health and health care in rural areas.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H15C0110D3FDB40E4ACFAF31CA936EFEC"> <enum>(8)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Coordinating with the Federal Office of Rural Health Policy of the Health Resources and Services Administration, as needed, to facilitate co-operation on rural health initiatives and avoid duplication of efforts.</text>
        </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

