<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEC22F3531B5E454D87B30065C5C7371F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3787 IH: Emergency Spending Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3787</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250605">June 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001188">Mr. Stutzman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001229">Mr. Shreve</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">Committee on the Budget</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to offset emergency spending, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9F4A7A3401EA4BA89F046ED057B09EF9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCAAC2AD4037343A2A60BEFFD069BD829" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Emergency Spending Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H67CC00874D5C4FA8A29014914443CC7E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sequestration to offset emergency spending</header> 
<subsection id="H8DE7389ADF1C410BB1B8A207F2C33AC1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sequestration</header> 
<paragraph id="H6ECA4CED3FAD4BFDAD2478489FAFA800" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to any direct spending or discretionary spending that is appropriated or otherwise made available during a fiscal year that is emergency spending, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall, on October 1 of the subsequent fiscal year and each of the 4 following fiscal years, issue a sequestration order that reduces total budgetary resources such that outlay savings equal one-fifth of the total amount of such emergency spending.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6128845F0A3E4AF8B4FCCBB27666547D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>The Director shall submit written notice to Congress on the date of any sequestration order under paragraph (1). Such notice shall include a list of any account affected by such order.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9061DCFF391C43B99405FB327A445752"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Discretionary and direct spending application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If emergency spending made available during a fiscal year is discretionary spending, any sequestration under subsection (a) with respect to such emergency spending may only be made with respect to discretionary accounts. If emergency spending made available during a fiscal year is direct spending, any sequestration required under subsection (a) with respect to such emergency spending may only be made to direct spending accounts.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA684B312CB144C8595ED78E23B99D2EF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any sequestration under subsection (a)—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDF87F1B2493A47449E439847D317E7C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>except as provided in subsection (c), and notwithstanding any other provision of law, no account is exempted from reduction;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1E69A0875FD04FD0A1F8BBF24BCE0489"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such reduction shall be at a uniform rate across all programs and activities that are subject to sequestration; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H255FC6829AD546F6ABD957AFA2430A8C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount of the sequestration shall be reduced by the amount of any offsetting reduction in discretionary spending or direct spending (as the case may be) in the measure enacted into law that provided the applicable emergency spending.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF5A9293C36C441FCBC146C95531F0273"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exempt programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following programs and accounts shall be exempt from sequestration under this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H36421790721F4E24B97AA7F59324FE8D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Benefits payable under the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program established under title II of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/401">42 U.S.C. 401 et seq.</external-xref>), and benefits payable under sections 3 and 4 of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/231">45 U.S.C. 231 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H03307B679B5240A8BB84044D279B2045"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any account within budget function 050 (National Defense).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A88A64C2455421DB565E7336F253B34"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All programs administered by the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85EBF9FCEFC247B98F559C323DD8164B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB0110E4B9BE149CFB28B1BEA5714EA6F" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirement for measures containing emergency spending</header> 
<paragraph id="H003DF801C21249518E464562C6EE68DB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reported measures</header><text>With respect to any bill or joint resolution favorably reported by any standing committee of Congress that includes emergency spending, the report accompanying such measure shall include a detailed justification of why each instance of such spending is necessary.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H45ADE717CC0A4ED5BF7955E519F0EE13"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other measures</header><text>Any measure considered by the House of Representatives not described in paragraph (1) that includes emergency spending shall include such a detailed explanation, to be published in the Congressional Record prior to consideration.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1D1CCFA17DE546139CCE22C6BD3A1444"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Any justification under paragraph (1) or (2) shall include reasons why such spending meets the definitions of the terms <term>emergency</term> and <term>unanticipated</term> (as those terms are defined in section 250(c) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8B6B2DC065AC447EBC71EBAC5A4B4537"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2AC584C871E54C519F28194DA87CCFE2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the terms <term>budget authority</term> and <term>outlays</term> have the meaning given those terms in section 3 of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B7D82ACF4BA4ACEB479D73BA018EB9E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the terms <term>budgetary resources</term>, <term>discretionary spending</term>, <term>direct spending</term>, and <term>sequestration</term> have the meaning given those terms in section 250(c) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF2C877F6DC564422B88654F63F879FE8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>emergency spending</term> means any budget authority—</text> <subparagraph id="H083CC927E36C4311AE5FF0E739CB3D59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is designated—</text> 
<clause id="H51E84B747BF6427A88780BF4DE8FA9BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under section 251(b)(2)(A), (D), or (F) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985;</text></clause> <clause id="H1C2E841C20174FD7BB8438C8D5E73F17"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>under section 4(g) of the Statutory-Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAA8FCC9E242C4251AA8A540DBBC60B07"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>under a concurrent resolution on the budget as being for an emergency; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6DC867E0A52644DBA286A9A9B8A44AFF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is otherwise exempted from counting against any Federal spending limitation, including the discretionary spending limits in section 251(c) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 or the PAYGO scorecards.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

