<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA7DF21CE8875405BB6FE2A8E6585143C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3307 IH: Eastern Mediterranean Gateway Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3307</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250508">May 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To increase cooperation with countries in the Eastern Mediterranean
      region in order to strengthen energy security and defense capabilities, and for other
      purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE31283936107431C975A9552C128DA26" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H230FC0603CD947EBAECBB21D45D1982C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Eastern Mediterranean Gateway Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H812F2CC3A8A24319A2580C6975FD4B16"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to support the role of Eastern Mediterranean countries as a strategic gateway in the India-Middle East-Europe Economic Corridor (IMEC).</text></section>
<section id="H48F23784D02E4FC691E6E5C94C21F636"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HCEA43E80008546229892C4EFB292E727"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The India-Middle East-Europe Economic Corridor (IMEC), launched at the G20 Summit in 2023 with G7 backing, enhances connectivity between Asia, the Middle East, and Europe while serving as a strategic alternative to China’s Belt and Road Initiative.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1CF5E2342B3A4E2E94B4614AEE07F951"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Eastern Mediterranean region is of strategic importance to the United States and its allies, as demonstrated by the United States founding role in the 3+1 framework with Greece, Israel, and Cyprus.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9684DEF217DC4444861DA2763B5C5DB4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Energy projects such as the Great Sea Interconnector, the Gregy Interconnection Project, the Greece-Bulgaria Interconnector, and the LNG terminals in the Eastern Mediterranean play a key role in European energy security and provide critical infrastructure that can serve as the backbone for linking India, the Gulf, and Europe through the Eastern Mediterranean.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C3E6315CD78430BB00178C67A6E5F41"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Cyprus, Greece, Egypt, and Israel are key United States partners in promoting stability, security, and economic development in the region.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3655AE710A5E4A12946B31027B57BBFB"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text>Enhanced defense and security cooperation, as well as educational and cultural exchanges, are essential for strengthening bilateral and multilateral ties.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A32E5F552C2414B9732930C37C50F07"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to Presidential Determination 2025–03, <quote>the furnishing of defense articles and defense services to the Republic of Cyprus will strengthen the security of the United States and promote world peace</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF944670EFB54B40A7CC2FF57903FD02"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The statement of policy in the Israel Relations Normalization Act of 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8601">22 U.S.C. 8601</external-xref> note), notably that it is the policy of the United States <quote>to expand and strengthen the Abraham Accords to encourage other nations to normalize relations with Israel</quote>, should guide the Secretary of State and other United States actors in their work to promote integration between India, the Middle East and southeast Europe.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7E3512124CBF47BFA655313D31B17649">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">India has strengthened strategic ties with Greece, Israel, and Cyprus, fostering economic, maritime, and security cooperation that aligns with United States regional priorities.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2269728E9A28443E9E62D80CB02820B2">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The success of the India-Middle East-Europe Economic Corridor depends on infrastructure, security, and innovation partnerships rooted in the Eastern Mediterranean region, which serves as the primary connective hub linking the Gulf and Indian subcontinent to Europe.</text>
      </paragraph></section> 
<section id="HAF9EC43843F34E20BA068731A86F4EE3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H3AFB1EB272B34827B48EA4EC4CC0F07C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the significance of diplomatic initiatives such as the Greece-Cyprus-Israel-US <quote>3+1</quote> format, the East Mediterranean Gas Forum and the Abraham Accords should be recognized and the United States should maintain its leadership role in these diplomatic initiatives;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H255CCFDFBE4F4EE1A708203057E8BD82"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States should continue to actively participate in the initiatives of the East Mediterranean Gas Forum;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H83D9262C5E13449C8F1AD653D8A9ABAD"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Eastern Mediterranean region is a key gateway that can link three continents and the United States should support energy and transportation infrastructure, connectivity initiatives, defense cooperation, and other forms of integration in and around the region;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0A3478211E834C6EB355D1A00075EEBF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States recognizes the unique role of Eastern Mediterranean countries as both a distinct subregion and a central connector within the broader IMEC corridor;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDCF418BF323B4EFAAA1C3FAF31FD6CB5"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <quote>3+1</quote> diplomatic initiative should resume with a meeting of the Secretary of State with the Ministers of Israel, Greece, and Cyprus; and</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE0C1E307AEC0402DA98ED77F61CA792B"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the statement of policy in section 203 of the Eastern Mediterranean Security and Energy Partnership Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2373">22 U.S.C. 2373</external-xref> note) should guide the Secretary of State in promoting connectivity between India, the Middle East and Europe, including participation in the trilateral dialogue on energy, maritime security, cyber security and protection of critical infrastructure conducted among Israel, Greece, and Cyprus.</text></paragraph> </section> <section id="HF36AD71250B64F9D9F34350017194F2B" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>Diplomacy in Eastern Mediterranean region</header> <subsection id="HB232532A4E7844898297ADE711B63207" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategic dialogues</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State may institutionalize multilateral strategic dialogues between the United States and IMEC countries, including dedicated formats with Eastern Mediterranean countries, with which the United States has a bilateral strategic dialogue.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB7E8B72DB2BA4AA3813A9FE9B1562421" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Prioritization of the Eastern Mediterranean</header>
 <text>The Secretary of State shall prioritize the Eastern Mediterranean region in United States foreign policy, focusing on energy security and defense cooperation with countries in such region.</text>
      </subsection> </section> 
<section id="H211B6B1BD5F842BD9032726C9751ABDB" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reports and studies</header> 
<subsection id="HB0E3AD7214714B23AE1D1C5F47C062AA" commented="no">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Report on implementation</header>
 <text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Energy, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing the implementation and effect of this Act, including an update on energy projects and defense cooperation that are being carried out pursuant to the authorities of this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H4848855AD15E485D95367D2F61261915"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on multilateral initiatives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a briefing on each multilateral initiative between the United States and IMEC countries.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3D8D3748A7E74D79BBB9512D96F807EB" commented="no"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Analysis of Cyprus Centre for Land, Open Seas, and Port Security</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall analyze insights gained from the operation of the Cyprus Centre for Land, Open Seas, and Port Security (in this section referred to as <quote>CYCLOPS</quote>) as a potential model for broad-based multilateral cooperation.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HBFF8506AADA841F2BB8488E4261E9FD3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Study of program creation and expansion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing the cost of, steps to, and feasibility of—</text> <paragraph id="H98E259E9B7504805898B232CA30BAC23"><enum>(1)</enum><text>creating bilateral programs with Eastern Mediterranean countries modeled on bilateral programs between the United States and Israel, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2D6A3E27052F4188A1F4BA7A6827761E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Binational Agriculture Research and Development Fund;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H625BAFF9BA2746388C3D7E136099603E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States-Israel Binational Industrial Research and Development Foundation (including projects relating to homeland security and cyber security);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8DB190E8ABB5490FBE8AA22C682B8204" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States-Israel Binational Science Foundation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFB64775F41D44D4EB291CF345DB88F19" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States-Israel Science and Technology Foundation; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2608CE4AB163427389BF11F4985395DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expanding bilateral programs between the United States and Israel, including the programs listed in paragraph (1), to include other Eastern Mediterranean countries and IMEC countries.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> <section id="H98F5A53FA8CB4DA490D49D07BC17770D" commented="no"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2F9E038008204BF384045FA9B4CC9123" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HFB59E6D598C94C0DA23B3819301C4D30"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H47A944C045B348E2887D5E6614742B13" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8AE9BE780BA04033803DD75571CD1359"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eastern Mediterranean country</header><text>The term <quote>Eastern Mediterranean country</quote> means the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9DF29AE7BE6C45C694A5A799ECAB9FFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Arab Republic of Egypt.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF82F5C4FD09E476F86837623CC1EBEA0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Hellenic Republic.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB7F3929162384A33BA528BB53B4DE631"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Republic of Cyprus.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5A2CC084F7A3473FBC02351623B9EABA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The State of Israel.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE63F9447F2854FC4925162F9268FC4D1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>IMEC country</header><text>The term <term>IMEC country</term> means the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H818E730D9CAB42719B7187913AE92DA2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The European Union.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H64770EDB540D4ACBAC852B72D44028C2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Republic of Germany.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFFA9641179D84C7F9A4B0A8496CC6A55" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The French Republic.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H80AB6B59C9ED41D8B912617BA1A24B16" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Italian Republic.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDB6AA62672A34808823E2E81211F0C89" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H167BBD54BDC045ABBD0AA5559B9F1ADA" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Republic of India.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H062FF312C7E7474FA76703ADE5DBDA5F" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United Arab Emirates.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE6292662A61545AD8A6E2B032A4C7A4F" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The United States.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H151706086D6348209BD9725380419172" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Any other country that the Secretary of State designates as an IMEC country for purposes of this Act.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

