<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6711C1F9C17544B29F22B59734DC5D34" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4452 IH: STEM Restoring Employment Skills through Targeted Assistance, Re-entry, and Training Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4452</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250716">July 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001307">Mr. Baird</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act to create a new national program to support mid-career workers in reentering the STEM workforce, by providing funding to small- and medium-sized STEM businesses so the businesses can offer paid internships or other returnships that lead to positions above entry level.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBD04B2828CD44A33A471C72F5EEFC6B4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H597E27E1446543D3857135E07E070393" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>STEM Restoring Employment Skills through Targeted Assistance, Re-entry, and Training Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STEM RESTART Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H45413002C30C40E387E1EBF5B3A5E906"><enum>2.</enum><header>Returning skilled workers to the stem workforce</header> <subsection id="HDB124008E7904F02A3F2F124BA26F79B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subtitle D of title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HBA74E6B8AC2D4E3383BC5EF864ABCE20"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 172 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3227">29 U.S.C. 3227</external-xref>) as section 173; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDC22FF9260A4F458587E0FE651053F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 171 the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3ED70949B61041CCB374DB6AD8B93AA1">
<section id="H09C3FB0CF03A4FBAAA13D4995268EF8E"><enum>172.</enum><header>Grants to support skilled workers in returning or transitioning to the stem workforce</header>
<subsection id="HD1EB59F1F4FC4F3694031D3748225468"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this section are to—</text> <paragraph id="H71BA0DE907C945F786423FCD822FD4B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prioritize expanding opportunities, through high-quality internships or other returnships in STEM fields for unemployed or underemployed workers, particularly workers from rural areas, who are mid-career skilled workers seeking to return or transition to in-demand industry sectors or occupations within the STEM workforce, at positions and compensation above entry level; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6CF136FD02754D67919F7BC8502F3AE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish grant funding and other incentives for small-sized and medium-sized companies in in-demand industry sectors or occupations to establish programs that provide on-the-job evaluation, education, and training for mid-career skilled workers described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2CAAC1C18DFC48739BF1253C8A6603B7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H33A151202ECD4833B6818F2E14A9C254"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Medium-sized enterprise</header><text>The term <term>medium-sized</term>, used with respect to an enterprise, means an entity that employs more than 499 and fewer than 10,000 employees.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H907CE88DC6834342AF139CCC7E28F089"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Restart grant</header><text>The term <term>RESTART grant</term> means a grant made under subsection (c).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE5F88AB3408746C5A5EBC839D76073F7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Returnship</header><text>The term <term>returnship</term> shall mean any internship, apprenticeship, re-entry opportunity, direct hiring opportunity with support, or other similar opportunity designed to provide workers seeking to return or transition to the STEM workforce with positions that—</text> <subparagraph id="H21AD341511B749F99CBE1F8CD5274A47"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are above entry level;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF4B73CCCBF8A48DF9AA746D9B7C238F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide salaries, stipends, or other payments, and benefits, that are above entry level; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDF58BFCC4C074A9C902020B9F2957CD9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide training that leads workers toward full-time careers and provides pathways toward advancement and leadership.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5941B5C59986416AB824920AA212D337"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rural area</header><text>The term <term>rural area</term> means an area that is not an urban area (within the meaning of the notice of final program criteria entitled <quote>Urban Area Criteria for the 2010 Census</quote> (76 Fed. Reg. 53030 (August 24, 2011))).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB891110CFE814EB09A71EC2769024758"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Small-sized enterprise</header><text>The term <term>small-sized</term>, used with respect to an enterprise, means an entity that employs more than 49 and fewer than 500 individuals.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H63A383312E1C44839E3D5BC3E4C1A72B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Stem</header><text>The term <term>STEM</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the America COMPETES Reauthorization Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6621">42 U.S.C. 6621</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H344503CE05534E7DB60668C94755217C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Unemployed or underemployed individual</header><text>The term <term>unemployed or underemployed individual</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H67FD1CEC163846DD912037D31BC3F8FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an unemployed or underemployed individual as defined by the Bureau of Labor Statistics; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8AA4AF8B3006420E90E08CF8F3D9E1BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a displaced or furloughed worker.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9FA6CAE0D4604D4A987A6D5C55719AE9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant</header>
<paragraph id="HC22E9B877C824E4BBA9E044B57FB3533"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From the amounts made available to carry out this section, the Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities, to carry out returnship programs that provide opportunities above entry level in STEM fields for mid-career skilled workers, and achieve the purposes described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H55D67C5A715F478BA187D5D3364A7B56"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Periods</header><text>The Secretary shall award the grants for an initial period of not less than 3 years and not more than 5 years.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAE3AD03827464FCB9473F05140751271"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Amounts</header><text>In awarding grants under this subsection, the Secretary shall award a grant—</text> <subparagraph id="HB1181AA580DA49BD8BB2389A4DEEDA12"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for a small-sized enterprise, in an amount so that each annual payment for the grant is not less than $100,000 or more than $1,000,000; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8B85050989954A18A2F5B2BB8117ECF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for a medium-sized enterprise or consortium, in an amount so that each annual payment for the grant is not less than $500,000 or more than $5,000,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF3F44DFABB9141E5978EB8EBC4A93681"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligibility</header> <paragraph id="H9D9DEB6CCDB84A549914AD0D62CC6072"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>To be eligible to receive a RESTART grant under this section, an entity shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H80F8B40786FB40A9B0764F0CCCC7D2FD"><enum>(A)</enum>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBBB71504EA0242BAB8D61C4DE242CFCE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be located in the United States and have significant operations and employees within the United States;</text></clause> <clause id="HB9F80F12681A4E189E07A1EAF8F16D10" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not be a debtor in a bankruptcy proceeding, within the meaning of section 4003(c)(3)(D)(i)(V) of the CARES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9042">15 U.S.C. 9042(c)(3)(D)(i)(V)</external-xref>) or under a State bankruptcy law; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HE546A2ED377F41ACAA1AF63D276166F3" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>be within an in-demand industry sector or occupation in a STEM field; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD6180CB089F5474CB8FF0A42344E7D01"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be—</text>
<clause id="H2361BD5CE1204E308EA7ED53818D86E1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a small-sized enterprise;</text></clause> <clause id="H927DE981FAC24C57853697D2AF9046B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a medium-sized enterprise; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H01952B081F134966AAE6B5AFAFFB7DAC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a consortium of small-sized or medium-sized enterprises.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E5CE7B18869447B95BAD36C9BCD08E0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible providers</header> <subparagraph id="H35D64974BBD347FDA178CBE6B1B830C5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity that desires to partner with a provider in order to carry out a returnship program under this section shall enter into an arrangement with an eligible provider.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD4A0AC06A96644948D90EC44643F0751"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Provider</header><text>To be eligible to enter into such an arrangement, a provider—</text> <clause id="H07AEA61915704B48A6D99E4D99063577"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may or may not directly employ skilled workers in STEM fields but—</text>
<subclause id="HB5BD90C64F8043309EAF336B819F36C4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall have expertise in human resources-related activities, such as identifying or carrying out staffing with skilled workers; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H50F982A443F64AE783CCF3644F748A38"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall be capable of providing high-quality education and training services; and</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H79F0666EE83F4494876548E021C48C46"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may be—</text> <subclause id="H1ECD369A877B426C904634452FDA4A3D"><enum>(I)</enum> <item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2FF17F1407994CAA8AAD87DA8EF78D25"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>an institution of higher education (as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>)); or</text></item>
<item id="HE4FD3145A9C443BCA47C1A0FBD054F4B" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a non-degree-granting institution that is governed by the same body that governs an institution of higher education described in item (aa);</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H9FCFA5624E04424E993CCEF04CA971DD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a public, private for-profit, or private nonprofit service provider, approved by the local board;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HD7631607FD9D478788941B37FBFE53FA"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a joint labor-management organization;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H49BE533E72724F01AE718E4172F8B794"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>an eligible provider of adult education and literacy activities under title II; or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HCBEE29F5B58E444C87F79EBD3A7ADD02"><enum>(V)</enum><text>an established nonprofit organization that conducts research or provides training on technical and employability skills and knowledge aligned to the needs of adult learners and workers.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0B74768582AD4097BFA48BA39D3BC132"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applications</header> <paragraph id="H3410CD7DD25F411FA700452355B6A3B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a RESTART grant to carry out a returnship program, an entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3966C727BD86476C9A4D223F9F20DCE7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Such an application shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HD35CD74BD18C493399C37597EC44E414"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the demand for skilled workers in STEM fields and how the RESTART grant will be used to help meet that demand;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA4E4784DDD774D48BD2EEE18405D5244"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of how the program will lead to employment of unemployed or underemployed individuals, particularly workers from rural areas, who seek to return or transition to the STEM workforce;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBC39AF351B5742CFBD099C621CC26551"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if the entity has entered into or plans to enter into an arrangement with an eligible provider as described in subsection (d)(2) to carry out a returnship program, information identifying the eligible provider, and a description of how the arrangement will help the entity build the knowledge and skills of skilled workers participating in the program;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H40389058D6554D4A9EA48FAB521911AB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of how the eligible entity will develop and establish, or expand, a returnship program that adds to the number of full-time employees employed by the entity, but does not displace full-time employees currently (as of the date of submission of the application) employed by the entity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H562F123C57464B578D287D10DFBBF753"> <enum>(E)</enum> <text>an assurance that any new or existing returnship program developed and established, or expanded, with the grant funds will last for at least 10 weeks and provide compensation to participants in the form of a salary, stipend, or other payment, and benefits, that are offered to full-time employees with equivalent experience and expertise, such as health care or child care benefits; and</text>
                  </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H60CE96C8F71D4B309F6525A6310C1466"><enum>(F)</enum><text>if the returnship program leads to a recognized postsecondary credential, information on the quality of the program that leads to the credential.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A5C8E704E4748188D8A4F119545161D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In making grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to entities who are proposing programs that prioritize returnships for workers in in-demand industry sectors or occupations, according to the State board or from rural areas.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H84BBB913F9E3444AA79A5C578EB99EAC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of funds</header>
<paragraph id="H94943D3847034DBB8A1FD86114EE94FC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An entity that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant funds to carry out a returnship program, of not less than 10 weeks, through which the entity provides for—</text> <subparagraph id="H2FE1D35A596A4B2C87136A9D38E03328"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the education and training of returnship participants; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9F7A8576CD4549FD926C862BFAEA5490"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the services of existing employees (as of the date the program begins) of the entity who are working with returnship participants in an educational, training, or managerial role, to maximize the retention rate and effectiveness of the returnship program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE6221F1238C44EFCAF66B6C0B47F8A31"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specific uses</header><text>The grant funds may be used—</text>
<subparagraph id="H70441882FEDB4963A60611A4142E41DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to pay for the evaluation, and entry into the program, and education and training of returnship participants, including payment for the duration of the program for the participants for—</text> <clause id="H2E9D66B3640846A2A842801C097728FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>equipment, travel, and (as necessary) housing;</text></clause>
<clause id="H004AAFBC8ABF40F9AC3CA0BF0C4E3D6C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>mentorship and career counseling; and</text></clause> <clause id="HBDA40140C4114D0D84BC50904F510C4A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>salaries, stipends, or payments, and benefits, described in subsection (e)(2)(E);</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2E2E6E89A5D746F79596DB075C215E9C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to supplement, and not supplant, the compensation of those existing employees of the entity who are directly supporting a returnship program through the work described in paragraph (1)(B); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H99FEED2646B544279D400DEB5F513384"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to enter into an arrangement with an eligible provider to carry out a returnship program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H07373AE59A6E45C889DDC2495B9BE5FA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Existing employees</header><text>Not more than 20 percent of the grant funds may be used to provide compensation for the existing employees performing the work described in paragraph (1)(B).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF69D2FBCAB4E415E9C632FD787DDE59B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Coordination with state boards</header><text>An entity that receives a grant under this section shall coordinate activities with the State board established under section 101, to ensure collaboration and alignment of workforce programs.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HBA5F70A555F9428AB10172695F4F8A2F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reporting and evaluation requirements</header>
<paragraph id="H4FBC9C6679C044788A6FB6B269FC0A71"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report to the secretary</header><text>An entity that receives a grant under this section for a returnship program shall prepare, certify the contents of, and submit to the Secretary an annual report containing data regarding—</text> <subparagraph id="H58CD96FFA8144A20B09C06E4EB0DECAB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total number of the participants, and the number of such participants disaggregated by sex, race, and ethnicity;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H16B81BA0366542148520FF6A9F348F24"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total number of the participants transitioned into full-time employment, and the number of such transitioned participants disaggregated by sex, race, and ethnicity; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H757008D0A4F14B85AD2794E2DE780412"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if the returnship program includes participants in an internship, the conversion rate of the internship participants to employees, for the total number of those participants and the conversion rate of those participants disaggregated by sex, race, and ethnicity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDD43D89A3CE64C5FABED437CA1136BD7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluation and report by the secretary</header><text>Not later than 180 days after receiving the annual reports from grant recipients under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H6F76B8CB9E424091BEBB91B431C8460C"><enum>(A)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9D2698BA272E4A33833678AC8DF4DA48"><enum>(i)</enum><text>prepare a report that presents the data collected through the reports, including data disaggregated by sex, race, and ethnicity, and an evaluation based on that data of the best practices for effectively implementing returnship (including internship) programs; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H9EAFD4D7EE8846C3BFB6400C0909E7FC" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit the report to the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H32860271F03D46A4938D66BA9A55B26D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>post information on a website on best practices described in subparagraph (A)(i).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H84FD83C4A0CD4DB2A78E9712A93659EB"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3A327F7E119E426680635F0EE6E88309"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H031A77FAC7184239AE0BC0C5D0C768E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating the item relating to section 172 as the item relating to section 173; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3E4FC8CF1FE74DA1A89E25A2FB53D397"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after the item relating to section 171 the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F2627B3F1DB4E5FA2B26FAEE3FB3251">
<toc>
<toc-entry level="section" bold="off">Sec. 172. Grants to support skilled workers in returning or transitioning to the STEM workforce.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H00AF0AF6019C4D198984CC5F9900A867">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Conforming amendment</header>
 <text>Section 8041(g)(2) of the Substance Use-Disorder Prevention that Promotes Opioid Recovery and Treatment for Patients and Communities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3225a">29 U.S.C. 3225a(g)(2)</external-xref>) is amended in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>172(f)</quote> and inserting <quote>173(f)</quote>.</text>
      </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

