<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H86A4B53D588C49139155B9F0B33ACA9D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2556 IH: Comprehensive Offshore Resource Enhancement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2556</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250401">April 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enhance national security and energy independence through comprehensive offshore energy resource assessment and mapping, to establish a framework for the regular review and standardization of offshore resource exploration methodologies, and for related purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5A9925106A4645B1B10C126AA73C0A9D" style="OLC"><section id="HC5D194E5FDC045DE89BB3C5E46656201" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Comprehensive Offshore Resource Enhancement Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CORE Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H678F1BE23360430F9169A0329DD2F839"><enum>2.</enum><header>Assessment of offshore energy resources and reserves</header><subsection id="H9114916FFE284955A1F64FE1023EA12F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H0B53F1BF3A094315A4AD20C01CD5BEED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exploration; development, production</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>exploration</term>, <term>development</term>, and <term>production</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 2 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06C74C6D6BE44E9EBA6DA2045582DEE1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretaries</header><text>The term <term>Secretaries</term> means the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Secretary of State.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF18AD21B95DC455AAE1FCD7EFEF84856"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on transboundary hydrocarbon reservoirs</header><paragraph id="HB179E21972824417BC5FFED66DA2DE1E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretaries shall jointly submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Committee on Natural Resources, and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a report that includes the following:</text><subparagraph id="H06F6BA145B5342F79A479933F256B33E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An identification and assessment of any existing transboundary hydrocarbon reservoirs, including those covered by bilateral maritime boundary treaties and agreements, and any potential transboundary areas for future exploration, development, and production of hydrocarbons.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96FA26E694D04DE6B08FFF1275846CFF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An analysis of the legal frameworks established by relevant maritime boundary treaties and agreements, including provisions related to the equitable exploration, development, and production of transboundary hydrocarbon reservoirs and mechanisms for resolving disputes, and their adoption by counterparty nations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B920F5D11B04E7B924DAEA822601D86"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation of the potential economic, environmental, and geopolitical implications of transboundary hydrocarbon exploration, development, and production, including impacts on domestic energy security, greenhouse gas emissions, and international relations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64AEB37652E84401A79557A2D04A8183"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations for enhancing cooperation and coordination among the United States and neighboring countries in the exploration, development, and production of transboundary hydrocarbon reservoirs, including mechanisms for information sharing, joint exploration, development, and production, and dispute resolution.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD860860C27A94B0AAB102B98F2BA8F81"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Data and insights derived from recent collaborative efforts between the United States and Canada, such as seismic data collection, and an analysis of how such efforts can inform the delineation of maritime boundaries.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8C8E1313F7643A2BE98917390D8D545" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>An examination of unresolved maritime boundaries between the United States and Canada, particularly those involving potential transboundary hydrocarbon reservoirs, and an identification of potential legal and diplomatic avenues to resolve disputes over such boundaries, including the possibility of involving international judicial bodies such as the International Court of Justice or a chamber constituted by such Court pursuant to a special agreement between the parties.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2536CB14E4334217BAD06C500C6FADBA"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A review of existing data on the potential for shared exploration, development, and production of transboundary hydrocarbon reservoirs in disputed maritime zones between the United States and Canada, with recommendations for further studies or negotiations to address uncertainties and maximize joint exploration, development, and production opportunities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86F7D107C42D43E6B8D4B10C6713FAF8"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comprehensive review of activities by neighboring countries, including Cuba, Mexico, Canada, the Bahamas, and Russia, regarding the exploration, development, seismic surveying, drilling, production, or any other activity related to transboundary hydrocarbon reservoirs, which such review shall include the status of any bilateral or multilateral agreements, an assessment of foreign exploration, development, and production efforts within transboundary zones adjacent to United States maritime boundaries, and an analysis of the potential implications of these activities for United States energy security, environmental impacts, and geopolitical considerations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE59E65F293448EC896F92CB57E13269" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other requirements</header><text>In preparing the report required to be submitted under paragraph (1), the Secretaries shall—</text><subparagraph id="HC0C2CD5137AC4900884F85824909B5E0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prioritize the acquisition and use of advanced geophysical, geological, and geotechnical data and methods;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D16F557727847028871F24B72088BAA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acquire and apply new and emerging modeling and analytic technologies, including data analysis tools, quantum computing, artificial intelligence, modeling, and geographic information systems, to approximate the quantity and establish a peer-reviewed range of resources in each regional planning area with a discussion of the upper and lower bound of the estimates with that discussion to include recommendations as to how to reduce the range of uncertainty; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57689112EBA545199E98E1414A203412" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in partnership with other relevant Federal agencies, including the National Science Foundation, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the Office of Naval Research, utilize any existing maritime vessels or deployed capability, including any geophysical, geological, or related mapping technologies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD8B78D4E75D943EDB33AA915AD0D6277"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Standardization of existing reports</header><text>Section 357 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15912">42 U.S.C. 15912</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H5C3D3802E7AF40539179F1DA818C60DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="HEA3BE2F0D34843CEBE45B404F5765B8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, in consultation with other relevant Federal agencies and not less frequently than once every 5 years,</quote> after <quote>Secretary shall</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00906D38D6AD47C8B1D88E8E47635E13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>of Mexico and Canada</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5115CD826C254697AF3D826EC34A7854"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (b) as subsection (d);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD34894151094F0F9F68B57E1658B4A1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H9C9390FF948D4AC2ABF06FB0FA7298FB" style="OLC"><subsection id="H983339F116DA428F90673266E0A5D178"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>An inventory and analysis conducted under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H9612F7F400554EFA8BFDA6273CC93F64"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of the approximate quantity of undiscovered resources in the Atlantic region, the Pacific region off the coasts of California, Oregon, Washington, and Hawaii, the Alaska region, the Gulf of America region, and offshore of territories of the United States, which shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="H133792A9AEF44C8480F5421553ABABA4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A detailed analysis of how the future production of these undiscovered resources could influence the United States capacity to competitively produce, market, and export hydrocarbons on a global scale. Such detailed analysis shall consider key market variables such as global supply and demand dynamics, projected price points, geopolitical factors, and the role of United States production in maintaining global energy security.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5F7BB52F01545069BB75D578F18F8D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An economic analysis of how the development and production of these undiscovered resources would affect domestic employment across the supply chain. Such economic analysis shall include direct, indirect, and induced job impacts, emphasizing the potential for job creation in exploration, production, refining, logistics, and associated industries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AE5AC0DB6D745958F8D618A18CA5ADD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An identification and assessment of how the unavailability for leasing of any lands that are withdrawn under section 12 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1341">43 U.S.C. 1341</external-xref>) or part of the National Marine Sanctuary System established by section 301(c) of the National Marine Sanctuaries Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1431">16 U.S.C. 1431(c)</external-xref>) affects—</text><subparagraph id="HEFE7B6DE99114B309684D8D19FA81C02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the exploration, development, and production of oil and gas;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1416ADBB37B744478D93F083C0C542A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>national security, including the Nation’s ability to supply the Armed Forces, its allies, and trade partners with products derived from offshore oil or gas;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H369DA4CBB3B444A1818729F869EF7938"><enum>(C)</enum><text>domestic jobs and employment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0FB2F054D304463B404A5F622FF2757" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the amount of revenue States and coastal political subdivisions receive pursuant to—</text><clause id="H0BE2124D96594C5A82764EE8C324F0C7" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text> section 105 of the Gulf of Mexico Energy Security Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331</external-xref> note);</text></clause><clause id="H062796354A2346BA9A3A390A7D8D5923" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Land and Water Conservation Fund (established under section 200301 of title 54, United States Code); and</text></clause><clause id="HBD8328549F1B40A19F9AB2EFCB793386" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>division A of subtitle III of title 54 (commonly referred to as the ‘National Historic Preservation Act’).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3100995879AD40B999DE5AF93F34855B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment, including identification of locations, of non-energy mineral resources for commercial or national security operations, including stone, sand, and gravel, and offshore critical minerals.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF92B792E359C4CAEBE4EEE4202E00F8C" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Updating models</header><paragraph id="HFF637134065C4E7D8316EBBCCEC30B8B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, in consultation with the National Petroleum Council, the Society of Petroleum Engineers, and the United States Association for Energy Economics, periodically conduct an assessment of the costs, benefits, and accuracy of the models utilized by the Department of the Interior to conduct an inventory and analysis under subsection (a). The first assessment under this paragraph shall be conducted not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>CORE Act of 2025</short-title>, and subsequent assessments not less frequently than once every 10 years thereafter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49A4D1CB97D0443EAD0FE4BB4180ED2D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updates and reports</header><subparagraph id="HB06AEF48E9B4462A86D65064E4AF7E7A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary conducts an assessment under paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Interior shall, based on such assessment—</text><clause id="HC2258C08ED694977BE7C630A9DDDD534" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>update the models described in such paragraph and publish a report on such update; or</text></clause><clause id="H1653BD1CBD3542DD909255247EE1541C" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>publish a report on why an update to such models is not necessary.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H240A35F0A92245428D23AC9E2B5C19CA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>Each report published under subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</text><clause id="HA397888CE1504A4489D5A412FD90D4BA" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A clear, detailed explanation of any updates made to the models described in paragraph (1) or why updates were not necessary.</text></clause><clause id="H4B1E4294AE414C2CB2B3F106F5B25A5D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An evaluation describing how any updates made under subparagraph (A) improve the accuracy, cost-effectiveness, and reliability of the inventories and analyses conducted under subsection (a).</text></clause><clause id="H4697BF5BB22F4AEC8334F786F45FA6F2" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any updates recommend by the National Petroleum Council, the Society of Petroleum Engineers, or the United States Association for Energy Economics are not incorporated, a detailed explanation of why such updates were not incorporated.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D34060E70C24410ADC3DB9EFE2BDCFE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (d) (as so redesignated)—</text><subparagraph id="H41E97ECFA9004DAF91A26DDB860D17DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Secretary shall submit</quote> and inserting <quote>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>CORE Act of 2025</short-title>, the Secretary shall submit</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA692843019D4FC8A853B0A64123BE69"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, within 6 months of the date of enactment of the section</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2D77D50740D04229B0809831A64FE0DB" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Comparative analysis of production practices from offshore producing country</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than once every 10 years thereafter, the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Energy, shall publish on the website of the Department of the Interior and submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a comparative analysis of the offshore oil and gas exploration, development, and production practices for each major offshore producing country. To the fullest extent practicable, such comparative analysis shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HBA5F84D9B1FF4315810D46C06E59018A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data on—</text><subparagraph id="H1E70874E5ED544E19FE6DDCFE126D1C4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of offshore acres offered for lease;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C85DE6B37DE47E581A317FCB016934B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the frequency of lease auctions, sales, and lease issuances; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61D2342DE16B46C19AFCFFC4FECE6E14" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>lease structures, fiscal terms, and the competitive positioning of each major offshore producing country relative to United States leasing practices.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DF7316F7E5C4409946770FAF8E8A5D7" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Detailed reporting on the volume of oil and gas produced (measured in barrels on an annual basis and cubic feet, respectively), including historical trends, production forecasts, and the influence of technological advancements on production efficiency and recovery rates.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2069F33D81F048498A167A1D5126CAE6" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An accounting of regional market demands, export capabilities, and contributions to energy diversification strategies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25097109CDAB46BEBB12A51D1576160A" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment, which shall be made in collaboration with the United States Geological Survey, of the volume of both undiscovered and discovered offshore oil and gas resources, including probabilistic estimates of resource volumes that consider geological, technological, and market factors impacting exploration, development, and production.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

