<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HA4D6507E3E7F4AB39C4A0ED3059CB269"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4782 IH: Local Farmers Feeding our Communities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4782</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250729">July 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001327">Mr. Bresnahan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000622">Mr. Riley of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000829">Mr. Wied</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a program under which the Secretary will enter into cooperative agreements with State, local, or Tribal governments to increase the purchase of local foods, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H54C34B8671254604883C7E53D0EBBBFA"><section id="HCBDE997CB00E4638AF8624AF56140EF7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Local Farmers Feeding our Communities Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HCD596A139CFB4B3B94D89FFF8C7DCA69"><enum>2.</enum><header>Local farmers feeding our communities program</header><subsection id="HFC49421EC29E4C4E8DD5B0A36CABE378"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall establish a program under which the Secretary will enter into cooperative agreements (on a noncompetitive basis) with eligible entities—</text><paragraph id="H22E9F583D0364329AF42DD90EEF885A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to help support covered local producers through building and expanding economic opportunities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5C13909F9C34332BD8B7CB5FFE38265"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to establish and broaden partnerships with such covered local producers and the food distribution community to ensure distribution of fresh and nutritious foods; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D0247A815614BF1BE0B26C71619898F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to strengthen such entity’s local and regional food security and systems.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7A5D2E0DBC5B487C92B9D452993BE80A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity selected to enter into a cooperative agreement under this section shall use funds received through such agreement—</text><paragraph id="HF965FB71417E4585973BFA9A4591880D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to purchase unprocessed or minimally processed local foods (including seafood, meat, milk and dairy products, eggs, produce, and poultry) from covered producers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA694D49FDEC4C01BA7E8F6FAE1A7E3B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to ensure that at least 25 percent of the total annual value of products purchased by the eligible entity comprises purchases from small-size producers, mid-size producers, beginning farmers or ranchers, or veteran farmers or ranchers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2954DB48A29A451A85E0AFA2F8DDA4DC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to provide technical assistance supporting—</text><subparagraph id="H6883ADD557D249A3AD9D557A20FE2984"><enum>(A)</enum><text>covered local producers, including in obtaining food safety training and certifications; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5FA4BDE20D448FA9B9E74D91D3EA02F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>efforts to grow the local agricultural value chain;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD243E8A1AA0244A09917BDFEE8218371"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to distribute such local foods to organizations that have experience in food distributiondistribution, including nonprofits, to improve access to healthy and nutritious food; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7597F15023D453E968B757E69B5B618"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to build and expand economic opportunity for covered local producers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H41224B62D84E403582E4728E8E79E0EA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation on use of funds</header><paragraph id="H4111EAF5C9374D539F4BE54FA85CB976"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Of the amount made available to an eligible entity through a cooperative agreement under this section, an eligible entity may use not more than 25 percent of such amount—</text><subparagraph id="H6D23F3D456154F4E9DA9C256FA074E47"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to cover administrative expenses; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H131C114F5B214AC38AD3A327A1865163"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to provide technical assistance described in subsection (b)(3);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFEF527796DF403293E83792008EC11E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allocation for technical assistance</header><text>Of the amount described in paragraph (1), an eligible entity shall use not less than 50 percent to provide technical assistance described in subsection (b)(3).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF705209AC3B846B6A68A4A23F4E2952A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technical assistance to eligible entities</header><text>The Secretary shall provide to eligible entities entering into a cooperative agreement under this section guidance, technical assistance, instruction, and monitoring throughout the life cycle of the cooperative agreement.</text></subsection><subsection id="H722F73F958844BBC9B858062787C7177"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Amount of allocation</header><text>Of the amounts made available to carry out this section for each fiscal year, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HA75E99C06C094523814C3F687A224502"><enum>(1)</enum><text>allocate 10 percent to Tribal governments, to be allocated using a funding formula determined by the Secretary; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACBDF607FAE74F61A5AA28A7F44F2186"><enum>(2)</enum><text>of the amounts remaining after making the allocation under paragraph (1), allocate 1 percent to each State (other than Tribal governments); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF092B9615F594A75B352C94BF7DB7013"><enum>(3)</enum><text>after making the allocations under paragraphs (1) and (2), allocate the remaining amounts to each eligible entity (other than Tribal governments) by applying the formula described in section 214 of the Emergency Food Assistance Act of 1983 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7515">7 U.S.C. 7515</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H33A54E7CE59245E9826CFF4961A93BC5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H4710B9FC0CD14C77875385D07799B86A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Beginning farmer or rancher; veteran farmer or rancher</header><text>The terms <quote>beginning farmer or rancher</quote> and <quote>veteran farmer or rancher</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 2501 of the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2279">7 U.S.C. 2279</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H765B4A7FA94B42B0B1E6E761A2EB2338"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered producer</header><text>The term <quote>covered producer</quote> means a fisherman, farmer, producer, rancher, processor, or cooperative processor that is—</text><subparagraph id="H79035C6B1A3A4BB2989510C04559496D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>within the geographic boundaries of the eligible entity in which the food will be delivered; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3870F220E134524B3EF72B64AC67928"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not more than 400 miles from the delivery destination of the food.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7990EFCA0DBE4E04AC629F853B85BCC4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means a State agency, commission, or department that is responsible for agriculture, procurement, food distribution, emergency response, or other similar activities within the State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7951605E0AB4DB19D5DE482F972A5A5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Mid-size producer</header><text>The term <quote>mid-sized producer</quote> means an individual whose annual gross cash farm income is equal to or exceeds $350,000 and is less than $999,999.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EEAC07EF8E149ABB35853BF7CE683D7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Small-size producer</header><text>The term <quote>small-sized producer</quote> means one whose annual gross cash farm income is less than $350,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D3BB6A967CB4587B0BCF796C6FF93CD"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, each territory or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5E57F18249647EF88170B1187B618FA"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Unprocessed or minimally processed local foods</header><text>The term <quote>unprocessed or minimally processed local foods</quote> means only those agricultural products that retain their inherent character. Such term includes—</text><subparagraph id="H123772DCF12E45DDBFFE5175105264C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>fruits and vegetables (including 100 percent juices);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A7F77409CD74B6B955E1C713B45B52C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>grain products, such as pastas and rice;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H638C974D7F8145C2B8CEC3BEB79B3C30"><enum>(C)</enum><text>meats (including whole carcasses, pieces thereof, or ground meat);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10062B5A458E4C45BD66B2DBEC7822A8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>protein sources that are meat alternatives (such as beans or legumes) and fluid milk and other dairy foods (such as cheese and yogurt); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7806DC661EA74E8A83EFA4BB862034CF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>foods in a wide variety of minimal processing states (such as whole, cut, or pureed) or forms (such as fresh, frozen, canned, or dried).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6F045E9EAFA04E1599290346C6708490"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Funding</header><paragraph id="HC15212FD037A46C1AB0C4F8C00183045"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mandatory funding</header><text>Of the funds of the Commodity Credit Corporation, the Secretary shall use to carry out this section $200,000,000 for fiscal year 2026 and each fiscal year thereafter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF88CDEB61A6644AF9C9DFD05A6D6F232"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $200,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030, to remain available until expended.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

