<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBAA27556A97D4219BBBDFCAAAAABCC3A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 642 IH: Myakka Wild and Scenic River Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 642</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250123">January 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate the portion of the Myakka River lying within Sarasota County, Florida as a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H92B771F1CDB54738A93421D61538A61C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF1A36D339BD24A68A7C659D6BF3F29F1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Myakka Wild and Scenic River Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6D861D1D4158434687357D243ADCFB58"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9ED9DF2B58D34E45B744FCDF08005D02"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Public Law 95–625 amended section 5 of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1276">16 U.S.C. 1276</external-xref>) to require the study of the Myakka River for potential inclusion in the national wild and scenic rivers system.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE59D182393044F9B93A11899A6EBDAAC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The study determined the Myakka River, was eligible for inclusion in the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8EA176AAF1874DB18B0BAFDE9E1E8CF3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The State of Florida has demonstrated its commitment to protecting this river by the enactment of the Myakka River Wild and Scenic Designation and Protection Act (Florida Statute Chapter 258.501).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3E75AA7C398242B4A725552007186ED0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Florida county of Sarasota and the cities of Venice and North Port have demonstrated their commitment to protect this river in their comprehensive land use plans, local ordinances, and land development regulations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB0CA2F59BB1341E0B249110E60B16B80"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The desire for designation of this river as a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System has been demonstrated through strong public support, State and local agency support, and the endorsement of designation by the Myakka River Management Coordinating Council, which represents a broad cross section of State and local agencies, agricultural interests, landowners, environmental, and nonprofit organizations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1FC683E26B16454C9011C5483E592C5B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A 12-mile segment of the Myakka River is within the Myakka River State Park with an additional 22-mile segment containing conservation lands held in public ownership or conservation easements within the Myakka River Watershed.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H4B5B8768445A4276BF132612837637BE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Designation of Myakka River, Florida, as a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System</header> 
<subsection id="H42C00AC4071E4FED8931B7A611B400CF"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD427F636A8234837B9496511E444CA25" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H9CE1C361BEA540E58069654F667E50E2"><enum>(___)</enum><header>Myakka River, Florida</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 34-mile segments, within Sarasota County referred to in this paragraph, to be administered by the Secretary of the Interior, in partnership with the Myakka River Management Coordinating Council. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H65991F74C64E4A5E90EBCA74FCF62012"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following segments of the Myakka River, within Sarasota County, to be administered in the following classifications: </text> <quoted-block id="HA860988A292D4FF890E518DEC4070E1A" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H285884D015454CCEA5AFB2CE39CB5AA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The approximately 8.0-mile segment from the Manatee County/Sarasota County line to S.R. 72, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC28632105E864F078939DA56EFEDE41F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The approximately 11.2-mile segment, from S.R. 72 to Laurel Road, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA210A2182914CADADD14B5543DC3F3F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The approximately 1.9-mile segment, from Laurel Road to Border Road, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA10C83083680465BBCD89DEFD99BCF86"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The approximately 1.5-mile segment, from Border Road to just south of the I-75 Bridge, as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6E6F382886204E52A361F32C2F329A21"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The approximately 1.5-mile segment, from south of the I-75 Bridge to Snook Haven, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5BEF5FCD26664E44B57A72114417EE64"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The approximately 3.2-mile segment, from Snook Haven to Ramblers Rest, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0BA47984B6B04A799C0E05B20B2FA3B7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The approximately 2.7-mile segment, from Ramblers Rest to U.S. 41, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB00F8012C03E406191FA54F3A766CEB8"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The approximately 4.0-mile segment, from U.S. 41 to the Charlotte County Line, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H9E015748DF864588B8DB877D70152CAA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Special requirements applicable to Myakka River</header> <subsection id="HBB97BFD478784C90988215716CFEB6F2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section and section 5:</text> 
<paragraph id="H861F7EC2D6DB4F5EBCF5352F44001C84"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Myakka river</header><text>The term <term>Myakka River</term> means the segments of the Myakka River in the State of Florida designated as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System by paragraph (_) of section 3(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)</external-xref>), as added by this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H345AB52B49FD4D01A1D159AC8E3559CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Council</header><text>The term <term>Council</term> means the Myakka River Management Coordinating Council established pursuant to Florida Statute Chapter 258.501.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC6883B48182846BFBB4AD14788FB6B95"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Comprehensive management plan</header><text>The terms <term>comprehensive management plan</term> and <term>plan</term> mean the Myakka River Wild and Scenic Management Plan developed by the Council shall be considered to satisfy the requirements for the comprehensive management plan under section 3(d) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(d)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1DAB01D95E14434B23C978F019F8169"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5EC04847D10C498C894E1193089FB15C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header> 
<paragraph id="H51E76ECD57A448EAB423BD9815B57E94"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Use authorized</header><text>In order to provide for the long-term protection, preservation, and enhancement of the Myakka River, the Secretary shall coordinate administration responsibilities under this section, and may enter into cooperative agreements pursuant to sections 10(e) and 11(b)(1) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1281">16 U.S.C. 1281(e)</external-xref>, 1282(b)(1)) with the State of Florida Department of Environmental Protection, Division of Recreation and Parks, appropriate local political jurisdictions of the State, the county of Sarasota, City of North Port, City of Venice and appropriate local planning and non-profit organizations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF2A04725B3E43398DFFFAB2D947F074"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of agreement</header><text>Administration of the Myakka River by the Secretary of the Interior through the use of cooperative agreements shall not—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB246FDB6E1EC45138B3C032C42D89E02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>constitute National Park Service administration of the Myakka River for purposes of section 10(c) of such Act ( U.S.C. 1281(c)); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF809529CFF0941B9BE5CD4977E6FA947"><enum>(B)</enum><text>cause the Myakka River to be considered a unit of the National Park System.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3CC54CDBD3F74D94BC1CA558D6C65755"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publicly owned lands</header><text>Nothing in this Act or an agreement under this Act shall affect the management of publicly or privately owned lands within the boundaries of the Myakka River watershed by the agencies having jurisdiction over the lands, in accordance with the statutory authority of Florida Statute 258.501 and the mission of such agencies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF4EFC2ADF7A741C4BE1377D0BE787504"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Technical assistance and other support</header><text>The Secretary may provide technical assistance, staff support, and funding to assist in the updating and implementation of the comprehensive management plan.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E7194583B1347A687383E5C37F077F8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Acquisition of land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the authority of the Secretary to acquire land for the Myakka River segments shall be limited to acquisition by donation or acquisition with the consent of the owner thereof.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H490952B3D67049348681358500E95FE1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>No condemnation</header><text>No land or interest in land may be acquired for the Myakka River segments by condemnation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6DE65801F9284493BD59574B925D678F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Myakka River Management Council</header> 
<subsection id="H8506B00DA3EB42409A26BCD9E385EF55"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Existing structure</header><text>the Secretary shall coordinate the management responsibilities of the Secretary with the Council in the updating and implementation of the comprehensive management plan for the Myakka River.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF3560280641947D29FFDC13D62F9B604"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Representative from DOI</header><text>The Secretary shall select a representative who shall be added to the Council to represent the National Park Service.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8E82769754664E9A961EA5CDC1FDC29C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional members</header><text>Other interested parties may be added to the Council, in accordance with the statutory authority under Florida Statute 258.501.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7600B538DB8943A29BBB19AA00F7C5E6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination with council</header><text>The Secretary shall coordinate the management responsibilities with the Council in the updating and implementation of the Management plan for the Myakka River, to assist the Secretary in carrying out the management responsibilities of the Secretary under this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

