<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1990297E62594E09BDF17BD63950AFFA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1831 IH: To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to carry out a pilot program for the prevention and mitigation of acts of terrorism using motor vehicles, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1831</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250304">March 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to carry out a pilot program for the prevention and mitigation of acts of terrorism using motor vehicles, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDF883C5BE46E46D0B494CECE41AC9D1E" style="OLC"><section id="H4DE67226E2A942D890FDF016264FB6BB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Pilot program</header><subsection id="H6955840934D543ABB21C490390FAB01E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish a pilot program, for a period not to exceed one year, to—</text><paragraph id="H6BF845AD447641639494D63BBEAF0EC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in consultation with representatives of the automotive sale and rental industry, develop a uniform standard for the type of information collected by rental agencies and the type of information used in submitting suspicious activity reports;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FEDF4FF0FDE419FBD82DE72988CB143"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide operators with a threat assessment prepared by the Undersecretary of Homeland Security for Intelligence and Analysis regarding the terrorism threat of large vehicles;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D07036BB7BB4778995B5F1F07091EC1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>distribute guidance for improving the suspicious activity reporting process, including training for designated employees to better identify suspicious activity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC28BBE78A49D4C9592E0D1073CB80C6B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to operators to better access suspicious activity reports; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB2BCEE23268484D988E069DD60EBE98"><enum>(5)</enum><text>if determined necessary by the Secretary, establish a procedure for checking information against a designated watch list that does not contain any classified information, and for dealers and rental companies to provide notice of a sale or rental to the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC57B49B6394A4F0B810FFFA1997B8E20"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><paragraph id="H41F92BF3A1D84F69A02EA16E49E574C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of establishment of the pilot program under subsection (a) and every 120 days thereafter until the conclusion of the pilot program, the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall jointly submit to Congress a report on the pilot program, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="H0766A9EAE10648808C15AA7E09B66B68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of the impact of the pilot program on privacy and civil liberties.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79B2E0B73FD1424DBBCF94E230E632CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the effect that permanent implementation of the pilot program would have on efforts to protect the United States against terrorist attacks.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H66FD317783F5489C898727D353B39094" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to Congress a study examining how to work with rental car and ride sharing companies (such as through peer to peer apps) to identify risks and threats of terrorist attacks.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA174D24D6162482FA8F5C4F7EF69AA4D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exemption from liability</header><text>A dealer or rental company shall not be liable for any action taken in accordance with this pilot program under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4A4DC3454DFF4C8F918BCCF3A348DD75"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H800697F3E2CC4B1FA99BF0847E5E9728"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered rental vehicle</header><text>The term <quote>covered rental vehicle</quote> means a truck, tractor, trailer, bus, semitrailer, or van capable of transporting more than 15 passengers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E46553CEF12495FBF6D069FD172A68C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dealer; rental company</header><text>The terms <quote>dealer</quote> and <quote>rental company</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 30102 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

