<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HLA25168-0J0-5C-CRF"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S956 IS: Customs Facilitation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 956</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250311" legis-day="20250310">March 11 (legislative day, March 10), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To facilitate the entry and processing of merchandise and trade enforcement, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id26d1cef85b524b03bc31e9f54eefc3b9"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Customs Facilitation Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide33774bf2376497799e2f20a6dfff98d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="S1">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id423582da1f534bb4b7ddb8ae680fa91c">TITLE I—One United States Government at the Border</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ide0e5e906e04a4521a5fe2f7aca532e10">Sec. 101. Border Interagency Executive Council.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id47371940005a4519998924fedfe0538b">Sec. 102. Establishment of single window import and export cargo processing release system.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id878eca6257a44480a03a205555079c08">Sec. 103. Continued modernization of the Automated Commercial Environment.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idb884dce004e14c49bb470bf76af086da">Sec. 104. Authorization of appropriations for uniform system for processing and release of cargo.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id721d1980f20045bda0841b35a646264d">TITLE II—Modernizing Customs Processes</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idd1d18065941c44658fa3291abc0d0b8a">Sec. 201. Simplification of drawback procedures.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ida38aab1eb0ae4c8d8b6b824326acd9bc">Sec. 202. Streamlined export processes.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idb40eccf24e884956b1f4e3bd23785128">Sec. 203. Treatment of clerical errors in submission of export data.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id4069a71c5e544e1a899d61f5f5e36ab3">Sec. 204. Government Accountability Office report on fee schedule of U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ide4ad63138c4949788468352f22134c05">Sec. 205. Improvements to Centers of Excellence and Expertise.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="idcbb7b36409a943699b8b7bd6636f6c55">TITLE III—Improving Customs Data and Transparency</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id25817e5062cd443cad5a7a633ba49511">Sec. 301. Requirements for regulations relating to data collection for trade enforcement and facilitation.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id2894ba6d944947c6b500e6b43dfaf7f4">Sec. 302. Updates to U.S. Customs and Border Protection website and Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism Trade Compliance Handbook.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ida8ce39a04884408abdecd1fd12ef6c01">Sec. 303. Establishment of deadlines for agency responses to trade community requests.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id93b965bced934bf9a2456b09a14dda9f">Sec. 304. Accessibility of contact information of representatives of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and Centers of Excellence and Expertise.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><title id="id423582da1f534bb4b7ddb8ae680fa91c" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>One United States Government at the Border</header><section id="ide0e5e906e04a4521a5fe2f7aca532e10"><enum>101.</enum><header>Border Interagency Executive Council</header><subsection id="idafbe6997fa2b4944bedf3a5ed3768650"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established an interagency working group, to be known as the Border Interagency Executive Council (in this section referred to as the <quote>Council</quote>), to serve as an interagency forum to facilitate the development of policies and processes to enhance coordination across customs, transport security, health and safety, sanitary, conservation, trade, and phytosanitary agencies with border management authorities—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id494979619e0a443dbbb48fa24caed321"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to measurably improve supply chain processes and the identification of illicit shipments; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69e032a6f6cb4e30a57a753f69776dbe"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to facilitate and expedite the flow of legitimate trade.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb19d7ae3b31040e5875757e07ff9cd58"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Oversight</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall oversee the Council.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide9317bbfa64d43faacd38a566faea3a0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chairperson; vice chairperson</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id12d426dd7e474d49afdd4c97856d66ad"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection or a senior-level designee from U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall serve as the chairperson of the Council.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida7153fd9dab646a6895c3ff6e1e3fd2b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vice chairperson</header><text>There shall be a vice chairperson of the Council, who shall be selected every 2 years from among the members of the Council by a process determined by the members.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8adcdd85aa9e468faa68a945b1b64a59"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id19e106abf6b045c99cd849b19d2bfa1e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the chairperson and vice chairperson, the Council shall include designated senior-level representatives who are full-time or permanent part-time employees of Federal agencies that provide approval before merchandise can be imported into or exported from the United States, or that otherwise have the authority to establish or enforce requirements relating to the importation or exportation of merchandise, including the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf9f25fed7a8e4a8a8d29b1b9d57e13a6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id88a792ee9e594b3fbfe2755a5bd1fc6c"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of the Treasury. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id54e81b5c3d854f789f77a4b576803430"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Defense. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb5bd69880aec4d1c8cbf6f1fe6dea7e2"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of the Interior. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7286570c75534055a68af8a8deaf980a"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Agriculture. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id95143d6f449f4d9ea53acedd20469abd"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Commerce. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idea14478cf27743cb880700105febfd34"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Health and Human Services. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9d729349a2af48ea8056187a050b63ea"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Transportation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida91fbba0ee184382825b6ede11052f50"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Homeland Security. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idacbe77c9f8534d0d8a464c984c77ea9b"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Environmental Protection Agency. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idee4a9dfd6a3f4e7eb3037163fc257045"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such other Federal agencies, including independent regulatory and quasi-judicial agencies and commissions, as the chairperson and vice chairperson consider appropriate. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc62a333c10849e7a4fa786bb336dcf8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Representatives of Executive Office of President</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council may also include appropriate representatives of the Executive Office of the President.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddd36d0a2dd704dff913029337cb3ac14"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Waiver of participation</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may waive the participation, in whole or in part, of representatives of any agency specified in paragraph (1) in the Council if the Secretary considers it appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida80771ceb952440ca98b4546d34187ff"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Functions of Council</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council shall—</text><paragraph id="id2ac911a4b676448ca7fbd84a6bbf28ca"><enum>(1)</enum><text>facilitate the development of common risk management principles and methods to inform agency operations associated with the review and release of cargo at the border and to support compliance with applicable law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id538cd5fdfa0b4a41b68c5afbd4bcaf7e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>facilitate the development of policies and processes to coordinate, improve, and accelerate agency review of electronic trade-related documentation or information transmitted, or otherwise made available, through relevant systems and provide coordinated and streamlined responses back to users to facilitate trade and support compliance with applicable law and international agreements;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4eef8f3430444e88bafc2b2eefa485d3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify opportunities to use documentation or information relating to the importation of merchandise, including documentation or information provided prior to the arrival of merchandise into the customs territory of the United States or the filing of an entry of merchandise with U.S. Customs and Border Protection, to facilitate priority processing and the expedited release of such merchandise from the custody of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and to reduce redundancies in the trade data that each party in a supply chain is required to provide;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9731a94c2d12447c94427dfafc55fc81"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identify opportunities to streamline Federal Government systems and reduce costs through the elimination of redundant capabilities and through enhanced utilization of the capabilities of the Automated Commercial Environment, or any successor system, as a means of improving supply chain management processes;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id181890f4cf2b439e92be62ec929dda85"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identify opportunities to enhance whole-of-Government trade processing capabilities, including capabilities relating to processing cargo manifests, collection of advance import and export data, uniform cargo admissibility and release processes, entry summaries, and cargo financial data, in the Automated Commercial Environment, or any successor system, that conform with the criteria for the admissibility of merchandise of all agencies represented on the Council;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idfa8b0f8748234fca8571b34567112528"><enum>(6)</enum><text>enhance uniformity, consistency, and transparency, by facilitating the development, to the extent practicable and consistent with applicable law, of a standard nomenclature, including definitions of relevant terms, across and within the Federal agencies represented on the Council for—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide008d5be70824946b25f6f94ca689951"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any party in the supply chain; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9cd6efe117404858825a35e94e95e468"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any event related to the importation or exportation of merchandise or any customs program; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id57c7a0138d104e34bb20b96d691064f1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>engage with and consider input from the trade community and other relevant stakeholders regarding opportunities to improve supply chain processes and the processing of imported and exported merchandise, with the goal of promoting economic competitiveness through enhanced trade facilitation and enforcement;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7a90b93bc93e4e8aafb67ff2a46b23ab"><enum>(8)</enum><text>encourage other countries to develop similar trade processing capabilities, including single window systems, to facilitate the sharing of relevant trade data, as appropriate, across governmental systems and with trading partners; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id96b599bf0d924369a7c76e45ad0ad6f0"><enum>(9)</enum><text>assess opportunities to facilitate electronic payment of duties, taxes, fees, and charges imposed under Federal law upon entry of merchandise.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide4e36b7e6b344494a0d624b88d59f1d1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69a9a61ccdc348b48642a05aeded2441"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not later than December 31 of every other year thereafter, the Council shall make available to the public a report that describes the progress that the Council has made toward carrying out the functions described under subsection (e).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f9bb7912dbe46c9b4a42cade6382857"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public comment</header><text>The Council shall provide an opportunity for public comment on the report required by paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08df29f6b97a4e02a51d62b9aaaa40dc"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Continuation of members</header><text>An individual serving as a member of the Border Interagency Executive Council established by Executive Order 13659 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1411">19 U.S.C. 1411</external-xref> note; relating to streamlining the export/import process for America’s businesses) on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act may continue to serve as a member of the Council established by subsection (a). </text></subsection></section><section id="id47371940005a4519998924fedfe0538b"><enum>102.</enum><header>Establishment of single window import and export cargo processing release system</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ffdb38c7fa546d5ac70d2a062dfa4d9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to advance the national economic security, trade enforcement, and trade facilitation missions of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and partner government agencies of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that a scalable, uniform automated platform provides a system for the processing and release of cargo being imported into and exported from the United States.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc20603eb02ef4655bdf24610d5f920c8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The system required by subsection (a) shall include the following elements:</text><paragraph id="id407bd83c710b4e9d8a1cfd5e61ccd5d7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Incorporation of whole-of-Government trade processing capabilities, including capabilities relating to processing cargo manifests, collection of advance import and export data, uniform cargo admissibility and release processes, entry summaries, and cargo financial data, in the Automated Commercial Environment, or any successor system, to conform with the admissibility criteria of—</text><subparagraph id="idb74a22f8b0104f04984a16ed51d7f7a1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Automated Commercial Environment, or any successor system; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd73d6a8ddcb6461fb90e2e1014788cc9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all agencies—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf08b068c23174d2a94b5b9e0d5dccba6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">participating in the International Trade Data System established under section 411(d) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1411">19 U.S.C. 1411(d)</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause id="id46a87404bcab49328e7a296ea1315a25"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>represented on the Border Interagency Executive Council, established in section 101.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id63774e77887e4d699bb2d9e03e824ebe"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Continued collaboration with the head of each agency participating in the International Trade Data System to make efforts to ensure that—</text><subparagraph id="id8d5a4a5a66af45f3a491bab4c82784ef"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if data required by a partner government agency is already available in the Automated Commercial Environment, or any successor system, as a result of a requirement of U.S. Customs and Border Protection or another agency, the system will populate that data for the purpose of reporting the data to the partner government agency and the data will not need to be reported again through a separate submission, unless U.S. Customs and Border Protection or the partner government agency determines an additional submission is necessary to confirm the accuracy of data received from 2 or more sources;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd317413046c4e86a4b95466272e5fbc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Automated Commercial Environment, or a successor system, provides a partner government agency with any data that is needed to facilitate the coordination and efficient execution of inspections conducted by that partner government agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2b2a6e79561c438a9e2d39ad5843c809"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a partner government agency interested in obtaining import and export data and conducting or directing its own inspections is able to do so through the manifest and entry functionality of the Automated Commercial Environment, or a successor system, and in real time when entries and manifests are submitted, rather than as a redelivery process when cargo may have already been delivered; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id61df1eed59ae4817b742f9e45f88b526"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a partner government agency interested in obtaining clearance data clearly indicates all headings and subheadings of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States that are subject to its jurisdiction, such that the agency is identified when any such heading or subheading of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule is submitted into the Automated Commercial Environment or a successor system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id03465bf61d3448e0b7cf06e75f0e0fde"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other feature determined by the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection to be necessary to substantially advance the national economic security, trade enforcement, and trade facilitation missions of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and partner government agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1a9788da2bb046b3897b3d05a76f8857"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assessment</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id01e4469886f249d7b0396f528ff652bf"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall complete an assessment of whether a technology solution that is capable of delivering the system required by subsection (a) is commercially available.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id21d8d78ef00d4199aa70586f4923d3b6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>If the Commissioner decides not to acquire a commercially available technology to satisfy the system requirement of subsection (a), the Commissioner shall submit to Congress a report that includes a description of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9a39b36fcadd45c69a086899f7df2916"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if applicable, the determination that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc198d2a2065345dc8645ebfb8cebb9c2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>developing the system required by subsection (a) is more cost effective than acquiring such system from a commercial source; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideaf4f9e108534dc09548cc1b7e62bf06"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a system developed by U.S. Customs and Border Protection can more adequately address the needs of partner government agencies and the trade community than a system acquired from a commercial source; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide3db3c0c273348d3823b8d398d134ce7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the manner by which the Commissioner will provide the system required by subsection (a) within the timeline and meeting the requirements set forth in subsection (d).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70d86b827e714176ac2770b0240fd9d8"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Implementation of the system</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb91165e0f73a4009944d6b91a54ae86f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under section 104 are first made available to U.S. Customs and Border Protection, the Commissioner shall implement the system required by subsection (a). </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8e9e471024ba46c099ffe89d544e4336"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In implementing the system required by subsection (a), the Commissioner shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd84a9afa44a445db8d55ec6f0cfeb3d1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collaborate with the Trade Support Network and other members of the trade community as the Commissioner considers appropriate; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7213e02fdb294d4bb173a8359c0007ea"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that the system provides the same or greater functionality as any system being replaced by the system required by subsection (a), to include functionality with respect to the ability of partner government agencies and the trade community to conduct ordinary business; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id247a11f4e9cc404783e3ec8b7222ac13"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that the system provides the features envisioned in the 21st Century Customs Framework of U.S. Customs and Border Protection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7c72e70498f5420b9d0e42c733ad9b37"><enum><italic></italic>(D)</enum><text>if unable to timely provide a feature of the system required by this section, consult with the Trade Support Network and other members of the trade community, as the Commissioner considers appropriate, to provide a feature of equal importance. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49c4f54a4a1543f4bbaa27569c3872d5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exemption from the Federal Advisory Committee Act</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to this section or to other efforts of U.S. Customs and Border Protection to collaborate with members of the trade community with respect to the development of the system required by subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide4bbde3d6c5543c09dbe1d03e765d1c5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Modifications To ensure operation of International Trade Data System</header><text>Section 411(d)(4)(A) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1411">19 U.S.C. 1411(d)(4)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7d9de5903c8b45e5b1dc0e81b9b82848"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>and the Interagency Steering Committee</quote> and inserting <quote>, the Interagency Steering Committee, and the Border Interagency Executive Council (established by section 101 of the <short-title>Customs Facilitation Act of 2025</short-title>), as appropriate, and in consultation with the Commercial Customs Operations Advisory Committee, Trade Support Network, and other members of the trade community as the Secretary considers necessary,</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8165fbc298644a581b33bc2fef44b8b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (i), by striking the semicolon and inserting <quote>; and</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb10dddd7d9164fd4836833930dac3a60"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking the semicolon and inserting a period; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida9fdcb1f85964294be747eaf3209a3d3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by striking clauses (iii) and (iv). </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id878eca6257a44480a03a205555079c08"><enum>103.</enum><header>Continued modernization of the Automated Commercial Environment</header><subsection id="idb1d8445e67754566987e77dbf08efe8b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order to advance the national economic security, trade enforcement, and trade facilitation missions of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and partner government agencies of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide for the continuous modernization of the Automated Commercial Environment or a successor system.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7e7132fd0a014845876dc04f0ef7284d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id46df6d8e2d624338b63cde1b3c51da45"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Development priorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, in consultation with the Commercial Customs Operations Advisory Committee (established under section 109 of the Trade Facilitation and Trade Enforcement Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4316">19 U.S.C. 4316</external-xref>)), the Trade Support Network, and any other member of the trade community the Commissioner considers appropriate, shall determine the development priorities for the Automated Commercial Environment, or a successor system. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3bd4e86721824f7cb415ca47c7fe2fd4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Collaboration with partner government agencies and industry</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbd67c47dca3744a1b2fa30ef3d7f20cf"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall collaborate with partner government agencies, the Commercial Customs Operations Advisory Committee, the Trade Support Network, and any other member of the trade community the Commissioner considers appropriate, to ensure that any enhancement to the Automated Commercial Environment, or a successor system, is effectively delivered to Federal agencies and to the trade community.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4fc3ae6004de4171b359d4780e2f629a"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Meetings</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0ebdad319c7f4dc7ae97e8c0cca86d55"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and as frequently as the Commissioner considers appropriate thereafter, but not less frequently than every 30 days, the Commissioner shall convene meetings to solicit feedback on enhancements to the Automated Commercial Environment, or a successor system.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id32b97913fb174a6bbc7279c086fac097"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Attendees</header><text>For each meeting convened under clause (i), the Commissioner shall invite— </text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e5e6d1942ab4b03a893695d40a71eb7"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any representative from a partner government agency or member of the trade community who has a stake in the system feature being discussed at the meeting; </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55ef5f20648d49af84631ff7abf7efcc"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any contractor or technical expert that the Commissioner considers appropriate; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idacce867190104f47a6f9170e98d91a92"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any other stakeholder the Commissioner considers appropriate. </text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfe3d9e5d4d9b4fc688f51eb304ae8992"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Tasks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each meeting convened under clause (i), the Commissioner shall—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id630602a8a1854cd2b17a454e55914ee1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solicit feedback on any enhancement to the Automated Commercial Environment, or a successor system, that is planned, in development, or newly implemented and is addressed at the meeting; </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc9f7786ef6ec4e1eb720a9e31e3ec4a3"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct user testing or research with respect to any enhancement to the Automated Commercial Environment that is planned, in development, or newly implemented; </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id730a4e81255f4b4e9b7eee7c541d6dbd"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain a summary of the feedback received with respect to each such enhancement; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id29f820cb9eb94688915d00e32a9aba9e"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>incorporate, to the extent practicable and as aligned with the development priorities determined under paragraph (1), the results of any testing or research conducted under subclause (II) into the development of any such enhancement. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf895c51e7dc54ee181e841cae94b7a35"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Management of communication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner shall establish, through the use of a ticketing system or such other means as the Commissioner considers appropriate, a mechanism to manage communication relating to the Automated Commercial Environment, or a successor system, under which users of the Automated Commercial Environment, or such successor system, may report feedback, including with respect to bugs or any other issue, and the appropriate contractor or agency may review and respond to such feedback.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id909f36049bab4873b1b24bd6f9a4c4d2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Commissioner shall submit to Congress and make available to the public a report that describes the development progress of the Automated Commercial Environment, or any successor system. </text></subsection></section><section id="idb884dce004e14c49bb470bf76af086da"><enum>104.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations for uniform system for processing and release of cargo</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Homeland Security for fiscal year 2026, and each fiscal year thereafter, such sums as may be necessary to carry out improvements in a scalable, uniform automated platform that provides a system for the processing and release of cargo being imported into and exported from the United States, including improvements to and integration of the Automated Commercial Environment, or any successor system, as described in section 102.</text></section></title><title id="id721d1980f20045bda0841b35a646264d" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Modernizing Customs Processes</header><section id="idd1d18065941c44658fa3291abc0d0b8a"><enum>201.</enum><header>Simplification of drawback procedures</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc06d9d35db174e5387966e8185927f0d"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 313 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1313">19 U.S.C. 1313</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after subsection (s) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd69009207d4f4fbea4d80338b5b1c798"><subsection id="id2aa9bfdabf074f82ab45e3dea2af41bc"><enum>(t)</enum><header>Simplification of drawback procedures</header><paragraph id="id8d5eb7af13de4e998dee46031a361cc5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Accelerated payment</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3a83b84fd6e749d9a3dd42bbf374b6c7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person that meets the requirements of paragraph (3) and files a claim for drawback under this section shall be paid all estimated duties, taxes, and fees covered by the claim while the liquidation of the claim is pending. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided9f29a119f04e73a3d5621cae2a6cb1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Estimated payment exceeds liquidated amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the amount of estimated duties, taxes, and fees paid by U.S. Customs and Border Protection under subparagraph (A) for a drawback claim exceeds an amount that is $20 more than the final liquidated amount for that claim, the person that filed the claim shall refund to U.S. Customs and Border Protection the amount by which the amount of estimated duties, taxes, and fees paid by U.S. Customs and Border Protection exceeds the final liquidated amount. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7de750134a664f70b627a78edfe4d62c"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Liquidated amount exceeds estimated payment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the final liquidated amount for a drawback claim exceeds an amount that is $20 more than the amount of estimated duties, taxes, and fees paid by U.S. Customs and Border Protection under subparagraph (A) for the claim, U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall provide to the person that filed the claim an additional refund in the amount by which the final liquidated amount exceeds the amount of estimated duties, taxes, and fees paid by U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide30127eda2464cb6b2742eca06cad4d5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prior notice of export not required</header><text>A person that meets the requirements of paragraph (3) shall not be required to provide notice to U.S. Customs and Border Protection of an export of merchandise to be used in a claim for drawback under this section before exporting the merchandise.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id88f17a3169b6451e9d5b2239cf0b22fc"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements for claimants</header><text>A person meets the requirements of this paragraph if the person has completed the following:</text><subparagraph id="idab2c58982f9549cf9d91d7ca9e25cb34"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Submitted to U.S. Customs and Border Protection information and supporting documentation kept by the person in the normal course of business that evidences the ability of the person to file for and claim drawback under this section, which submission shall—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id120872becc184518b0366b1487c37e1f"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be deemed complete when submitted to U.S. Customs and Border Protection by the person; and </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5b55593c5b2a4e588b9d87436a906a66"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">apply to all claims for drawback filed by the person under this section after the completion of the submission.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id56d7727177024ef097ed8a309028edcb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Obtained a properly executed bond securing, pending liquidation of a drawback claim, repayment of 100 percent of the estimated duties, taxes, and fees covered by the claim.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id84c964fac5ec4e60887f1b16653f32ea"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Electronic filings for drawback claims</header><text>A person making a claim for drawback under this section shall be allowed to file an amendment to, or perfection of, a drawback claim through electronic means.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id6de1985c2e1e433f93aff4703c85fc7f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prior approval not required for substitution drawback</header><text>Section 313(b) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1313">19 U.S.C. 1313(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id31338768046B411E9DD2522A17C3330F"><paragraph id="idba519fa6e6e748cfb401f7fc2f936f2f"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Advance approval of claims not required</header><text>A person filing a claim for drawback under paragraph (1) shall not be required to obtain any ruling or approval authorizing drawback under that paragraph from the U.S. Customs and Border Protection before filing the claim, but shall exercise reasonable care in determining whether to obtain such a ruling in advance of the filing.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id528b7fa1b3ed40f8ad82dbbaeab5d034"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall prescribe regulations specifying the information required to be included in submissions made under subsection (t) of section 313 of the Tariff Act of 1930, as added by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="ida38aab1eb0ae4c8d8b6b824326acd9bc"><enum>202.</enum><header>Streamlined export processes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 304 of title 13, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69EB33DBC9C94F1C96FD51B8F483F51D"><subsection commented="no" id="id5874733130274a6280e70185ed003a0a"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations relating to advance information</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideb2b71554cf34c8aade7ce3b4dfe100f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce shall prescribe regulations to account for advance documentation or information and reports described in subsection (a) made available with respect to cargo before the exportation or transportation of the cargo. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6ec09fcce5a24d9c974178122b1f2f82"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consideration of timelines for submission</header><text>In prescribing regulations under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id906fcb32210546c8bb97920c6a885714"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider how the different business models of persons submitting advance documentation or information under subsection (a) impact the availability of the documentation or information; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id54e8c1d001424bf8bc1b5421cb5bf236"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adjust the timelines required for the submission of that documentation or information as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2c3fc2ba8cf8423085d7dde5719d81ba"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Avoidance of redundancy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If information relating to the exportation or transportation of cargo provided under this section or section 431 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1431">19 U.S.C. 1431</external-xref>) is redundant with information required to be provided under any other provision of law, the Secretary shall, pursuant to the regulations prescribed under paragraph (1), work jointly with the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection to ensure that the provision of the information under this section or such section 431 satisfies the requirement to provide the information under such other provision of law, to the extent practicable.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idb40eccf24e884956b1f4e3bd23785128"><enum>203.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Treatment of clerical errors in submission of export data</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 305(b) of title 13, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id039a1f0264874fb48d6722a7fb71ea33"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id567B0FDDEC754C4F945CA40EA68E9FFA"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc491edba23d044a0b9070198ffe4bb70"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbd07d7841656475eb2e06a50bb4943a2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD2112FA811AE419AA4627D566ABF4420"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf703af04f8464127b16fba3f2c1315b2"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Treatment of clerical errors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1), clerical errors or mistakes of fact are not violations unless they are part of a pattern of violative conduct. The mere nonintentional repetition by an electronic system of an initial clerical error does not constitute a pattern of violative conduct.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id4069a71c5e544e1a899d61f5f5e36ab3"><enum>204.</enum><header>Government Accountability Office report on fee schedule of U.S. Customs and Border Protection</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the fee schedule of U.S. Customs and Border Protection that includes—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4beff695a2e34746aa9496cb207b045a"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc1d31d9555a4af1aed0aa0e7c074598"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how that schedule might be restructured; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddab2c1e5c21544848b09815e023216c2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ways—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id793ebbfc111a40358194ec7a40774425"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to reduce costs for the entities in the trade community that are the most compliant with the customs and trade laws of the United States (as defined in section 2 of the Trade Facilitation and Trade Enforcement Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4301">19 U.S.C. 4301</external-xref>)); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id684ac561429446ed96bb6426b919c1da"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to ensure that all entities that benefit from customs services provided by U.S. Customs and Border Protection pay for those services; and </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfee7e81e39a348c49d942b543cb405ce"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations for Congress. </text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide4ad63138c4949788468352f22134c05"><enum>205.</enum><header>Improvements to Centers of Excellence and Expertise</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 110(a) of the Trade Facilitation and Trade Enforcement Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4317">19 U.S.C. 4317(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc394f0084b60466583990c7bf33cf0e9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc3b9bce13814f19931ea5f472668302"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking the period and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida6d3832345784d53b1cf36a27d79de1d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id87AD0DC05AEB45DD9CC0A6F41E76A7A0" act-name=""><paragraph id="id4E18866823E7473EBCE32C9EE0A49410"><enum>(10)</enum><text>develop procedures, informed compliance publications, or other guidance with respect to the entry of merchandise in compliance with the law; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5e429a0c0cdd47a4b16f4e384fa4d66d"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide guidance to importers on the post-entry and clearance procedures for imported merchandise impacted by admissibility issues including alleged violations of section 307 of the Trade Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1307">19 U.S.C. 1307</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></title><title id="idcbb7b36409a943699b8b7bd6636f6c55" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Improving Customs Data and Transparency</header><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id25817e5062cd443cad5a7a633ba49511"><enum>301.</enum><header>Requirements for regulations relating to data collection for trade enforcement and facilitation</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id58cd05d6f2ea43919f26177488df0ec6"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Requirements for new regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing and imposing regulations requiring the collection of additional information for the purposes of trade enforcement and facilitation, each official described in subsection (b) shall adhere to the following:</text><paragraph id="idb5fe1108b12b484aa0e34291303faf4d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The official shall solicit comments from and consult with a broad range of parties likely to be affected by the regulations, including importers, exporters, carriers, customs brokers, platforms, and freight forwarders, and other interested parties.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id235f4b4bdb774b878e1fb1afc506bffa"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In general, the requirement to provide particular information shall be imposed on parties with direct knowledge of that information, as appropriate. Where requiring information from a party with direct knowledge of that information is not practicable, the regulations shall take into account how, under ordinary and reasonable commercial practices, information is acquired by a party on which the requirement is imposed, and whether and how such party is reasonably able to verify the information. Where information is not reasonably verifiable by a party on which a requirement is imposed, the regulations shall permit that party to transmit information on the basis of what the party reasonably believes to be true based on commercially reasonable practices.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id300e1bb93ca54c6c922ae98a0276c056"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The official shall take into account the existence of competitive relationships among the parties on which requirements to provide particular information are imposed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id34e6295d0ccd4f119ef4974dd7f6a5bb"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Where the regulations impose requirements on carriers of cargo, the regulations shall take into account differences among different modes of transportation, including differences in commercial practices, operational characteristics, and technological capacity to collect and transmit information electronically.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4bf1a60283214f3285e0e56a18530448"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The regulations shall take into account the extent to which the technology necessary for parties to transmit and U.S. Customs and Border Protection to receive and analyze data in a timely fashion is available. To the extent the official determines that the necessary technology will not be widely available to particular modes of transportation or other affected parties until after promulgation of the regulations, the regulations shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77933f30f30c4524b2ce46e1f6dac817"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide interim requirements appropriate for the technology that is available at the time of promulgation; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id88c847320076460faa5021b65be32c16"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other accommodations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id862892f271fd4633bc91f7be9885b499"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In determining the timing for transmittal of any information, the official shall balance likely impact on flow of commerce with impact on trade enforcement. With respect to requirements that may be imposed on carriers of cargo, the timing for transmittal of information shall take into account differences among different modes of transportation, as described in paragraph (4).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2b064ba6b90c4ad385864d059e38c4a0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Where practicable, the regulations shall avoid imposing requirements that are redundant with one another or that are redundant with requirements in other provisions of law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1d64fef0094c4f82aa1122ee0fdd5ba6"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The official shall determine whether it is appropriate to provide transition periods between promulgation of the regulations and the effective date of the regulations and shall prescribe such transition periods in the regulations, as appropriate, taking into account different business models.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7956445e05204fa4b1e52bf903a6f402"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The official shall, in collaboration with the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and the Postmaster General, prescribe regulations requiring the United States Postal Service to transmit the information described in this subsection to the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection for international mail shipments by the Postal Service (including shipments to the Postal Service from foreign postal operators that are transported by private carrier). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id10891bd30db642d4abb0ffd8f40bde3e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Officials described</header><text>The officials described in this subsection are—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5114ab982079419aaa2a0cc530599938"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of the Treasury;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ee47cce4e8342cb87113f1f4da11fe3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Homeland Security; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf76cc118a5184be8a4ecb96892d48159"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the head of each agency represented on the Border Interagency Executive Council established by section 101. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id2894ba6d944947c6b500e6b43dfaf7f4"><enum>302.</enum><header>Updates to U.S. Customs and Border Protection website and Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism Trade Compliance Handbook</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5404793c36de41f288faf1cc234d760f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notification of changes</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5e7f3ad7964c49fa802ccaac103792c8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall consult with and notify members of the trade community if content related to minimum security criteria is added to or removed from the publicly accessible website of U.S. Customs and Border Protection or the Trade Compliance Handbook for the Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0d3a2873d50e4270830af8ff24654312"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Content of notifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A notification required by paragraph (1) shall include a summary and explanation of the reasons for the addition or removal of the content.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id64a13d62259b4e88946bd5a588bb1106"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Model</header><text>The Commissioner shall use the process of the United States International Trade Commission for disclosing modifications to the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States as a model for the notification required by paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide3bf570feada4536bd7ce8100afc4af1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additions to Trade Compliance Handbook</header><text>In addition to providing the notification required by subsection (a)(1), the Commissioner shall consult with members of the trade community with respect to any new requirements that may be added to the Trade Compliance Handbook of the Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc32745bfd9964c1b9fafecfa639cd7ab"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Revisions to Trade Compliance Handbook</header><text>The Commissioner shall revise the Trade Compliance Handbook of the Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism to include constructive and detailed context for best practices for mitigating the risk of importing merchandise produced using forced labor.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3683b20307154935ab3a8d3427b36584"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultations with Forced Labor Enforcement Task Force</header><text>In revising the Trade Compliance Handbook of the Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism under this section, the Commissioner shall consult with the Forced Labor Enforcement Task Force to ensure consistent messaging and streamlining of resources. </text></subsection></section><section id="ida8ce39a04884408abdecd1fd12ef6c01"><enum>303.</enum><header>Establishment of deadlines for agency responses to trade community requests</header><subsection id="idfb5c9a74eaab42e1b1dadb81c971de53"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e08be555293430ab9981451828e01cb"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall review any regulations governing deadlines for rulings and decisions of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, including with respect to petitions, protests, and requests for advice, and customs rulings; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98193995546847dbac805976099720d4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may, in consultation with members of the Commercial Customs Operations Advisory Committee, revise such regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6fc7d1422f3b4020bc07ea82dbe9868b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Updates to existing deadlines</header><text>In a case in which a deadline is already established for a response described in subsection (a), the Commissioner shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id853d98e6300945ecb5988de90c5e5287"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review the deadline; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd13112ea52c24f67bee96726f5c79c9b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if appropriate, revise the deadline to be more expeditious.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3f11189e3ed141a18238c1efbc087cce"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress and make available to the public a report on rulings and decisions of U.S. Customs and Border Protection that includes—</text><paragraph id="id52ba0894dde1440499a449b56091c5f4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of—</text><subparagraph id="idd81e908bab1e408889ca42ef03038d54"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the average annual number of rulings and decisions described in subsection (a) considered by U.S. Customs and Border Protection, including such rulings and decisions that are not subject to a statutory or regulatory deadline;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id808d4d9582ca40dcb35dc1f4d4b66b8f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the average response time of U.S. Customs and Border Protection to petitions, protests, and requests for advice, including the total amount of responses made before and after the applicable statutory or regulatory deadline;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id35e434adbe5f40258b7254d6657a2b68"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the average time for issuance of customs rulings by U.S. Customs and Border Protection, including the total amount of rulings issued before and after the applicable statutory or regulatory deadline;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id207ef6e5388e4b17ae50789884b073f2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>for deadlines not met, the average time it took for U.S. Customs and Border Protection to respond or issue a ruling; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf404605b4a184213a604d477db0155be"><enum>(E)</enum><text>reasons provided by U.S. Customs and Border Protection explaining why the deadlines were not met; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idddaf5a753c6c4a49abd66b60b89cda33"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of rulings and decisions not subject to a statutory or regulatory deadline, reasons for the length of time for issuing such rulings and making such decisions;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf611d03cb5374757aaf94dee87e6519d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the petition and protest process, including timelines that apply under statutes or regulations as of the date of the report; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc31ddb3d1d654e188558ab6488911dbd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations for Congress on improving the time taken by U.S. Customs and Border Protection to respond to petitions, protests, and requests for advice and to issue rulings. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id93b965bced934bf9a2456b09a14dda9f"><enum>304.</enum><header>Accessibility of contact information of representatives of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and Centers of Excellence and Expertise</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall develop a system to assist members of the trade community in quickly and easily identifying up-to-date contact information for—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2a21b3445e2f498b8db06cd733e8ebd7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">personnel within the headquarters of U.S. Customs and Border Protection that interact with members of the trade community;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc23676c4add8446f809c50362b466abe"><enum>(2)</enum><text>personnel of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and partner government agencies at ports of entry that interact with members of the trade community; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id123ec0cfa4374622844962b77fb11311"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">personnel of the Centers of Excellence and Expertise established under section 110 of the Trade Facilitation and Trade Enforcement Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4317">19 U.S.C. 4317</external-xref>) that interact with members of the trade community.</text></paragraph></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

