<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCB47119165A54718A70787AC2B943E57" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 705 IH: To direct the Secretary of Defense to establish a compensation fund for military firefighters exposed to PFAS.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 705</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250123">January 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to establish a compensation fund for military firefighters exposed to PFAS.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8B790D6ADE7642C3B0B41F5DB2891F8C" style="OLC"><section id="H0B59C71008E84A768632FC9193E5197B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Compensation fund for military firefighters</header><subsection id="H485C4D4D134C4D668928466EE08663D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program and fund established</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall establish a program and fund to be known as the <quote>Military Firefighters Compensation Fund</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1112D3446D8D46D2AC078312812447BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose of program</header><text>The purpose of the compensation program is to provide for timely, uniform, and adequate compensation to current and former military firefighters and, where applicable, survivors of such employees, suffering from illnesses incurred by such employees in the performance of duty for the Department of Defense and certain of its contractors and subcontractors due to exposure to per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances, or PFAS.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD89A44EB2948400999975ACAA8ACF9B4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>PFAS exposure</header><text>Current and former military firefighters shall, in the absence of substantial evidence to the contrary, be determined to have been exposed to PFAS in the performance of duty for the purposes of the compensation program if such firefighter was employed at a military installation, facility of the National Guard, of formerly used defense site during a period when PFAS would have been present at such facility.</text></subsection><subsection id="H873FEBB8E6634BD0BC51AEC080B1719C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Compensation provided</header><text>A current or former military firefighter, or the survivor of such firefighter if the firefighter is deceased, shall receive compensation for the disability or death of that employee from that employee’s occupational illness.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEA396B6EA179462E8336E5AEA12A5103"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Payments in the case of deceased persons</header><paragraph id="H426647B911B243DE816DC6B8818326AB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Claim filed</header><text>In the case of a military firefighter who is deceased at the time of payment of compensation under this section, whether or not the death is the result of the firefighter’s occupational illness, such payment may be made only as follows:</text><subparagraph id="H423C72AEB81F48CFBC2DEBC3A33FF7FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>If the military firefighter is survived by a spouse who is living at the time of payment, such payment shall be made to such surviving spouse.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFDF0AA7F6D34FD5878FEA9166E09998"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If there is no surviving spouse described in subparagraph (A), such payment shall be made in equal shares to all children of the military firefighter who are living at the time of payment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E94B11590E44FCA9B3FAB82C1DA6E49"><enum>(C)</enum><text>If there is no surviving spouse described in subparagraph (A) and if there are no children described in subparagraph (B), such payment shall be made in equal shares to the parents of the military firefighter who are living at the time of payment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F1934511EA7466182E7473E23C51F0E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>If there is no surviving spouse described in subparagraph (A), and if there are no children described in subparagraph (B) or parents described in subparagraph (C), such payment shall be made in equal shares to all grandchildren of the military firefighter who are living at the time of payment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD808F495130E4F68A9FF2A0D75F7A737"><enum>(E)</enum><text>If there is no surviving spouse described in subparagraph (A), and if there are no children described in subparagraph (B), parents described in subparagraph (C), or grandchildren described in subparagraph (D), then such payment shall be made in equal shares to the grandparents of the military firefighter who are living at the time of payment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5123BAFC40C4D84A6088624A0B302FD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Notwithstanding the other provisions of this paragraph, if there is—</text><clause id="H5C1DA5EBFE2D4D6D966BF27EDC61D2FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a surviving spouse described in subparagraph (A); and</text></clause><clause id="H75B923CF41D74057AF1BBFF9EF26EA22"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at least one child of the military firefighter who is living and a minor at the time of payment and who is not a recognized natural child or adopted child of such surviving spouse, then half of such payment shall be made to such surviving spouse, and the other half of such payment shall be made in equal shares to each child of the military firefighter who is living and a minor at the time of payment.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4EFF25273DD4593933DFF39FCAB7B5E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Before filing of claim</header><text>If a current or former military firefighter eligible for payment dies before filing a claim under this section, a survivor of that firefighter who may receive payment under paragraph (1) may file a claim for such payment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BBAEC60A8FE4E3CADC9D7CC06929BA5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="HD5E9686AB3B145AE947D19CB16128F1C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <quote>child</quote> includes a recognized natural child, a stepchild who lived with an individual in a regular parent-child relationship, or an adopted child.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94CA10F6785143D8B43578D0A1DC3F79"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <quote>grandchild</quote> means the child of a child of an individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0A94BE747F74DF3A30676556C133575"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term <quote>grandparent</quote> means the parent of a parent of an individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD90A9AD9A83E485CBAFCB976D29C509F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The term <quote>parent</quote> includes fathers and mothers through adoption.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB3C0761324347B88B6D89B6084E6D99" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The term <quote>spouse</quote> means the wife or husband of a deceased individual who was married to such individual for at least one year immediately before such death.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7240B761E6C04CD9BC117A4F0A5DBF15"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Medical benefits provided</header><text>The Secretary shall furnish, to an individual receiving medical benefits under this section for an illness, the services, appliances, and supplies prescribed or recommended by a qualified physician for that illness.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFAA0DAC8CC6E4943B40EFB4F32DCB9F1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Transportation and expenses</header><text>The individual may be furnished necessary and reasonable transportation and expenses incident to the securing of such services, appliances, and supplies.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF537719491E747658E8A6355DADE2064"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Commencement of benefits</header><text>An individual receiving benefits under this section shall be furnished those benefits as of the date on which that individual submitted the claim for those benefits in accordance with this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8720BF5685FA48D998D2C60E5C53C1BF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H79A9D7F1EA714921A4E9F9D848E52795"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>military firefighter</quote> means a member of the Armed Forces or a civilian employee of the Department of Defense whose military occupational specialty or primary duties are fire suppression and prevention.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4311DED94DCF4245B2A2D1E922DA37B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>military installation</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2801(c)(4) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DE9AA4311D847AABFF33E464144B3F3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>PFAS</term> means perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BC298B1FF2D4CACA27CE037BF0DCB22"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>perfluoroalkyl substance</term> means a man-made chemical of which all the carbon atoms are fully fluorinated carbon atoms.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H82226FDA69B543709C09A99EF07F5F44"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>polyfluoroalkyl substance</term> means a man-made chemical with at least one fully fluorinated carbon atom and at least one nonfluorinated carbon atom.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5449F975F480418F9B0DFB75F9FA4175"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization for compensation fund</header><text>There is hereby authorized such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

