<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H384CEF2EBED74D99987B01BB20B15134" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5733 IH: Community Mental Wellness Worker Training Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5733</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251010">October 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, to award grants to train community mental wellness workers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H319BE181EBC44525B2DE2D3C3FAF5593" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE2B3042A7E2B4FCEB223DCE5D6C22564" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community Mental Wellness Worker Training Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HDE7CAF01DA8346AAA6D0765CE23B2D93"><enum>2.</enum><header>Training community mental wellness workers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part D of title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290dd">42 U.S.C. 290dd</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H07D459DA197F438AAF9B1B3C585B561C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H4E1A98BD560744D59FC3425272CCB0B0"><enum>554.</enum><header>Training community mental wellness workers</header> 
<subsection id="HB22C4A4C38F446898CC3C037ADD311B0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, may award grants to eligible entities to implement community mental wellness worker training programs.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H39528018916B4344BF1561096672C690"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall use the funds received through such grant to carry out a community mental wellness worker training program, which may include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3BF2ADAC020F4BA4BFD8306050F3C6E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting training, certification, and supervision during and after training of community mental wellness workers and community mental wellness supervisors—</text> <subparagraph id="HFEBED845E27F41C39A0AC07E5E5BB9BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to screen for common mental health and substance use conditions; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7782BB14158746F69B3B5A57D31C37F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to deliver evidence-informed, culturally and linguistically competent counseling and interviewing interventions addressing basic psychosocial or psychotherapeutic treatment needs of persons with or at risk for mental and substance use disorders, including safety planning and interventions to reduce suicide risk; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD73CAD3EDF5F4A3FB462A27BDAD0AF3E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>covering costs associated with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H37C401B352FB4099BB71EEF224E81588"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the acquisition and use of digital platforms to provide the screening, training, supervision, and ongoing quality assurance monitoring, outcomes evaluation, and delivery of evidence-based treatments;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA99002CBD61E409C84B853D744DEFD20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the delivery of counseling and interviewing interventions described in paragraph (1)(B); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBF198A5828FB4BEFB8396C71EA86FE3E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the clinical supervision (during and after training) of community mental wellness workers and the certification of such workers upon the completion of required training.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA0C8BB5C45B641C093E35DC4B2851A65"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Community mental wellness technical assistance</header> <paragraph id="HB7D0DFDF5CD444E599092B67F88147D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may provide appropriate training and technical assistance to eligible entities receiving a grant under this section in meeting the requirements of this section, including by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H22E5F54A83CC4BF0BAC760699A0C51F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consulting with such recipients on evidence-based employment practices for community mental wellness workers, including assistance with integrating community wellness workers into the workflows of such recipients and other eligible entities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8A25C5EE49AB4652ADECFE11D23121DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifying a diverse array of candidates for community mental wellness worker training; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H869F7AC468594EAC97568794B8BC950D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identifying behavioral health providers who may benefit from and employ community mental wellness workers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H115C9C13F89441D8AD88CE8BC08EDE4F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional dissemination of technical assistance</header><text>The information and resources provided by the Secretary under paragraph (1) shall be made available to States, political subdivisions of States, Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act), outpatient and inpatient substance use treatment providers, other community-based behavioral health organizations, and other entities as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H211349EAEAEA4798AAF9621F68C1B742"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that are located—</text> <paragraph id="H46EF1FC9B71A43C7B235B13A749F5CE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in an area with rates of poverty and unemployment that exceed the average in the United States, as determined by the survey conducted by the Secretary of Commerce commonly referred to as the ‘American Community Survey’ (or any successor survey);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1FE12CF74F064672BCF9B48E8EE827E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in a medically underserved community;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3504BC86BEE84B3FAA73D5BBA083CA0D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in an area with rates of substance use that exceed the average in the United States, as determined by the National Institute on Drug Abuse; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H16D07E2459CC4D31A56A59F60BCE12BB"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serving communities with rates of individuals who are dually eligible for both the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act and the Medicaid program under title XIX of such Act that exceed the average in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H46A38F79D3EC4A76AA157D140EFEFFDD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Malpractice and negligence suits against community behavioral health clinic and community mental health centers</header> <paragraph id="HB344A8987CE449D48729FA998D69366B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as inconsistent with this subsection, the provisions of section 224, including subsections (g), (h), (i), (j), (k), and (l) of such section, shall apply with respect to acts and omissions of a covered entity that occur during the period of the grant under this section, to the same extent and in the same manner as such provisions apply with respect to an entity described in subsection (g)(4) of such section 224, and any officer, governing board member, employee, or contractor of such an entity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H506FD5977BE14FF4A2AD843638C861CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>List required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each covered entity described in paragraph (3)(A) shall submit to the Secretary, and update as necessary, a list of each officer, governing board member, employee, or contractor participating in the entity’s program funded through a grant under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H93929F80EFF343CB8E1E28FF7B5A5020"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered entity defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>covered entity</quote> means an entity that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF7E60482E8D74D2ABA82619E1B9C767E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is an eligible entity (as defined in subsection (g)(3)) in receipt of a grant under this section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3D2E7B5426394636A842506BFAC08557"><enum>(B)</enum> <clause id="H93CF55BAD785442BBD3E13D20A7FD490" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is an officer, governing board member, or employee of such an entity or a contractor of such an entity who is a physician or other licensed or certified health care practitioner; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBC346A3BD93C4FD3A83A4DA14C972870" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is participating in the entity’s program funded through a grant under this section, as indicated in a list submitted pursuant to paragraph (3).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H746DE9E5AC1D410BAC9EA6DE62DA8FE4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Delayed applicability</header><text>This subsection applies beginning with respect to the first full fiscal year that begins after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0F697FE90D684E7C832B27C9D291BDD5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<paragraph id="HFE2C2DD37E9849809C0EA02F6E478975"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>The Secretary shall submit to Congress—</text> <subparagraph id="H74366F3A5919440294C7C45198FFC80B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than one year after the date of enactment of this section, an interim report on the results of the grant program under this section; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H86E140434CAA40A484613A05F0015DED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than the end of fiscal year 2030, a final report of such results.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4FF641BC87A843A3A85760B76D1E1E71"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The reports required by paragraph (1) shall each include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBA2611F89DF04A92AA8F0E4A00B6D739"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total number of community mental wellness workers participating in the grant program under this section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H05005E87A5014D6E8D21144371BBB8FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total number of community mental wellness workers who obtained certification through such participation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6E61F9E7C13B4331A1F298FF5D094C06"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H628413DCEF264380B50127AB6AB2544F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community mental wellness worker</term> means an individual trained and certified by an eligible entity to assist with providing basic screening and evidence-based treatments to individuals with a mild to moderate mental health or substance use disorder, including depression, anxiety, post-traumatic stress disorder, and alcohol use disorder.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6B7188975EF8498CB6868188A1AEB891"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>culturally and linguistically competent</term> means, with respect to the provision of counseling and interviewing interventions, providing such services in a manner that acknowledges, and is responsive to, cultural differences that may derive from characteristics of the individual receiving such services, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H4DD05D284ED546C5A52602EC193DAD41"><enum>(A)</enum><text>gender;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE95EDD6BD5A541D2825BE15B5E7DC954"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sex;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H45ED26D7850144A0B04FECEF3B694541"><enum>(C)</enum><text>sexual orientation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5587C2D6D01A4BA187CAD4877BF08103"><enum>(D)</enum><text>race or ethnicity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2F88EAB1D2764E12B97FD76613AE3BCF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>nationality;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H535626106DEA4E0B8A395B712DC92C23"><enum>(F)</enum><text>socioeconomic level;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5372413DE92F4901A381B1BDC29503D4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>immigration status;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5A30E1DDECE14F2BA0508716C1FA8088"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disability;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2C04625625F14832870FBB5DDA214C9E"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Tribal affiliation; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA4B427E83DAE40BFA145499540509102"><enum>(J)</enum><text>veteran status.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H336268AA34994CF2B0139A43D91A2170"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC2682773DB4D4FEFB93A029D2C39621D">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>a certified community behavioral health clinic (as described in section 223(a) of the Protecting Access to Medicare Act of 2014);</text>
                            </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4A0950F019AF47F8B358F89A1B6D0C1D">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>a community mental health center (as described in section 1913(c));</text>
                            </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6F092958D9604CE6AD22A694926A44B6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a hospital that is described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC658C755256343A887AF53804883D2BC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such other community behavioral health organizations as the Secretary may specify, in consultation with—</text> 
<clause id="H01F7C3FF7855412A8E052FCC1FF84E9B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>State authorities responsible for regulating substance use and mental health providers and facilities receiving reimbursement under a State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act (or a waiver of such plan); and</text></clause> <clause id="HA062231FF78349DEA32B3F5AAE55C209"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other State substance abuse and mental health agencies.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEBF390E7518A4F448B645E58D8E6357C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>medically underserved community</term> has the meaning given such term in section 799B.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1A4A79DAA0624730A8F4B69D3E406380"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Funding</header> <paragraph id="HB4F447C8AA9A4C9D84AB1DD1C05BEB9A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H31DD85A12CD24DC69481883562EE3396"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allocation</header><text>Of the funds authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section for a fiscal year, not less than 20 percent shall be reserved for the provision of training and technical assistance under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

