<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4D8E3D9415AA43DF94710DB214A29CC9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1725 IH: Sgt. Isaac Woodard, Jr. and Sgt. Joseph H. Maddox GI Bill Restoration Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1725</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C000537">Mr. Clyburn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to extend to Black veterans of World War II, and surviving spouses and certain direct descendants of such veterans, eligibility for certain housing loans and educational assistance administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB7C9571E66FC49CB8B604FACACFEED1F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7DB4A5E40665444AA0C8F18D1193C9F3" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sgt. Isaac Woodard, Jr. and Sgt. Joseph H. Maddox GI Bill Restoration Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1A5EEF33BEBF4F26BD668145744DD4C9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HA46A8B411673482786F22146C5C8BEE8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">African Americans played a pivotal role in the war effort during World War II, with more than 1,200,000 African Americans serving in the Armed Forces, and, by 1945, approximately 1.9 percent of all officers in the Armed Forces were African Americans.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H743B0C52AC664C8C82649C7769152C11"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following World War II, the Servicemen’s Readjustment Act of 1944 (58 Stat. 284, commonly known as the <quote>GI Bill</quote>) offered substantial material benefits to 16,000,000 veterans to assist them in reintegrating into civil society.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA8EC9367D2C44659AAD545720E8A9BDA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The GI Bill offered a range of economic and educational benefits administered by the Federal Government through the Secretary of the Veterans Administration, including monetary assistance to access higher education, government guarantees for housing loans, unemployment allowances, and civilian workforce reentry assistance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H321050D9AE114873AED2B67DBEB277F8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Though the legislative text of the GI Bill was race neutral, the administration of benefits through national, State, and local Veterans Administration offices resulted in a pattern of discrimination against racial minorities, especially African Americans.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDC4A904D71464C93A274DBC89B31D26D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Veterans Administration benefits counselors denied African Americans access to educational benefits at certain universities and funneled applicants into industrial and vocational schools rather than higher education opportunities, with just 6 percent of African-American veterans of World War II earning a college degree, compared to 19 percent of White veterans of World War II.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3679636AFAB6419B8846DFD05AF1B122"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In administering its housing guaranty program, the Veterans Administration adopted the Federal Housing Administration’s racial exclusion programs, also known as redlining, which excluded a significant number of African Americans from taking full advantage of the housing guaranty program.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0D66F6F33537457D88B36CF560A2BC2E"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The GI Bill created substantial economic growth and wealth accumulation for those who could benefit, but discriminatory administration of the program prevented many African-American veterans of World War II from enjoying the full economic prosperity of the post-war period.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H15053C98E131490F8E9D2101DC6E94FF" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Housing loans guaranteed by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for Black veterans of World War II and survivors and certain direct descendants of such veterans</header> <subsection id="HD2E6EBD98DCA4D4B8B1A646707622AFF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/37">Chapter 37</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended as follows:</text>
<paragraph id="HADE618BB3C124BDE8D7B72FDA9ED2A4A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>Section 3701(b) of such title is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H41413D8BD42D47A2A7D008A4A84A520D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H968D4EFEF7F9424D9C4D595E11F5C095"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>veteran</quote> also includes, for purposes of housing loans, an individual who—</text>
<subparagraph id="HF9BC01A1AD4D423E8E74B870234428CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is Black;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H176A86E4E25D4D8A94470C05B65B31C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>served on active duty as a member of the Armed Forces during World War II; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2877486F94C947E4BD147FFC816C964A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>certifies to the Secretary that such individual was denied a specific benefit under the Servicemen's Readjustment Act of 1944 (58 Stat. 284) on the basis of race.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF3FE72BFC2B746889BBAC75A3ABF1EA8" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>veteran</quote> also includes, for purposes of housing loans, an individual who—</text>
<subparagraph id="H60C82A4F77DE478CB9074608A63ABA89"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is the surviving spouse, child, grandchild, or other direct descendant of a veteran described in paragraph (8);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H265350C36D8B4B93B89035091AA176C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certifies to the Secretary that such veteran described in paragraph (8) was denied a specific benefit under the Servicemen's Readjustment Act of 1944 (58 Stat. 284) on the basis of race; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9FE7320AA9CC49BFADD782EEC468BB14"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is living on the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Sgt. Isaac Woodard, Jr. and Sgt. Joseph H. Maddox GI Bill Restoration Act of 2025</short-title>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA62D2AAE34A94512BE950862A59BE25E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Basic entitlement</header><text>Section 3702(a)(2)(E) of such title is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H7506C49C80A6410198D3BA6B341DD3BE" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subparagraph id="HF775930F85684C5AB1B6A4B7E3201295" indent="up1"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each individual—</text> <clause id="H57AA157A0D0347D9A35915FE0B958304"><enum>(i)</enum><text>described in paragraph (8) or (9) of section 3701(b) of this title; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HF28A57E6FDF9466C85039A328697C35D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who applies for a housing loan during the five-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Sgt. Isaac Woodard, Jr. and Sgt. Joseph H. Maddox GI Bill Restoration Act of 2025</short-title>. </text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6ECC5BC133F741EA83FE6BE20BA0B924" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out the amendment made by this section not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H8B8EE89F88FC4AA6964E1873D16E9501"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall prescribe regulations to carry out the amendments made by this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5492B0A6A9844CDEA6557B785A0CE1C7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the deadline under subsection (b), the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report regarding—</text>
<paragraph id="HE97A1A08517644028A8F738027B447C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of individuals who received housing loan benefits pursuant to the amendments made by this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3E4055017A0046788E71EE243032DE82"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total value of housing loan benefits administered by the Secretary pursuant to the amendments made by this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H08E93121FD2E40FC86CE70C454BD476F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Educational assistance for survivors and certain direct descendants of Black veterans of World War II</header>
<subsection id="H3E33AD22654A4A0BA656D42FD872E3BE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Entitlement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (b) of section 3311 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HEEDE6CBD63CB421BBD22D7734BAFD141" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HF77A950050A94C109CE756FF6A177074"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual—</text>
<subparagraph id="HB2ACB05437BC463784BAF1BDD3D38401"><enum>(A)</enum><text>described in section 3701(b)(9) of this title; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H99DA9FCBC11E4AD8BECA4C3F6BCE66A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who applies for educational assistance under this chapter during the five-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Sgt. Isaac Woodard, Jr. and Sgt. Joseph H. Maddox GI Bill Restoration Act of 2025</short-title>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HDE05847B186B487EB751810F0BF22AA2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out the amendment made by this section not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HADA499B9AD8D446881F1B329149D9FC4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall prescribe regulations to carry out the amendment made by this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H7ACCD3036E354E30AE78B19A8444EA70"><enum>(d)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text>Not later than one year after the deadline under subsection (b), the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report regarding—</text> <paragraph id="H3625EB69EA6F48F2932FB3D2B2CF8C41"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of individuals who received educational assistance pursuant to the amendment made by this section; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBAEE200A13DA46C0A1BA1597D11830AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount of educational assistance paid by the Secretary pursuant to the amendment made by this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H834FCE915D7249629FF1068C238D21E3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Blue Ribbon panel on benefits and assistance for female and minority veterans</header> <subsection id="H86C5CA98401240A0B22104FFBBB5EF6D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall, pursuant to the Federal Advisory Committee Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/92/463">Public Law 92–463</external-xref>; 5 U.S.C. App.), appoint a panel of independent experts on—</text>
<paragraph id="H2116974E59724BF4BF37C9825A54DA3D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>inequities in the distribution of benefits and assistance administered by the Secretary; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H034B4D3A601A45B5A92A5E78E7A49EE7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>military service by female and minority members of the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7CD7F2B1B00C45E5B19A3CF2FAED5B4B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The panel shall develop recommendations regarding additional benefits and assistance for individuals described in subsection (a)(2), and related legislation.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE8A0049BD5874D9E8F96FF5C0FE298D0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the panel shall submit to Congress and the President a report containing the recommendations developed under this section.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

