<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H21BD9C74440C4091A283AF9A37D3C9E9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4054 IH: Accreditation Choice and Innovation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4054</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250620">June 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to reform accreditation.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA8ADF5B34E1E4D149B96C1A799117970" style="OLC"><section id="HA8C7722F35054DE7BC8EE3336C6644C0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Accreditation Choice and Innovation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H87F3EF3840AC48C6A4BB96096C3DE154"><enum>2.</enum><header>Accrediting agency recognition</header><subsection id="HC90B3E053B324A20A7AA1C29392C7FEC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Criteria required</header><text>Section 496(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HDDF6C699AA614BB7846B381398156687"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>or training</quote> and inserting <quote>or skills development</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCB67A7F30B742B9A7F42A41A7C12C0E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H4C2EAE4FAFCA4C6E9AF02B5F686404FC" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HE66E890552C440B5A7E8CEFCACD185E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the accrediting agency or association (other than an accrediting agency or association described in paragraph (2)(D)) shall be a State or national agency or association and shall demonstrate the ability to operate as an institutional or programmatic accrediting agency or association within the State or nationally, as appropriate;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HD28F0AE32161482C99005B9BE90110B4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="HADB40E3C219640378D037A911DEC5B69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="HE50BE866218A47D69165F866A484D05C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>principal</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HF010298804B14A3CAE44A2C463A6EABE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>its principal</quote> and inserting <quote>a</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAB1CE6D160C419C9A71E9D5D8BA364E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H354022DB76844ADAA62516AB9E161B25"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by inserting <quote>or</quote> at the end; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD2E598E27A04939B64F90015F7A6921"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H903CE10B03A64AF3B8ABC8FD0CBEA579" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HA6FB5236D945499AA8736ADD04224181"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is an entity (such as an industry-specific quality assurance entity) that has been—</text><clause id="H3374E440FEF64F08AF17909309D7F51E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>determined by a State to be a reliable authority as to the quality of education or skills development offered in such State for the purposes of this Act; and</text></clause><clause id="HB0EE3B27904F41B08456B8733F90AB69"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>designated (in accordance with subsection (b)(1)) by such State as an accrediting agency or association with respect to such State for such purposes;</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H95DDBC4D974946A8AD7D89803CC21606"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text><subparagraph id="H978A385805D647F1BEBF72FD654798C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H1469F3D74D4F46018258B942BFC1E19D" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H73668A1480464BD5A175BFE94D06DB8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subparagraph (A), (C), or (D) of paragraph (2), then such agency or association is—</text><clause id="H6C8B5D988DA6493DBBD5B1D19A5EDD61"><enum>(i)</enum><text>distinctly incorporated or organized; and</text></clause><clause id="H87F2A1670A454699A099B58B6D79D2EE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>both administratively and financially separate from, and independent of, any related, associated, or affiliated trade association or membership organization, by ensuring that—</text><subclause id="HB8D358FCA9F94A1995361B8F4161C8CB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the members of the board or governing body of the accrediting agency or association are not elected or selected by the board or chief executive officer (or the representative of such board or officer) of any related, associated, or affiliated trade association or membership organization;</text></subclause><subclause id="H279C330A760A4BDCADB965F8F77786EC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>among the membership of the board or governing body of the accrediting agency or association—</text><item id="H01620E96D5AF4F3C9859A4250F9F0A83" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>if such board or body is comprised of 5 or fewer members, there is a minimum of one member who is not also a member of any related, associated, or affiliated trade association or membership organization (referred to in this subclause as a <quote>public member</quote>) and who represents business; and</text></item><item id="H12EA84FF22AF449F835BB7ECA6B3FEF6" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>if such board or body is comprised of 6 or more members, there is a minimum of 2 public members (at least one of whom represents business) for every 6 members; </text></item></subclause><subclause id="HBA90D0B875744D8F9EA434EEF0D90EF2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>guidelines are established for such members to avoid conflicts of interest, including specific guidelines to ensure that no such member is an employee of any institution accredited by the agency or association or has a financial interest in any such institution;</text></subclause><subclause id="H117AF1D69A9A4DF08FF4B2776126B67E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>dues to the accrediting agency or association are paid separately from any dues paid to any related, associated, or affiliated trade association or membership organization; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H13068914449745088EBCB94B93B18B72"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the budget of the accrediting agency or association is developed, determined, and maintained by the accrediting agency or association without any review by, consultation with, or approval by any related, associated, or affiliated trade association or membership organization;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE316CB8CF484AD084AA9F0A3C84D90C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D19F32432FB4033AC7C126E24CB8936"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (C);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B3E4781C08C4DEFAEA2D3CD93BEF0E9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text><subparagraph id="H35F8065D730B4D6B94469057BD29E617"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H575FEB9A99D0413E91A0BC0F1F978F2B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(in the manner described in subparagraph (B))</quote> after <quote>religious missions</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H72A8BB0D44B0463291A15B260261D397"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5A7E9B97A6E45CF967A5C8393F45EE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H86153D43372E40A8BE40C78DE10722DB" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HC74CD5A188AF446A91478BFB71BFA1B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such accrediting agency or association consistently applies and enforces standards that respect the stated religious mission of an institution of higher education by—</text><clause id="H0F29EDC425B24338BB35A224DCB11852"><enum>(i)</enum><text>basing decisions regarding accreditation and preaccreditation on the standards of accreditation of such agency or association; and</text></clause><clause id="H25627C4B5BEA4D85B7F4BACDDA28A51E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not using as a negative factor the institution’s religious mission based policies, decisions, and practices in the areas covered by subparagraphs (B), (C), (D), (E), and (F) of paragraph (5), except that the agency or association may require that the institution’s or a program of study’s curricula include all core components required by the agency or association that are not inconsistent with the institution’s religious mission; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82BEEFA2ACB645158E962FB6D8437C95"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such agency or association demonstrates the ability to review, evaluate, and assess the quality of any instruction delivery model or method such agency or association has or seeks to include within its scope of recognition, without giving preference to or differentially treating (such as through separate standards, procedures, or policies) a particular instruction delivery model or method offered by an institution or program, except that in a case in which an instruction delivery model allows for the separation of the student from the instructor, the agency or association requires the institution to have processes through which the institution establishes that the student who registers in a course or program with such an instruction delivery model is the same student who participates in the course or program of study (including, to the extent practicable, the testing or other assessments required under the course or program of study), completes the course or program of study, and receives the academic credit for such course or program of study;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3B7AF79B8724A5F8665C205A3C185F5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)—</text><subparagraph id="HE1FCC91270BF47F8A2327492DAC349EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="HA02FFC6FD7914E05BA61DDBC867FF842" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H8A988F175EDE484B990EB8CBAB1C5077"><enum>(A)</enum><text>success with respect to student achievement outcomes in relation to the institution’s mission and to the programs the institution offers, or the mission of a specific degree, certificate, or credential program, which may include different standards for different institutions or programs of study, and which shall include—</text><clause id="H4E57D81B753B4BFA96D419EA1ED9BF27"><enum>(i)</enum><text>standards for consideration of student success outcomes measures, including—</text><subclause id="H8FF5128DB3744D2AA347A4CA4ABC8291"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a comparison of the total price charged to students for a program of study to the value-added earnings of students who completed such program (such as a comparison, with respect to students who completed the program in the same award year, of the median total price charged to such students to the median value-added earnings of such students);</text></subclause><subclause id="HAF70680A30D64D59BA48597A7B671C28"><enum>(II)</enum><text>completion rates;</text></subclause><subclause id="H5C14686C009C4D6EA74082EBA5835DD7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>retention rates; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HF4B44C5D5E9B43BF9609901DECCF4349"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>loan repayment rates); </text></subclause></clause><clause id="H3183010FF35241B68F70D5E4B450E627"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>standards for consideration of learning outcomes measures (such as competency attainment and licensing examination passage rates); and</text></clause><clause id="HFFE2E762A4E6494CAF15A7D8F86411F8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>standards for consideration of labor market outcomes measures (such as employability measures, earnings gains, or other similar approaches); and</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE935CFA7CE604862B967676313577E83"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (I) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H715341D4798540AD9CFA86AD485A1DBC" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H69F01849D76449ED8F97898F7B9D2533"><enum>(I)</enum><text>record of student complaints received by, or available to, the agency or association, and a process for resolving complaints received by the institution; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C56ADFB991A4EBD8A9361D2C68AC9EF" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the matter following subparagraph (J), by striking <quote>subparagraphs (A), (H), and (J)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph ((J)</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA7E3C2D885C47FAB74B6FC301CAC959"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Secretarial requirements and authority</header><text>Subsection (b) of section 496 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H1A7B780087F64919A8BEE4EE382CB815" style="OLC"><subsection id="HB101E9D273AB491D8FEE6F9C9D14C85A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Secretarial requirements and authority</header><paragraph id="HAE3464C7AD6B4D0784E1F50DBF01D4DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State designated accrediting agency</header><subparagraph id="H4CE0D735822A4E6F8CFBFECBA01DA959"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Approval of state plans</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><clause id="HC5F57D3B55F14B73B77B9AC79ACB2D60"><enum>(i)</enum><text>approve a State’s designation of an entity as an accrediting agency or association for the purposes described in subsection (a)(2)(D) for a 5-year period, beginning not later than 30 days after receipt of the plan from such State with respect to such designation, if such plan includes each of the elements listed in subparagraph (B);</text></clause><clause id="H6FBF90992DF848A2B058C37EE619AF03"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit to the State and the authorizing committees, and make publicly available the Secretary’s response to the State with respect to such plan, including whether the plan includes each of the elements listed in subparagraph (B); and</text></clause><clause id="H4A9B07139FC0480FAF42017098E1E5E7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if a State’s designation of an entity as an accrediting agency or association is approved pursuant to this subparagraph, publish in the Federal Register with a 30-day public comment period—</text><subclause id="H8D5FCF50E7C24F0FB18F92DAFBE354D0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the plan submitted by such State with respect to such designation; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H0F39D862C68C4F959CE9C00C80FC7534"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Secretary’s response to such plan.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECDC3E7FF6374CFFB4365529DA8E5E9D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Required plan elements</header><text>The required elements of a State plan submitted under subparagraph (A) with respect to the designation of an entity as an accrediting agency or association are as follows:</text><clause id="HB4A513C108AD4E0F9292C68BCD180529"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A description of the process the State used to select the entity for such designation.</text></clause><clause id="H53AA6694D15E4996B8E48BF8D623E24A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A justification of the State’s decision to select the entity for such designation.</text></clause><clause id="H689E9B222DAE48D09DF7C6D2F727FDDD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A description of any requirements (in addition to the requirements of this section), that the State required the entity to comply with as a condition of receiving and maintaining such designation, including a requirement for the entity to use, to the extent practicable during such designation, the common terminology developed pursuant to paragraph (3).</text></clause><clause id="H868832CCCB5C4202AB234633AAF8E06D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A copy of the standards, policies, and procedures of the entity that the State considered in selecting the entity for such designation.</text></clause><clause id="H9367533D3FB84AED9A397270B05D823B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The State’s assessment of how the standards for accreditation of the entity will be effective in meeting the requirements of subsection (a)(5).</text></clause><clause id="H9A8EACE1BAB047989020AE441ACDC3EA" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Evidence that at least one other State has determined that such entity is a reliable authority as to the quality of education offered for the purposes of this Act. </text></clause><clause id="HCC9747397B9D4B8B8E493DB5B60DF778"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>An assurance that the State will comply with the monitoring requirements described in subparagraph (C).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48BA6D99B44747E49D4ADBED65A8A4AE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>State monitoring</header><clause id="H45D8F36DD34C47D48EB2EA2105665279"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State that has designated an entity as an accrediting agency or association for the purposes described in subsection (a)(2)(D) shall submit to the Secretary, and to the State authorizing entity, as appropriate, a report at the end of the 5-year period for which the entity has received such designation, which shall include, with respect to each program of study or institution that has been accredited by such entity during such period, and disaggregated by type of credential, certification, or degree—</text><subclause id="H49F77E40537F467DA1C9C601A15863E2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number and percentage of students who have successfully obtained a postsecondary education credential, certification, or degree offered by such program or institution; </text></subclause><subclause id="H69894B25A0EB4DD3BA7DD82749080D05"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number and percentage of students who were enrolled and did not successfully obtain such a credential, certification, or degree within 150 percent of the program length; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H5F56E2148FAD4107B29E3F3B05046E3C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the results of the State’s assessment described in subparagraph (B)(v).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H5D73B375C9BC436687FAF616C038034D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Counting transfer students</header><text>For purposes of clause (i)(I), a student shall be counted as obtaining a credential, certification, or degree offered by a program of study or institution that was accredited by the entity during the period for which the report under this subparagraph is being submitted, if the student obtains such credential, certification, or degree after transferring to another institution during such period.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F608E224A40465ABD74AAEE451CF0CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority to provide an accelerated path to recognition</header><text>With respect to a prospective accrediting agency or association that submits to the Secretary an application for initial recognition under this Act, the Secretary may provide such recognition to such agency or association within 2 years after receipt of such application, if such application—</text><subparagraph id="H71C9526F91834A3B8C3174B6336E3A3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>demonstrates that the agency or association—</text><clause id="H649AB3F359584DEF9BB2A9E16EF7B259"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has at least one year of experience in making accreditation or preaccreditation decisions; and</text></clause><clause id="HA5870F93F29640BABA58A46B6AB15477"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has policies in place that meet all the criteria under subsection (a) for recognition covering the range of the specific degrees, certificates, institutions, and programs of study for which the agency or association seeks such recognition; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H793A86DA074F473EAE54EE0ED828D71A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides an assurance that if the agency or association receives such recognition, the agency or association will submit to the Secretary monitoring reports regarding accreditation or preaccreditation decisions, as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA5AFFCB343D41EBB095624B15C6804E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Development of common terminology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of the Accreditation Choice and Innovation Act, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H37C53674B2DB4875B8DC43709D703D05"><enum>(A)</enum><text>convene a panel of experts to develop common terminology for accrediting agencies or associations to use in making accrediting decisions with respect to programs of study and institutions, such as a common understanding of monitoring, warning, show cause, and other relevant statuses, as appropriate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4480AFAFFF344B23B39BEC8C35947A45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publish the recommendations for such common terminology in the Federal Register with a 60-day public comment period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HE19692BBA78B45AB911531045698FBBB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Operating procedures required</header><paragraph id="H75A8C423039B45758378B3C42DD809DF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>On-site inspections and reviews</header><text>Paragraph (1) of section 496(c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H3BBC7B86855E47E7823720C0718D837A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(which may vary based on institutional risk consistent with policies promulgated by the agency or association to determine such risk and interval frequency as authorized under subsection (p))</quote> after <quote>intervals</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD75C1B6F385A43DD85DC8D133AB4CDB5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, including those regarding distance education</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EDB4C4E982C4DF19EF921001E5AD067"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mechanism to identify institutions and programs experiencing difficulties</header><text>Section 496(c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b(c)</external-xref>) is further amended—</text><subparagraph id="H16163EF88BC54A16BE280F3850C3F24E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) through (9) as paragraphs (3) through (10), respectively; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC22866B7D1E4407C86166F515CFE70D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H5C9198171C5A4A4A9F066DE41F08A3B6" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H97DDD6AA69A346B0B98F1A12078CB0C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develops a policy process to identify any institution or program of study accredited by the agency or association that is not meeting the standards for accreditation of the agency or association, with a focus on the standards assessing an institution’s or program of study’s student success outcomes described in subsection (a)(5)(A)(i), which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H7232CBF17898468FAD412D757886B9E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not less than annually, evaluating the extent to which such an identified institution or program of study continues to be in compliance with such standards or other indicators; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94A027DA02284C4B8202BA7C3494C1DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as appropriate, requiring the institution or program of study to submit a plan, on an annual basis, to the accrediting agency or association to—</text><clause id="H4591B40DCA9A4473AF389F4B598B75D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>address and remedy performance issues with respect to such compliance; and</text></clause><clause id="H154532B2A82A4A77A4F383CA8D9C3A65"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensure that such plan is successfully implemented;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC058E2F73A54BE9BE83E2F9BA7DA972"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Procedures with respect to substantive changes</header><text>Paragraph (5) of section 496(c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b(c)</external-xref>) (as redesignated by paragraph (2)(A)) is amended to read as follows: </text><quoted-block id="HEB6527C6A4044F62A9107C2B3C831EC9" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HB0065DCF31EA44709BF217850D33050F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>establishes and applies or maintains policies to ensure that any substantive change of an institution described in subparagraph (B) after the agency or association has granted the institution accreditation or preaccreditation status does not adversely affect the capacity of the institution to continue to meet the agency’s or association’s standards for such accreditation or preaccreditation status, which shall include policies that—</text><subparagraph id="HCCF3B86573AE41428B84FF41317A1129"><enum>(A)</enum><text>require the institution to obtain the agency’s or association’s approval of the substantive change before the agency or association includes the change in the scope of the institution’s accreditation or preaccreditation status; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9902D9E520774AB98AC8DD156624609F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>define substantive change to include—</text><clause id="HB959D47D39294E15961D821062EAB06F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any change in the established mission or objectives of the institution;</text></clause><clause id="H7168CC9F98CA476FA3E57F24EB3AC5FE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any change in the legal status, form of control, or ownership of the institution, including the acquisition or addition of any other institution or new location where more than 50 percent of a program of study is offered;</text></clause><clause id="H69564F787588437EA6BC8D9F65D2D414"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>changing the credential level offered by a program of study that was previously accredited by the agency or association when the program of study offered a different credential level; and</text></clause><clause id="H8BB58674238C4F2FB33FEB25F08C011F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the entering into a contract under which another institution or an organization not eligible to participate in programs under this title offers more than 25 percent but less than 50 percent of the instruction of a program of study of the institution with such accreditation or preaccreditation status; </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CB4EBEA77A34AC2852793C8B732FA8B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>Section 496(c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b(c)</external-xref>) is further amended—</text><subparagraph id="H29113E0E532B4CB39225D9314F7AA860"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (8) (as redesignated by paragraph (2)(A))—</text><clause id="H3BD05157DEC64A3AB5A66EA49CDC1DCF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>, on the agency’s or association’s website,</quote> after <quote>public</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H1B205234CC0C41BAB7C9BBA202DB9A08"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, and a summary of why such action was taken or such placement was made</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE718FA26BCE4E2B8AEEA01490FEC70B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (9) (as so redesignated), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8E4848DF0BE47BBBBD917191517CE03"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (10)(B) (as so redesignated), by striking the period at the end and inserting the following: <quote>, including an assurance that the institution does not deny a transfer of credit based solely on the accreditation of the institution at which the credit was earned;</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36DAB53A285F4173893EE79A2BEF343B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H5E8177AC50C74982AE53365D3B9BF393" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H21E6B59CFD944354806B88284FC4FFAF"><enum>(11)</enum><text>such agency or association shall make publicly available, on the agency or association’s website, a list of the institutions of higher education or program of study accredited by such agency or association, which includes, with respect to each such institution or program of study—</text><subparagraph id="HF2CB111367C048E9A2F2514065C70B87"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the year accreditation was first granted;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF92DB30FEDC64E0FA5A06F773D821A47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the most recent date that accreditation or reaccreditation was granted; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2395E340809247C18EF5EC3EE8B9DF4B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the anticipated date of the institution’s next evaluation for reaccreditation;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2F192FCBDBB4335A4E92C4D8397EE79"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Prohibition on assessment of elected or appointed officials</header><text>Section 496(c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b(c)</external-xref>) is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H77114CD73F3D4015AB9EB173A3884C57" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H879A8DA4E80941A3A7B1612937C85823"><enum>(12)</enum><text>confirms that the standards for accreditation of the agency or association do not assess the roles (including actions or statements) of elected and appointed State and Federal officials and legislative bodies; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H05A046B0444249A4AB62D66E97FC9758"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Prohibition of practices that result in credential inflation</header><text>Section 496(c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b(c)</external-xref>) is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H5119DFB3C0C4415FB93FC010A3FCC7E6" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H25E061BD33684218984C5AE0088D7C62"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">confirms that an institution’s or program of study’s compliance with a standard for accreditation of the agency or association does not require the institution or program to take any action (such as developing a new program of study) that would result in a violation of any other such standard (including the standards for consideration of student success outcomes described in subsection (a)(5)(A)(i) that relate to comparing the total price charged to students for a program of study to the value-added earnings of students who completed such program).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H70D3E09C5C14447094CC6CE0F5DB6866" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on scope of criteria</header><text>Section 496 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b</external-xref>) is further amended by amending subsection (g) to read as follows: </text><quoted-block id="H6B3CBEC8FB7C4C1EB9F996ECAD634B00" style="OLC"><subsection id="H83F36B6BD54A427E9A718EEC6AD5F017" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Limitation on scope of criteria</header><paragraph id="H821FC69C9D9F45A6952668CA9C5F290A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall not establish criteria for accrediting agencies or associations that are not required by this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1690FDFD44A426A81BF40983F4F22D9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institutional eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution of higher education shall meet the accreditation requirements for certification as an institution of higher education under section 102 and subpart 3 of this part, if the institution is in compliance with the standards of its accrediting agency or association that assess the institution in accordance with subsection (a)(5), regardless of any additional standards adopted by the agency or association for purposes unrelated to participation in programs under this title. </text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H9988069C126A4FA5A88DFF8A5E216B91"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Change of accrediting agency</header><text>Section 496 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b</external-xref>) is further amended by amending subsection (h) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="HD69B36C1848149A890B88708A8D784D5" style="OLC"><subsection id="HB516165845964E83A94CC9EDB05AD7C6"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Change of accrediting agency or association</header><paragraph id="HA0342BF0E8914B28B07267F6F25F760E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to an institution or program of study that is not subject to a covered action and that seeks to change its accrediting agency or association for a reason not related to any such covered action (such as compliance with State law)—</text><subparagraph id="H3E2DC30BD15A421CB03C09C038F073D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary shall recognize the accreditation of such institution or program of study while the institution or program is in the process of changing its accrediting agency or association as long as, not later than 10 days before the start of such process, the institution or program of study provides written notification to the Secretary of such process; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68F146483BFD4A409709372F08816D68"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such institution or program may make such a change without the approval of the Secretary as long as, not later than 10 days after the accreditation decision by the new accrediting agency or association, the institution or program and such new accrediting agency or association, provide written notification to the Secretary of the effective date of the accreditation by such agency or association of such institution or program. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CB99FD9F04D4F27ADCC28D583A8026D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered action defined</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>covered action</term> means one or more of the following, when used with respect to an institution or program of study:</text><subparagraph id="H1A7D581B0E564BD280A5A9F1B74CA129" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A pending or final action brought by a State agency to suspend, revoke, withdraw, or terminate the institution’s legal authority to provide postsecondary education<italic></italic> in the State. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0B3116409FF498AA117CF99DD1CE31B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A decision by a recognized accrediting agency or association to deny accreditation or preaccreditation to the institution or program of study. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAEE29427607454C9995D72DE2131A02" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A pending or final action brought by a recognized accrediting agency or association to suspend, revoke, withdraw, or terminate the accreditation or preaccreditation of the institution or program of study. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71B7761187EA44F5B38AA2167CDBC6A3" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Probation or an equivalent status imposed on the institution or program of study by a recognized accrediting agency or association.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BEB744EEB3C4127A9397DAB45D90810"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The institution is in the process of a substantive change (as described in subsection (c)(5)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HFA70657E30D4431F9B5FD830E09CFA8C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Dual accreditation rule</header><text>Section 496 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b</external-xref>) is further amended by amending subsection (i) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H65019BE6834A4909A19401647307A3F3" style="OLC"><subsection id="HD6EE3E1DA4424A539D1443863006AE91"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Dual accreditation rule</header><paragraph id="H258804E859E3467AA6B4199BD30CF298"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Recognition by secretary</header><text>The Secretary shall recognize the accreditation of any otherwise eligible institution of higher education if the institution of higher education is accredited, as an institution, by more than one accrediting agency or association.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF516DC9221546B188327E07D88871B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation by institution</header><text>If the institution is accredited, as an institution, by more than one accrediting agency or association, the institution—</text><subparagraph id="H1BE28D4FC73A42FCBA6D1C131F588F49"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall designate which agency’s or association’s accreditation shall be utilized in determining the institution’s eligibility for participation in programs under this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB0B0A5D2825402E848ECA45B3BD26E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may change this designation at the end of the institution’s period of recognition.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC75E58B7926F461886925EB9493AC831"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Religious institutions rule</header><text>Section 496 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b</external-xref>) is further amended by amending subsection (k) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="HAA6685724A904CB892046AFAF9E5F821" style="OLC"><subsection id="H6C3994E884F34B2BABEC3FDA18186A5E"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Religious institution rule</header><paragraph id="HBD4E88F042C2419380158F3F6DF165D1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (j), the Secretary shall allow an institution that has had its accreditation withdrawn, revoked, or otherwise terminated, or has voluntarily withdrawn from an accreditation agency, to remain certified as an institution of higher education under section 102 and subpart 3 of this part for a period sufficient to allow such institution to obtain alternative accreditation, if the Secretary determines, in accordance with paragraph (2), that such withdrawal, revocation, or termination—</text><subparagraph id="H657DC886AEDC40F98BB7428732C95F10"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is related to the religious mission or affiliation of the institution; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7515B2CFB8B42BE9BE48BA3E7529BB9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not related to the accreditation criteria provided for in this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF73E9251123D41178523197F93F6C5B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative complaint for failure to respect religious mission</header><subparagraph id="HDF2120AD4C084149AEA3BBCE67AD06ED"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><clause id="HEDC7B0E3503741C9BD190C2C329D3897"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Institution</header><text>If an institution of higher education believes that an adverse action of an accrediting agency or association fails to respect the institution’s religious mission in violation of subsection (a)(4)(B), the institution—</text><subclause id="HD17B0DFE5CD44CD89F1BB6BE0D69C1BC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>may file a complaint with the Secretary to review the adverse action of the agency or association; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HCBCDFFB8CE2D49239F92FD562AB57880"><enum>(II)</enum><text>prior to filing such complaint, shall notify the Secretary and the agency or association of an intent to file such complaint not later than 30 days after—</text><item id="HCA231444E1F742B8A0A010FC4A2164DA"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>receiving the adverse action from the agency or association; or</text></item><item id="H7B25BB888D3E4CA4BF8E01C5D4B8246A" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>determining that discussions with or the processes of the agency or association to remedy the failure to respect the religious mission of the institution will fail to result in the withdrawal of the adverse action by the agency or association. </text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H7D9D0EB7EEA14D748E940CD4F4888CED"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Accrediting agency or association</header><text>Upon notification of an intent to file a complaint and through the duration of the complaint process under this paragraph, the Secretary and the accrediting agency or association shall treat the accreditation status of the institution of higher education as if the adverse action for which the institution is filing the complaint had not been taken.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H783B474F59784B85BF1A6721F2DC49F1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Complaint</header><text>Not later than 45 days after providing notice of the intent to file a complaint, the institution shall file the complaint with the Secretary (and provide a copy to the accrediting agency or association), which shall include—</text><clause id="H402ABADDAFE14976A3E29F27425D87D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the adverse action;</text></clause><clause id="HCD83C07FFD2042C3BDF99600AEF47327"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>how the adverse action fails to respect the institution’s religious mission in violation of subsection (a)(4)(B); and</text></clause><clause id="H4781DFA65DC14861A1770BC13AE39B24"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other information the institution determines relevant to the complaint.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F128065A27B4937845AB7FEAE9548E6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Response</header><clause id="HEB5928A3705C49A5AD13AAE7C0E16D1E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The accrediting agency or association shall have 30 days from the date the complaint is filed with the Secretary to file with the Secretary (and provide a copy to the institution) a response to the complaint, which response shall include—</text><subclause id="HD4DA3ED6ACD640CB8B5873D7470FD452"><enum>(I)</enum><text>how the adverse action is based on a violation of the agency or association’s standards for accreditation; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H98087FE3611549029105E6A3C3D96D2D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>how the adverse action does not fail to respect the religious mission of the institution and is in compliance with subsection (a)(4)(B).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H64D37B68A5364262A2A0B2F6D31C3476"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><subclause id="H87EFD615CBFC4A7F8EF0D455AE3D2767"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The accrediting agency or association shall bear the burden of proving that the agency or association has not taken the adverse action as a result of the institution’s religious mission, and that the action does not fail to respect the institution’s religious mission in violation of subsection (a)(4)(B), by showing that the adverse action does not impact the aspect of the religious mission claimed to be affected in the complaint.</text></subclause><subclause id="H1A40E0F21495470E8A818CDF25686959"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Insufficient proof</header><text>Any evidence that the adverse action results from the application of a neutral and generally applicable rule shall be insufficient to prove that the action does not fail to respect an institution’s religious mission.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B7B40A0F7ED448EB339B595A4A7CD0F"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Additional institution response</header><clause id="HC74556A228F84884B23D1065F395E120"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The institution shall have a 30-day period beginning on the date on which the agency or association’s response is filed with the Secretary to file with the Secretary (and provide a copy to the agency or association) a response to any issues raised in the response of the agency or association.</text></clause><clause id="H3381CF335B6E4078BD089E4D173926D2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Waiver of right to respond</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution that does not file such a response during the 30-day period described in clause (i) shall be deemed to have waived the institution’s right to respond to the response of the agency or association.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE89B16B3CF244065AFD171BE68C2F6B7"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Secretarial action</header><clause id="H7BEE31657DE047B0BEFB1D9B9D9BECE9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the 30-day period described in subparagraph (D)(i)—</text><subclause id="HCE01ABB8E39240F59B45551FBBB26D15"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Secretary shall review the materials to determine if the accrediting agency or association has met its burden of proof under subparagraph (C)(ii)(I); or</text></subclause><subclause id="H615CC989378B4DD1A900C597970BD258"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in a case in which the Secretary fails to conduct such review—</text><item id="H925C20732FFD498EBB707C92E1B10119"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the Secretary shall be deemed as determining that the adverse action fails to respect the religious mission of the institution; and</text></item><item id="HF156FBE0873A4AD08AB7D94E20036E33"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the accrediting agency or association shall be required to reverse the action immediately and take no further action with respect to such adverse action.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HDD26058AFFB441F78C2FCE7BAC165F5E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Review of complaint</header><text>In reviewing the complaint under clause (i)(I)—</text><subclause id="H55583A36E2DD478CAEE0FD377E2EA999"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Secretary shall consider the institution to be correct in the assertion that the adverse action fails to respect the institution’s religious mission and shall apply the burden of proof described in subparagraph (C)(ii)(I) with respect to the accrediting agency or association; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H2738233F2BDC4B558D4056A384E8DBD2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the Secretary determines that the accrediting agency or association fails to meet such burden of proof—</text><item id="H1262268B5F0141728A81F61113F23D01"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the Secretary shall notify the institution and the agency or association that the agency or association is not in compliance with subsection (a)(4)(B), and that such agency or association shall carry out the requirements of item (bb) to be in compliance with subsection (a)(4)(B); and</text></item><item id="HB98769A8993948E0B78B43E9B337EBAC"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the agency or association shall reverse the adverse action immediately and take no further action with respect to such adverse action.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H30DDC17EE2204DEBA9243669688B4DCC"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Final departmental action</header><text>The Secretary’s determination under this subparagraph shall be the final action of the Department on the complaint.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58DDA977C67D4D668C16994EA8DFBA44"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall prohibit—</text><clause id="H5DDB988023674BAC959B6A803C9F7B47"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an accrediting agency or association from taking an adverse action against an institution of higher education for a failure to comply with the agency or association’s standards of accreditation as long as such standards are in compliance with subsection (a)(4)(B) and any other applicable requirements of this section; or</text></clause><clause id="HA224B80B1B424A689DBE6D86C91EBEB0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an institution of higher education from exercising any other rights to address concerns with respect to an accrediting agency or association or the accreditation process of an accrediting agency or association.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE88BBAEA772C4E90BCD2A78C5EF398D7"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Regulations and guidance</header><clause id="H32DCFF65254F41C088B38A3DAEC9B12B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may only issue regulations and guidance under this paragraph that explain or clarify the process for providing notice of an intent to file a complaint or for filing a complaint under this paragraph.</text></clause><clause id="HC041B6B97B90489C96A37505DBCCE1AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>The Secretary may not issue regulations, guidance, or otherwise determine or suggest, when discussions to remedy the failure by an accrediting agency or association to respect the religious mission of an institution of higher education referred to in subparagraph (A)(i)(II)(bb) have failed or will fail.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H915439FD1FB64FF68F66F38A52CC305A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Independent evaluation</header><text>Section 496(n)(3) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b(n)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by striking the last sentence.</text></subsection><subsection id="H886643498D384EAD99700D2B1CFB04BB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Section 496(o) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b(o)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>, or with respect to the policies and procedures of an accreditation agency or association described in paragraph (2) or (5) of subsection (c) or how the agency or association carries out such policies and procedures</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF7EF0B00D7E642B6BBFD50AF0721B6AF"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Risk-Based review processes or procedures; waiver</header><text>Section 496 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b</external-xref>) is further amended—</text><paragraph id="H7C26BE15AF6D47BBBE6199F1D5D335BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsections (p) and (q); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C81A14512A04AD2813CED4F33F532E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HB6B29993228541A6A77F404A1CEAF45E" style="OLC"><subsection id="HB381C52F834B4FE88AB13FF19CDE1D06"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Risk-Based or differentiated review processes or procedures</header><paragraph id="HEB0B49251FDF4348AF2B7FF31D2B70A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including subsection (a)(4)(A)), an accrediting agency or association shall establish risk-based processes or procedures for assessing compliance with the accrediting agency or association’s standards (including policies related to substantive change and award of accreditation statuses) under which the agency or association—</text><subparagraph id="HC8E20616083F4D9FA7F3AB215CCBBB68"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">creates a system for understanding the performance of each institution and program of study being reviewed by such agency or association in comparison with the performance of other similarly situated institutions or programs of study (which may include the past performance of the institution or program with respect to meeting the accrediting agency or association’s standards, including the standards relating to the student success outcomes described in subsection (a)(5)(A)(i)); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23B41E2C34D1440BA316DE2F44718A50" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to each institution and program of study designated as high-risk, as determined using the accrediting agency or association’s system described in subparagraph (A), requires the institution and program of study to submit the annual plans described in subsection (c)(2)(B) to the agency or association that address the performance issues of such institution or program of study that resulted in such designation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7F3EF088BA342B5BC67C64A76A7EFC6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to each institution and program of study whose performance meets or exceeds the standards of the accrediting agency or association, as determined using the system described in subparagraph (A), reduces any compliance requirements with respect to such standards that are not assessing the institution or program of study in accordance with subsection (a)(5) (such as on-site inspections); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB116237C27AE41C3BCFA7684AC8CB106"><enum>(D)</enum><text>may require an institution or program of study that has declining performance (such as an institution or program of study with a high-risk designation described in subparagraph (B)), which has not improved as required by the annual plan submitted under subsection (c)(2)(B), to take actions to avoid or minimize the risks that may lead to revocation of accreditation (such as limiting certain program of study enrollment or recommending to the Secretary to limit funds under this title for such an institution or program).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE465314E80C4253A5D995F659ACB675"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Any risk-based review process or procedure established pursuant to this subsection shall not discriminate against, or otherwise preclude, institutions of higher education based on institutional sector or category, including an institution of higher education’s tax status.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H31AE7A7E9F3E47F28BF67D19A2DE4F6C"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 496 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b</external-xref>) is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HD208CECA324545728210B454847DBFCC" style="OLC"><subsection id="HF14DA182A916458F8DA8887457C49999"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this Act:</text><paragraph id="H5C1F6187AAEB4EA0B20048328F594F71"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Program length</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term ‘program length’ means the minimum amount of time in weeks, months, or years that is specified in the catalog, marketing materials, or other official publications of an institution of higher education for a full-time student to complete the requirements for a specific program of study.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2672B1DC9C284381A1DC0BE963DC9A76"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program of study</header><subparagraph id="H4838E47319D547BF8FAFDA07B8E0935E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>program of study</term> means an eligible program at an institution of higher education that is classified by a combination of—</text><clause id="H40CB8A69A7D54729831972D6274B055D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>one or more CIP codes; and</text></clause><clause id="H305D93C8E72448D1A1FFC69DBE117A8A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>one credential level, determined by the credential awarded upon completion of the program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAC00E4735B5474C95079976A55E3CB2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>CIP CODE</header><text>The term <term>CIP code</term> means the six-digit taxonomic identification code assigned by an institution of higher education to a specific program of study at the institution, determined by the institution of higher education in accordance with the Classification of Instructional Programs published by the National Center for Education Statistics.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7483204DE5B48FE96D87EA87C16299D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Credential level</header><clause id="H8B7EEB2AD3C6418A9ABE0B66FE01BF98"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>credential level</term> means the level of the degree or other credential awarded by an institution of higher education to students who complete a program of study of the institution. Each degree or other credential awarded by an institution shall be categorized by the institution as either undergraduate credential level or graduate credential level.</text></clause><clause id="H105D0E34BF74453E81B6E7BB531999F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Undergraduate credential</header><text>When used with respect to a credential or credential level, the term `undergraduate credential' includes credentials such as an undergraduate certificate, an associate degree, a bachelor's degree, and a post-baccalaureate certificate (including the coursework specified in paragraphs (3)(B) and (4)(B) of section 484(b)).</text></clause><clause id="H33178F226D4F435DBE04FBE4D3F792C4"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Graduate credential</header><text>When used with respect to a credential or credential level, the term <term>graduate credential</term> includes credentials such as a master's degree, a doctoral degree, a professional degree, and a postgraduate certificate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H32C135CBAB4D40F4A39CC31EF19B70F4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Religious mission</header><text>The term <term>religious mission</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HA93C92E5B1A641F1A681FD70E05AB225" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a published institutional mission that is approved by the governing body of an institution of higher education and that includes, refers to, or is predicated upon religious tenets, beliefs, or teachings; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF4ABDCD5F734D3D898181BA471C48D7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be reflected in any of the institution’s policies, decisions, or practices related to such tenets, beliefs, or teachings (including any policies or decisions concerning housing, employment, curriculum, self-governance, or student admission, continuing enrollment, or graduation).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H323B0B4C5B0948FA9C15BD3E9EE92F73"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Total price</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a student who received Federal financial assistance under this title and who completes a program of study, the term ‘total price’ means the total amount, before Federal financial assistance under this title was applied, a student was required to pay to complete the program of study. A student’s total price shall be calculated by the Secretary as the difference between—</text><subparagraph id="HC6D24A9B47D14333AA80562D5A3F0467"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total amount of tuition and fees that were charged to such student before the application of any Federal financial assistance provided under this title; minus</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6B380F0DBBB433AA8B3FD24A209BC56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total amount of grants and scholarships described in section 480(i) awarded to such student from non-Federal sources for such program of study.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BEE44CC8A4B48E1860B857056A46324"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Value-added earnings</header><subparagraph id="H27B1BBB70F414859ABD6D66F7A4572AF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to a student who received Federal financial aid under this title and who completed a program of study offered by an institution of higher education, the term ‘value-added earnings’ means—</text><clause id="H5990421440BC4343B98B5C5C89D1E3EB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the annual earnings of such student measured during the applicable earnings measurement period for such program (as determined under subparagraph (C)); minus</text></clause><clause id="H0041E0E8AA33495D8EAA83486EA370BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a student who completed a program of study that awards—</text><subclause id="HF6334A725ED34833813CD62DB48AF4B3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an undergraduate credential, 150 percent of the poverty line applicable to a single individual as determined under section 673(2) of the Community Services Block Grant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9902">42 U.S.C. 9902(2)</external-xref>) for such year; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HF2ABA50E836947DFAF19D651871C97D8"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a graduate credential, 300 percent of the poverty line applicable to a single individual as determined under section 673(2) of the Community Services Block Grant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9902">42 U.S.C. 9902(2)</external-xref>) for such year.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H032A9A4CD9C44C858570D0E388985257"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Geographic adjustment</header><clause id="H30824C08112B4175B58F419B56F38E0B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in clause (ii), the Secretary shall use the geographic location of the institution at which a student completed a program of study to adjust the value-added earnings of the student calculated under subparagraph (A) by dividing—</text><subclause id="HD623AECBFF8D42E18DBEA48203DF9F61"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the difference between clauses (i) and (ii) of such subparagraph; by</text></subclause><subclause id="H135B7C8863F04D2CB732D2C4275A11C6"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the most recent regional price parity index of the Bureau of Economics Analysis for the State or, as applicable, metropolitan area in which such institution is located.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6577346908D44AC0911D17ADB26C638B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The value-added earnings of a student calculated under subparagraph (A) shall not be adjusted based on geographic location in accordance with clause (i) if such student attended principally through distance education.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A8C09FDFA6F49A5ADF06EB78B39414F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Earnings measurement period</header><clause id="H5D97C2959CF748C883AE89D077587334"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of calculating the value-added earnings of a student, except as provided in clause (ii), the annual earnings of a student shall be measured—</text><subclause id="H124229D5A54643E38661F5E02CC6E6E9"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a program of study that awards an undergraduate certificate, post baccalaureate certificate, or graduate certificate, 1 year after the student completes such program; </text></subclause><subclause id="H4FC11B7E9058428881D93A8A4C93AAC6"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a program of study that awards an associate’s degree or master’s degree, 2 years after the student completes such program; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HB6E03F2D0BD547CAB189942818E55942"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a program of study that awards a bachelor’s degree, doctoral degree, or professional degree, 4 years after the student completes such program.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HB86024EFCFA541C6B415CAE1F5EF708A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may, as the Secretary determines appropriate based on the characteristics of a program of study, extend an earnings measurement period described in clause (i) for a program of study that—</text><subclause id="HC8FB62075D1C42FF87DBEC5214A9FEB4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>requires completion of an additional educational program (such as a residency or fellowship) after completion of the program of study in order to obtain licensure or board certification associated with the credential awarded for such program of study; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H88B944ADBACB4594969E23C5236C11DF"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">when combined with the program length of such additional educational program for licensure or board certification, has a total program length that exceeds the relevant earnings measurement period prescribed for such program of study under clause (i), </text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">except that in no case shall the annual earnings of a student be measured more than 1 year after the student completes such additional educational program. </continuation-text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H9FB464404F414284A1A816EDFFCC955C"><enum>3.</enum><header>National Advisory Committee on Institutional Quality and Integrity (NACIQI)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 114 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1011c">20 U.S.C. 1011c</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB6D8792C86604E5D8F371CC83304A1F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H26C92429ACEA449C8B3AD285CBE1D8EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by redesignating subparagraphs (A) through (C) as clauses (i) through (iii), respectively, and adjusting the margins accordingly;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34D86844B928476A98B33B63A4128569"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Individuals</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="HACCEA2B7869346FD980EC041598585B9" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H8E3134349BAD4E58909ECF1F7AC977D2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Individuals</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1523F7B151B643068487DE196C2228A2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in clause (ii), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>and training</quote> and inserting <quote>and skills development</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H240D58BC9EED449CA365A013D8A224D1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end of paragraph (2) the following:</text><quoted-block id="HD9A356237B1F468B97C2DA7CE4E0F3A8" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HA86950F4B1D74EF5BD03D1988FEE79BF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disqualification</header><text>No individual may be appointed as a member of the Committee if such individual has a significant conflict of interest, such as being a current regulator (such as a State authorizer), that would require the individual to frequently be recused from serving as a member of the Committee.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H110D1838E7BD4EF2B7E7A335308F2C23"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text><clause id="HF8E92E6E431047A2BDDAA53506112DFF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Except as provided in paragraph (5), the term</quote> and inserting <quote>The term</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HF282F041969343698309F05AD33E6778"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: <quote>If, during a term of office of a member of the Committee, the member has a changed circumstance that results in such member having a significant conflict of interest (as described in paragraph (2)(B)), such member shall vacate such office and a new member shall be appointed to serve the remainder of such term in accordance with this paragraph.</quote></text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6147142DBAD407496FFFEB3C0693419"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="H40AC1D5FE49F4EBC81ABA96CF287CEBB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF1BF4FA26AA47579467A81C78DEE382"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>; and</quote> at the end and inserting a period; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9BE22F7640F43E2B9961EE258B406BA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (6);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H44BB382C52054513AFC117C53B45FF0E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(2), by inserting at the end the following: <quote>The name of any member of the Committee who has been recused with respect to an agenda item of the meeting shall be included in such agenda.</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H622545DF10C043C78A805DCEE6E3B01A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(2)(D), by striking <quote>, including any additional functions established by the Secretary through regulation</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3B4E602BE164C7CAB41EF748539C8AB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (f), by striking <quote>September 30, 2021</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2028</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

