<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ARP25002-CX5-70-2DG"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1019 IS: Rural Water System Disaster Preparedness and Assistance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1019</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250313">March 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to establish an emergency preparedness and response technical assistance program to assist entities that operate rural water or wastewater systems in preparing for and responding to natural or manmade disasters.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rural Water System Disaster Preparedness and Assistance Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idf02615e3f5cf4ba182562376e7c2eaca"><enum>2.</enum><header>Emergency preparedness and response technical assistance program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 306(a) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1926">7 U.S.C. 1926(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id45DDC8B4B8AC4BE1BAA2A4A470A58918"><paragraph id="id4d96d0a965894f1ea1aea99efbe8a01b"><enum>(27)</enum><header>Emergency preparedness and response technical assistance program</header><subparagraph id="idb82a3e71fc3a4ed3827fb00c73c4f895"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish an emergency preparedness and response technical assistance program to provide grants to eligible entities to assist associations described in paragraph (1) that operate rural water or wastewater systems in preparing for and responding to natural or manmade disasters, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4a5c6ac8b3614b5abc7e7da441810bd4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>An entity eligible to receive a grant under subparagraph (A) is a nonprofit organization that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd56c458222b34e75abd1b55b2d1582b6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has demonstrated experience providing emergency technical assistance for disaster preparation, recovery, and response activities to water and wastewater utilities nationwide; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id80df0da307134303b8bccac7f3c5f125"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has the capacity to deploy personnel that possess—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id22a2c59198f64a63b8a7412fa7f888c7"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an active water or wastewater system operators’ license; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id533d74e24e5d4fc28604775c6ee16467"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">knowledge of water and wastewater utilities necessary to carry out activities described in subparagraph (C).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbb08ccb4dfb24b71ac1b291fed47c1e5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Eligible activities</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under subparagraph (A) shall use the grant—</text><clause id="id06e7c1d454f547898019bf2b01f2e831"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to provide onsite personnel and equipment to assist with water and wastewater systems in the event of a disaster;</text></clause><clause id="id380c6335734242bca9fa09b8df38bcfd"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to coordinate with statewide emergency response networks to assist with water and wastewater systems;</text></clause><clause id="idf96f64a3930e413792429ccdef092d67"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to facilitate the development of disaster action plans between associations described in subparagraph (A), units of local government, the Federal Emergency Management Agency, and State emergency management agencies;</text></clause><clause id="idf7ded5c01aba42c18879525f64f4b8c3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to improve resiliency and mitigation planning with respect to water or wastewater systems; </text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idf1877187535e47c489d181c3f1efe485"><enum>(v)</enum><text>to provide geographic information system mapping of water and wastewater systems;</text></clause><clause id="ide84fb17cd70840879ea8249964cb625b"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>to prepare or update predisaster vulnerability assessments, emergency response plans, communication protocols, or hazard recognition and evaluation skills with respect to water and wastewater systems;</text></clause><clause id="idcbe75849284e48c78283dce0fc13e7c8"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>to conduct preliminary damage assessments of critical infrastructure in the event of a disaster;</text></clause><clause id="id267328d586134402ab6905fc39ce61dd"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>to provide emergency services with respect to water and wastewater systems to restore service in the event of a disaster, including—</text><subclause id="idaacec8ebb0e44c65bb4aac81247dd8b4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>pump and motor evaluation and repair;</text></subclause><subclause id="id017635495e974581948daea824b9c58f"><enum>(II)</enum><text>water disinfection and flushing;</text></subclause><subclause id="id2dd0c4107cae4fce811cd0a8012e641f"><enum>(III)</enum><text>leak detection;</text></subclause><subclause id="id7e9b8e030c6c4cad9974f623476b338c"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>line repair;</text></subclause><subclause id="id4e4a7606ae584286bcb94fd3e1c58049"><enum>(V)</enum><text>water main and valve location;</text></subclause><subclause id="id97f7b7eb444f404d9e30eb664c4c1002"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>emergency power generation;</text></subclause><subclause id="iddd32de13fb444dfc85e04917c440b6e8"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>bypass pumping;</text></subclause><subclause id="id2138e96af8ef43e18579b918353fcecb"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>water treatment; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id631b105a9bad426da99be9fe1cf1eeea"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>maintaining safety measures;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idb25b1337ccf2433b9567c80f5340cad6"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>to address outstanding deficiencies focused on resolving health-based regulatory, operational, financial, and managerial deficiencies that impact the sustainability of water and wastewater systems;</text></clause><clause id="id11881f45f79146beb01c3741e527a9c5"><enum>(x)</enum><text>to assist with application and reporting requirements for Federal and State agencies, including the Federal Emergency Management Agency and insurance recovery claims, with respect to water and wastewater systems; and</text></clause><clause id="id81c44fd674144ca380af474a7d9f8c5c"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>to provide for disaster preparation, support, and response activities targeted to disadvantaged communities that lack the financial resources and human capital necessary to adequately address significant health, safety, or sanitary concerns with respect to the water and wastewater systems of those communities.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd093de219d714d59b044cca9c0a17251"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id17ecef4a5a97421ea17e7f9c0f00eefc"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under subparagraph (A) may use the grant for salaries, supplies, and expenses relating to the activities described in subparagraph (C).</text></clause><clause id="id1038f03bf4a04cf8b0af04b97078e276"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Not more than 25 percent of the amount of a grant under subparagraph (A) may be used to purchase or reimburse the rental costs of appropriate emergency equipment, as determined by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id720858a35a174304bf86e291b7ba5946"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Restriction</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under subparagraph (A) may not use the grant funds to pay for eligible activities for which the eligible entity receives other Federal funds. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide8b1cc74ebc54f7ba5b188fb1ebfa840"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this paragraph $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

