<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE37A5C9DC74F4408B19ACF9F73DB5E13" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3250 IH: Developing and Advancing Innovative Learning Models</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3250</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250507">May 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To create a grant program to support the development of innovative learning models, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6FB841F68F604CA7B27F966489D3B2AA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE4F8937BC69E4ED9B1659FA6DB5AC1BE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Developing and Advancing Innovative Learning Models</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H238997F425484FE9A91B423010E1457B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA9A5FBA624C74570946F66B99C1A2BDF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure that the Institute for Education Sciences—</text> <subparagraph id="HA9142FC16AD9489F820B35909E4EE1E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>supports the sustained development to expand knowledge and understanding of innovative learning models;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF8FA362BD1EE492A99F4EEE1E826DAA9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promotes the adoption and continued growth of innovative learning models;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCAAAFA3FF39448D480A424D1DCF5AE03"><enum>(C)</enum><text>studies and conducts research on the impact of innovative learning models;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0BC5C51599634EDC87C2A93EACA8FC8E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>collects, reports, analyzes, and disseminates data related to innovative learning model development, research, and implementation in the United States; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5102EE08B0A04D14B3D45D385322D36A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>identifies and makes recommendations concerning Federal and State policies that may present barriers to the adoption and successful implementation of innovative learning models;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H19176253EF38417C8D151595D7C8998D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>invest in the development of innovative learning models and in the organizational capacity of innovative learning model providers; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC89061D3B20A432098546A1E27A1B212"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support the adoption of innovative learning models by States, local school districts, schools, and school communities.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H5CB91EC174A941F69B3B95F3643E4EA5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purposes of this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H56D74521E0D3403FAEA07604EA0287F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Education.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H31D6329AE68B4FD19B05259CCCAE5EC5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC1C41C7A72DF42BA836B6C18644E18E7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>ESEA terms</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>high school</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>outlying area</term>, <term>poverty line</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, <term>State</term>, and <term>State educational agency</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2E2FEC722EAC424DAF3DA56490FC5A04"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Evidence-based</header><text>The term <term>evidence-based</term>, when used with respect to an innovative learning model, means an innovative learning model that—</text> <subparagraph id="HB6C5D46D503B4A7993C7A1B6F6D17C74"><enum>(A)</enum><text>demonstrates a statistically significant effect on improving student outcomes or other relevant outcomes based on—</text> 
<clause id="HBFB446183EA445FAB00F9726D9742596"><enum>(i)</enum><text>strong evidence from at least 1 well-designed and well-implemented experimental study;</text></clause> <clause id="HB8CFF7D48205401CA04CF4B20FC3E06B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>moderate evidence from at least 1 well-designed and well-implemented quasi-experimental study; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9170C845747846DB8A3C586C1E126A68"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>promising evidence from at least 1 well-designed and well-implemented correlational study with statistical controls for selection bias;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8A831586866941E79772FC7D44973237"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstrates a rationale based on high-quality research findings or positive evaluation that such innovative learning model—</text> 
<clause id="H7BEAC8A62FCB4FC5A83F26AF0B666B1B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is likely to improve student outcomes or other relevant outcomes; and</text></clause> <clause id="HCC43CFFF4C5C4FD18B9BEE0BD81DC98D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes ongoing efforts to examine the effects of such innovative learning model; or</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCAF96A90DDA04FA9A94FEB0153011FDF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is consistent with theoretical and empirical findings from research and will continue to be reviewed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H619714DFFB634674AD5C9DAB3B6FB04D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Innovative learning model</header><text>The term <term>innovative learning model</term> means a comprehensive program which elementary schools, secondary schools, and high schools can adopt that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5AA57D993B364A248F25A1F98355DC39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>bundles together an interconnected set of tools, resources, systems, and instructional practices in order to shape student learning experiences toward clear objectives;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAC8F23D73ED04186A4DB963431427959"><enum>(B)</enum><text>integrates and includes—</text> 
<clause id="HD075EE43A3614A5E8AC24141F0F13555"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an instructional design that incorporates components such as content, assessment, research, and student engagement;</text></clause> <clause id="H88792F23095744C8B2BF55C613205366"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an aligned set of pedagogical practices that is sustainable for teachers;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6E6A8433857743AA96ED88FFBE8296DF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an operational design that reimagines teacher workflow, the use of time, and classroom design; and</text></clause> <clause id="HAC032992AB3B45B580E18CBDAE60B381"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a technological design that includes the use of student-level data and relevant technological tools;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8F90C622912E45B89D35FAF52F345448"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not simply a technological platform or point solutions;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7A6901E6009046BBAC7C0720D1E66743"><enum>(D)</enum><text>comprehensively integrates the concepts identified in subparagraph (B);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H938B815FFFA1462CAFA41DFED005726E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>is created and implemented with input from school communities; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF20A3378689F4EF79FDD50F2BBC87E7A"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be designed as a model for the operation of an entire school or focus on a specific academic subject or function, such as social-emotional support.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE201AA40E4674ABDAB2C4070CE511FD0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Innovative learning model provider</header><text>The term <term>innovative learning model provider</term> means an organization that—</text> <subparagraph id="HDCC24BB70BC347FBB906B34DF196E709"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designs innovative learning models; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5551632C3DF546598F1E10284A3F9124"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">partners with schools and school communities to support the implementation of such models (directly or in collaboration with a third party), while sharing accountability for student outcomes as measured by the State in accordance with section 1111(c) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6331">20 U.S.C. 6331(c)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <title id="HF8F0050E3CFF4CA9A73228F42B624ED4"><enum>I</enum><header>Investing in the development and research of innovative learning models</header> <section id="H00983EC55F3C4E7682A60C5045CA5138"><enum>101.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this title is to authorize a program of competitive grants that enable eligible entities to support the development and research of innovative learning models.</text></section> 
<section id="HB48FDFFA3C864312BE20CF392781B47C" commented="no"><enum>102.</enum><header>Grants for innovative learning model development and research</header> 
<subsection id="H895B7DC098FE4236AD6891BA0277FBD1" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header> 
<paragraph id="HB73990CD0BA34A38BCDF062D31A94980" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Development grants</header> 
<subparagraph id="HEA153D89A0F440E68796DB8DDAE3EECF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amount reserved by the Director under section 104(c)(1), the Director shall award, on a competitive basis, grants to eligible entities having applications approved under subsection (c) to enable such entities to create, develop, implement, replicate, or take to scale entrepreneurial and evidence-based innovative learning models to improve student outcomes.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6892FDBFF28D4187BA8751519A8E3372" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Description of grants</header><text>The grants described in subparagraph (A) shall include—</text> 
<clause id="H5F35C5F254F7466DA603B990C9617134" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>early-phase grants to fund the development, implementation, and feasibility testing of an innovative learning model, which prior research, including research conducted under paragraph (1), suggests has promise, for the purpose of determining whether the innovative learning model can successfully improve student achievement or attainment when successfully implemented with fidelity;</text></clause> <clause id="HEB11B29208064087B78BE07B8E5C4A66" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>mid-phase grants to fund implementation and a rigorous evaluation of an innovative learning model that has been successfully implemented under an early-phase grant described in clause (i) or other effort meeting similar criteria, for the purpose of measuring the model’s impact and cost effectiveness, if possible, using existing administrative data; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H148469D88EC94045A671771F519996D2" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>expansion grants to fund implementation and a rigorous replication evaluation of an innovative learning model that has been found to produce sizable, important impacts under a mid-phase grant described in clause (ii) or other effort meeting similar criteria, for the purposes of—</text> <subclause id="H1CCBF23D7A3D4426BD4633E900539296" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>determining whether such impacts can be successfully reproduced and sustained over time; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HC38CFC729927448B8209710BC1C66CE4" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>identifying the conditions, including subgroups of students (as described in section 1111(c) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)), in which the program is most effective.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF91E58FB43F480E9D2B1BC8963B6D20" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Research grants</header><text>From the amount reserved under section 104(c)(2), the Director shall award, on a competitive basis, grants to eligible entities to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6FBFCCC7049640ADA44E32C10FBE4CD1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct high-quality research on existing innovative learning models; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H88F168C127F24347A4BDAB4A28F1B143" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluate innovative learning models developed with grants awarded under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCC8B66741245459F93BA681C701604C0" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding development grants under this section, the Director shall prioritize eligible entities that propose early-phase projects under paragraph (1)(B)(i).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA0053DB1F88415E9BDDA1476846C06D" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Standards</header><text>The Director shall ensure that activities supported with grants under this section—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA52AB3FF48934395B8F43BAFB4B72418" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conform to high standards of quality, integrity, accuracy, validity, and reliability;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7D1EA8C7E5FE42C6A3A5CFDB0B3434E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintain data privacy and security in a manner that is consistent with any relevant Federal law relating to privacy or data security; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB135DFC21BE24ABCA98F1F82BC6C1684" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>are objective, secular, neutral and nonideological, and are free of partisan political influence or any implicit or explicit bias.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A352C52C9B946A7B3F2E8AE66C5F525" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Sufficient size and scope</header><text>Each grant awarded under this section shall be of sufficient size and scope for the eligible entity to carry out the activities required for such grant.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF46CB0C4AFE141E0B3B5B1791CE4F1F3" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Grants under this title may be awarded for not more than 6 years.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H44C27DEC6C9C49F4AA4C67DCC380C5DA" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>In this title, the term eligible entity means an innovative learning model provider, as defined in section 3.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H006B17968FFB42578B8BE3D5A1E1F16C" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this title, an eligible entity shall submit to the Director an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Director may reasonably require.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8872018D3F584430AA470BE20E552E1C" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Peer review</header><text>The Director shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H10D97A9F04A441229FE2892570F98296" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>implement a peer review process to assist the Director in the review of applications under this title and to make recommendations to the Director on awarding grants under this title;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0CA6756637844F57B3C47FF17342FC84" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop and maintain published peer review standards for the conduct and evaluation of all development and research carried out under this title; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5259AAF965264F89B43254E2E78C51C2" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that the peer-review teams consist of practitioners and experts who are knowledgeable about innovative learning models, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HD4092E5A64A54B5393B78C9AD87E42AC" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>individuals with experience researching and developing innovative learning models for all types of students, including English learners, children with disabilities, and disadvantaged students; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCC32AC52B1EB457A980F0408A1526EFE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>individuals with experience implementing innovative learning models.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H992CF8C3B80E4BF49475CB9DE0639022" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Training program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From funds otherwise reserved for technical assistance under this title, the Director may establish a program to train employees of public and private educational agencies, organizations, and institutions, and may establish a fellowship program to appoint such employees as temporary fellows that may assist in carrying out this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H51D99F32968B4FC1AA197D3EDA0B5D92" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>Grant funds provided under this title shall be used to supplement, not supplant, other Federal or State funds made available to carry out activities described in this title.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H716C0F5B32114D0FAE326E56DC40DBC5" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, nothing in this title shall be construed as requiring an eligible entity who is awarded a grant under subsection (a) to measure or evaluate the impact or success of an innovative learning model through the use of a randomized control trial.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HA238D9485865497BA1B523F416B6FC53"><enum>103.</enum><header>Reporting and evaluation</header> 
<subsection id="H5884206470254E8B97D6C6249B27E34A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Activities summary</header><text>Not later than two years after the date that an eligible entity receives a grant under this title, and on an annual basis thereafter, the eligible entity shall submit to the Director a summary of the activities assisted under the grant.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAE4FFABF0A4740FFBB18D0430F74C4B5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Director shall provide to Congress, and make publicly available, an annual report on the implementation of the program carried out under this title, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEA7B8D5FABFB4ADF962E93DC20AC1B8D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information on eligible entities that received grant funds under this title, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H6C18B2F49292467E863AE4FF1E4CE2C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information provided by eligible entities to the Director in the applications submitted under section 103(c);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCB3266A8E60040F9B3DE8A2629F1E199"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the summaries received under subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB221EDBE9A6E4D8C8344EC58E144F332"><enum>(C)</enum><text>grant award amounts;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H501CE28D0C7442138F43E7D2488EEC9C">
                        <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">student outcomes and other relevant impacts on students, including comprehensive learning growth, from schools that implement an innovative learning model that was developed or implemented under this title; or</text>
                    </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H074C3B1CEF1840F3AAE29A26AD6ED67C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>information and recommendations concerning any Federal policies that have been identified as presenting barriers to the adoption and implementation of innovative learning models.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3EA484F3D948470DBF6427EF39716F72"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>From amounts reserved by the Director under section 104(b)(1), the Director shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H325E4A58C95E4220A6A927F441659629"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out an independent evaluation to measure the effectiveness of the program assisted under this title; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HECC89F856D664C3881373EFF03CBF31F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make the results of such evaluation publicly available.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDBE88FEA329F4361862B3DEE044699E4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The reports and evaluation provided under subsections (b) and (c) shall be made readily available to the public.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9F3FC3CC78EB467D8DC7D4D5C39DA953"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Privacy protections</header><text>The reports and evaluation provided under subsections (b) and (c) shall not reveal personally identifiable information about any individual.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H40EEC7033AD44022BA8F984A090AB1D6"><enum>104.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> 
<subsection id="HD0D25F7EAD874C5082ED1C937B1CA1B6" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this title in each of the fiscal years 2026 through 2035.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3507EF471B1A42E68C44B7C93A94542E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reservations</header><text>From the amounts appropriated under subsection (a) for such fiscal year, the Director may reserve—</text> 
<paragraph id="H032E98A019BB4D729CA0FA357FA033B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not more than 1 percent to conduct the evaluation required under section 204(c); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H15AF6396B0FA4F268B4D8FDF9FB2E496"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not more than 1 percent to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC2B0034552A64847BB062B353B79A877"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide technical assistance for eligible entities, which may include pre-application workshops, web-based seminars, and evaluation support; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDDE71850F74D4089B625C065870C6BF2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disseminate best practices concerning the successful development and implementation of innovative learning models.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7DD699E1C9504224B2F96F061191436A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding allotment</header><text>From the amount made available under subsection (a) and not reserved under subsection (b) for a fiscal year, the Director shall—</text> <paragraph id="HBC68C712E452467D81CF21B65233BFF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reserve not less than 93 percent to award grants to eligible entities under section 103(a)(1); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCA91793E18E5460E997E91B918949EC6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reserve not less than 5 percent to award grants to eligible entities under section 103(a)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title> <title id="H264D8142FB18410CAB5C4E5242678D4C"><enum>II</enum><header>Investing in the early adoption of innovative learning models</header> <section id="H96AAA284BBA44E2D8D2BEF433AE0A0E9"><enum>201.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this title is to provide grants to State educational agencies and to provide subgrants to local educational agencies to increase the adoption and expansion of innovative learning models in elementary and secondary schools.</text></section> 
<section id="H2D3B51E0AFCC4C6285AF943ABBB66CC2"><enum>202.</enum><header>Formula grants to States</header> 
<subsection id="H002B78F961EF48C0955CC91B75D62D44"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reservation of funds</header><text>From the total amount appropriated under section 205 for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall reserve—</text> <paragraph id="H76EDDC40DE814E63807395E5D0546B10"><enum>(1)</enum><text>one-half of 1 percent for allotments for the outlying areas, to be distributed among those outlying areas on the basis of their relative need, as determined by the Secretary, in accordance with the purpose of this title; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD9A5FD50BD9647B195C643A63A3F8F1F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>one-half of 1 percent for the Secretary of the Interior for programs under this part in schools operated or funded by the Bureau of Indian Education.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H625B4A1B7EBB408583EE6A9072481FC4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State allotments</header> <paragraph id="HDA60EDFA08034868B6C21671C0D2FCB6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From funds made available under section 205 for a fiscal year and not reserved under subsection (a), the Secretary shall allot to each State the sum of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3EAC6754A6CE478E9C33F92AA2CAAB0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an amount that bears the same relationship to 20 percent of such funds for such fiscal year as the number of individuals aged 5 through 17 in the State, as determined by the Secretary on the basis of the most recent satisfactory data, bears to the number of such individuals in all such States, as so determined; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFBF96B7577FB427A8F58975B10517AA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amount that bears the same relationship to 80 percent of such funds for such fiscal year as the number of individuals aged 5 through 17 from families with incomes below the poverty line in the State, as determined by the Secretary on the basis of the most recent satisfactory data, bears to the number of such individuals in all such States, as so determined.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H232C40B265CF4FF884B45B9DDE8E94D1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>No State receiving an allotment under paragraph (1) may receive less than one-half of 1 percent of the total amount appropriated under 205 after the reservations under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) for a fiscal year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H015063C5395B476498983950E7F0D7D7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Ratable reduction</header><text>If the funds described in paragraph (1) are insufficient to pay the full amounts that all States are eligible to receive under paragraph (1) for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall ratably reduce such amounts for such fiscal year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H70C97984B18D442EAA6CB4FEF1B52DF6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reallotment</header><text>If a State does not receive an allotment, the Secretary shall reallot the amount of the allotment for such State to the remaining States in accordance with this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6567039031BA43E0AC0F7B9E97016FC1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State plan</header> <paragraph id="H1F5E5A4915B34AEABED8EA2F307000A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order to receive an allotment under this section for any fiscal year, a State shall submit a plan to the Secretary, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE3537EA9A57C4106BBF00A4CA92923F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each plan described under paragraph (1) shall include, at a minimum, the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H5027787952104FD9953BDFB1F98BD975"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of how the State educational agency will use funds received under this title for State-level activities.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBEE5B562B8C54C9DB9C52E92C38ED72B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of how the activities carried out with funds under this title are expected to improve student achievement.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF25DC5C1D1484EA9BFA3324A9329F59B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of how the State educational agency will work with local educational agencies and the communities of such agencies to develop, adopt, and implement innovative learning models.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA9747088BB154C899699C6EC4F94C977"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Assurances that the State educational agency will—</text> <clause id="HB5BD45724C1F4FEC9BC5C74422324209"><enum>(i)</enum><text>review existing resources and programs across the State and coordinate any new plans and resources under this title with such resources and programs;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9D5CF4E03F7C4C21B38B80E511A0104F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>monitor the implementation of activities under this title and provide technical assistance to local educational agencies in carrying out such activities; and</text></clause> <clause id="H6F2D0B2B285C4CD697582F06A6636A44"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide for equitable access for all students to the activities supported under this title, including compliance with the requirements of all applicable Federal civil rights laws.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2A3EDF48F93F4F88A563239BD0B14FB8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>State use of funds</header> 
<paragraph id="H54BD2634F0734B448C4B2C237DAE0E1D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided under paragraph (3), a State that receives an allotment under subsection (b) for a fiscal year shall reserve not less than 95 percent of such allotment to make subgrants to local educational agencies for such fiscal year, as described in section 203.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB29DD2F380F14201B5B43430E0CFF0AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State administration</header><text>A State educational agency may use not more than 1 percent of the amount allotted to such State under subsection (b) for the administrative costs of carrying out such State educational agency’s responsibilities under this title.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H84F15F863AB94FCDAE6E4061A19D3AB0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State activities</header><text>The State educational agency for a State that receives an allotment under subsection (b) may use funds not reserved under paragraphs (1) and (2) for activities and programs designed to meet the purposes of this title, which may include—</text> <subparagraph id="H7CC35D32CA1C49A489EBF61A5AB77F72"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing monitoring of, and training, technical assistance, and capacity building to, local educational agencies that receive subgrants under section 203;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2A91DE0E63E345C3AAE10D04EABFC0C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifying and eliminating State barriers to the development, implementation, and adoption of innovative learning models by local educational agencies and schools; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2AA7296A4CD46B782230EEE1391C6B5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>supporting local educational agencies in adopting and implementing innovative learning models in schools.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6A692360C5E247D498DD4FB91054F338"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the Secretary or any other officer or employee of the Federal Government to—</text> <paragraph id="HC64D7EC109054F82B461C46AF04A9C7E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>mandate, direct, or control the development, adoption, or implementation of any learning model by any State, local educational agency, or school; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBDCBE679255C4243BF2B99995F59781C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>influence or incentivize the receipt of any grant, contract, or cooperative agreement the receipt of any priority or preference under such grant, contract, or cooperative agreement upon a State, local educational agency, or school’s adoption or implementation of any specific learning model, instructional content, curricula, or any program of instruction.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8CEF1C00086C45F2896A11968DD4BE11"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>Grant funds provided under this section shall be used to supplement, not supplant, other Federal or State funds made available to carry out activities related to the activities described in this section.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HEAB6747B83DA4FFF947B99B1287CB83A"><enum>203.</enum><header>Subgrants to local educational agencies</header> 
<subsection id="H3B17901F6D9A4355A0449FC8A1493CB8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allocation of funds to local educational agencies</header> 
<paragraph id="H7A284CEB304C4CCE8E5F85CA0D29FFAE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Allocation formula</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From funds reserved by a State under section 202(d)(1) for a fiscal year, the State educational agency shall allot to each of the eligible local educational agencies in the State for a fiscal year the sum of—</text> <subparagraph id="HD735FF71F0A5422F917EC76DBCCBBC00"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amount that bears the same relationship to 20 percent of such funds for such fiscal year as the number of individuals aged 5 through 17 in the geographic area served by the local educational agency, as determined by the Secretary on the basis of the most recent satisfactory data, bears to the number of such individuals in the geographic areas served by all eligible local educational agencies in the State, as so determined; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFD205B0391CA4DCDB39282A13E2D9AA5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amount that bears the same relationship to 80 percent of such funds for such fiscal year as the number of individuals aged 5 through 17 from families with incomes below the poverty line in the geographic area served by the local educational agency, as determined by the Secretary on the basis of the most recent satisfactory data, bears to the number of such individuals in the geographic areas served by all eligible local educational agencies in the State, as so determined.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAE20AF968DE84E8787CD6C00B35DFAF3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum local educational agency allocation</header><text>No allocation to a local educational agency under this subsection may be made in an amount that is less than $10,000.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4F584B3F3ED34509A8DD77F20BBA631E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Ratable reduction</header><text>If the amount reserved by the State under section 202(d)(1) is insufficient to make allocations to local educational agencies in an amount equal to the minimum allocation described in subsection (a)(3), such allocations shall be ratably reduced.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6E26742BA264A0D809BD6BD34281A57"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>From the amount allotted under paragraph (1), a local educational agency may reserve not more than 1 percent of such amount for the direct administrative costs of carrying out the local educational agency’s responsibilities under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H881D845381994D6EA7E2CC9FF912AA81"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Local applications</header> 
<paragraph id="H09FB5993ACA148F4A281EDD7A6F80CA7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive an allotment under this subsection (a), a local educational agency shall submit an application to the State educational agency at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the State educational agency may reasonably require.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4B879025B7994CCDA0A5050CA39B1891"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of application</header><text>Each application submitted under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5ADD1D65B6A4402CB197715A9F8C2575"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the activities to be carried out by the local educational agency under this section;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE4A033B6956C4AFD8719ABB1BC766706"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of how the local educational agency will prioritize funds to schools served by the agency that are implementing comprehensive support and improvement activities and targeted support and improvement activities under section 1111(d) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(d)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8955A5BF6F034B15B75C163A1D10FE4E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of how the local educational agency will use data and ongoing consultation with experts and stakeholders to continually update and improve activities supported under this section;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H430D3D6B00B7434F8EAF8E19FAF5EF1C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of how the local educational agency will meaningfully collaborate with teachers, principals, other school leaders, paraprofessionals (including organizations representing such individuals), and other relevant stakeholders in school communities; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8DA05E5DFD224B379515A8BF45A735DF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other information that the State educational agency may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEBD9BA030FE44E8A9CACB44A7523F38F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Local uses of funds</header> <paragraph id="HE7F13190139D4345B12094A9EE35EFFE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A local educational agency that receives an allotment under subsection (a) shall develop, implement, select, and evaluate innovative learning models in schools served by such agency, which may be carried out—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC39A96B1E04B4D55ADD4D02C6D2DC7AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>through a grant or contract with a for-profit or non-profit entity; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H700141920CD649E5BC612CD8E7B47C85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in partnership with an institution of higher education or an Indian Tribe or Tribal organization (as such terms are defined under section 4 of the Indian Self 7 Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0695EA6F92294D5B9E2C4DB44E7A3764"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Types of activities</header><text>The innovative learning models developed and implemented under this section shall be in accordance with the purpose of this title and shall address the learning needs of all students, including children with disabilities, English learners, gifted and talented students, and students who are otherwise at-risk.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7178DAC0B4CA40089D11DD4190AEFD75"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>Grant funds provided under this section shall be used to supplement, not supplant, other Federal or State funds available to carry out activities related to the activities described in this section.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H2AF38999AA6948E6AFF580951B200951"><enum>204.</enum><header>Reporting and evaluation</header> 
<subsection id="H1057C4D6E6604A948FFAD429FDBC970F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State and local reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H6D33FC6DE28C4A1D944F886A60C5F35F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State report</header><text>Each State educational agency receiving funds under this title shall annually submit to the Secretary a report that provides—</text> <subparagraph id="H4E5357BBD9D24716A3A95E5810523DC7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of how the State is using grant funds to meet the purpose of this title; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5D7EF23D1EA64478BCB479A01E82F447"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other information that the Secretary determines are necessary and appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H56B75AC4D0A545BB8D88F3B24AA7EAE5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Local educational agency report</header><text>Each local educational agency receiving funds under this part shall annually submit to the appropriate State educational agency such information as the State may require, which shall include how the local educational agency is using grant funds to meet the purposes of this title.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE35138129E8946E0AA51867EC79D7C1E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The reports and information provided under paragraphs (1) and (2) shall be made readily available to the public.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H70D8336F87C04A6F96FB878C10BE6872"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Privacy protection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The reports and evaluation provided under subsections (b) and (c) shall not reveal personally identifiable information about any individual.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1A8F27181A9F4A1CB421FDF37FE6C00E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Secretary’s report</header><text>The Secretary shall provide to Congress an annual report on the implementation of the program carried out under this title, including—</text> <paragraph id="HDE280D938DE249E5B03627EB463950D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information provided by States to the Secretary in the applications submitted under section 204(1);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3DB230B03455449CAD751D76E2E7ED03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount allotted to each State and outlying area; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE4B8A17655D4A22A227CD87FA0DE6C0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>student academic and, as applicable, growth data from the schools participating in the programs supported under this title.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6A1636F820D742C2A35DF24863E9057A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Evaluation and technical assistance</header> 
<paragraph id="H0B0A64FCBE0147F09BB02D76342B23BA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reservation of funds</header><text>Of the total amount made available for this title for a fiscal year, the Secretary may reserve for such fiscal year not more than 1 percent for the cost of the evaluation under paragraph (2) and for technical assistance in carrying out this title.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB0CBF28DFE8740B798143B5779F9E59D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluation</header> <subparagraph id="HA11C4543AE054F8CBFD7027131FFBCCD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From amounts reserved under paragraph (1), the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall carry out an independent evaluation to measure the effectiveness of the program assisted under this title.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA158DADBA27C48FB8AD77DF14A648492"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The evaluation under subparagraph (A) shall measure—</text> <clause id="H8FE8F2B918C84F209DBD528D13560DE4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the effectiveness of each program assisted under this title in improving student academic achievement and growth;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBF181CE764DA4E18B90C235CF7665809"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the effectiveness of individual learning models in improving student academic achievement and growth; and</text></clause> <clause id="H170682C5EA4B4CC28780A5F837B9960C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other information that the Director may require.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC571EAAB37A84C348F06749FE1F4BA28"><enum>205.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purposes of carrying out this title, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this title in each fiscal years 2027 through 2036.</text></section></title> </legis-body></bill>

