<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL25161-Y4R-WM-S20"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1025 IS: FCC Legal Enforcement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1025</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250313">March 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the Federal Communications Commission to enforce its own forfeiture penalties with respect to violations of restrictions on the use of telephone equipment, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id534eb1adb1234d6ba1d5e73265e33a9a"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>FCC Legal Enforcement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="S1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Enforcement of forfeiture penalties by Federal Communications Commission</header><subsection id="idC47B8D67AF6743F9A071EDDA6F4B4367"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title V of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/501">47 U.S.C. 501 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id128EF1AAB4B1488284E721D08377EA7B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 503(b)(3)(B) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/503">47 U.S.C. 503(b)(3)(B)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>In such action,</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>If, during the 120-day period beginning on the date of a referral of an unpaid forfeiture penalty imposed for a violation of section 227 (relating to restrictions on the use of telephone equipment), the Attorney General does not commence an action to recover the amount assessed, the Commission may commence and supervise the litigation of such an action and any appeal of such an action in its own name by any of its attorneys designated by it for such purpose. In any action under this subparagraph,</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA5DD87D9384C4FAE9BA0DB7A61CD2B0D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 504(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/504">47 U.S.C. 504(a)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="id52A2D47050294179925EAD72E60DD4DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>It shall be the duty</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in the subsequent sentence, it shall be the duty</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id36315D09417F4E8798BC8CD60337EC13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The costs and expenses of such prosecutions</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>If, during the 120-day period beginning on the date on which the Commission refers an unpaid forfeiture penalty imposed for a violation of section 227 (relating to restrictions on the use of telephone equipment) to the Attorney General for prosecution under this subsection, the Attorney General does not commence such a prosecution, the Commission may prosecute for the recovery of the forfeiture penalty. The costs and expenses of a prosecution under this subsection</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H124EF13E822D4E3486DCEA2B39E27ED2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In carrying out the amendments made by subsection (a) of this section, the Federal Communications Commission shall prioritize enforcement of unpaid forfeiture penalties imposed for a violation of section 227 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/227">47 U.S.C. 227</external-xref>) (relating to restrictions on the use of telephone equipment) that are greater than $25,000,000.</text></subsection></section><section id="id64064ba052eb42009d204a97802692ca"><enum>3.</enum><header>Regulations for restrictions on use of automated telephone equipment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 227(b)(2) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/227">47 U.S.C. 227(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended, in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting before the period the following: <quote>as necessary in the judgment of the Commission to protect subscribers from unwanted calls</quote>.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

