<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR25047-1NW-PP-7S3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S127 IS: Whole-Home Repairs Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 127</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250116">January 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a whole-home repairs program for eligible homeowners and eligible landlords, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Whole-Home Repairs Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id90e721ae535a4e08b3d4b6f9c690725b"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id6f1b9d42da4f4c939c94ce7857e2cc00"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affordable unit</header><text>The term <term>affordable unit</term> means a unit with a rental payment that is affordable to a tenant with an income at or below 80 percent of the area median income, as defined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id320402aa99964bc99bf13cb9b154f089"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assisted unit</header><text>The term <term>assisted unit</term> means a unit that undergoes repair or rehabilitation work through a whole-home repairs program administered by an implementing organization under this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4ef53200b42b4673a7bf0303517aaa6e"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible homeowner</header><text>The term <term>eligible homeowner</term> means a homeowner—</text><subparagraph id="id5f81c32d54604291827e6fcc314942f0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with a household income that—</text><clause id="idc4ee45833ad64caa8527f192f5b8d046"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not more than 80 percent of the area median income;</text></clause><clause id="idd3ee1aeba340400bb3d17b083ad0be8b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not more than 200 percent of the Federal poverty guidelines, as determined by the Secretary of Health and Human Services; or</text></clause><clause id="id6c4930cf4fcc4a10842c2b79a857bcbf"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>meets the income eligibility criteria of another program used by a Federal agency for programs focusing on families of limited means, as determined by the Secretary; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc01a8bf9589b4578bf805dfb66efd7d9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who is—</text><clause id="id11d91447997140d0984b28a228156ea0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an owner of record as evidenced by a publicly recorded deed and occupies the home on which repairs are to be conducted as their principal residence;</text></clause><clause id="idaacb6824d0e54840b584c90806e3ea1a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an owner-occupant of the manufactured home on which repairs are to be conducted; or</text></clause><clause id="id16d1f8f4a6fa45708093d422fc1b56df"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an equitable owner who can demonstrate an ownership interest in the property on which repairs are to be conducted, including a person who has inherited an interest in that property. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd3130518bc1c4800875af3b4a4083a81"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible landlord</header><text>The term <term>eligible landlord</term> means an individual—</text><subparagraph id="id410dfc071eaf4c21a9f938a00de38715"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who owns, as determined by the relevant implementing organization, fewer than 10 residential rental properties, with a majority of affordable units and not more than 50 total units, operated as primary residences in which a majority ownership interest is held by the individual, the spouse of the individual, or the dependent children of the individual, or any closely held legal entity controlled by the individual, the spouse of the individual, or the dependent children of the individual, either individually or collectively; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida3f83335435b4993bc87e14d96e77a64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who agrees to the provisions described in section 3(c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide7cd45fb1f2c43be8bbf4cf3b087aa1a"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Eligible rental property</header><text>The term <term>eligible rental property</term> means a residential property that is leased, or offered exclusively for lease, as a primary residence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfeda90626cd441228e2f8575c9cd16a3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Forgivable loan</header><text>The term <term>forgivable loan</term> means a loan—</text><subparagraph id="id3212691f30f542419be0b820515d51ed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>made to an eligible landlord;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaec94e5310db4392877815bb99f7fb68"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is secured by a lien recorded against a residential property; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc9c36a060d75423b84620a74eca1943d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that may be forgiven by the implementing organization not later than the date that is 3 years after the completion of the repairs if the eligible landlord has maintained compliance with the loan agreement described in section 3(c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc283aa47b6a14cf6bad5108b9188d998"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Implementing organization</header><text>The term <term>implementing organization</term>—</text><subparagraph id="idbdffdcbd75b04c508f3626b27f4fbea4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a unit of general local government or a State that will administer a whole-home repairs program through an agency, department, or other entity or enter into agreements with 1 or more local governments, municipal authorities, other governmental authorities, or qualified nonprofits to administer a whole-home repairs program as a subrecipient; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc8c288dad26941f0af7079cc7e097afa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a redundant entity in a jurisdiction already served by a grantee under section 3. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbc5dd6af7af24be39ad585c5bcd2a357"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Indian tribe</term> in section 4 of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4103">25 U.S.C. 4103</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida72280770a42434883f6e92c9d9d819d"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Qualified nonprofit</header><text>The term <term>qualified nonprofit</term> means a nonprofit organization that has—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idadebda190d1b4b44a33e22e67c6bebdf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>received funding, as a recipient or subrecipient, through—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idac9ba5f08643466aace324f8ff2b91b1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Community Development Block Grant program under title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5301">42 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id461b627a0c704b0d9e270b9176491f1c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the HOME Investment Partnerships program under subtitle A of title II of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12741">42 U.S.C. 12741 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide257584ce08c44dc92acfb95dfd2225c"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Lead-Based Paint Hazard Reduction grant program under section 1011 of the Residential Lead-Based Paint Hazard Reduction Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4852">42 U.S.C. 4852</external-xref>) or a grant under the Healthy Homes Initiative administered by the Secretary pursuant to sections 501 and 502 of the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1701z-1">12 U.S.C. 1701z–1</external-xref>, 1701z–2); </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id869fa11eb12a4e039cb2f9366a307663"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Self-Help and Assisted Homeownership Opportunity program authorized under section 11 of the Housing Opportunity Program Extension Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12805">42 U.S.C. 12805</external-xref> note);</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id513b0bf6fdb24665a3d269a69fe48728"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a rural housing program under title V of the Housing Act of 1949 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1471">42 U.S.C. 1471 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="id99e95d1d2d9b47b9aca3654ae4dd5310"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation established under the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8101">42 U.S.C. 8101 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></clause><clause id="id825772f4032c4457955702adbc371e82"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>any other program as determined by the Secretary; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8bd7385a4a874b7d8d718276ae116ec7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordinated, performed, or otherwise been engaged in weatherization, lead remediation, or home-repair work for not less than 2 years; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id76695956b71f47ea95afe0d93bf8cbb6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>been certified by the Environmental Protection Agency, or by a State authorized by the Environmental Protection Agency to administer a certification program, as— </text><clause id="idc6336f0a4b6f4649a43d901b6316c1cf"><enum>(i)</enum><text>eligible to carry out activities under the lead renovation, repair and painting program; or </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddda33f9333a9463fa5f4df9c97a7d601"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Home Certification Organization under the Energy Star program established by section 324A of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6294a">42 U.S.C. 6294a</external-xref>) or the WaterSense program under section 324B of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6294b">42 U.S.C. 6294b</external-xref>), or recognized or otherwise approved by the Environmental Protection Agency as a Home Certification Organization under either of those programs.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd8eaa6ec32bd4f328ea216ca1adc54ca"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idab651c9281cf459d83d8ee45dca670e1"><enum>(11)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd997e766daf741e89bcd99f25b0e44bc"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each State of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id03cc9ef35d924b9bb5dfc25ebb558bfa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the District of Columbia;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3654a20c1864466196dd1933fbbdab3a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide89dc6e343f944b2947ae2faa18dfc79"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any territory or possession of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id693d7f284524476d9d90523972b8f193"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id61c85fbc6fb64e5c88eb196a018f2de6"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Whole-home repairs</header><text>The term <term>whole-home repairs</term> means modifications, repairs, or updates to homeowner or renter-occupied units to address—</text><subparagraph id="id9fa2f1857ee04f93883d29151546f76e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>physical and sensory accessibility for individuals with disabilities and older adults, such as bathroom and kitchen modifications, installation of grab bars and handrails, guards and guardrails, lifting devices, ramp additions or repairs, sidewalk addition or repair, or doorway or hallway widening;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id03853aa17aa9465c96c3d1a057b1aa74"><enum>(B)</enum><text>habitability and safety concerns, such as repairs needed to ensure residential units are fit for human habitation and free from defective conditions or health and safety hazards;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id07f929520f424bcf9478b371aab752be"><enum>(C)</enum><text>energy and water efficiency, resilience, and weatherization; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaae42a33ac3a40beba9b267fb91d69a0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other conditions as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id69c0c27b9f484ba180fc63d373796316"><enum>3.</enum><header>Pilot program</header><subsection id="idf51d43a89e3e49a6b27f53bb5cc57c5e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a pilot program to provide grants to implementing organizations to administer a whole-home repairs program for eligible homeowners and eligible landlords.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3a04521e1fe9453f9e81a284afb9cfeb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An implementing organization that receives a grant under this section—</text><paragraph id="id86c07735a6c74eccae5c9b2af3f0ca40"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall provide grants to eligible homeowners to implement whole-home repairs up to a maximum amount per unit, which maximum amount should—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb6b4390a6a0e41f390d3f6d29e0f3d61"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reflect local construction costs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idad7c3e014a724bf78200e69685f9d503"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be calculated by the implementing organization; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6fbba864cb174b39a6dd7e46b3067470"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be approved by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddc481297294b4c04afd29dcb80b2762e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall provide loans, which may be forgivable loans, to eligible landlords to implement whole-home repairs for individual affordable units, public and common use areas within the property, and common structural elements up to a maximum amount per unit, area, or element, as applicable, which maximum amount should— </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id500416E8061F4E49A1C212530079B4B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reflect local construction costs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0EEF6010F60A45079678BCD3125351E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be calculated by the implementing organization; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id90372EA7146F4D248F19D6C20A4D9897"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be approved by the Secretary; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbb06267f241f4e3bb353a760d885ded0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall evaluate, or provide assistance to eligible homeowners and eligible landlords to evaluate, whole-home repair program funds provided under this section with Federal, State, and local home repair programs to provide the greatest benefit to the greatest number of eligible landlords and eligible homeowners and avoid redundancy; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idebcd0d8040d9464188afb9556beda910"><enum>(4)</enum><text>shall ensure that—</text><subparagraph id="id50a440db2531462c88681102e0a2863a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all repairs funded or facilitated through an award under this section have been completed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2bbe9c61cb5f4cb8bd5855cf6b7a301c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if repairs are not completed and the plan for whole-home repairs is not updated to reflect the new scope of work, that the loan or grant is repaid on a prorated basis based on completed work; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8dd99411cfac4743987e0e3f711301e8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any unused grant or loan balance is returned to the implementing organization;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id60c0bdb7b89a4de197509a6887222445"><enum>(5)</enum><text>may use not more than 10 percent of the awarded funds to carry out related functions, including workforce training, which shall be related to efforts to increase the number of home repairs performed and approved by the Secretary; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc6b35f2bb04f4b8a807ebc84f8789f78"><enum>(6)</enum><text>may use not more than 10 percent of the awarded funds for administrative expenses; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0d376ec91acc4340a160006e14824261"><enum>(7)</enum><text>shall comply with Federal accessibility requirements and standards under applicable Federal fair housing and civil rights laws and regulations, including section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida8f0f03e75544fda8a7a66f8076fba85"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Loan agreement</header><text>In a loan agreement with an eligible landlord under this section, an implementing organization shall include provisions establishing that the eligible landlord shall, for each eligible rental property for which a loan is used to fund repairs under this section—</text><paragraph id="ided16b23bad2648d2af22a9989ac4f1f4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>comply with Federal accessibility requirements and standards under applicable Federal fair housing and civil rights laws and regulations, including section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="iddb171fb0df594719bdda26c257477874"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id7355e64d05704aa389e97fd147ffefdc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the landlord is renting the assisted units available in the eligible rental property to tenants receiving tenant-based rental assistance under section 8(o) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)</external-xref>), under another tenant-based rental assistance program administered by the Secretary or the Secretary of Agriculture, or under a tenant-based rental subsidy provided by a State or local government, comply with the program requirements under the relevant tenant-based rental assistance program; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf7fdd38b9f0c48f8b0a6b0c0b9035bf0" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the eligible landlord is not renting to tenants receiving rental-based assistance as described in subparagraph (A)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47b5983d18034d39bdd31bc78cf1327d"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="ide4517705e6484601a8fdb7ca6f55d074"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">offer to extend the lease of current tenants on current terms, other than the terms described in clause (iv), for not less than 3 years beginning after the completion of the repairs, unless the lease is terminated due to failure to pay rent, property damage, performance of an illegal act within the rental unit, a direct threat to the safety of the tenants, or a violation of an obligation of tenancy that the tenants failed to correct after notice; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="idb5645bd1cd31461e87d6438389b89987"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the tenant of an assisted unit moves out of the assisted unit at any point in the 3-year period following the loan agreement, maintain the unit as an affordable unit;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="idaad4ce38be054befa4eb53f1228bf451"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide documentation verifying that the property, upon completion of approved renovations, has met all applicable State and local housing and building codes;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id159b0e488cc44848933c003a8954cc4d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>attest that the landlord has no known serious violations of renter protections that have resulted in fines, penalties, or judgments during the preceding 10 years; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef5d640ff5c44e5286c7b6af3b5453bd"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cap annual rent increases for each assisted unit at 5 percent of base rent or inflation, whichever is lower, for not less than 3 years beginning after the completion of the repairs.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf417861e4d3943a3b84552e3555a1c36"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><paragraph id="idf8f4aedf2eeb4401b82abc13348fcbbc"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An implementing organization desiring an award under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application that includes—</text><subparagraph id="id8ffc993b02de46e1a3eb5b77ace475dd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the geographic scope of the whole-home repairs program to be administered by the implementing organization, including the plan to address need in any rural, suburban, or urban area within a jurisdiction; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc05d0105d8ee4b03b63493119aa9ad10"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a plan for selecting subrecipients, if applicable;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida414e98a8d4649e799e0c07cebbc79cb"><enum>(C)</enum><text>how the implementing organization plans to execute the coordination of Federal, State, and local home repair programs, including programs administered by the Department of Energy or the Department of Agriculture, to increase efficiency and reduce redundancy; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id665fdcbab97c4c75a891f53036a09a2b"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">available data on the need for affordable and quality housing, and any plans to preserve affordability through the term of the award;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7a7de2ad638e44c2b0e5e98da20e521d"><enum>(E)</enum><text>how the implementing organization plans to process and verify applications for grants from eligible homeowners and applications for loans from eligible landlords; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7d3ac0c58f924c06888f014c633c72da"><enum>(F)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary requires to determine the ability of an applicant to carry out a program under this section. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idde5cae39fb054f0695000620cf5360e5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In making awards under this section, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="id71ac79c4c93f4a55977b699a7df61d4f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to applications submitted by States other than the District of Columbia and the territories of the United States, prioritize those applications with a demonstrated plan to—</text><clause id="id5ba118abf8de4b41a233b30ba2d0f7a5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>make a good faith effort to implement the pilot program in every jurisdiction; and</text></clause><clause id="ide6ae844780ae409081d107467fb26d3b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide non-metropolitan areas, or subrecipients serving non-metropolitan areas if applicable, with a share of total funds commensurate to their population; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ided1e2ac4c0094611ac54b8aedaf120e9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>aim to select applicants so that the awardees collectively span diverse geographies, with an intent to understand the impact of the pilot program under this section in urban, suburban, rural, and Tribal settings; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id381da371881b46db878405ac0a05e4e9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not disqualify implementing organizations that were awarded grants under the pilot program in prior application cycles. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idad0d2a88f4964c9094c6465e4835cae9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Program information</header><text>The Secretary shall make available to grant recipients under this section information regarding existing Federal programs for which grant recipients may coordinate or provide assistance in coordinating applications for those programs in accordance with subsection (b)(3).</text></subsection><subsection id="id19a0fde7e81c488b95c02d3f50ff3004"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Grant number</header><text>In each year in which an award is made under this section, the Secretary shall award assistance to—</text><paragraph id="id2077b47e027c4f9b9852509c52a62218"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not less than 2, and not more than 10, implementing organizations, as application numbers and funding permit; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc3d1fd42acd74aa8929668760d651cc0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not more than 1 implementing organization in any State.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0270e7fda05c4d36a4e5a6e692945604"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Loans that are not forgiven</header><text>If a loan made by an implementing organization under subsection (b)(2) is not forgiven, the loan repayment funds may be reused by the implementing organization for a new whole-home repair grant or loan under this section. </text></subsection><subsection id="id891c9501afbd4c7dbffef48cb1846168"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>Amounts awarded under this section to implementing organizations shall supplement, not supplant, other Federal, State, and local funds made available to those entities.</text></subsection><subsection id="id2f56bb0652054745bb8d83ce53187ab3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Streamlining program delivery and ensuring efficiency</header><text>To the extent possible, in carrying out the pilot program under this section, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4cc6568d422f4c799fdefb31bde622bc"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">endeavor to improve efficiency of service delivery, as well as the experience of and impact on the taxpayer, by encouraging programmatic collaboration and information sharing across Federal, State, and local programs for home repair or improvement, including programs administered by the Department of the Agriculture; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6c494bbef05f489c9552e60b65197b06"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enhance collaboration and cross-agency streamlining efforts that reduce the burdens of multiple income verification processes and applications on the eligible homeowner, the eligible landlord, the implementing organization, and the Federal Government, including by establishing assistance application procedures for income eligibility under this Act that recognize income eligibility determinations for assistance using any of the criteria under section 2(3)(A) that have been used for assistance applications during the 1-year period preceding the date on which an eligible homeowner or eligible landlord applies for assistance under this Act. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9274a8d9218947c6a3dffe80e62de831"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><paragraph id="id0bbf484c77364ee49aceed603a388b7a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>An implementing organization that receives a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an annual report on initial funding that includes— </text><subparagraph id="idbf3cb5943c7b49d7a37d9c47f8145251"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of units served, including reporting on both homeownership and rental units;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7d61389a3744486684f3aa39076e9737"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the average cost per unit for modifications or repairs and the nature of those modifications or repairs, including reporting on both homes and rental units;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idff2b0add01584e8e89599cd486bba67a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of applications received, served, denied, or not completed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide94c43ab19e4444890f1d97a1eeb9c68"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the aggregated demographic data of grant recipients, which may include data on income range, urban, suburban, and rural residency, age, and racial and ethnic identity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9454fdf965fc4387955c10706a1f7116"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the aggregated demographic data of loan recipients, which may include data on income range, urban, suburban, and rural residency, age, and racial and ethnic identity; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4e61a72fcc0c4069b142d45c7fa5bc2e"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in the first year of receiving a grant, and as certified in subsequent reports, a comprehensive plan to prevent waste, fraud, and abuse in the administration of the pilot program, which shall include, at a minimum—</text><clause id="idaa3d68e546eb4f2d9551f2073ff91374"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a policy enacted and enforced by the implementing organization to monitor ongoing expenditures under this title and ensure compliance with applicable regulations, including compliance with Federal accessibility requirements;</text></clause><clause id="idd00fb4a2fe9548559ff01659e585a13c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a policy enacted and enforced by the implementing organization to detect and deter fraudulent activity, including fraud occurring in individual projects and patterns of fraud by parties involved in the expenditure of funds under this section; </text></clause><clause id="ide5bfca3d3ed74748a321f3803e985d99"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a statement setting forth any violations detected by the implementing organization during the previous calendar year, including details about steps taken to achieve compliance and any remedial measures; and</text></clause><clause id="id3f070470a6f44a3e8519f05c72f4054c"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a certification by the chief executive or most senior compliance officer of the organization that the organization maintains sufficient staff and resources to effectively carry out the above-mentioned policies; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9f000ac2e521483db9f908ac7d2a2c7e"><enum>(G)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may require. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id133a0b615a35435bb1e0b0252fdd8612"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reporting requirement alignment</header><text>To limit the costs of implementing the pilot program under this section, the Secretary shall endeavor, to the extent possible, to structure reporting requirements such that they align with the data reporting requirements in place for funding streams that implementing organizations are likely to use in partnership with funding from this section, including the reporting requirements under—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id15b13e30299d4e78b0b4f4190c1d832b"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Community Development Block Grant program under title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5301">42 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</external-xref>); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id80EAFC6BF8F645E29857BC0B15F2E3ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the HOME Investment Partnerships program under subtitle A of title II of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12741">42 U.S.C. 12741 et seq.</external-xref>); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id481aae3b6cc341e797d6d21754a39bcd"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Weatherization Assistance Program for low-income persons established under part A of title IV of the Energy Conservation and Production Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6861">42 U.S.C. 6861 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide63c5830260a42d282867be012674b2f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4101">25 U.S.C. 4101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id566ef1377c7244caacce05d4dd664948"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Pilot program period reports</header><text>Not less frequently than twice during the period in which the pilot program established under this section operates, the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Housing and Urban Development shall complete an assessment of the implementation of measures to ensure the fair and legitimate use of the pilot program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfa836683be7a4ca485215e2790109e94"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Summary to Congress</header><text>The Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives an annual report providing a summary of the data provided under paragraphs (1) and (3) during the 1-year period preceding the report and all data previously provided under those paragraphs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2715d889fa40427bb2900d2ff3a81cad"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to use up to $25,000,000 of funds made available as provided in appropriations Acts for programs administered by the Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes to carry out the pilot program under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida46a3637298a45b9bf3791a027edf4ef"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The pilot program established under this section shall terminate on October 1, 2030. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

