<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE63626ED1BC0493287F04EA0612977A9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 760 IH: Restoring Access to Mountain Homes Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 760</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250128">January 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To make certain repairs, replacements, and restorations of private roads and bridges eligible for reimbursement under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H289BCF8C08F847EC939DC31EBE89E127" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2EB05E8B39A948FAABBF95AC9A05DCA4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Restoring Access to Mountain Homes Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H8C6A2A0A016F4F2F8413A44E0EEC623F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reimbursement for repair, replacement, and restoration work on private roads and bridges impacted by Tropical Storm Helene</header> <subsection id="HF9DFD4EE74224FF18781EA585BBA286A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Eligibility for reimbursement</header><text>Notwithstanding any provision of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>) or the regulations governing the public assistance program of the Federal Emergency Management Agency under such Act, the State, Indian Tribal, and local governments in North Carolina covered under major disaster declaration FEMA–4827–DR–NC (relating to Tropical Storm Helene) shall be eligible for reimbursement for the cost of repairs, replacements, or restoration to private roads and bridges, without regard to pre-existing condition, under section 428 of such Act that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H494C14C752634F1A99F7F5A78E6B854F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are used as the sole means of access to primary residences or essential community services;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H66474BB09DC349009A628C1B6B2F1C1F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are significantly damaged or destroyed as a direct result of Tropical Storm Helene as identified in FEMA–4827–DR–NC; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE7D3EC7991D244CEBC96762D7ADC82D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>does not duplicate work that has already been completed.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H550B60B45204411786A7DF487D9BDE04"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conditions of reimbursement</header><text>Reimbursement under this section shall be subject to the following conditions:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB2777A9CD64F4015AF913CF0761DD9D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Private roads or bridges shall be inspected by appropriate State, Indian Tribal, or local government officials or their designees to verify the scope, need, and cost-effectiveness of any mitigation measures for the proposed repair, replacement, or restoration.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF2D8616B02344AD8750ADE16991EE54"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The State, Indian Tribal, or local governments requesting assistance shall ensure that the private roads or bridges being repaired, replaced, or restored remain open for disaster recovery activities for the duration of the repair, replacement, or restoration process.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H121AE99AB5B5437AB891683EF53FD945"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The State or Indian Tribal governments shall be responsible for documenting all costs associated with repairs, replacements, or restorations within their jurisdiction in accordance with Federal Emergency Management Agency policy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H16464FF1F9AB4F5CB216A3EF8D46E87E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The State, Indian Tribal, or local government applying for public assistance funding shall obtain authority or permission to perform the work to permanently repair, replace, or restore the private roads and bridges.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4F9C99305A7646B49F74D5D77C7796D4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The State, Indian Tribal, or local government applying for public assistance funding shall ensure the work under this section is performed in compliance with all applicable State and Federal regulations and requirements that pertain to work that is permanent in nature.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3158CA73B9184ED9B416F4C105AC6A01"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duplication of benefits</header> <paragraph id="HE728F677CBE9487581B38D2FBCD7F5FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any individual or household that has received assistance prior to the date of enactment of this section pursuant to section 408 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174</external-xref>) for the purposes of repairing a private road or bridge eligible under this section may proceed with such repairs or return any such assistance to have such repair eligible pursuant to this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA0EFAAEF56864ADDACF94E806062385E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Calculation</header><text>In the event the individual or household chooses to proceed with such repairs utilizing assistance provided pursuant to section 408 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174</external-xref>) for a private road or bridge, such assistance shall not be counted against the maximum amount of assistance for such individual or household under such section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEFF9AA588D334599895052A1629348A3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible costs</header><text>In determining eligible costs, the Administrator shall base such determinations on properly conducted and certified cost estimates prepared by professionally licensed engineers (mutually agreed upon by the Administrator and the applicant). Once certified by a professionally licensed engineer and accepted by the Administrator, the estimates on which grants made pursuant to this section are based shall be presumed to be reasonable and eligible costs, as long as there is no evidence of fraud.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

