<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0CDF30604B5C4133A4083E4103DC31E6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2681 IH: Moab UMTRA Project Transition Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2681</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250407">April 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000403">Mr. Kennedy of Utah</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001228">Ms. Maloy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Strom Thurmond National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1999 to provide for the transfer of the Moab site to Grand County, Utah, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H53A2F97669CB4165ACD7C8E18F833FC4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H996195F133514E67B13D773FB90853AC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Moab UMTRA Project Transition Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5B1EE93A37B245B58CDA59D14C1ABD39"><enum>2.</enum><header>Moab UMTRA project</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3405(i) of the Strom Thurmond National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/8720">10 U.S.C. 8720</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/261">Public Law 105–261</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD2FE0C2572444B26BCE316D7EB237B9B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (5);</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E8168451C804D24B5BA0A846CD9FEA2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (6) as paragraph (5); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D14A641E7D04D7E82487B4B346F9DC6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H75F9AE8B87234060940508A74F2591D5" style="OLC" act-name=""> <paragraph id="H907B1919535B42E6AAC770901CABCD3F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Transfer of Moab site to Grand County</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4A40CC5FB6547C2A1DDEBB35AA554E0"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraphs (B), (C), and (D), on achieving a remedial action completion status sufficient for land conveyance, as determined by the Secretary of Energy in consultation with relevant regulatory authorities, and subject to any regulatory or use restrictions, if determined necessary to protect human health and safety by the Secretary of Energy or the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (including restrictions pursuant to the Uranium Mill Tailings Radiation Control Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7901">42 U.S.C. 7901 et seq.</external-xref>) and part 192 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations)), the Secretary of Energy shall convey, at no cost, all available right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Moab site to Grand County, Utah.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7684BBAD7C3842D393A89D0F7B6C197F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Retention of certain water rights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the conveyance under subparagraph (A), in accordance with applicable law, the Secretary of Energy shall ensure that the United States retains such water rights as the Secretary of Energy determines necessary to carry out the responsibilities of the Secretary of Energy under the Uranium Mill Tailings Radiation Control Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7901">42 U.S.C. 7901 et seq.</external-xref>), part 192 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), and other applicable requirements, including, if the remediation of groundwater is ongoing at the time of the conveyance, such rights as are necessary to maintain access to wells and the associated surface footprint of those wells.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE50836CFB2AC44B6AE45441C3085B3B7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>The conveyance under subparagraph (A) shall include a provision that prohibits Grand County, Utah, from reconveying to a private entity or nonprofit organization any portion of the land conveyed to Grand County, Utah, under that subparagraph.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB0BB89C30AF1444ABEA95604E2D5771D"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Additional terms and conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy may require such additional terms and conditions in connection with the conveyance under subparagraph (A) as the Secretary determines necessary to protect the interests of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

