<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H61B93962FD584ECCA221EF641BDA112A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2406 IH: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Sexual Harassment and Assault Prevention Improvements Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2406</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to address sexual harassment and sexual assault involving National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration personnel, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBFD040A8A75B4F0BAC14C70E4FEC0A6A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBC8872CD211E4D51BA710C9585DA15AB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Sexual Harassment and Assault Prevention Improvements Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H91E28F385C714B259BB69C53E2EF821C"><enum>2.</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise specifically provided, whenever in this Act an amendment or repeal is expressed in terms of an amendment to, or repeal of, a provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to a provision of subtitle C of title XXXV of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/894">33 U.S.C. 894 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></section> 
<section id="H9D6B8DC1777348F793B8CFD8EE3E0C14"><enum>3.</enum><header> Policy on prevention of and response to sexual harassment involving National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration personnel</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3541(f) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/894">33 U.S.C. 894(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB5CA5866E4154720BABED6C49717F83C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and equal employment</quote> after <quote>sexual harassment</quote> in each place it appears; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAD8DDC3FDBA0469895D9D13A769F425F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="H3802F05A89504AF79B91854D563E3E79"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subparagraphs (C) and (D) as subparagraphs (D) and (E), respectively; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H94A081FB0DA84204B21D8DDC440F3113"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (B) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H604FB4E8390D4FBFBAED9D093B762326" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="HDED9158D09F34E0FA180FE5C251909FB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Relevant data, including—</text> 
<clause id="H486BBDFC7C4D489AACEAFCD74FD4DB94"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a synopsis of each case and the disciplinary action taken, if any, with respect to each such case; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB89EAA07746049DAA52770236F24F02D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">data collected pursuant to the Notification and Federal Employee Antidiscrimination and Retaliation Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/2301">5 U.S.C. 2301</external-xref> note).</text> </clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HAA2071D0570B4B558C437650DEC5DE49"><enum>4.</enum><header>Annual report on sexual harassment, sexual assault, and equal employment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3548 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/894e">33 U.S.C. 894e</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC35857823CDA441789F940687F8DBAB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking the section heading and inserting the <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Annual report on sexual harassment, sexual assault, and equal employment in National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</header-in-text></quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9875BEA67B8643CDAF5AEEEF31F3F6CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>the sexual assaults involving</quote> and inserting <quote>sexual harassment and sexual assault cases involving, and the equal employment of,</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H17A4967D6997407AA2E6A431E129BE58"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8F91C40152A84E52888BE61D92670914" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>assaults</quote> and inserting <quote>harassment and sexual assault cases</quote>; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEDDE172A1B454A819E6F6619730BCB85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by inserting <quote>, including a synopsis of each sexual harassment and equal employment case and the disciplinary action taken, if any, with respect to each such case</quote> before the period at the end; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCD576B997F3142B79C6B9A49A6E32FF2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4240EC0470DE4E2397E5C796B9102978" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H6CF70CC763EB41C49CD7132155FBB23A"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A summary of the number of change of station, unit transfer, and change of work location requests submitted to the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere, under subsection (a) of section 3544, including the number of such requests the Secretary denied under that subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5BDF9F59DCD94659AD0845B7927CE563" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A summary of the number of cases reported to the Commandant of the Coast Guard under section 3550.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H38D28F4A2ABE411DB3DC4B1DDD93A1C7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The number of alleged sexual harassment and sexual assault cases involving fisheries observers, protected species observers, and endangered species observers, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H97D12D3C3B134139A9D8EABCCAABC31B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a synopsis of each case and the status of each such case;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3C3A27C330DF4AD394AF805BA4915964"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the disposition of any investigation; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA953DCFDFE684F2589950858DCEC34F2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the fishery management region and fishery or the geographic region and type of permitted operation in which the incident of sexual harassment or sexual assault is alleged to have occurred, as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2BF07256918642CABD89CE899525B7C1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>assault</quote> and inserting <quote>harassment or sexual assault case</quote>. </text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H193398E1CABA4787B88BF07D81942C2C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Investigation and criminal referral requirements</header> 
<subsection id="H10B4DF0B55D5469CB3181C363723DB15"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sections 3548 and 3549 (33 U.S.C. 894e and 894f) are redesignated as sections 3551 and 3552, respectively.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC9980A555FC44844A1A1CCDA1DF0FB88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criminal referral</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3547 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/894d-2">33 U.S.C. 894d–2</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H006C9B9DB8F64666915DA1399D6F497C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>pursuant to</quote> and inserting <quote>at the onset or during the course of</quote>; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HE6964F558BEA45909987B7103624B615"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and, with respect to a licensed mariner, the Commandant of the Coast Guard</quote> after <quote>United States Attorney</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H61BC1743E46F4426A2A49D5689186B3B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle C of title XXXV (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/894">33 U.S.C. 894 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 3547 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/894d-2">33 U.S.C. 894d–2</external-xref>) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBE6DE51739E3457A89DC7EC74D721265" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H0C9B87AC208A4E08B5D6188D0F220C43"><enum>3548.</enum><header>Exceptions regarding anonymity of victims in certain cases</header> <subsection id="H542F7C5A19BD46BF82244F521ED0A6DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which an employee of the Administration, member of the commissioned officer corps of the Administration, or covered personnel elects restricted or unrestricted reporting under section 3541(b)(3)(B) or 3542(b)(5)(B), disclosure to the following persons or organizations of the personally identifying information of such individual is authorized for the following reasons:</text> 
<paragraph id="H18426AFF81934C879876FAA37AF2B6A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To Administration staff or law enforcement personnel, if authorized by the victim in writing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C3767F94A9743FA83E2CF204535808C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To Administration staff or law enforcement personnel to prevent or lessen a serious or imminent threat to the health or safety of the victim or another person.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B4682CC263940D894AD3A853FB58463"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To a victim advocate or healthcare provider, if required for the provision of victim services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5244075A069B4ED199F6A473D8D2463C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To a State or Federal court, if pursuant to a court order or if disclosure is required by Federal or State statute.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8BD3C044407F44BABF93D390B1CF37C1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice of disclosure; privacy protection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If information described in subsection (a) is disclosed under that subsection, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H6C866B9F5C2C447BBA815F406544F5C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make reasonable attempts to provide notice to the individual the information of whom is so disclosed; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90EFF33A9C6A42D7A88E53BE3C74672F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>take such action as is necessary to protect the privacy and safety of the individual.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H26F005E4F0BD495985B8633161951FB1" commented="no"><enum>3549.</enum><header>Restricted reporting update</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Sexual Harassment and Assault Prevention Improvements Act of 2025</short-title>, the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere, shall update the policies developed under sections 3541 and 3542 with respect to the mechanism established under subsections (b)(3)(B) and (b)(5)(B) of those sections, respectively, such that each such mechanism provides for a restricted reporting system that allows an employee of the Administration, member of the commissioned officer corps of the Administration, or covered personnel who alleges to have been sexually harassed or sexually assaulted to confidentially disclose the details of such sexual harassment or sexual assault to specified individuals and receive the services outlined in this subtitle—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE6896B23428246FA94FB4AB34D4C8902" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>without the dissemination of the personally identifying information of such individual, except as necessary for the provision of such services and as provided by section 3548(a); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD530058379E34E0E9207C9BF6E2B51F3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>without automatically triggering an investigative process.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H105F7ACF888D443C92680E40301ADB4C" commented="no"><enum>3550.</enum><header>Mariner reporting</header> 
<subsection id="H0EF937D238A441998CA15D9C535C9CE8" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mandatory reporting by responsible entity of a vessel</header> 
<paragraph id="H87981BC32C6F404CA58B13592E4EC2F9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unrestricted reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The responsible entity of a vessel shall report to the Commandant of the Coast Guard any incident of sexual harassment or sexual assault in violation of employer policy or law, of which the responsible entity of a vessel is made aware, involving—</text> <subparagraph id="H3D05ABF9E9754FDD98A338D2722EB1AC" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an employee or contractor of the Administration who is required to hold a valid merchant mariner credential as a condition of employment; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD98FD91F955B4EFBB48D9BC1CF0EA09F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a crewmember of a vessel that, at the time of such incident, was operating under a contract with the Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9012D2EE22BC4B229EAC0B8FC083CC2F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Restricted reports</header><text>Paragraph (1) does not apply with respect to an incident of sexual harassment or sexual assault reported on a restricted basis pursuant to the mechanisms established for such reporting under sections 3541(b)(3)(B) and 3542(b)(5)(B), respectively.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9376F6141FAA40F3B63CEF1F0410AA0C" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting procedures</header> 
<paragraph id="H12FBCAEDE3544138AAC0A475C45EA82D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header> 
<subparagraph id="HE84CD3004B7146D1967A8399B88BA4CB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Timing of reporting</header><text>The responsible entity of a vessel shall make a report required under subsection (a)(1) as soon as the responsible entity of a vessel is made aware of the incident of sexual harassment or sexual assault that is the subject of the report.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFC5A4FDB02524C6F80BCC8BA2AFC2AB9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Mode of reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The responsible entity of a vessel shall make a report required under subsection (a)(1) to a single entity in the Coast Guard designated by the Commandant of the Coast Guard to receive such reports by the fastest telecommunication channel available to the responsible entity of a vessel.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H494F08CB2FE8441D826702F661944594" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report made under this section shall include, to the best of the knowledge of the responsible entity of a vessel—</text> <subparagraph id="H7D8D109019854DC897B8F3DCF54183A1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the name, Coast Guard merchant mariner credential reference number, if applicable, official position or role in relation to the vessel, and contact information of each individual involved in the incident of sexual harassment or sexual assault that is the subject of the report;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5E2B5120DC31436AA8972590E963290C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the name and official number of the vessel;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7292D8BCB0B64363B01077C74BB6CEA3" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the time and date of the incident of sexual harassment or sexual assault;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7C977FA564C44C919ED63747C6325E7B" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the geographic position or location of the vessel when the incident of sexual harassment or sexual assault occurred; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HECEA82649AE948B4909EBDD7A93034D2" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a brief description of the incident of alleged sexual harassment or sexual assault being reported.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H98EEF6C7F2594BCAA1C96AD0E83D0C82" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification by Secretary</header> 
<paragraph id="H725A10F3488440C5AFD6E999C1693790"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere, shall notify the Director of the Office of Marine and Aviation Operations of each report of an incident of sexual harassment or sexual assault received by the Secretary.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H191EF806A0E6435EB1513C0F5BC4326E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification contents</header><text>Each notification under paragraph (1) shall include, to the best of the knowledge of the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0C0C769DB08A4F75A33D2201B5E5454D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to an unrestricted report submitted pursuant to section 3541(b)(3)(B) or 3542(b)(5)(B), the information required under subsection (b)(2) of this section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H54D80D6935334D78A767A3A68FD7DD41" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a restricted report submitted pursuant to section 3541(b)(3)(B) or 3542(b)(5)(B), the information required under subsection (b)(2) of this section that does not include the personally identifying information of the individual that submitted the restricted report.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="H2EF96043DB314EFCA39EDA57200A7C24"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3552, as redesignated by section 5(a) of this Act, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC6F78AF1E75F43DCAB1D3B0AC1C032B4" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="HE9A4ADA342C54DD69E5C89AF7C69F1CB"><enum>3552.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subtitle:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0AE0B42FA46940D69CCAEC6C80F5366E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Administration</term> means the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H826D7B13812447A3B31955AC976B4E1D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered personnel</header> <subparagraph id="HFDF52A4F905F40E1B379F9E98FA49BDA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>covered personnel</term> means an individual who works with or conducts business on behalf of the Administration.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC1433042C420469AB6A61DA4FF227365"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>The term <term>covered personnel</term> includes—</text> <clause id="HCDE0A458628441ECBBC6D76C6536970E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">observers, at-sea monitors, and catch monitors required by the National Marine Fisheries Service to operate on or in commercial fishing vessels, other privately owned vessels, barges, or platforms, and shoreside processing facilities for—</text> 
<subclause id="H053C0D013A014F20860D656B1EF7C8D6"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commercial fisheries observation required by the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/13/1801">13 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subclause> <subclause id="H00D8E6165283441DA10627D1F7179C1C"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">protected species or endangered species observation required by the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1361">16 U.S.C. 1361 et seq.</external-xref>) or the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1351">16 U.S.C. 1351 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HB6005C4CB5FA4EEC92FCCE1B69E0E748"><enum>(III)</enum><text>platform removal observation; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HC9A303953976471CAE8D5E4BE7FFD14B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">voting members and executive and administrative staff of each Regional Fishery Management Council established by section 302 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1852">16 U.S.C. 1852</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7E085102C5FA4EF4A5F1352745729A29" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Responsible entity of a vessel</header><text>The term <term>responsible entity of a vessel</term> means the Director of the Office of Marine and Aviation Operations, with respect to each vessel owned or operated by the Administration.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HD435A5496FDE44959B1EFCFC8413CD03"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sexual assault</header><text>The term <term>sexual assault</term> has the meaning given the term in section 40002(a) of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (42 U.S.C. 13925 (a)).</text></paragraph> </section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H72352F3E976B4DC88514D5CA109A1F9B"><enum>7.</enum><header>Conforming and clerical amendments</header> 
<subsection id="HF95DA182313B44DBACE5DEFE712D76EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle C of title XXXV (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/894">33 U.S.C. 894 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H69F60CF6F4C74E508E1930F3B8D5B505"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>individuals who work with or conduct business on behalf of the Administration</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>covered personnel</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8DBB73338F84491CAA7F825388AAFF44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>National Oceanic and Atmospheric</quote> each place it appears, except—</text> <subparagraph id="H869B5EE98CF1479C900589A560748513"><enum>(A)</enum><text>when it appears as <quote><short-title>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Sexual Harassment and Assault Prevention Improvements Act of 2025</short-title></quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H52E69A0233EE4831ADC932DF9AB5AE71"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 3551, in the section heading; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H23B2D8978D804F6FAA502A6ED79441F0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in section 3552(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HBD78F6C3CBDE444B8940C8D7ECD2FE82"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each of the tables of contents in section 2(b) and at the beginning of title XXXV are amended by striking the items relating to sections 3548 and 3549 and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H46802DE8DE4143AFA3B918197CF43C35" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 3548. Exceptions regarding anonymity of victims in certain cases.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 3549. Restricted reporting update.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 3550. Mariner referral.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 3551. Annual report on sexual harassment, sexual assault, and equal employment in the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 3552. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H8D7A043F26BC48888E3E140EFE1E33B3"><enum>8.</enum><header>Prohibited acts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 307(1)(L) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1857">16 U.S.C. 1857(1)(L)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAA3D54F5A9794BB187421E717E169910"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>forcibly</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDED69E2CC6124DADA2F4C20F3F594FA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>on a vessel</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HC9F671FDFB964BF4AFD65BF986900C69"><enum>9.</enum><header>Prohibition on service in Commissioned Officer Corps of National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration by individuals convicted of certain sexual offenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 261(a) of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Commissioned Officer Corps Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3071">33 U.S.C. 3071(a)</external-xref>) is amended— </text> <paragraph id="H92481CE0196143D6935480ECB34838F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (26) as paragraph (27); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7961999A910A408AAE2E51DE7198F9FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (25) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H238D3C66A0624E6A962C819FA2EDC611" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H72EDDC2B7F2E4C128FD4A12766497088"><enum>(26)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 657, relating to prohibition on service by individuals convicted of certain sexual offenses.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

