<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H27372E31DA1A4ACBA8310DCB1B52DDB2" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 587 IH: Encouraging all public, private, and charter high schools, colleges, and universities in the United States to establish and support flag football programs for girls, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 587</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250716">July 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Encouraging all public, private, and charter high schools, colleges, and universities in the United States to establish and support flag football programs for girls, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas flag football for girls is one of the fastest growing sports in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas flag football can help girls develop critical life skills such as character, teamwork, resiliency, leadership, and confidence while also providing beneficial physical activity; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas flag football is a low-contact sport, with no height or weight restrictions, that is open to girls of all skill levels, and is affordable, accessible, and all-inclusive;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas over 100 colleges have established varsity flag football programs for women and girls; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the expansion of high school and collegiate flag football programs for girls would be beneficial not only to the girls and women joining such programs, but also for towns, cities, counties, States and communities throughout the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HD73A28121E984CD797757749C5254DAA"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HB53209E78B004935B371FD03D9BD195A"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives encourages all public, private, and charter high schools, colleges, and universities to establish and support flag football programs for girls and women to expand upon existing endeavors and opportunities. </text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

