<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25065-9C6-W6-FKS"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S185 IS: Justice for Victims of Sanctuary Cities Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 185</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250122">January 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide a civil remedy for individuals harmed by sanctuary jurisdiction policies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Justice for Victims of Sanctuary Cities Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id9380a19328c449ab801b6d22b26cb3e4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="ided7a61edfea54fef8e75345d98eb78be"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Alien</header><text>The term <term>alien</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(3)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id099302c2b515436c9cd8faecc1472e33"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sanctuary jurisdiction</header><subparagraph id="id8b5db3f6c06242a7a3a3c9ae315c75e8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>sanctuary jurisdiction</term> means any State or political subdivision of a State that has in effect a statute, ordinance, policy, or practice that prohibits or restricts any government entity or official from—</text><clause id="id4ed9538ba12f440e808b281664360342"><enum>(i)</enum><text>sending, receiving, maintaining, or exchanging with any Federal, State, or local government entity information regarding the citizenship or immigration status of any alien; or</text></clause><clause id="id9b81b4ab71934dd1ab24100b8c4da405"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>complying with a request lawfully made by the Department of Homeland Security under section 236 or 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1226 and 1357) to comply with a detainer for, or notify about the release of, an alien.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1bbeb9a05a924c39af912790b86b8f94"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>A State or political subdivision of a State shall not be deemed a sanctuary jurisdiction based solely on having a policy whereby its officials will not share information regarding, or comply with a request made by the Department of Homeland Security under section 236 or 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1226 and 1357) to comply with a detainer regarding, an alien who comes forward as a victim or a witness to a criminal offense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idebbe4f046dee443992c71fb740ba0070"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sanctuary policy</header><text>The term <term>sanctuary policy</term> means a statute, ordinance, policy, or practice referred to in paragraph (2)(A).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id510b5cbe38d6405cb065f19daa4fb593"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sanctuary-related civil action</header><text>The term <term>sanctuary-related civil action</term> means a civil action brought against a sanctuary jurisdiction by an individual (or the estate, survivors, or heirs of such individual) who—</text><subparagraph id="id40e7d6021ee94edd86e4093e3e11c668"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is injured or harmed by an alien who benefitted from a sanctuary policy of such sanctuary jurisdiction; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id10b379eca94a41e081ed838fda9fa7ff"><enum>(B)</enum><text>would not have been so injured or harmed if such alien had not been so benefitted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="idbd6a479b18db4b3288a918d67ed9864d"><enum>3.</enum><header>Civil action for harm by an alien that benefitted from a sanctuary policy</header><subsection id="id898ac6ef34e6481ea1342c39db281911"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><paragraph id="id0554d7b9e1ce4a5e9a485483b540c23c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cause of action</header><text>Any individual, or a spouse, parent, or child of such individual (if the individual is deceased or permanently incapacitated), who is the victim of a murder, rape, or any felony (as defined by the State in which the crime occurred) for which an alien has been arrested, convicted, or sentenced to a term of imprisonment of at least 1 year, may bring an action for compensatory damages against a State or a political subdivision of a State, in the appropriate Federal or State court, if such State or political subdivision failed—</text><subparagraph id="id841C9520EADD4E8F9F6492F3557B3988"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to comply with a request with respect to an alien that was lawfully made by the Department of Homeland Security pursuant to section 236 or 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1226 and 1357); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1070B935895145D9B2784F33623044FA"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id1c05ac6e15ba4f8bae4b1dd906fe11c4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to comply with a detainer for such alien; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6abd3001fc684262807e7dc20bd35369" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to notify the Department about the release of such alien.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6ae45c01459f4e758b2e0bfe2e7182b0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Statute of limitations</header><text>An action described in paragraph (1) may not be brought later than 10 years after the later of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e09ff285ff74b0d91e26a392cf06f4e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the occurrence of the crime referred to in paragraph (1); or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d32d4d6270c4b64933360c338d18531"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the death of a person that resulted from such crime.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id370711b50bd44157a188b414c0a3ecc0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Attorney’s fee and other costs</header><text>In any action or proceeding under paragraph (1), the court shall allow a prevailing plaintiff to recover a reasonable attorney’s fee as part of the costs of the litigation, which shall include any applicable expert fees.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb2160a4b5d51474da5afd7786cca2540"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver of immunity</header><paragraph id="id43c05b893cf24c3f83c65e3fcb09c5c3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any State or political subdivision of a State that accepts a grant described in paragraph (2) from the Federal Government shall agree, as a condition of receiving such grant, to waive any immunity of such State or political subdivision relating to a sanctuary-related civil action.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id098515d2bd304e6fa0a9424e6f5d49f1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grants described</header><text>The grants described in this paragraph are—</text><subparagraph id="id1e51739dc3a14313b4d038330097683b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a grant for public works and economic development under section 201(a) of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3141">42 U.S.C. 3141(a)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5946115043164d8eb87ef155b8427e6a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a grant for planning and administrative expenses under section 203(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3143">42 U.S.C. 3143(a)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id28190daa1356497e9f7b9dd0f282cc6a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a supplemental grant under section 205(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3145">42 U.S.C. 3145(b)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id34f5119e3cac4463a9de507b66b6dad5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a grant for training, research, and technical assistance under section 207(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3147">42 U.S.C. 3147(a)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id25a298032d1c430d95f379786cf79d73"><enum>(E)</enum><text>except as provided in paragraph (3), a community development block grant made pursuant to title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5301">42 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7FF88DBB8DBE4A45B2D9481B1DC874FA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Grants described in paragraph (2)(E) shall not include any disaster relief grants to address the damage in an area for which the President has declared a disaster under title IV of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id9bc57b7ebf3e4b1e89f709f038b9bcdb"><enum>4.</enum><header>Ensuring cooperation between Federal and local law enforcement officers to safeguard our communities</header><subsection id="idb99fb060db194045b376e4f02618a907"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To cooperate with Federal officials</header><text>A State, a political subdivision of a State, or an officer, employee, or agent of such State or political subdivision that complies with a detainer issued by the Department of Homeland Security pursuant to section 236 or 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1226 and 1357)—</text><paragraph id="id895874612c904266a21fc6a2740923d5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be deemed to be acting as an agent of the Department of Homeland Security; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9015b9522f22490c85a938da81b80779"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall comply with section 287(d) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1357">8 U.S.C. 1357(d)</external-xref>) and section 287.5(d) of title 8, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5e4ae9adc5f14f9ab3663da38d6c7c8d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Legal proceedings</header><text>In any legal proceeding brought against a State, a political subdivision of State, or an officer, employee, or agent of such State or political subdivision challenging the legality of the seizure or detention of an individual pursuant to a detainer issued by the Department of Homeland Security under section 236 or 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1226 and 1357)—</text><paragraph id="ide32652b63ff6452c9b1d3fa8e4ccc841"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the State or political subdivision of a State shall not be liable for any action taken in accordance with the detainer; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7e2d317010624921bb72a5f0bcf0e718"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the actions of the officer, employee, or agent of the State or political subdivision were taken in accordance with the detainer—</text><subparagraph id="idc3ffda31f76f4317bf0ac01739161c9b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the officer, employee, or agent shall be deemed—</text><clause id="id92711b7cd2c947a3a1acb8a6e8a7b417"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to be an employee of the Federal Government and an investigative or law enforcement officer; and</text></clause><clause id="id4547ffb2a0a14bfd9a65ff8bd9820fa0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to have been acting within the scope of his or her employment under section 1346(b) of title 28, United States Code, and chapter 171 of such title;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0db8fc8d6558405e81ca56107dfb17c7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 1346(b) of title 28, United States Code, shall provide the exclusive remedy for the plaintiff; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3df35c81ae83434590634dc708700e2d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the United States shall be substituted as the defendant in such proceeding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida2b6c586d3f14b2bb8cdc7ea68af047c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to provide immunity to any person who knowingly violates the civil or constitutional rights of an individual.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

