<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP25054-RLW-RD-V2C"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S232 IS: Preventing Algorithmic Collusion Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 232</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250123">January 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prevent anticompetitive conduct through the use of pricing algorithms by prohibiting the use of pricing algorithms that can facilitate collusion through the use of nonpublic competitor data, creating an antitrust law enforcement audit tool, increasing transparency, and enforcing violations through the Sherman Act and Federal Trade Commission Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Algorithmic Collusion Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id12bc409497aa4efeb32d658088771b11"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idae72d4a65bf544348db86feb26d683d8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Antitrust laws</header><text>The term <term>antitrust laws</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3d0e3fbc3d40430db64a35c7b8f1ef9c"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the meaning given that term in subsection (a) of the first section of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12</external-xref>); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfb846971b90d466981ca64b9ee7e0c6d"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id16ca3401869d4ec5aaae681ab00e936a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commercial terms</header><text>The term <term>commercial terms</term> means— </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id104331bb60b44087ba234bd88ef8d97c"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">level of service; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide519816cd7684926baba0bda0f289683"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">availability; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id50028f5090724a44ad6d244c37f398b2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>output, including quantities of products produced or distributed or the amount or level of service provided; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id00c3aa59d5a343349e06be1901c4c62c"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rebates or discounts made available.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id90cf0bfd0616481eb265b60f4ef90640"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4febf7525a484feb88538f74a83bcf01"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Distribute; distribution; distributing</header><text>The terms <term>distribute</term>, <term>distribution</term>, and <term>distributing</term> include selling, licensing, providing access to, or otherwise making available by any means, including through a subscription or the sale of a service. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id694A4ECCDE3B4C4DB18F245702AA23F3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Nonpublic competitor data</header><text>The term <term>nonpublic competitor data</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1a6e69a48ca54526ba76416c6d83feaf"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means nonpublic data that is derived from or otherwise provided by another person that competes in the same market as a person, or a related market; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55092c8a802842328c2c7d10c7e53109"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include information distributed, reported, or otherwise communicated in a way that does not reveal any underlying data from a competitor, such as narrative industry reports, news reports, business commentaries, or generalized industry survey results. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf41ea335e73549fe8dd000d0ded6ba2d"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Nonpublic data</header><text>The term <term>nonpublic data</term> means information that is not widely available or easily accessible to the public, including information about price, commercial terms, and related products or services, regardless of whether the data is attributable to a specific competitor or anonymized.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcac929c386cf4682aa01558521ab8beb"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> has the meaning given that term in subsection (a) of the first section of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5dd91ec28d30496a9472ab40775f0b63"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Price</header><text>The term <term>price</term> means the amount of money or other thing of value, whether tangible or not, expected, required, or given in payment for any product or service, including compensation paid to an employee or independent contractor for services provided.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id52f8862c446c44929bc3836571f548ad"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Pricing algorithm</header><text>The term <term>pricing algorithm</term> means any computational process, including a computational process derived from machine learning or other artificial intelligence techniques, that processes data to recommend or set a price or commercial term that is in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idcc6dea5a2bce49719578da4e60385424"><enum>3.</enum><header>Competition law enforcement audit</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5591e3724f75405f839b663f4f58c381"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person using or distributing a pricing algorithm, upon a written request by the Attorney General or the Commission, shall, not later than 30 days after the date of the written request, or any later date approved by the Attorney General or the Commission, respectively, provide to the Attorney General or the Commission, respectively, a written report on each pricing algorithm identified in the request.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida0517409807340bba1cd055cd089f6f3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34c179bfda8d4a42a5a677d663120223"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on whether the person is responsible for the development or distribution of the pricing algorithm, or whether a third party is responsible for the development or distribution of the pricing algorithm, including the identity and contact information of any other person responsible for the development or distribution of the pricing algorithm;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3d317b6d0b8c442c9522bd997c8b5a67"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information on whether the pricing algorithm autonomously sets prices or commercial terms and whether there is human review of any recommendation or decision of the pricing algorithm;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5abcbdc0cb7d4e6fb017b1962baafd5e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an explanation of the rules or processes that the pricing algorithm uses to set or recommend prices or commercial terms;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb3fd708af6dc4dc18397b813452a8f0f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of all data the pricing algorithm uses to set or recommend prices or commercial terms, including data used to train the algorithm;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddab54298df394b988fc7cec5b08b6f37"><enum>(5)</enum><text>all sources and collection processes, including the frequency of collection, of any data that the pricing algorithm uses to set or recommend prices or commercial terms;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id89e32b3b1cca4a1b8d2fbff4088d4062"><enum>(6)</enum><text>whether the pricing algorithm engages in price discrimination by setting or recommending different prices or commercial terms for—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c221e77ed934c29b986a581693e33a1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">different customers seeking identical or nearly identical products or services, and if so, the factors used in differentiating among such customers; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd93081da31e242a6a7ac6a1891f8321c"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">different employees or independent contractors providing substantially similar services, and if so, the factors used in differentiating among such employees or independent contractors; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc6d1efd8eac24c1ab8af3215d70a156c"><enum>(7)</enum><text>any changes made to the pricing algorithm between the date of receipt of the request under subsection (a) and the date of certification under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id86b1f915f06d46a4a0114597e95ec613"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certification of report</header><text>The Chief Executive Officer, Chief Economist, Chief Technology Officer, or a corporate officer of similar authority of a person shall certify, under penalty of perjury, the accuracy of a report under subsection (a) submitted by the person.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3e82e1fc89464f7686664ff204fe3936"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text>All information submitted in a report under subsection (a) shall be treated as confidential and shall be considered to be privileged and confidential trade secrets and commercial or financial information exempt under subsection (b)(4) of section 552 of title 5, United States Code, from being made available to the public under subsection (a) of that section.</text></subsection><subsection id="id03aaf3c1f25844bcabc03f7943422a7b"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Information sharing</header><paragraph id="iddf0ec2ff8548452bb63593567a0e09d6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A report under subsection (a) may be shared—</text><subparagraph id="idd936162e1e7f45ef9dc09f10293854da"><enum>(A)</enum><text>between the Department of Justice and the Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida3ddb6b6605e46e4b4c4b2a59d2dd1ea"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with the National Institute of Standards and Technology for technical assistance in understanding the report.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb94e22e2b2124d018aadfddc1ead8489"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The National Institute of Standards and Technology shall not disclose the contents of a report shared under paragraph (1) or the analysis of the report by the National Institute of Standards and Technology to any person, except the Department of Justice or Commission, whichever sought the technical assistance. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9dc3ec7e8d2342b6a4788cd68478b834"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb73f2791f3204c3e8ad77215297f90fa"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">limit the ability of the Commission or the Attorney General to issue a civil investigative demand, to issue a subpoena, to seek discovery in the course of litigation, or otherwise obtain information through other means available to the Commission or the Attorney General; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbf16e3cfa1d04e4ca8e5f7c81ab54a02"><enum>(2)</enum><text>restrict the use of information submitted in a report under subsection (a) in the course of a formal investigation, enforcement action, litigation, trial, or other proceeding, in accordance with the confidentiality procedures applicable to such proceeding.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id38f661113a2b41cb8c597e717ba94cf2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Preventing collusive activity in pricing algorithms</header><subsection id="id6c4ca6d49d5c43a18bbccafe874e4a9c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a person to use or distribute any pricing algorithm that uses, incorporates, or was trained with nonpublic competitor data.</text></subsection><subsection id="id1ee43f151b61462897be7e4224baa571"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil action</header><text>If the Commission or the Attorney General has reason to believe that a person has violated subsection (a), the Commission, in its own name by any of its attorneys designated by it for such purpose, or the Attorney General may bring a civil action against the person in an appropriate district court of the United States to seek to recover—</text><paragraph id="id21e58cff1ead4b459faf5b22d036d4d2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a civil penalty of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18260cad8c7c4822a6c651e58f8bf3c0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than $10,000, adjusted for inflation on the basis of the Consumer Price Index, for each day during which the violation occurs or continues to occur; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id73fedf5a32b74c1cb5e0a81fa0776ecb"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the sum of the price of each product or service sold using the pricing algorithm in violation of subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9e77289b12ae4b6d8a99d6d6a0ccb214"><enum>(2)</enum><text>other appropriate relief, including an injunction or other equitable relief.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id40ee04c56c76431f82449481cd8e2a58"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text>Subsection (a) shall take effect on the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="id1e0458bdfd6249debd96f4364af982d8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Algorithmic price fixing</header><subsection id="id53b715e9474b491c8aa15076fc3e8665"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Presumption of agreement</header><text>With respect to the use of a pricing algorithm that would violate section 4 of this Act, there shall be a presumption for purposes of section 1 of the Sherman Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1">15 U.S.C. 1</external-xref>) that the defendant entered into an agreement, contract, combination, or conspiracy in restraint of trade and for purposes of section 5(a) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45(a)</external-xref>) that the defendant has engaged in an unfair method of competition if the plaintiff establishes that—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8e5c7b7adf0041239181b8b608c6891a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the defendant distributed the pricing algorithm to 2 or more persons—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f4afcbb5cd340de8dff46e76aa0992f"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with the intent that the pricing algorithm be used to set or recommend a price or commercial term of a product or service in the same market or a related market; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id041075bf8a8d47b88e452a59d5e54b9d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>and 2 or more persons used the pricing algorithm to set or recommend a price or commercial term of a product or service in the same market or a related market; or </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3fa1375ec34f46699e9daf5e09563b06"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id4b95c0685a044159a421a8f45b16f287"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the defendant used the pricing algorithm to set or recommend a price or commercial term of a product or service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide634dac0ec5647928243d48556671f51" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the pricing algorithm was used by another person to set or recommend a price or commercial term of a product or service in the same market or a related market.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id41123851c40d4161ba7c34acb98a3d84"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rebuttal</header><text>The presumption under subsection (a) shall not apply to a defendant if the defendant did not develop or distribute the pricing algorithm and the defendant demonstrates by clear and convincing evidence that the defendant did not have actual knowledge or could not have reasonably known that the pricing algorithm used nonpublic competitor data.</text></subsection><subsection id="idd759ad6236354847b8b7aab449664236"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Joint and several liability</header><text>In a civil case in which the presumption under subsection (a) is applicable, any persons that distributed the pricing algorithm and knew, or could reasonably have known, that the pricing algorithm would use, incorporate, or be trained with nonpublic competitor data shall be jointly and severally liable for any violation of section 1 of the Sherman Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1">15 U.S.C. 1</external-xref>) or section 5(a) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45(a)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id0b4618ef1f6d41139220b20c2636619e"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Relation to antitrust laws</header><text>Nothing in this section shall impair or limit the applicability of the antitrust laws.</text></subsection><subsection id="id83e11ad85e984167881b6968ab87425a"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Subsection (a) shall take effect on the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="id1207f2b0dacc4b0a95bac502dd00d86d"><enum>6.</enum><header>Transparency in pricing algorithms</header><subsection id="idf84b4407b1244049a02a566fd828ca05"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any person that has $5,000,000 or more in annual revenue that uses a pricing algorithm to recommend or set a price or commercial term shall clearly disclose, as applicable—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide9f904fe5e774cca8c31d295ef420fd3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to a customer, before the customer purchases the relevant product or service, that the price or a commercial term, as applicable, is set or recommended by a pricing algorithm; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4780ca152ec14009a16e13f6c33614b8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to a current or prospective employee or independent contractor that the price or a commercial term for services rendered as an employee or independent contractor is set or recommended by a pricing algorithm.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbf472ef8d7a8426c8f235a0f4ccd5e85"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional disclosures</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7bf843dbea334309a3d79312a005246f"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Price discrimination</header><text>If applicable, a disclosure under subsection (a) shall state that the pricing algorithm sets or recommends different prices or commercial terms for—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id27ea001326d7436fb855793d5f413c14"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">different customers seeking identical or nearly identical products or services; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide53890439698490bbd18da8272b7b888"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employees or independent contractors providing substantially similar services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb02e4054d5e34c9f94397bc75ee92b18"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Third-party algorithm</header><text>If applicable, a disclosure under subsection (a) shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id68127e3557b54260a9120bd1d01d9881"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">state that the pricing algorithm was developed or distributed by a person other than the person making the disclosure; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce9bf2693e0246b58106f4c2bc14d9d3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide the identity of the person that developed or distributed the pricing algorithm.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idcd5291fd9b6941d897bd1b7ef4063d85"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>Failure to provide a disclosure under subsection (a), including the information required under subsection (b), shall constitute an unfair or deceptive act or practice under section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id56c4948a9b3e4f59a871587da966c3b8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Civil action</header><text>If the Commission has reason to believe that a person has violated subsection (a) or (b), the Commission, in its own name by any of its attorneys designated by it for such purpose, may bring a civil action in an appropriate district court of the United States to recover—</text><paragraph id="id0472f7cf15a34c749776102baacbe32d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a civil penalty of not less than $5,000, adjusted for inflation on the basis of the Consumer Price Index, for each day during which the violation occurs or continues to occur; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id124a840aceb34b928723d07fa4afde28"><enum>(2)</enum><text>other appropriate relief, including an injunction or other equitable relief.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb71b490731e4479787c17e182b640a1f"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Relation to antitrust laws</header><text>Nothing in this section shall impair or limit the applicability of the antitrust laws.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idf9c208f784364c469c545a45d3e3faa0"><enum>7.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">FTC study</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall publish the results of a study of the use of pricing algorithms, including information on—</text><paragraph id="id60351e601fb34525bdb1d6795ed7e60b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the prevalence of pricing algorithms;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida63ac3a5b4704b69bdf88032f429593e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the frequency of the use of pricing algorithms to engage in price or wage discrimination;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id79cd6f3173ea44fab2c9cfddc5d46c3c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the potential for persons to use pricing algorithms to engage in behavior that increases prices, lowers wages, reduces output, lowers quality, deters innovation, or otherwise harms the competitive process outside of the price fixing context;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf931a6ef0c0f462d8b37302ce970ff1e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the potential benefits or efficiencies of pricing algorithms;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3296446399934d9dac2a24797f166bf2"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any industries, sectors, or markets in which pricing algorithms may warrant additional oversight or regulation to protect competition and consumers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbe34122b5d9d476ea5a12f44cba5a914"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for additional legislation, regulation, or rulemaking relating to competition and consumer protection issues arising from the use of pricing algorithms.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

