<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HLA25134-9CK-PY-NT3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S776 IS: Undertaking Negotiations on Investment and Trade for Economic Dynamism Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 776</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide the President with authority to enter into a comprehensive trade agreement with the United Kingdom, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Undertaking Negotiations on Investment and Trade for Economic Dynamism Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>UNITED Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="idfc089efcf3cd43ab8aeabac331f67031"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="id4268b543abbb467aa79e0548baa443aa"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States should pursue more open trade and investment relationships with its allies to strengthen the economy of the United States, improve the standard of living of the people of the United States, and advance the strategic interests of the United States; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc656d028bb384051a07f993fa185640c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>agreements to reduce or eliminate barriers to trade and investment between the United States and its allies will foster mutually beneficial economic relationships that advance the economic interests of workers, farmers, ranchers, and businesses of all sizes in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf4f58099f1ee4b4ba893c6f8b62eae22"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the shared values and long history of the <quote>special relationship</quote> between the United States and the United Kingdom present a unique opportunity to deepen the mutually beneficial economic and strategic relationship between those countries and further expand prosperity for the citizens of those countries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3eb6c7b5750c408ab45069406dc2db9f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a high-standard, comprehensive trade agreement between the United States and the United Kingdom would help strengthen that relationship, improve the economic prospects of people in both countries, increase the resilience of critical supply chains, and create export opportunities for businesses of all sizes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id79cd8f3209f74238805866dee5357c3b"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the efforts of the United States-United Kingdom Trade and Investment Working Group and the bilateral negotiations initiated by President Donald J. Trump have laid groundwork toward a comprehensive trade agreement;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc3397a71cf184b7d8736017b61795572"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the United States-United Kingdom Dialogue on the Future of Atlantic Trade, initiated by President Joseph R. Biden, along with the signing of the document entitled <quote>Atlantic Declaration: A Framework for a Twenty-First Century U.S.-U.K. Economic Partnership</quote>, continued efforts to improve economic cooperation between the United States and United Kingdom; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8294982c1ce54e7ba3366151cea4af46"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the robust labor and environmental protections in the United Kingdom reduce the risk of regulatory arbitrage that undercuts workers and businesses in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbfc059d23d8a4f03aa3471a220e7adb0"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Congress passed the USMCA with overwhelming bipartisan support, setting high standards in North America with respect to labor rights, the environment, intellectual property, non-market practices, and services, and those standards should inform future negotiations; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id27f73287e6334b8baf66b7c42b8cf96a"><enum>(9)</enum><text>trade agreements with foreign trading partners that share the values and ambition of the United States offer an opportunity to build on the USMCA and set high international standards across many important policy areas;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8d148f3cc22a4e47aac86bbcba178ef7"><enum>(10)</enum><text>any trade negotiations between the United States and the United Kingdom must honor the agreement between the Government of Ireland and the Government of the United Kingdom signed on April 10, 1998 (commonly known as the <quote>Good Friday Agreement</quote>), and any trade agreement between those countries must advance peace, stability, and prosperity in Ireland and Northern Ireland;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9a7a663ac2b3450db1019003d46f8588"><enum>(11)</enum><text>the United Kingdom, like many key trading partners of the United States, is actively negotiating for expanded access to foreign markets, and the United States must likewise seek to advance its access to foreign markets to ensure that businesses, consumers, farmers, ranchers, and workers in the United States are not left behind; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbcfc3781de8a49a98667d6be8bbc5250"><enum>(12)</enum><text>to effectively pursue comprehensive trade negotiations with the United Kingdom for purposes of a trade agreement between the United States and the United Kingdom, Congress must grant new negotiating authority to the President, which should—</text><subparagraph id="idb669688e7fc1478aab9e5b25e442640c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enable the swift negotiation and passage through Congress of such an agreement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc6e4d573420d44e4b0700b3ad7c42719"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be narrowly tailored to provide clear direction to the executive branch of the United States Government. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id0b371c57dada4fa7b3368836c1fd0a53"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id03a7521e91a84d2f83f9c5c2a0934142"><enum>(1)</enum><header>USMCA</header><text>The term <term>USMCA</term> means the Agreement between the United States of America, the United Mexican States, and Canada, which is—</text><subparagraph id="id08a602e213a342da9cf01252a7f23242"><enum>(A)</enum><text>attached as an Annex to the Protocol Replacing the North American Free Trade Agreement with the Agreement between the United States of America, the United Mexican States, and Canada, done at Buenos Aires on November 30, 2018, as amended by the Protocol of Amendment to the Agreement Between the United States of America, the United Mexican States, and Canada, done at Mexico City on December 10, 2019; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4923f96fb58640588df8c53d4eebd28c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>approved by Congress under section 101(a)(1) of the United States–Mexico–Canada Agreement Implementation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4511">19 U.S.C. 4511(a)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8bb8c86fba8a4b069e6e4e0f0cc619da"><enum>(2)</enum><header>United Kingdom</header><text>The term <term>United Kingdom</term> means the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idf5b58a5d88754f9f9fad80cd59ea8935"><enum>4.</enum><header>Negotiating and trade agreements authority for comprehensive agreement with the United Kingdom</header><subsection id="id91fad48ea1c74c09be974b7597ccf51e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initiation of negotiations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, in order to enhance the economic well-being of the United States, the President shall seek to initiate negotiations with the United Kingdom regarding tariff and nontariff barriers affecting any industry, product, or service sector.</text></subsection><subsection id="id251e8c94dc254d33b38a8bccf2d5463f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority for comprehensive trade agreement with the United Kingdom</header><paragraph id="idbabd98593509419e8b0a1c3f305fec28"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To strengthen the economic competitiveness of the United States, the President may enter into a comprehensive trade agreement with the United Kingdom regarding tariff and nontariff barriers affecting trade between the United States and United Kingdom.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id009adeb4a3184fd09fd865ac8a3362cc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination of authority</header><text>The authority under paragraph (1) terminates on March 1, 2029.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2aec2e4e271a4caeb6886d6489d2cf2f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Modifications permitted</header><paragraph id="id04ae5be4fa4d4fe6a19c7e61df005579"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the President may proclaim such modification or continuance of any existing duty, continuance of existing duty-free or excise treatment, or such additional duties as the President determines to be required or appropriate to carry out an agreement entered into under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4dba0e46bac74d7b87d4854b5d046908"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations</header><subparagraph id="idE8468F2A1B32479299D051B741260A07"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Modifications or additions to agreement</header><text>Substantial modifications to, or substantial additional provisions of, an agreement entered into after March 1, 2029, are not covered by the authority under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idea6b83065ae342a19ad25b91e60ebd76"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount of duty modification</header><text>No proclamation may be made under paragraph (1) that—</text><clause id="id83ae789421ed4e9295e242638bbe72b7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reduces any rate of duty (other than a rate of duty that does not exceed 5 percent ad valorem on the date of the enactment of this Act) to a rate of duty that is less than 50 percent of the rate of such duty that applies on such date of enactment;</text></clause><clause id="iddb91191f07f94069b0daea07c6047106"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reduces the rate of duty below that applicable under the Uruguay Round Agreements (as defined in section 2(7) of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/3501">19 U.S.C. 3501</external-xref>)) or a successor agreement, on any import sensitive agricultural product; or </text></clause><clause id="idccd5a133d50147228baa41f244a6b290"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>increases any rate of duty above the rate that applied on the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id481f31a8c4134ad1a189fc08d150ef00"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation with and notification to Congress</header><text>To ensure the alignment of the trade policy priorities of Congress with the content of any agreement under this section, the President shall consult with Congress before and throughout negotiations initiated under subsection (a) and shall notify Congress of the intention of the President to enter into an agreement under subsection (b) or to make a proclamation under subsection (c). </text></subsection><subsection id="id52e260b0992c458a8f352ed30e8aa6ed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Bills qualifying for trade authorities procedures</header><paragraph id="id3da16391627b48f897860c65732971bf"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementing bills</header><subparagraph id="id7bd0c54ebec843908b6be91bc59060f0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The provisions of section 151 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2191">19 U.S.C. 2191</external-xref>) apply to a bill of either House of Congress that contains provisions described in subparagraph (B) to the same extent as such section 151 applies to implementing bills under that section. A bill to which this paragraph applies shall hereafter in this section be referred to as an <quote>implementing bill</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id405e61fd534243bfb2ecd8d2b2a1058a"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Provisions specified</header><text>The provisions described in this subparagraph are—</text><clause id="id8e328690268f435a81cd3117e747a63b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a provision approving a trade agreement entered into under this section and approving the statement of administrative action, if any, proposed to implement such trade agreement; and</text></clause><clause id="id4f2d54e5a59f46b89b555c163d9c4777"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if changes in existing laws or new statutory authority are required to implement such trade agreement, only such provisions as are strictly necessary or appropriate to implement such trade agreement, either repealing or amending existing laws or providing new statutory authority.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idac708cfc62c1439d964977b38245e97b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline for submission of bill</header><text>The procedures under paragraph (1) apply to implementing bills submitted with respect to a trade agreement entered into under this section before March 1, 2029.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc79f9a2037bf43fd9c31ffc9edda6642"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitation on waiver, suspension, or termination</header><text>An agreement entered into under this section shall not be waived, suspended, or terminated, in whole or in part, with respect to the United States without the express approval by Congress of such termination. </text></subsection><subsection id="id06c4ac97387b428ab8c4550c701002ea"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Relationship to Bipartisan Congressional Trade Priorities and Accountability Act of 2015</header><text>An agreement under this section shall not enter into force with respect to the United States and an implementing bill shall not qualify for trade authorities procedures under subsection (e), including an agreement that does not require changes to United States law or an implementing bill in connection therewith, unless the following requirements under the Bipartisan Congressional Trade Priorities and Accountability Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4201">19 U.S.C. 4201 et seq.</external-xref>) are carried out with respect to that agreement or implementing bill to the same extent as would be required of an agreement entered into under section 103(b) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4202">19 U.S.C. 4202(b)</external-xref>), notwithstanding the expiration of authority to enter into an agreement under such section 103(b):</text><paragraph id="idee79d8f169e74b27b29cdd82ff9689ba"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The trade negotiating objectives under section 102 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4201">19 U.S.C. 4201</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id28723c6a559f43379b94dde08771e10a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The congressional oversight and consultation requirements under section 104 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4203">19 U.S.C. 4203</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id08c4715cc467492986715b92c903a95b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The notification, consultation, and reporting requirements under section 105 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4204">19 U.S.C. 4204</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id95897159c52844d083408778086f101b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The implementation procedures under section 106 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4205">19 U.S.C. 4205</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcfc293b62dec4ee2b48851993091f1e0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The provisions related to sovereignty under section 108 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4207">19 U.S.C. 4207</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

