<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H6F777392A3B74CCA9EE9980CFEA23FBE" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 5 EH: Adopting the Rules of the House of Representatives for the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="no">119th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="no">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. RES. 5</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20250103">January 3, 2025</action-date>
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Adopting the Rules of the House of Representatives for the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body style="OLC" id="H33763836938744DBBEF1D6194FB1B4B8"> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="H34351662C68542B8A63F14781F0D77E6"><enum>1.</enum><header>Adoption of the rules of the One Hundred Eighteenth Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Rules of the House of Representatives of the One Hundred Eighteenth Congress, including applicable provisions of law or concurrent resolution that constituted rules of the House at the end of the One Hundred Eighteenth Congress, are adopted as the Rules of the House of Representatives of the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress, with amendments to the standing rules as provided in section 2, and with other orders as provided in this resolution.</text></section> <section id="H2355A9D2713C432988E97D9552E25EBB" section-type="subsequent-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>2.</enum><header>Changes to the standing rules</header> <subsection id="H5638DA2849D44B34891D0B0AA54528FF" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Resolution Declaring the Office of Speaker Vacant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In clause 2(a) of rule IX, add the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="traditional" id="H22E65C3EC0EC481D993ED7626A898AF4" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HA504F972144A4ADA9E3001DB0EE7B146" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A resolution causing a vacancy in the Office of Speaker shall not be privileged except if it is offered by a member of the majority party and has accumulated eight cosponsors from the majority party at the time it is offered.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H7DE6A77B26454F68AB0FC06C77364444"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Permitting electronic voting in committee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In rule XI—</text> 
<paragraph id="H49DD6465898D4E5180EBEEAC12E49CFE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause 1(d)(2)(E), strike <quote>clauses 2(n), (o), or (p)</quote> and insert <quote>clauses 2(o), (p), or (q)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA49DDDC839B74EB3B58534B320FB461D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause 2, insert after paragraph (m) the following new paragraph (and redesignate the succeeding paragraphs accordingly):</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H42614CBC8A3E449C99A1D88F9C309AEE" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<rules-paragraph id="H3BE54ABE4CF34207B2FBE6EA173F8D8D" indent="up1"><enum>(n)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A committee may adopt a rule or motion permitting the use of electronic voting in accordance with regulations submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the chair of the Committee on Rules and the chair of the Committee on House Administration.</text></rules-paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H064AC232F9224651B7F000FD5CD92892"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clarification of role of Chief Administrative Officer in vacant offices</header><text>In clause 4 of rule II, add at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9AD7B81EB8AA422DAAC1AC251F8A54D7" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<rules-paragraph id="HDDB8D77116F946D196467552C0BB629F" indent="up1"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief Administrative Officer shall assist the Clerk in carrying out the responsibilities described in clause 2(i).</text></rules-paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HB86954E8B972461F807C0CF83121DC42"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Designating Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</header><text>In the standing rules, strike <quote>Committee on Oversight and Accountability</quote> each place it appears and insert (in each instance) <quote>Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDBB494C1327A4995AD79397E44F3FEFF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Designating Committee on Education and Workforce</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In rule X—</text> <paragraph id="H88D8013493014504A0F80623F13766C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause 1(e), strike <quote>Committee on Education and the Workforce</quote> and insert <quote>Committee on Education and Workforce</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7EDD8E8B5FAB40008D112449194BD820"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause 3(d), strike <quote>Committee on Education and the Workforce</quote> and insert <quote>Committee on Education and Workforce</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H66344F4C85104976BAFB1BD11AB167F3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Striking Office of Diversity and Inclusion</header> <paragraph id="H74AF2075E6B945B6B5E89E9B21DA26C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Strike</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In rule II, strike clause 9 and redesignate the succeeding clause accordingly.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4BFEC928E6044B0FA8DCD2518B5AB0A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>In clause 4(d)(1)(A) of rule X—</text> <subparagraph id="HE7173DC7AB564AB2B4A9B39690B9FDEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>strike <quote>the Office of Diversity and Inclusion,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7055DF0F362A46C99198C26F6820A36F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>strike <quote>Inspector General, Office of Diversity and Inclusion</quote> and insert <quote>Inspector General</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0C94DC7BFB9947C0BE9AB1FF493A389C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Codification of long-standing separate orders</header> <paragraph id="H46B3E1CAD2A34850B35EB7FA09BB03F3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Memorials submitted pursuant to article V</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In clause 3 of rule XII—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0CE55303ECE9418AB043036F47F69ECE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>strike <quote>If a Member</quote> and insert <quote>(a) If a Member</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA36B1FECB4C244CB8C45EB588866842C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>add at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="traditional" id="H365ED7E31DCA4DC89302FF530A0D5B58" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HFFD15E305B294D92BCDC293428F8B452"><enum>(b)</enum><text>With respect to any memorial presented under paragraph (a) purporting to be an application of the legislature of a State calling for a convention for proposing amendments to the Constitution of the United States pursuant to Article V, or a rescission of any such prior application—</text> <paragraph id="HBAE64497869941D4851F157182D683D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the chair of the Committee on the Judiciary shall, in the case of such a memorial presented in the One Hundred Fourteenth Congress or succeeding Congresses, and may, in the case of such a memorial presented prior to the One Hundred Fourteenth Congress, designate any such memorial for public availability by the Clerk; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2E71B19D8F5D4D51BE6B6BC28B80EBD1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Clerk shall make such memorials as are designated pursuant to subparagraph (1) publicly available in electronic form, organized by State of origin and year of receipt, and shall indicate whether the memorial was designated as an application or a rescission.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H979BF8882E904B0BBDD762EB9E73052A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Numbering of bills</header><text>In clause 7 of rule XII, add at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD780F19D28374A169AA8DF95B2E74F6E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<rules-paragraph id="H99BD78DF24A84D8F8EA21C31593DCA97" indent="up1"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The first 10 numbers for bills (H.R. 1 through H.R. 10) shall be reserved for assignment by the Speaker and the second 10 numbers for bills (H.R. 11 through H.R. 20) shall be reserved for assignment by the Minority Leader.</text></rules-paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89F5CC95C21F4B49B6DB6DEBBDF897E1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>District work periods</header><text>In rule I, add at the end the following new clause:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H34493EB9F6954CB8AA05B84FF0E44A56" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<rules-clause id="HA48095FEE73C4624BFF45AAF52A0CE02"> 
<rules-clause-header> District work periods</rules-clause-header><enum>13.</enum> 
<subsection id="H700F5E8D514342D097B4D5988BB8E65E" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On any legislative day occurring during a ‘district work period’ as designated by the Speaker—</text> <paragraph id="H9F6196DCFACE4D13A931F7AECE1B6420"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Journal of the proceedings of the previous day shall be considered as approved; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE03A1969791A4A73BFE1EC3C3AB4A429"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Chair may at any time declare the House adjourned to meet at a date and time, within the limits of clause 4, section 5, article I of the Constitution, to be announced by the Chair in declaring the adjournment.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDB10E93150254EC98E7B93E8EBEE2B65" indent="up1"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker may appoint Members to perform the duties of the Chair for the duration of a district work period described in paragraph (a) as though under clause 8(a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H180B5477EA3642D1A6BEED9F1FEFCA67"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Each day during a district work period described in paragraph (a) shall not constitute—</text> <paragraph id="H8757D99743004137B456C250FBB9EB56"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a calendar day for purposes of section 7 of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1546">50 U.S.C. 1546</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H388C3DB2CD064309ADDAFC0810017842"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a legislative day for purposes of clause 7 of rule XIII;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC41B3EF6B55410F8778DFF1A9A3C269"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a calendar or legislative day for purposes of clause 7(c)(1) of rule XXII; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H11B7D93233F04DE4B8D4D4924608E0C9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a legislative day for purposes of clause 7 of rule XV.</text></paragraph></subsection></rules-clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAECB9FE6D6BC454D9DBA65B7FE8A28FB"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Restoring family-centric language</header><text>In rule XXIII—</text> 
<paragraph id="H905E6528B4E344AD987F7EBFC42987EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause 8(c)(3), strike <quote>parent, child, sibling, parent’s sibling, first cousin, sibling’s child, spouse, parent-in-law, child-in-law, sibling-in-law, stepparent, stepchild, stepsibling, half-sibling, or grandchild</quote> and insert <quote>father, mother, son, daughter, brother, sister, uncle, aunt, first cousin, nephew, niece, husband, wife, father-in-law, mother-in-law, son-in-law, daughter-in-law, brother-in-law, sister-in-law, stepfather, stepmother, stepson, stepdaughter, stepbrother, stepsister, half brother, half sister, grandson, or granddaughter</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5275CC32F894480AB2E337A23840066B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause 15(d)(2), strike <quote>parent, child, sibling, spouse, or parent-in-law</quote> and insert <quote>father, mother, son, daughter, brother, sister, husband, wife, father-in-law, or mother-in-law</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2BF35DE3647E4E18B034BCE48488C2DC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Suspensions</header><text>In clause 1(a) of rule XV, add at the end the following new sentence: <quote>The Speaker may not entertain a motion that the House suspend the rules except on Mondays, Tuesdays, and Wednesdays.</quote>. </text> </subsection> <subsection id="H6512EBC80A66429A8AAD72157915E775"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Technical corrections</header> <paragraph id="HF0C36FD247E54241B525B8D17A5ECF90"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interim funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In clause 7(b) of rule X, strike <quote>In the case of the first session of a Congress, amounts</quote> and insert <quote>Amounts</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H88CD808040BD414D8AF774DCDCE7DF74"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Day count</header><text>In clause 6(d) of rule XIII, insert <quote>thereafter</quote> after <quote>seven legislative days</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HC6C22A525C4A49E8BD25FCAE4A1E872D" section-type="subsequent-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>3.</enum><header>Separate orders</header> <subsection id="HEE3B745C86F54CDF82729CFBC6B0751A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Holman rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress, any reference in clause 2 of rule XXI to a provision or amendment that retrenches expenditures by a reduction of amounts of money covered by the bill shall be construed as applying to any provision or amendment (offered after the bill has been read for amendment) that retrenches expenditures by—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEB2FD7673A4A42DEA8F0C78AA710D27C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reduction of amounts of money in the bill; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H07B2172F226B42E183DD3A40071FEB35"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the reduction of the number and salary of the officers of the United States; or </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H472309355E674135A5BBB2DCAE470AD4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the reduction of the compensation of any person paid out of the Treasury of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H98E30B9289224D419EB4E2E23609A36C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Spending reduction amendments in appropriations bills</header> <paragraph id="HFAB73C32AE1045FFBDF0250D70661F58"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the reading of a general appropriation bill for amendment in the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union, it shall be in order to consider en bloc amendments proposing only to transfer appropriations from an object or objects in the bill to a spending reduction account. When considered en bloc under this paragraph, such amendments may amend portions of the bill not yet read for amendment (following disposition of any points of order against such portions) and are not subject to a demand for division of the question in the House or in the Committee of the Whole. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H780477338B5243F79581816375DB8F13"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraph (1), it shall not be in order to consider an amendment to a spending reduction account in the House or in the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H75CC5F2C32B045E6AE1B1B3DBF135E1B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A point of order under clause 2(b) of rule XXI shall not apply to a spending reduction account. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEC324148687A493F9D985908EA2F77F7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A general appropriation bill may not be considered in the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union unless it includes a spending reduction account as the last section of the bill. An order to report a general appropriation bill to the House shall constitute authority for the chair of the Committee on Appropriations to add such a section to the bill or modify the figure contained therein.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H975889BF766B46F5967FFD5778D14F38"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>spending reduction account</term> means an account in a general appropriation bill that bears that caption and contains only—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA28CA7FCEC7D4FB3A6718C9672F3759E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a recitation of the amount by which an applicable allocation of new budget authority under section 302(b) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 exceeds the amount of new budget authority proposed by the bill; or </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC696F0CA6D614409A8407AFB2F1FA28F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if no such allocation is in effect, <quote>$0</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6C7DAA3E88854892B56CDC4BB00E06AD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Budget matters</header> 
<paragraph id="HE99D1BDF2B9746A7B325B7824A35C150"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Long term spending point of order</header> 
<subparagraph id="HB71943B913F04BF7A6F75E01517307C6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Congressional Budget Office analysis of proposals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Congressional Budget Office shall, to the extent practicable, prepare an estimate of whether a bill or joint resolution reported by a committee (other than the Committee on Appropriations), or amendment thereto or conference report thereon, would cause, relative to current law, a net increase in direct spending in excess of $2,500,000,000 in any of the 4 consecutive 10-fiscal year periods beginning with the first fiscal year that is 10 fiscal years after the current fiscal year.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAAC64B0E6F5A42A38265CACC47B9A013"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Point of order</header><text>It shall not be in order to consider any bill or joint resolution reported by a committee, or amendment thereto or conference report thereon, that would cause a net increase in direct spending in excess of $2,500,000,000 in any of the 4 consecutive 10-fiscal year periods described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H88A93B9E0B814F1AA9B434933DCFBC4F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Determinations of budget levels</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the levels of net increases in direct spending shall be determined on the basis of estimates provided by the chair of the Committee on the Budget.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1887B8D3546740139920246B808C0408" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scoring conveyances of Federal land</header> <subparagraph id="H927DB00856C545E7B966AA0ED6DC299D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress, for all purposes in the House, a provision in a bill or joint resolution, or in an amendment thereto or a conference report thereon, requiring or authorizing a conveyance of Federal land to a State, local government, or tribal entity shall not be considered as providing new budget authority, decreasing revenues, increasing mandatory spending, or increasing outlays.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCA2C3A7D023E4E06AAB3CF26AC936296"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text> <clause id="H9A623BA0E80F4482B64125276F1801BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>conveyance</term> means any method, including sale, donation, or exchange, by which all or any portion of the right, title, and interest of the United States in and to Federal land is transferred to another entity.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD05E40E0575D4E50AA4B878671590197"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The term <term>Federal land</term> means any land owned by the United States, including the surface estate, the subsurface estate, or any improvements thereon.</text></clause> <clause id="HF59AA9751FFC483A9B37C7B5E6109188"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The term <term>State</term> means any of the several States, the District of Columbia, or a territory (including a possession) of the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2FFE8D7726ED4ED18ECAF1C31A7D9F98"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Analysis of inflationary impact for certain legislation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress, if an estimate provided by the Congressional Budget Office under section 402 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 shows changes in mandatory spending that cause a gross budgetary effect in any fiscal year over a 10-year period that is equal to or greater than .25 percent of the projected gross domestic product (measured by the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers) for the current fiscal year, or upon the request of the chair of the Committee on the Budget, then such estimate shall include, to the extent practicable, a statement estimating the inflationary effects of the legislation, including whether the legislation is determined to have no significant impact on inflation, is determined to have a quantifiable inflationary impact on the consumer price index, or is determined likely to have a significant impact on inflation but the amount cannot be determined at the time the estimate is prepared.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4ADB32786165416580A6CC67ED06214E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Content of CBO analysis for certain legislation affecting the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund or the Old-Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance Trust Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress, if an estimate provided by the Congressional Budget Office under section 402 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 shows that legislation impacting either the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund or the Old-Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance Trust Fund (OASDI) causes a gross budgetary effect in any fiscal year over a 10-year period that is equal to or greater than .25 percent of the projected gross domestic product (measured by the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers) for the current fiscal year, or upon request of the chair of the Committee on the Budget, then such estimate shall, to the extent practicable, display—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA2D18D3D75DD4A129A05054E255EED7B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of legislation on the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund’s unfunded liabilities over a 25-year projection, solvency projections, and the net present value of those liabilities; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H04B3F78F2ECE40399718ED43047AB97F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the impact of legislation on the OASDI trust fund’s unfunded liabilities over a 75-year projection, solvency projections, and the net present value of those liabilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4FE3D076EEDA4C9FA7DF937B2C4A88FD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Congressional Member Organization transparency reform</header> 
<paragraph id="H35B89896901C44FBA1773B27B2F7DEC0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payment of salaries and expenses through account of organization</header><text>A Member of the House of Representatives and an eligible Congressional Member Organization may enter into an agreement under which—</text> <subparagraph id="H79C7D0C7CFA947E0AE69DC25B5D76399"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an employee of the Member’s office may carry out official and representational duties of the Member by assignment to the Organization; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H15F2C406B70C46EBA7DF9687742AEE9A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the extent that the employee carries out such duties under the agreement, the Member shall transfer the portion of the Members’ Representational Allowance (MRA) of the Member which would otherwise be used for the salary and related expenses of the employee to a dedicated account in the House of Representatives which is administered by the Organization, in accordance with the regulations promulgated by the Committee on House Administration under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H963EF3FB5EC3419791A3B24F39C501F0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Committee on House Administration (hereafter referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Committee</quote>) shall promulgate regulations as follows:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA59F34200A49456C9AC15AAF9ACA7E5E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Use of MRA</header><text>Pursuant to the authority of section 101(d) of the House of Representatives Administrative Reform Technical Corrections Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/5341">2 U.S.C. 5341(d)</external-xref>), the Committee shall prescribe regulations to provide that an eligible Congressional Member Organization may use the amounts transferred to the Organization’s dedicated account under paragraph (1)(B) for the same purposes for which a Member of the House of Representatives may use the Members’ Representational Allowance, except that the Organization may not use such amounts for franked mail, official travel, or leases of space or vehicles.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDCF172DD56874691933C6FF99E132260"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Maintenance of limitations on number of shared employees</header><text>Pursuant to the authority of section 104(d) of the House of Representatives Administrative Reform Technical Corrections Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/5321">2 U.S.C. 5321(d)</external-xref>), the Committee shall prescribe regulations to provide that an employee of the office of a Member of the House of Representatives who is covered by an agreement entered into under paragraph (1) between the Member and an eligible Congressional Member Organization shall be considered a shared employee of the Member’s office and the Organization for purposes of such section, and shall include in such regulations appropriate accounting standards to ensure that a Member of the House of Representatives who enters into an agreement with such an Organization under paragraph (1) does not employ more employees than the Member is authorized to employ under such section.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAF80B5538F7449E5B9E659B3421D4262"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Participation in student loan repayment program</header><text>Pursuant to the authority of section 105(b) of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4536">2 U.S.C. 4536(b)</external-xref>), relating to the student loan repayment program for employees of the House, the Committee shall promulgate regulations to provide that, in the case of an employee who is covered by an agreement entered into under paragraph (1) between a Member of the House of Representatives and an eligible Congressional Member Organization and who participates in such program while carrying out duties under the agreement—</text> <clause id="HAD82D2EDC6FF4C28A9EE2550AA414CC0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any funds made available for making payments under the program with respect to the employee shall be transferred to the Organization’s dedicated account under paragraph (1)(B); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3F815C5477BC47688C044B727506619E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Organization shall use the funds to repay a student loan taken out by the employee, under the same terms and conditions which would apply under the program if the Organization were the employing office of the employee.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H610B3B8FDD964706896A99A1AF752222"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Access to House services</header><text>The Committee shall prescribe regulations to ensure that an eligible Congressional Member Organization has appropriate access to services of the House.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H02D90D36F34F466CA2E52F5533503651"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Other regulations</header><text>The Committee shall promulgate such other regulations as may be appropriate to carry out this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB722B3736B194B8FA9B51248F34896F0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible congressional member organization defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>eligible Congressional Member Organization</term> means, with respect to the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress, an organization meeting each of the following requirements:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H62D802E172D34A5F8999D9620B66DB39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The organization is registered as a Congressional Member Organization with the Committee on House Administration.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8A9D7197DA874DFCB563C50EDB123967"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The organization designates a single Member of the House of Representatives to be responsible for the administration of the organization, including the administration of the account administered under paragraph (1)(B), and includes the identification of such Member with the statement of organization that the organization files and maintains with the Committee on House Administration.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6693F48181924C77A825DB1417CBFA46"><enum>(C)</enum><text>At least 3 employees of the House are assigned to perform some work for the organization.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8AF6EF63E24E4F6F8FE55EE25B54B277"><enum>(D)</enum><text>During the One Hundred Eighteenth Congress, at least 30 Members of the House of Representatives used a portion of the Members’ Representational Allowance of the Member for the salary and related expenses of an employee who was a shared employee of the Member’s office and the organization.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7A6FE1A33BA44303810DEDD278E92A8C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The organization files a statement with the Committee on House Administration and the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives certifying that it will administer an account in accordance with paragraph (1)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF29EF62771E84F3B8E4F4E370FAFEAEF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Determination with respect to placement of measure on Consensus Calendar</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress, not later than 2 legislative days after a measure is placed on the Consensus Calendar pursuant to clause 7(c) of rule XV, the Majority Leader shall, in the case such measure is not in compliance with any legislative protocols of the Majority Leader, submit to the Congressional Record a determination with respect to such noncompliance.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFBFDA9855C844F318CB95EF0DEF065B8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Further expenses for resolving contested elections</header> 
<paragraph id="H4C9B0A5E674B4A45BFCF92FA3077B7C6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amounts for expenses of Committee on House Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be paid out of the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives such sums as may be necessary for further expenses of the Committee on House Administration for the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress for resolving contested elections.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H44D091ACB8844040B610893ED3E65C35"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Session limitation</header><text>The amount specified in paragraph (1) shall be available for expenses incurred during the period beginning at noon on January 3, 2025, and ending immediately before noon on January 3, 2026.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H27A0B57324B44B3EBCA1939BB0D1DBCA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Vouchers</header><text>Payments under this subsection shall be made on vouchers authorized by the Committee on House Administration, signed by the chair of the Committee, and approved in the manner directed by the Committee.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE8A52CD33D94A208544EEADA17F4CCA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Amounts made available under this subsection shall be expended in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Committee on House Administration.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA5A33EC7CB8B44AB98A73F95DAD6483D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Question of consideration for germaneness</header> 
<paragraph id="H05045E4F9F5A469097EB46DBC47833C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress, it shall not be in order to consider a rule or order that waives all points of order against an amendment submitted to the Committee on Rules otherwise in violation of clause 7 of rule XVI. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCAFF0784202448A088092203ED8F39D7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disposition of point of order</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As disposition of a point of order under paragraph (1), the Chair shall put the question of consideration with respect to the rule or order, as applicable. The question of consideration shall be debatable for 10 minutes by the Member initiating the point of order and for 10 minutes by an opponent, but shall otherwise be decided without intervening motion except one that the House adjourn.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H45F6C77A1AAF49C281575273B4086D8E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Restoring legislative branch accountability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The regulations adopted pursuant to House Resolution 1096, One Hundred Seventeenth Congress, shall have no force or effect during the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDF8133FAAF2E4FB991D47EBBB65B4E75"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Remote appearance of witnesses</header> <paragraph id="HE7D4F1DED22141E584A895E3692BF606"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress, at the discretion of the chair of a committee and in accordance with regulations submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the chair of the Committee on Rules—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H759CFEFFA58E4B928BCE72873BC2F079"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">witnesses at committee or subcommittee proceedings may appear remotely; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H852CCF76FA044B95B47C7CBEB1761860"><enum>(B)</enum><text>counsel shall be permitted to accompany witnesses appearing remotely; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H749A527D70FB4F64814CDF0F203A136C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an oath may be administered to a witness remotely for purposes of clause 2(m)(2) of rule XI.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H714C40D9BE7E4072B987F9245345D297"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This subsection shall not apply to witnesses representing the executive branch of the United States government.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEECD79C3CB584A29BA5BA76FF8AE8953"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Addressing the use of artificial intelligence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on House Administration, the Clerk, the Chief Administrative Officer, and other officers and officials of the House shall continue efforts to integrate artificial intelligence technologies into the operations and functions of the House in the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress, in furtherance of the institutional priorities outlined in the House Information Technology Policy 8 (HITPOL 8) Artificial Intelligence (AI), which shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H3D66961A48C84227B411B1BC3558C9B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>incorporating appropriate guardrails and specific AI principles from HITPOL 8 that will guide both Members and institutional offices if they choose to incorporate this technology into their operations; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC00A08DF83D04D6AB67704CA3963883E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>exploring the use of AI applications to streamline administrative processes and enhance decision-making capabilities for House staff; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H050F02AEA2A148899525ED406B44D0FB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>continuing to advance AI-driven tools to support effective oversight through efficient legislative drafting, analysis, and comparative assessments of legislative texts. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H48EC5204F55D4447B4ED337D9C3A020E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Broadening availability and utility of legislative documents in machine-readable formats</header><text>The Committee on House Administration, the Clerk, and other officers and officials of the House shall continue efforts to broaden the availability and utility of legislative documents in machine readable formats in the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress in furtherance of the institutional priorities of—</text> <paragraph id="H1D31D6865AE04852845FE59B1AD2873C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improving public availability and use of legislative information produced by the House and its committees; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB1E54CE0DF27493C8DE3136826440653"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enabling all House staff to produce comparative prints showing the differences between versions of legislation, how proposed legislation will amend existing law, and how an amendment may change proposed legislation.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H62826D4CACF44AF5B65D0AB7DCF9598A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Improving the Committee electronic document repository</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Clerk, the Committee on House Administration, and other officers and officials of the House shall continue efforts to improve the electronic document repository operated by the Clerk for use by committees of the House in the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress, including streamlining the process of cross-posting documents simultaneously by the Committee on Rules, in furtherance of the institutional priority of increasing public availability and identification of legislative information produced and held by House committees, including votes, amendments, and witness disclosure forms.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDD6CCFF38E3C4041A2E1F2A4DC75E95A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Exercise facilities for former Members</header><text>During the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress:</text> <paragraph id="H15652023ED4F45C68E9231946205C51C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The House of Representatives may not provide access to any exercise facility which is made available exclusively to Members and former Members, officers and former officers of the House of Representatives, and their spouses to any former Member, former officer, or spouse who is a lobbyist registered under the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 or any successor statute or who is an agent of a foreign principal as defined in clause 5 of rule XXV. For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>Member</term> includes a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5908231570AF465BB68B2F290D39B4AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Committee on House Administration shall promulgate regulations to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H102CC2FD36C540AF8A533281E766ACDA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Displaying statement of rights and protections provided to House employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on House Administration shall issue regulations to provide that each employing office of the House of Representatives shall post in a prominent location in the office (including, in the case of the office of a Member, Delegate, or the Resident Commissioner, a prominent location in each district office) a statement of the rights and protections provided to employees of the House of Representatives under the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995, including the procedures available to employees of the House under such Act for responding to and adjudicating allegations of violations of such rights and protections.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCCD1191406B14F62AF81EF801249673E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Non-disclosure agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any non-disclosure agreement imposed by any employing or contracting authority in the House of Representatives to which a paid or unpaid employee or contractor is or was required to agree as a term of employment shall—</text> <paragraph id="H0DCE931866D342F8878E50837F2F2DEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide clear guidance that the employee or contractor may communicate concerning any matter with the Committee on Ethics, the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights, or any other office or entity designated by the Committee on House Administration without prior, concurrent, or subsequent notice or approval; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9C8B853CCBFC438293B9E734FAF7420D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not be binding and shall have no legal effect to the extent to which it requires prior, concurrent, or subsequent notice or approval from anyone on any matter with respect to communications from an employee or contractor to any of the committees, offices, or entities described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9F3F1232303143EA92A511213AD3D4E7"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Requiring Members to pay for discrimination settlements</header> <paragraph id="H4982854AE3BA454C8FA30C6AFC457DA5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a settlement of a complaint under the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 in connection with a claim alleging a violation described in paragraph (2) which is committed personally by a Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner, if the Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner is not required under law to reimburse the Treasury for the amount of the settlement, the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on House Administration may not approve the settlement pursuant to clause 4(d)(2) of rule X unless, under the terms and conditions of the settlement, the Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner is required to reimburse the Treasury for the amount of the settlement.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6951FEC0E6A746C6BEEC743659DF632B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Violations described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation described in this paragraph is—</text> <subparagraph id="H37A39316866C485AA2B483B8EA9C175C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a violation of section 201(a) or section 206(a) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4CA3108F4CF14E4B90424B287698129C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a violation of section 208 of such Act which consists of intimidating, taking reprisal against, or otherwise discriminating against any covered employee under such Act because of a claim alleging a violation described in subparagraph (A). </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H13B4604E4AA14B1789BD0A1F7ACC15E2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Mandatory anti-harassment and anti-discrimination policies for House offices</header> <paragraph id="H10D719E380B245329EE316237A8DCE1F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requiring offices to adopt policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each employing office of the House of Representatives under the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 shall adopt an anti-harassment and anti-discrimination policy for the office's workplace.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H86213C25682D43D28DB5EE5D3EB1F5C0" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than April 1, 2025, the Committee on House Administration shall promulgate regulations to carry out this subsection, and shall ensure that such regulations are consistent with the requirements of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995, rule XXIII, and other relevant laws, rules, and regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEB7ACB6A03E74766A07FBD06A31A6110" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(r)</enum><header>Member day hearing requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the first session of the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress, each standing committee (other than the Committee on Ethics) shall hold a hearing at which it receives testimony from Members, Delegates, and the Resident Commissioner on proposed legislation within its jurisdiction, except that the Committee on Rules may hold such hearing during the second session of the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H970475A0AEE0464FB5BAC2E7DB04A9D0"><enum>(s)</enum><header>Information to committees of Congress on request</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress, the chair of the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform shall be included as one of the seven members of the Committee making any request of an Executive agency pursuant to section 2954 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE27EB5A53BAA4DBB927F36529776B8FD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(t)</enum><header>Deposition authority</header> <paragraph id="HB592664C7CA947CB994E6C40E97D7543"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress, the chair of a standing committee (other than the Committee on Rules), and the chair of the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, upon consultation with the ranking minority member of such committee, may order the taking of depositions, including pursuant to subpoena, by a member or counsel of such committee.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC752177287384C91A01F4530D8356D84"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Depositions taken under the authority prescribed in this subsection shall be subject to regulations issued by the chair of the Committee on Rules and printed in the Congressional Record.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD6801EF022F48F0B9995136F7A581CC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Persons permitted to attend depositions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Deponents may be accompanied at a deposition by two designated personal, nongovernmental attorneys to advise them of their rights. Only members, committee staff designated by the chair or ranking minority member, an official reporter, the witness, and the witness’s two designated attorneys are permitted to attend. Other persons, including government agency personnel, may not attend.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H77821DB172694D76B063C426FB0CE780"><enum>(u)</enum><header>War Powers resolution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress, a motion to discharge a measure introduced pursuant to section 6 or section 7 of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1545-46">50 U.S.C. 1545–46</external-xref>) shall not be subject to a motion to table.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC161FD8276404EB5ACB397E47AC84DBE"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Continuing litigation authorities</header> <paragraph id="HCC9A2BB1B066455CBA4AD54ECA27BBCE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The House authorizes the chair of the Committee on the Judiciary (when elected), on behalf of the Committee on the Judiciary and until such committee has adopted rules pursuant to clause 2(a) of rule XI, to issue the following subpoenas:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD55ADC1D41B84BC08484CB6FD18EE33D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To Attorney General Merrick Garland related to the Special Counsel’s audio recordings of interviews with President Joseph R. Biden and his ghostwriter Mark Zwonitzer.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC8871DFEB30446DDA8787EA4D916B0E0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>To Mark Daly of the Department of Justice for a deposition related to the Department of Justice’s investigation into R. Hunter Biden.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3D125CA4204945D5B5D43BB5F2020633"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To Jack Morgan of the Department of Justice for a deposition related to the Department of Justice’s investigation into R. Hunter Biden.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD0989DFD93BA41ADAD2E26CF815D004B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enforcement of subpoenas</header><text>The House further authorizes the chair of the Committee on the Judiciary (when elected), on behalf of the Committee on the Judiciary, consistent with clause 8(c) of rule II, and the Office of General Counsel to take all necessary steps as may be appropriate to continue the civil actions authorized by the House during the One Hundred Eighteenth Congress concerning the enforcement of the subpoenas issued to such individuals.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H914E6AA8F63245ECB7E592C946B68DCB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Committees, commissions, and House offices</header> 
<subsection id="HCC37A13FB7B941DABAE9DEC66A52DCED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Select Committee on the Strategic Competition between the United States and the Chinese Communist Party</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">House Resolution 11, One Hundred Eighteenth Congress, as amended by House Resolution 78, One Hundred Eighteenth Congress, shall apply in the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress in the same manner as such resolution applied in the One Hundred Eighteenth Congress, except that—</text> <paragraph id="H479C746B16144E86830946F8F442D4F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Select Committee concerned shall submit all reports to the House or policy recommendations to the relevant standing committees under section 1(e) not later than December 31, 2026; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F072FE0B6CD4E34A8B6528CEC03BC7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the investigative jurisdiction of the Select Committee shall consist of policy recommendations on countering the economic, technological, security, and ideological threats of the Chinese Communist Party to the United States and allies and partners of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6E985E374E4C404884853871C298CFE2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>House Democracy Partnership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">House Resolution 24, One Hundred Tenth Congress, shall apply in the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress in the same manner as such resolution applied in the One Hundred Tenth Congress, except that the commission concerned shall be known as the House Democracy Partnership.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H13439EEFE8E44627BDF99CFF59166B05"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Tom Lantos Human Rights Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sections 1 through 7 of House Resolution 1451, One Hundred Tenth Congress, shall apply in the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress in the same manner as such provisions applied in the One Hundred Tenth Congress, except that—</text> <paragraph id="HC91375E807D24173B18244CEE0312D52"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Tom Lantos Human Rights Commission may, in addition to collaborating closely with other professional staff members of the Committee on Foreign Affairs, collaborate closely with professional staff members of other relevant committees;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4FF3202EB1CA45F089D4187495D2A670"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the resources of the Committee on Foreign Affairs which the Commission may use shall include all resources which the Committee is authorized to obtain from other offices of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE180507D18F0428588DDB52036B8560F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any amounts authorized to provide full-time professional staff and resources to the Tom Lantos Human Rights Commission shall be in addition to and separate from the amounts authorized for salaries and expenses of the Committee on Foreign Affairs as provided by resolution of the House, shall be administered by the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and shall be distributed equally between the co-chairs of the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDB09BB3F94314667B1F4C3C1ED05BAE3" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Office of Congressional Conduct</header> 
<paragraph id="HE89A5E5C5F1841FFA61D1578CA5D5540" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>References in the standing rules to the Office of Congressional Ethics shall be construed as references to the Office of Congressional Conduct. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8027A70349674A15B071EAF1992A1FC1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Office of Congressional Conduct</header><text>Section 1 of House Resolution 895, One Hundred Tenth Congress, shall apply in the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress in the same manner as such provision applied in the One Hundred Tenth Congress, except that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H11375476AE504BB9BDA12285B0C37FDA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Office of Congressional Ethics shall be known as the Office of Congressional Conduct (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>); </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1DD883F16EB24836A041551292CC8F44" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>references to the Office of Congressional Ethics shall be construed as references to the Office;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3180EFB078B047BDB48ABE659911F8C2" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Office shall be treated as a standing committee of the House for purposes of section 202(i) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4301">2 U.S.C. 4301(i)</external-xref>); </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD8127C89518B4913B81C40F2A1B1AD7E" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>references to the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct shall be construed as references to the Committee on Ethics; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H79B98209F6A748B08CC718D39D9595CD" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any requirement for concurrence in section 1(b)(1) shall be construed as a requirement for consultation; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H629578264B66498D87110795D963A51D" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any individual who is the subject of a preliminary review or second-phase review by the board shall be informed of the right to be represented by counsel and invoking that right should not be held negatively against such individual; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAD6BD6E5C34445E2A77EC7BE23911AD1" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Office may not take any action that would deny any person any right or protection provided under the Constitution of the United States; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H955D74DF95DA41BE9D3F42E4DEF2122B" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any member of the board currently serving a term in excess of the limitations of section 1(b)(6) of such resolution shall be considered as removed from the board; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H768A4CF3D27A48E1B80F14E9A233BD39" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the provision regarding appointment and compensation of staff shall require an affirmative vote of at least 4 members of the board not later than 30 calendar days after the board has been fully constituted. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H4D7324FC6796480D8F925B616D66DE11" section-type="subsequent-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>5.</enum><header>Orders of business</header> <subsection id="HCF4279D4F89845B7947163E919CDA0DC"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House any bill specified in subsection (b). All points of order against consideration of each such bill are waived. Each such bill shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in each such bill are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on each such bill and on any amendment thereto to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the Majority Leader and the Minority Leader or their respective designees; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC247433C42FC433A8F37A1F98034D97F"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The bills referred to in this subsection are as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HF3C0A8ED7B754D6091005C7203966A7C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The bill (H.R. 28) to amend the Education Amendments of 1972 to provide that for purposes of determining compliance with title IX of such Act in athletics, sex shall be recognized based solely on a person’s reproductive biology and genetics at birth. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HACEE4709F26C4495849E8432DDF567E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The bill (H.R. 29) to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to take into custody aliens who have been charged in the United States with theft, and for other purposes. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H32C1C50EC8BB4DA99705D87C6E9F44E8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The bill (H.R. 30) to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide that aliens who have been convicted of or who have committed sex offenses or domestic violence are inadmissible and deportable. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7CE4C7BF350D4751A9DDBEB04E3E79D2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The bill (H.R. 31) to make the assault of a law enforcement officer a deportable offense, and for other purposes. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H461A15C4447F42D3BCDCB81FDCB7DD16"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The bill (H.R. 32) to provide that sanctuary jurisdictions that provide benefits to aliens who are present in the United States without lawful status under the immigration laws are ineligible for Federal funds intended to benefit such aliens. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58FC42A547BA4A3CB9C39E59F02057B0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The bill (H.R. 35) to impose criminal and immigration penalties for intentionally fleeing a pursuing Federal officer while operating a motor vehicle. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H93DE6B70899640969E9A3D5BC8DD53F5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The bill (H.R. 21) to amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit a health care practitioner from failing to exercise the proper degree of care in the case of a child who survives an abortion or attempted abortion. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC592DEE0960B4BBF8002618B68029C00"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The bill (H.R. 23) to impose sanctions with respect to the International Criminal Court engaged in any effort to investigate, arrest, detain, or prosecute any protected person of the United States and its allies. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E2FA21D064F4C0A9C8DE59566F58D4E"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The bill (H.R. 33) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide special rules for the taxation of certain residents of Taiwan with income from sources within the United States. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7DCF2542CB224DFC810055C298C3F721"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The bill (H.R. 22) to amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to require proof of United States citizenship to register an individual to vote in elections for Federal office, and for other purposes. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E49B7F18928402A87C17E094583E485"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The bill (H.R. 27) to amend the Controlled Substances Act with respect to the scheduling of fentanyl-related substances, and for other purposes.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB0031F9EC0AF4DB19A1546C9936A6FF9"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The bill (H.R. 26) to prohibit a moratorium on the use of hydraulic fracturing.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </resolution-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </resolution> 

