<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-MAR25060-Y7C-VP-C5H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 SRES 300 ATS: Designating June 15, 2025, as “World Elder Abuse Awareness Day” and the month of June 2025 as “Elder Abuse Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 300</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250624">June 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating June 15, 2025, as <quote>World Elder Abuse Awareness Day</quote> and the month of June 2025 as <quote>Elder Abuse Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2021, approximately 55,800,000 residents of the United States, or about 1 in every 6 individuals, had attained the age of 65, and by 2060, 95,000,000 individuals in the United States, or about 1 in every 4 individuals, will be over the age of 65, according to estimates by the Bureau of the Census;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2034, it is anticipated that older adults will outnumber children for the first time, according to the Bureau of the Census;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas elder abuse remains a challenging problem and can come in many different forms, often manifesting as physical, sexual, or psychological abuse, financial exploitation, neglect, and social media abuse;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation have no boundaries and cross all racial, social, class, gender, and geographic lines, according to the Elder Justice Coalition;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas about 1 in 10 adults over the age of 60 are subjected to abuse, neglect, or financial exploitation each year, according to the National Institute on Aging;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the annual loss by victims of financial abuse over the age of 60 is estimated to be at least $28,300,000,000, according to the National Council on Aging;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas for older adults over the age of 60, the Department of Justice reported the following scam-related financial losses for 2023—</text><paragraph id="id7af596dc5bd745ae83febaa68dac875e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$1,200,000,000 from investment scams;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4142156c2baf4a6b8f94f2664465173e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$590,000,000 from tech support scams;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id88ae168e6b594c0b82c58532022af55d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$382,000,000 from business email compromise scams;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4fd48cf2c8934dbe8ef5d7ce66577a9b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$356,000,000 from romance scams; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id444bd6854c1644adaee70e3752a76dfc"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$179,000,000 from government impersonation scams;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas older adults reported losses of $4,885,000,000 related to internet scams and fraud in 2024, and filed over 147,000 complaints related to internet crimes, according to the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas adults over the age of 60 are less likely than younger adults to report losing money to fraud according to the Federal Trade Commission;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas most reported cases of abuse, neglect, and exploitation of older adults take place within private homes, and approximately 90 percent of the perpetrators in elder financial exploitation cases are family members or other trusted individuals, according to the National Adult Protective Services Association;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas research suggests that elderly individuals in the United States who experience cognitive impairment, physical disabilities, or isolation are more likely to become the victims of abuse than those who do not experience cognitive impairment, physical disabilities, or isolation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas other risk factors for elder abuse can include low social support, poor physical health, and experience of previous traumatic events, according to the National Center on Elder Abuse;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas close to half of elderly individuals who suffer from dementia will experience abuse during their lifetime, according to the Department of Justice;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas only 1 in 24 cases of elder abuse is reported, and only 1 in 44 cases of elder financial exploitation is reported , according the New York State Office of Children and Family Services;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the COVID–19 pandemic has led to the emergence of new scams against older adults, including those related to vaccines;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 1 in 5 older persons reported elder abuse during the COVID-19 pandemic, an over 80 percent increase from previous years, according to the National Institute of Health;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during the last 5 years, Congress passed and the President signed 2 measures that make nearly $400,000,000 available for implementation of the initiatives under the Elder Justice Act of 2009 (subtitle H of title VI of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>; 124 Stat. 783), the largest funding stream related to such initiatives in the history of the Act; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress, in passing the Elder Justice Act of 2009 (subtitle H of title VI of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>; 124 Stat. 783), the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3001">42 U.S.C. 3001 et seq.</external-xref>), the Elder Abuse Prevention and Prosecution Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/21701">34 U.S.C. 21701 et seq.</external-xref>), the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/2">Public Law 117–2</external-xref>; 135 Stat. 4), and the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>; 134 Stat. 1182), recognized the importance of protecting older people of the United States against abuse and exploitation: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idd7fe55e733944485aae4b3790468f686"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates June 15, 2025, as <quote>World Elder Abuse Awareness Day</quote> and the month of June 2025 as <quote>Elder Abuse Awareness Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id66af4df7f6094550b99fcae0f882b845"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes—</text><subparagraph id="id966baa9adfaf43b6854b0683b7eb3b59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>judges, lawyers, adult protective services professionals, law enforcement officers, social workers, health care providers, advocates for victims, and other professionals and agencies for their efforts to advance awareness of elder abuse;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id74b6c244e58440148bfb8e97c6f3ba7d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the important work of the Elder Justice Coordinating Council, which has continued through the previous 3 Presidential administrations and involves 15 different Federal agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfc137405ab9f4df8ae8051f3aa5fdca6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the essential work done by adult protective services personnel, who regularly come to the assistance of victims, investigate reports of abuse, and actively prevent future victimization of older people in the United States, especially during the COVID–19 pandemic as the social isolation of elderly individuals, due to stay-at-home orders, only increased the risk of abuse and neglect; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id94d028da5dc54dfd9f0ea3f8eef3cb3d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the importance of supporting State long-term care ombudsman programs, which help prevent elder abuse and neglect in nursing homes and other long-term care facilities, where infection prevention and control deficiencies pose persistent challenges;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idac61e684d4494881be5ea1f94b206198"><enum>(3)</enum><text>applauds the work of the Elder Justice Coalition and its members, whose efforts to increase public awareness of elder abuse have the potential to increase the identification and reporting of this crime by the public, professionals, and victims, and can act as a catalyst to promote issue-based education and long-term prevention; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id03b4edd9804440358b58ef888b24228f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages—</text><subparagraph id="idaa240f37f57c4a5aae6ad7f5a6cc4016"><enum>(A)</enum><text>members of the public and professionals who work with older adults to act as catalysts to promote awareness and long-term prevention of elder abuse—</text><clause id="id4b48579225374c5f94662846d7ae7281"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by reaching out to local adult protective services agencies, State long-term care ombudsman programs, and the National Center on Elder Abuse; and</text></clause><clause id="id39384754d58242a6b7b00f46f69a18cc"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by learning to recognize, detect, report, and respond to elder abuse;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc11e4ae7128345b6bf93eee80a4a57c2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>private individuals and public agencies in the United States to continue work together at the Federal, State, and local levels to combat abuse, neglect, exploitation, crime, and violence against vulnerable adults, including vulnerable older adults, particularly in light of limited resources for vital protective services; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf80cf388d24248ad98dba33688d54a11"><enum>(C)</enum><text>those Federal agencies with responsibility for preventing elder abuse to fully exercise such responsibilities to protect older adults, whether such older adults are living in the community or in long-term care facilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

