<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1D722D3B85824A1AAB601AF78A0BE0C9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2825 IH: Postal Service Clusterbox Responsibility Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2825</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 39, United States Code, to require the United States Postal Service to continue maintaining cluster mailboxes that the Postal Service has historically maintained, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H228043A462F7438E9635E3BC686DB0A6" style="OLC"><section id="HC7507043F091448E99C215759937A92F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Postal Service Clusterbox Responsibility Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5735000D96FF4B5CA277A660D7D3828F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Historically maintained cluster box units</header><subsection id="H95D817FB1357495EA092876DBA4E0AC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/39/29">Chapter 29</external-xref> of title 39, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A52B717E3F843EC882772A1C3DEA7B3"><section id="H28275E17ADA845EBB22F763C5B2C10C8"><enum>2904.</enum><header>Historically maintained cluster box units</header><subsection id="HD4814CFFCDE546C099D4F24E4AC47B58"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Postal Service shall, in accordance with this section, maintain covered cluster box units, including—</text><paragraph id="HF3E61B5D74DD4E199F7B4E1690B5F992"><enum>(1)</enum><text>repairing and replacing covered cluster box units; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H301A6FDF4F0C4351B4FB56B5D2635C79"><enum>(2)</enum><text>adding mailboxes to covered cluster box units in accordance with subsection (c)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H359A245117C449DE819BCEA9414E7272"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Maintenance determination</header><paragraph id="HBF3613EFFD354E0C9967D90952722CFC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Postal Service shall determine whether a cluster box unit is a covered cluster box unit.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4476CFE92E5428AB953487712E49C25"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A covered person for a cluster box unit seeking a determination that such cluster box unit is a covered cluster box unit shall submit to Postal Service an application at such time and in such manner as the Postal Service determines, and containing—</text><subparagraph id="HBF1F068CBABD492EA22065B46D1695CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">documentation evidencing that the Postal Service has primarily maintained such cluster box unit for a period of not less than 20 years;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AA4A4AF2FD04E6AB7BE974012D8CBBC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>written permission for the Postal Service to maintain such cluster box unit; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FC42BF642754DE28155CE4D898F75FC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such other information as the Postal Service determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6618C2318B304204A1BE6D129BF5C027"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Postal service documentation</header><text>In making the determination under paragraph (1), the Postal Service shall—</text><subparagraph id="H29FB741F69954A32882195D7EFBC21A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>undertake a reasonable investigation to identify any documents and other information of the Postal Service or reasonably available to the Postal Service that are relevant to such determination; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H308369CA3F49411A918FB8AE2D3DC8A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consider such documents and other information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9604A70C2D347E3A11E6CA93BB4D6AA" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The Postal Service shall make the determination under paragraph (1) with respect to a cluster box unit and notify the covered person who submitted the application under paragraph (2) with respect to such cluster box unit not later than one month after the date on which such covered person submitted such application.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H465BD440AC874D779BF316AF18475131"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional mail receptacles</header><paragraph id="H1E534137871043A38FAE3A55914B625C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Postal Service additions</header><subparagraph id="H84BA11A023A94C5C9E6B2D19053B240E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Postal Service shall add a mailbox to a covered cluster box unit if a covered person for such covered cluster box unit submits to the Postal Service a notice under subparagraph (B) and the Postal Service determines that such an additional mailbox is necessary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69F14B3B9B234FB59D234077ACA2D855"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>A covered person for a covered cluster box unit seeking the addition of a mailbox to such covered cluster box unit shall submit to the Postal Service a notice at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Postal Service determines appropriate, including evidence of the need for such additional mailbox.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H158540834A2041A3887999D02FB24545"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additions by others</header><text>If a covered person for a covered cluster box unit adds a mailbox to such covered cluster box unit in accordance with all other laws and regulations, the Postal Service shall maintain such covered cluster box unit, including any such additional mailboxes, in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H75B77BA90ABC44C18A107970CC25A251"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Maintenance by others</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit or otherwise limit a covered person for a covered cluster box unit from maintaining such covered cluster box unit.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1A846128019243D6B0B985C6DD8A9AFA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Postal Service shall not perform any maintenance under this section that—</text><paragraph id="HAC4C9A182B01405D9AE8432B9F44278C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is not necessary for the function of a covered cluster box unit, except that the Postal Service shall make repairs to the extent that such repairs are incident to maintenance that is necessary for the function of the covered cluster box unit;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H343816B896864003A37BC946571CA060"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is required as a result of a covered person for a covered cluster box unit or any individual residing at an address served by such covered cluster box unit—</text><subparagraph id="H0C089A0750504DBD821BDF6EF33B04E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>intentionally or willfully damaging such covered cluster box unit, as determined by the Postal Service; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD363624920E3486DA710BDEB72A1F19F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>making any change to such covered cluster box unit that is not necessary for the function of such covered cluster box unit; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H89061B17A33143F29AB9BD6F93BCB599"><enum>(3)</enum><text>pertains to the structure of a building.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA75770FBA4D44F3D8ED008799B152CA4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reimbursement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Postal Service incurs or will incur costs to perform maintenance under this section on or for a covered cluster box unit that is required by circumstances creating a legal liability on an individual or entity (other than the United States) to pay damages with respect to such maintenance, the Postal Service may request the beneficiary to—</text><paragraph id="H555757D3790941F589006CBD6AAECE68"><enum>(1)</enum><text>if the beneficiary enforces such liability, assign to the Postal Service any right of the beneficiary to share in money or property received in satisfaction of such liability to the extent of such costs; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5D1CD94805A4FDB913BC6A3E6DBB224"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the beneficiary does not enforce such liability—</text><subparagraph id="H51C9D7BC2F5946CBB9C975EB8A589285"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assign to the Postal Service any right of action such beneficiary may have to enforce such liability; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71C0605E1DE14C59931E75AF39750576"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enforce such liability and comply with paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H27A42957B2CD4944BDE55ADDFF5C7A45" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination</header><paragraph id="HBBBF797DC29B4DF0B6E4310177C76A83" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered cluster box unit shall cease to be a covered cluster box unit if—</text><subparagraph id="HE3614AA16C344F07B2E66F1D2491DD55" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a covered person for a covered cluster box unit withdraws permission for the Postal Service to maintain such covered cluster box unit;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B55963EBB4F4DB1BD4ABE19146C2FA4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a beneficiary that is a covered person refuses a request from the Postal Service described in subsection (f) with respect to maintenance for such covered cluster box unit; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95B34CC439B64163844DD8399B16E597" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Postal Service permanently ceases delivery and collection of mail to all addresses served by a mailbox in such covered cluster box unit or any associated receptacle for parcels.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H745CD3ED55F347D7BBD030EC482F0105" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Withdrawal of permission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The owner of a covered cluster box unit may withdraw permission for the Postal Service to maintain such covered cluster box unit only by submitting to the Postal Service a written notice.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3C307AAC663543BD8AD0E06E5001BEA0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Cluster box unit maintenance fund</header><paragraph id="H64D43AF47AE047C29B1C4F4BBE5AAE43"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a revolving fund to be called the Cluster Box Unit Maintenance Fund, which shall be available to the Postal Service without fiscal-year limitation to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5F31D3651714434BE72BFFB06BA6E5A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deposits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 2003(b), there shall be deposited in the Fund, subject to withdrawal by check by the Postal Service, amounts appropriated for the use of the Postal Service to carry out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA0888F1B66E54C529EF326318AA0847F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H00A063FDA43F44C1BF4A0207CD1F067D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cluster box unit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>cluster box unit</term> means a centralized unit of individually locked compartments for the delivery and collection of mail.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD59223A0098049D7A6EEF08D4386FE46"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered cluster box unit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered cluster box unit</term> means a cluster box unit that—</text><subparagraph id="H8C2D313785174B92B3C90BA48E8210DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is owned by an individual or entity, other than a public entity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB6D0268828D457F9B995AC6433DCC97"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Postal Service has primarily maintained for a period of not less than 20 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDAF1808E623449A3A5459F4108C8D18E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered person</header><text>The term <term>covered person</term> means, with respect to a cluster box unit, an individual or entity that may give to and withdraw from the Postal Service permission to maintain such cluster box unit.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DA4DB6C038B4FCEB8960CB08D80115D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Primarily maintained</header><text>The term <term>primarily maintained</term>, with respect to a cluster box unit, means paid for or performed the majority of the maintenance necessary for the function of the cluster box unit, including repairs and replacing the cluster box unit when necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H5D0AD479AFAA49F395A50071A133EC39"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/39/29">chapter 29</external-xref> of title 39, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H407009E82B09437CB7E06031AC65733D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">2904. Historically maintained cluster box units.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H46334AFED619440AACA75F4F84DD4ED0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the United States Postal Service shall issue regulations carrying out the amendments made by this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

