<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H639EB6303F77413EB9890A54D1C3B770" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 48 IH: Honoring Reverend Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., by celebrating diversity, promoting tolerance, and condemning hate.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 48</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250116">January 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000489">Mr. Turner of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000537">Mr. Clyburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hernández</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring Reverend Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., by celebrating diversity, promoting tolerance, and condemning hate.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Nation will celebrate the 96th anniversary of the birth of Reverend Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., on Monday, January 20, 2025; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Dr. King taught that the blessing of diversity is our strength; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Dr. King fought, marched, and preached for the inalienable rights of all people, particularly Black Americans;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas among these rights is the inviolable right of every person to cast their vote and make their voice heard in a representative democracy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas tolerance for one another’s difference in race, ethnicity, gender, culture, religion, sexual orientation, age, or disability is a profound virtue; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas civil discourse in a land of democratic freedom is the true promise of our country; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Dr. King once wrote in his 1963 Letter from a Birmingham Jail, <quote>Whatever affects one directly, affects all indirectly</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H5E1171D00DC846B3A1C76A5657AB32CA"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HB9879EFE7DC841F5990E544BDA7B1638"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H32B749BC55464938B569BEED588B1174"><enum>(1)</enum><text>celebrates the 96th anniversary of the birthday of Reverend Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., on January 20, 2025, which shall serve as a reminder that hate and hateful conduct based on differences has no place in the United States in tribute to his life and teachings;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H916E2E75378946649331A5F02EB45A05"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affirms the words of Reverend Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., <quote>Anyone who lives inside the United States can never be considered an outsider anywhere within its bounds</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AE6CA0547EE42B59627BCB4222B9F72"><enum>(3)</enum><text>honors the life, legacy, works, and heroism of Reverend Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB02BF167026E4F0F813D9E04DA3DC74E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">condemns any form of harassment, discrimination, or prejudice targeted at any minority ethnic group, including the Black community, Indigenous people, the Jewish community, the Asian-American and Pacific Islander community, the Muslim community, and the Hispanic and Latino communities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC37466BAF4A64B8CB7D1BAC6F7C8D67A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>condemns any form of harassment, discrimination, or prejudice based on a person’s gender, including the trans community and LGBTQ+ individuals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEF8FCE5D3BC455EA695F89C2FEED656"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">abhors the violence and animus that led to the untimely death of Reverend Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A5B51774AFA4D4DB8A6D393DDCDBC32"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls on all people across the Nation and the world to uphold Reverend Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.’s values and teachings of justice, equality, peace, advocacy, and tolerance.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

