<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB6F21633DEDC4DBF89CA07CB47146AED" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2605 IH: Service Dogs Assisting Veterans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2605</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250402">April 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000603">Mr. Luttrell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000619">Mr. Rulli</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000601">Mr. Goldman of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000404">Ms. King-Hinds</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000598">Mr. LaLota</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to award grants to nonprofit organizations to assist such organizations in carrying out programs to provide service dogs to eligible veterans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H58D42FE9550543768FA51C32305B0629" style="OLC"><section id="H5AB35EDD17C745AE8546846155CB5487" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Service Dogs Assisting Veterans Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAVES Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HADBB221352C443C5B87EA3EFD72B85B0" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs pilot program to award grants for the provision of service dogs to veterans</header><subsection id="H0640EE919AA945DE83DE4C5D40979811"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="H1B2CE7D132C540E485F15973BC2C38C3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Pilot program required</header><text>Not later than 24 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish a pilot program under which the Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to nonprofit entities to provide service dogs to eligible veterans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96BCAA8B51C9455D9F849B129213B7B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program during the five-year period beginning on the date on which the first grant is awarded under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H80C13EDA39B4430DBEA7B4055D70EBF7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applications</header><paragraph id="H23EFAEA87F3F4AECAD789F7700113F29"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a nonprofit entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such commitments and information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBE124BC709D4EADA1AFCE25754B7885"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>An application submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="H63A8DF3B80B349DA8963A0D7EE392D68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A proposal for the provision of service dogs to eligible veterans, including how the nonprofit entity will communicate with the Secretary to ensure an increasing number of service dogs are provided to veterans.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A88D31345224810A94ECF64C6A24B66"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the following:</text><clause id="H73884DD2665240589195A99E1D4DB0B5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The training that will be provided by the nonprofit entity to eligible veterans.</text></clause><clause id="H279A0A5EF3F841719281DA18B597677F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The training of dogs that will serve as service dogs.</text></clause><clause id="H4CD213A2A419442581AE22F6FC017519"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any additional support or services the nonprofit entity will provide for such dogs and eligible veterans.</text></clause><clause id="H1A0662BD08AB404396315C5FDDF68411"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The plan for publicizing the availability of such dogs through a marketing campaign that targets eligible veterans.</text></clause><clause id="H4E6C31758D6F4FA4BAE037FBBF735499"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The commitment of the nonprofit entity to have humane standards for animals.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E7339F22F5046BEA5D004472B1B93C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Documentation that demonstrates that the nonprofit entity has experience in training dogs as service animals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFE9A92E410504ABD990B8F0920F3C8AE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Award of grants</header><paragraph id="H35E973402505412F8F7C92D34ED3EB0C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award a grant to each nonprofit entity for which the Secretary has approved an application submitted under subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CDD31616B9149B5897B3CCF2A497235"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agreement required</header><text>Before the provision of any grant amounts to a nonprofit entity selected to receive a grant under this section, the Secretary shall enter into an agreement, containing such terms, conditions, and limitations as the Secretary determines appropriate, with such entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H690E5B795C1A4404A33206FB6ACC64E3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Maximum grant amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant under this section may not exceed $2,000,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C6001C953684A62BB22DC95B8560ED8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Payments</header><text>The Secretary shall establish intervals of payment for the administration of each grant awarded under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1200ED040D1F4A74A995E27B1D41E3AC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><paragraph id="HEF0ADF9074FA4D91B144AC770EEB22C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A recipient of a grant under this section shall use the grant amounts to plan, develop, implement, or manage (or any combination thereof) one or more programs that provide service dogs to eligible veterans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H422F960502AB4D8185E4D66D5A7659D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>The Secretary may establish a maximum amount for each grant awarded under this section that may be used by the recipient of the grant to cover administrative expenses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD170D224A04047D99B0364D6329543DB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other conditions and limitations</header><text>The Secretary may establish other conditions or limitations on the use of grant amounts under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDA270D0D54A34868BB023AFD2BC7D359"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Requirements for grant recipients</header><paragraph id="H7C9AECDF061B4C3DBD14F0526D74322F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notifications and information</header><text>A recipient of a grant under this section shall—</text><subparagraph id="H6F42C6F3C0E74920B762B15132BC30A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notify each veteran who receives a service dog through such grant that the service dog is being paid for, in whole or in part, by the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD3DB04F51754433BCF7319A5000D739"><enum>(B)</enum><text>inform each such veteran of the benefits and services available from the Secretary for the veteran and the service dog.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA159B92B5F8C49EEAA6CDE8EA780667A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on certain fees</header><text>A recipient of a grant under this section may not charge a fee to a veteran receiving a service dog through such grant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3E93C4CAD89E40A4BA31106A27E56738"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Veterinary insurance</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28AC3CE1C1A644C6B6C77875E6670A2C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide to each veteran who receives a service dog through a grant under this section a commercially available veterinary insurance policy for the service dog. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8FD5A62D8791475EB59DBFF62AC447E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continuation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary provides a veterinary insurance policy to a veteran under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall continue to provide the policy to the veteran without regard to the continuation or termination of the pilot program. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFA1DF63C5D484941A33777794CF6079E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Training and technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary may provide training and technical assistance to recipients of grants under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2D4F5FD09B2047F798300AD909F2486E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Oversight and monitoring</header><paragraph id="H29C63FFAAE83415B8E4BE2F4F270865A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="H6AA4EACF31BE4163B5E94131486F4C58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall establish such oversight and monitoring requirements as the Secretary determines appropriate to ensure that grant amounts awarded under this section are used appropriately; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB428D5FE246A4DD49BE1D123958C47C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may take such actions as the Secretary determines necessary to address any issues identified through the enforcement of such requirements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H419494FF3E38434DA6EBC15EB68D09F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports and answers</header><text>The Secretary may require each recipient of a grant under this section to provide, in such form as may be prescribed by the Secretary, such reports or answers in writing to specific questions, surveys, or questionnaires as the Secretary determines necessary to carry out the pilot program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6863E93723C84C4A932D558DB3E3CC83"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HADA826844FAF427698372408CA5F2E80" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>eligible veteran</term> means a veteran who has a covered condition=.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC19CB1372BF34F048C44F95630C8A5B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered condition</quote> means any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H8F9712C4E1E64EE795AEE7A3BCF75D12"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Blindness or visual impairment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5B10A2D3D274F008A26B501080AB17C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Loss of use of a limb, paralysis, or other significant mobility issue, including mental health mobility.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H429364E8D8B84B418347157A5242781B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Loss of hearing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC17A9B13CDC9471C840694EB9515D505"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Post-traumatic stress disorder.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7DA225FBBFA44F2879441EE1CE7BD17"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Traumatic brain injury. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBA7F74AC30648BC81CD216AF9ED1666"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any other disability, condition, or diagnosis for which the Secretary determines, based on medical judgment, that it is optimal for the veteran to manage the disability, condition, or diagnosis, and live independently through the assistance of a service dog.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H759702F16F404C4C8F6E163DA9BAED95"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>service animal</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 36.104 of title 28, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulation).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EC162A02C664121AA69DCEE2775FE44"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>service dog</term> means any dog that is individually trained to do work or perform tasks that are—</text><subparagraph id="H42FCB46942054766BDC05C52975F4E2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for the benefit of a veteran with a covered condition; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4436492028547C0939EE550C6EED28F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">directly related to the covered condition of the veteran.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H47091D9FC09D462CA3F91E0ECA58C4AD"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of the five consecutive fiscal years following the fiscal year in which the pilot program is established under subsection (a). </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

