<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCA1AFCBC5ACA4DCD91A940B1669D92FB" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 143 IH: Impeaching Paul Engelmayer, judge of the United States District Court for the Southern District of New York, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 143</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250218">February 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Impeaching Paul Engelmayer, judge of the United States District Court for the Southern District of New York, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H2838A9152FBC4599911620A2CD688680"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HC555D46B3EB445E48828D330DAD2FB2E"><enum/><text>That Paul Engelmayer, judge of the United States District Court for the Southern District of New York is impeached for high crimes and misdemeanors and that the following articles of impeachment be exhibited to the United States Senate:</text><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAD0283BFF97F4D0086CCB6F0B7364305"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Articles of impeachment exhibited by the House of Representatives of the United States of America in the name of itself and of the people of the United States of America, against Paul Engelmayer, judge of the United States District Court for the Southern District of New York in maintenance and support of its impeachment against him for high crimes and misdemeanors.</text></subsection></section><section id="HF09DCF7AB2CA43328D8198A267C0D7AF" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum/><header>Article I: Judicial Misconduct and Abuse of Judicial Authority</header><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H306C993B1C8F41BE975B548146FFC4F6"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paul Engelmayer, as a judge of the United States District Court for the Southern District of New York, engaged in judicial misconduct when he halted President Donald J. Trump’s Executive order establishing and implementing the President’s Department of Government Efficiency on purely political grounds, demonstrating clear bias and prejudice against the President and the 74,000,000 Americans who voted for him.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9CB5275E285242709E0CD3BE6B0DB389"><enum/><text>Paul Engelmayer has acted outside the bounds of judicial propriety, including—</text><paragraph id="H97396A12071D4B7C806C77BBA9FA1210"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by submitting this ruling that demonstrates clear bias and prejudice against the President; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6D30F643D26463490767BC0766BDD5A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by willfully disregarding established legal precedent in the issuance of rulings, by submitting this injunction in the middle of the night, which may have been done with the intent to influence the outcome of cases to favor certain parties.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H85BF9B4744884625B4C48F965D47D242"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wherefore, Judge Paul Engelmayer is guilty of high crimes and misdemeanors and should be removed from office. </text></subsection></section><section id="HB6545766F6BD4A80A7A43853AAF7C12A" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum/><header>Article II: Abuse of Judicial Power</header><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4688764C80764107BAC27E1DFFBE116E"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Judge Paul Engelmayer has abused his judicial office by using his authority to further personal or political interests, contrary to the constitutional responsibility to apply the law impartially, including the improper handling of this case in a manner that demonstrates favoritism or undue influence, undermining the fundamental principles of justice.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8D19F1030EAE4DB7B4BE9CBD34237013"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wherefore, Judge Paul Engelmayer is guilty of high crimes and misdemeanors and should be removed from office. </text></subsection></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

