<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE7730FDE282C43BBA0D90500C545FC48" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4672 IH: To extend the break-in-service consideration for firefighter retirements, and other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4672</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. Scott Franklin of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To extend the break-in-service consideration for firefighter retirements, and other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4375EFCFEFED458092598B806C311774" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H234B549C91274870BA9AE4386AEF75DF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Continuing accrual of service for firefighters</header>
<subsection id="HFDE6F1DF62414FFE8491AF86F727BD78"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal employees’ retirement system</header><text>Section 8401(14) of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HFAF8CA317E394E00ADCE2EC7EC3AA8FD" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H138ECBADA32B49489110F4B3BED9A18F"><enum>(14)</enum><text>the term <term>firefighter</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H9D3E422B35F64571830AEC339AA60CA6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an employee, the duties of whose position—</text> <clause id="HB861090128FC43D99B559F940B1863B9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are primarily to perform work directly connected with the control and extinguishment of nonwildland fires; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H43AD7EE490A247188B359E9F475ECF9C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are sufficiently rigorous that employment opportunities should be limited to young and physically vigorous individuals, as determined by the Director considering the recommendations of the employing agency;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H70FC7612073242438D51D86035E7EA6E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an employee, the duties of whose position—</text>
<clause id="H537DA682B6F641ED89910A62A724BD01"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are primarily to perform work directly connected with the control and extinguishment of wildland fires; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB5548F10E22C411BB2013C3ED950E327"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are sufficiently rigorous that employment opportunities should be limited to young and physically vigorous individuals, as determined by the Director considering the recommendations of the employing agency;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H339A98817B484865957CC5A5F1CBC5F4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an employee who—</text> <clause id="H1417C7C8E4B34ECF9C1679830177D854"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is transferred directly to a supervisory or administrative position after performing duties described in subparagraph (A) for at least 3 years; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HFF146B2F9A2F496B819D33C81F7FCAEF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>while serving in such supervisory or administrative position, has no break in service; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H23BDD871AB1E4A6181F95B45159E8107"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an employee who—</text>
<clause id="H54AF874FD11842069B8C840DD0A684B9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>occupies a supervisory or administrative position after performing duties described in subparagraph (B) for not less than 3 years; and</text></clause> <clause id="HCADA2AB835EB4070818FCE865E71C2AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has not more than 24 months in total time of breaks in service;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H6F7761AE481F4EE5AA2C067BCC3ED065"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Service before date of enactment</header>
<paragraph id="HA58F5195DE6C4D049DFBF66E0EF36993"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the requirements under paragraph (2), service performed before the date of enactment of this Act by an individual who, on the date of enactment of this Act, is an employee (as defined in section 8401(11) of title 5, United States Code) shall, for the purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/84">chapter 84</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, be treated as service performed by a firefighter if—</text> <subparagraph id="H6DBB95B84D1245069865A31B7BB5996A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such service was performed during the period beginning on October 1, 2003, and ending on the day before the date of enactment of this Act;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6AF7FB1E4EB145758FFF50D5DCBCCD1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at the time of performing such service—</text> <clause id="H8232EA20FEF64D6495618336E055547D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the individual did not meet the requirements to be a firefighter under section 8401(14) of title 5, United States Code, because of a break in service; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HD1A2E339337A41EB86209BF3076DD352"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>would have met the requirements to be a firefighter under section 8401(14)(D) of title 5, United States Code, as amended by this Act; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5FCD5DF303BE48DFB75B47738D34632E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>appropriate deductions and withholdings under sections 8422 and 8423 of title 5, United States Code, were made during such service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1A12407B590D4A73826F0428A387EC94"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Credit for service</header><text>To receive credit for eligible service under paragraph (1), the applicable individual shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HD574FC63B5E246E58FF23B3CC7779734"><enum>(A)</enum><text>before the date on which the individual separates from service in the agency in which the individual holds a position on the date of enactment of this Act, submit a written election to the agency employing the individual;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF458130FE0674BF7B75BC49F789564CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the individual is not employed by the agency that employed the individual when the service described in paragraph (1) was performed, submit a written election to such agency; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H67626F9AD0984791ADAC8C5D15D4E693"><enum>(C)</enum><text>remit to the agency that employed the individual when such service was performed the additional amount that would have been deducted during the period of prior service under section 8422 of title 5, United States Code, from the pay of the individual if the amendments made by subsection (a) had been in effect during the prior service, plus any applicable interest computed under section 8334(e) of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDA9E3BCE7FA940D2BCCDD353EE569D8E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Government contributions</header><text>If an individual remits payment under paragraph (2)(C) with respect to service described in paragraph (1), the agency that employed the individual when such service was performed shall remit to the Office of Personnel Management (for deposit in the Treasury of the United States to the credit of the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund) the total additional amount of Federal contributions that would have been paid under section 8423 of title 5, United States Code, if the amendments made by subsection (a) had been in effect during the prior service, plus any applicable interest computed in accordance with section 8334(e) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC09E230922F4682851A4F8D5E8E0D83"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notification and assistance requirements</header><text>The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H082DF008766A43788BE63C5C36EBCA87"><enum>(A)</enum><text>take such action as may be necessary and appropriate to inform individuals entitled to have any service credited under this subsection, or to have any annuity computed under this subsection, of the entitlement to the credit or computation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB983B7F1A2A746A2B7FEA68165610BFB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon request, assist any individual described in subparagraph (A) in obtaining such information in the possession of the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of the Interior, as applicable, as may be necessary to verify the entitlement of the individual to have any service credited, or to have any annuity computed, pursuant to this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H70C23D45659943E194AD979F0B72CE55"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit or require the making of any contribution to the Thrift Savings Fund that would not otherwise have been permitted or required but for the enactment of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

