<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H367B978EE6404EF182A123E79C3483BF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 984 IH: To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide timely equitable relief to an individual who suffers a loss based on an administrative error by the Secretary, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 984</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250205">February 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide timely equitable relief to an individual who suffers a loss based on an administrative error by the Secretary, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H04E72EF1D6EE4E6CAD6B74AD8F13CEC6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFA3613AFAFE24B21984F05EB6B4E13B4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Improvements to equitable relief in the case of an administrative error by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header> 
<subsection id="H0339E393F3D349DBB1DC34E0623D7C06"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Affirmative duty To provide timely equitable relief</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 503 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>may</quote> both places it appears and inserting <quote>shall, not later than 120 days after such determination,</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF073BDFABAD747508F55987E2465752D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cancellation of debt collection</header><text>Section 5314 of such title is amended, in subsection (a), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HCD43D26A332E40FA96172B562CDFDAC3" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H929E8B92BA244A9B9219B781804F7DC2" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall promptly cancel any agreement, entered into by the Secretary with a debt collector (as defined in section 803 of the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1692a">15 U.S.C. 1692a</external-xref>)) to collect an amount of indebtedness described in paragraph (1), if the Secretary determines that the determination of such indebtedness was in error.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

