<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25H46-L1F-2K-YPK">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2934 IS: Protecting Americans from Russian Litigation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2934</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250929">September 29, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on
                    the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To limit the availability of civil actions affected by United States
            sanctions.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="idaa957e97b04a49d5aa9706d03bb39509" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Americans from Russian Litigation Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5264cd3c6f1d4c2ea386d6574b05fa68">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Statement of policy</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text> <paragraph id="idba08562bc639417c9a8aafbf8cca074e"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>to ensure that United States persons are not disadvantaged for actions or omissions undertaken to comply with United States sanctions or export controls; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id5c15f0f6d8cd41ed9ae18e8225ee8c61">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>to ensure that foreign persons, or persons acting on their behalf, cannot obtain compensation for any action related to United States persons attempting in good faith to comply with their obligations under United States sanctions or export controls.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd8135726157449c196e8866612cbeae6">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Limitation on civil actions affected by
                United States sanctions</header>
            <subsection id="id5cf00bff2dfa412683ecd3a394f28b8a">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/111">Chapter 111</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
                <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a5f60603a044425a25f9ab1dabb50bc">
                    <section id="idfc7c41ebc4c3467dac3350f15c362039">
                        <enum>1660.</enum>
                        <header>Limitation on civil actions affected by United States
                            sanctions</header>
                        <subsection id="id8a6f643668e74848b15f91254b08bac9">
                            <enum>(a)</enum>
                            <header>Limitation</header>
 <text>Notwithstanding any provision of law, no person (other than the United States or a person acting on behalf of the United States) may bring a civil action in Federal or State court to enforce any foreign judgment or foreign arbitral award arising from a claim where—</text>
                            <paragraph id="id03bba06384a045d39f2ffd17fd42f4d0">
                                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the underlying conduct or circumstances giving rise to the claim resulted from actions to comply with United States sanctions impeding the performance of a contract; or</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="id00d1040d8ed14520bc6c5c6be6b9f36c">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the court or tribunal issuing the judgment or arbitral award asserted jurisdiction based, in whole or in part, on the imposition of United States sanctions or export controls (or any foreign law enacted in response to the imposition of United States sanctions or export controls).</text>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="id319d4221851744e3a3e007b920f519dd">
                            <enum>(b)</enum>
                            <header>Removal and dismissal</header>
 <text>An action to recognize or enforce a foreign judgment or foreign arbitral award described in subsection (a) may be removed by any defendant to the appropriate United States district court, which shall dismiss the action.</text>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="id41ee877ec6664ed2b20d7ea07a7bf8aa">
                            <enum>(c)</enum>
                            <header>Rule of construction</header>
 <text>Nothing in this section may be construed to limit—</text> <paragraph id="idc238deb0ce2a4dbf88da49bb38afd0aa"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>the authority of the President, any delegate of the President (including the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury), or any other officer or official of the United States to bring any action or exercise any responsibility under any applicable State or Federal law; </text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="idb69e73b927034acab93159792f3907f6">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>any right, remedy, or cause of action available to a victim of international terrorism, torture, extrajudicial killing, aircraft sabotage, or hostage taking, who is, or was at the time of the victim’s injury, a national of the United States, a member of the United States Armed Forces, an employee of the United States Government, or an individual performing a contract awarded by the United States Government acting within the scope of the individual's employment, or a family member of any such victim, under any applicable State or Federal law, including—</text>
                                <subparagraph id="idf76d608c9ae442038978a4532209f9f4">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>chapter 97 of this title;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id8d2de4b7d9a54f739391623df2c7636d"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/113B">chapter 113B</external-xref> of title 18; and</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="id1c471f2eba29402091f723ff6b4d5485">
                                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8701">22 U.S.C. 8701 et seq.</external-xref>) and any other laws providing for the application of sanctions with respect to Iran or Syria; </text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="id0d1ea2f45ced4e248bdd855e41abc153">
                                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>any right, remedy, or cause of action available to any party arising under or relating to the party’s contractual rights (other than an action to enforce a foreign judgment or foreign arbitral award described in subsection (a)) where the parties agreed to resolve all disputes by litigation in a State or Federal court within the United States or by arbitration within the United States; or</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="id135b0ff3f6b648098d38cf9f3b2b69ac">
                                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>any other right, remedy, or cause of action available to any party arising under State or Federal law (other than an action to enforce a foreign judgment or foreign arbitral award described in subsection (a)) where the underlying conduct or circumstances giving rise to the claim resulted from the imposition of United States sanctions or export controls.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="ide08cec62834840788b043270fe9efb4b">
                            <enum>(d)</enum>
                            <header>United states sanctions defined</header>
 <text>In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id50cf2a98944740b4ac7745002bdf42b4"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>United States sanctions</term> means any prohibition, restriction, or condition on transactions involving any property in which any foreign country or national thereof has any interest that is imposed by the United States to address threats to the national security, foreign policy, or economy of the United States pursuant to—</text>
                                <subparagraph id="idbc2ae4b246a54f82a9138a82cabef3ae">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>section 203 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1702">50 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref>); or</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="idf7b357aee86245589dd837ad7bc2380a">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>any other provision of law, including any provision of law relating to export controls.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide76a934fbe0e45ee808088f2054140e4">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
                                <header>Duties</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>United States sanctions</term> does not include the imposition of a duty on the importation of goods.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection>
                    </section>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idb38ada2181044d4280262f5892df874e">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Clerical amendment</header>
 <text>The table of sections for such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1659 the following new item:</text>
                <quoted-block style="USC" id="id5b0f8b39-73a0-4838-b212-5126df03219e">
                    <toc>
                        <toc-entry level="section">1660. Limitation on civil actions affected by
                            United States sanctions.</toc-entry>
                    </toc>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idb5fa4ce9b01d4c6fa48571c8192af397">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Application</header>
 <text>Section 1660 of title 28, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), applies with respect to civil actions pending on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

