<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-joint" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-DAV25L14-L82-7F-3LP">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SJ 90 IS: To direct the removal of United States Armed Forces from hostilities within or against Venezuela that have not been authorized by Congress.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>IIA</distribution-code>
        <congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. J. RES. 90</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action display="yes">
            <action-date date="20251016">October 16, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr.
                    Schiff</cosponsor>) introduced the following joint resolution; which was read
                twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign
                    Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
        <official-title display="yes">To direct the removal of United States Armed Forces from
            hostilities within or against Venezuela that have not been authorized by
            Congress.</official-title>
    </form>
    <resolution-body>
        <section id="id2d935a4cb65640d399efb68dff614409" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Findings</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="id2ffc5d22255f45ceb77a9b3ea5f9990d"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>Congress has the sole power to declare war under article I, section 8, clause 11 of the United States Constitution.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id70b05b36d31044c7a2a419a6faf9dd09">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Congress has not yet declared war upon Venezuela or any person or organization within Venezuela, nor enacted a specific statutory authorization for use of military force within or against Venezuela.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id6474c2a3c0c64b369380a4aeb9bbb864">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>United States Armed Forces actions within or against Venezuela, within the meaning of section 4(a) of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1543">50 U.S.C. 1543(a)</external-xref>), are either hostilities or a situation where imminent involvement in hostilities is clearly indicated by the circumstances into which United States Armed Forces have been introduced.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id2b0306da4af04342b74dfe5f982e4bfb">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>The publicly reported authorization for the Central Intelligence Agency to conduct covert lethal operations within Venezuela, the significant augmentation of United States Armed Forces assets, personnel, and operations in proximity to Venezuela, and statements from United States Government officials regarding planning for ground strikes within Venezuela indicate imminent involvement of United States Armed Forces in hostilities within or against Venezuela.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id8f26e4a92aff4fcebc81424137770cb0">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>The question of whether United States forces should be engaged in hostilities within or against Venezuela should be answered following a full briefing to Congress and the American public of the issues at stake, a public debate in Congress, and a congressional vote as contemplated by the Constitution.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id29335d508004462b89c8b6f88b2412a2">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>Section 1013 of the Department of State Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1984 and 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1546a">50 U.S.C. 1546a</external-xref>) provides that any joint resolution or bill to require the removal of United States Armed Forces from imminent engagement in hostilities without a declaration of war or specific statutory authorization shall be considered in accordance with the expedited procedures of section 601(b) of the International Security and Arms Export Control Act of 1976.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="idf8674cd4b3814eb1a2fb91f217a1389a">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Termination of the use of United States forces for hostilities within or against
                Venezuela</header>
            <subsection id="idd2ed567485644aedab5f0a5c1a919bc5">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Termination</header>
 <text>Pursuant to section 1013 of the Department of State Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1984 and 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1546a">50 U.S.C. 1546a</external-xref>), and in accordance with the provisions of section 601(b) of the International Security Assistance and Arms Export Control Act of 1976, Congress hereby directs the President to terminate the use of United States Armed Forces for hostilities within or against Venezuela, unless explicitly authorized by a declaration of war or specific authorization for use of military force.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id409c945e6bc240078c8dcbac9359cf1d">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Rule of construction</header>
 <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent the United States from defending itself from an armed attack or threat of an imminent armed attack.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </resolution-body>
</resolution>

