<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8193C01465454C65A897EEB830AC1387" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 978 IH: Superior National Forest Restoration Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 978</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250205">February 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000470">Mrs. Fischbach</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001323">Mr. Begich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001228">Ms. Maloy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To rescind Public Land Order 7917, to reinstate mineral leases and permits in the Superior National Forest, to ensure timely review of Mine Plans of Operations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1E348072A1FA4F419D3A8AA45026A62F" style="OLC"><section id="HEE46EF4B06914917BF15C7D362673A60" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Superior National Forest Restoration Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2687486EF29546CE8E8E6940DFB5389B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Superior National Forest System Lands in Minnesota</header><subsection id="HF1A4857620F04CA590F802B45E0894F0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rescission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The order titled <quote>Public Land Order No. 7917 for Withdrawal of Federal Lands; Cook, Lake, and Saint Louis Counties, MN</quote>, issued by the Bureau of Land Management and dated January 31, 2023, is hereby rescinded.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4349EF49C032401D948142937EE0CA8F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timely review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall complete all necessary environmental and regulatory reviews, including processes subject to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>), for all Mine Plans of Operations within the Superior National Forest lands in the State of Minnesota—</text><paragraph id="H1EF6993CFCBF4C98BC03150C2CE7C3E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a Mine Plan of Operations submitted or resubmitted in the 10-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this section, not later than 18 months after the date on which such Mine Plan of Operations is submitted or resubmitted; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8997FC87390D4693BE61E550BD518F0B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a Mine Plan of Operations reviewed pursuant to this section, all necessary supplemental environmental and regulatory reviews shall be reviewed by the Secretary not later than 6 months after the date on which such supplemental Mine Plan of Operations is submitted, and all necessary regulatory and environmental permits shall be issued not later than 6 months after the Mine Plan of Operations is approved.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H04ED2A1E2DBA4D1BA72DCEBFE6C753E8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reissuance of mineral leases</header><paragraph id="H556CE07173204816A01CB1BE3F320B85"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue each mineral lease, preference right lease, and prospecting permit canceled by the Secretary relating to lands within Superior National Forest during the period beginning on January 31, 2021, and ending on the date of the enactment of this section. Such mineral leases, preference right leases, and prospecting permits shall be reissued on the same terms as were in effect on the date of such cancellations, except that—</text><subparagraph id="HF23E83DBB2B5474DB9EE2174504C506D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prospecting permits shall be reissued with their original terms and conditions as established upon initial issuance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF304979C4A464E63997265BEB73C5912"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all mineral leases and preference right leases shall be modified to—</text><clause id="H1FD26E03BFE14452A8A04D16C03D770F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an initial term of 20 years beginning on the date of the enactment of this section;</text></clause><clause id="H8091CC0F42704E86A881A1366614396C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a nondiscretionary right to renewal for 5 subsequent 10-year terms; and</text></clause><clause id="H96CD8F5D75654BC28D001F7A00C46D9B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a right to make reasonable adjustments of the rental and royalty terms at renewal.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H004A3137268745EB9B23CEA6D5975FBE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A lease or permit issued under paragraph (1) is not subject to judicial review.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5B94FAFC5A4C4BBA8B76D2D321F392B3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Issuance of new preference right leases</header><paragraph id="H36C9056F16D8497E84626D724B9CC68C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, not later than 5 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall grant preference right leases for any preference right lease applications that were rejected after January 31, 2021, and prior to the date of the enactment of this section and have received a notice of preliminary valuable deposit determination.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5D165EE375345D5B28B938D1CD09651"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Lease terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such preference right leases shall be issued with terms consistent with subsection (c)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE024D14BD7E44748805704ED8D6FF858"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Permits for use of surface lands</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to lands subject to a lease pursuant to subsection (d), the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, may issue permits for the use of surface lands not included in the lease for purposes connected with, and reasonably necessary to, the exploration, development, and use of the deposits covered by the lease.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4EA3EFDC01C9410CBCBF7BD27EF2C523"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Secretary defined</header><text>For the purposes of this section, the term <term>Secretary</term> means—</text><paragraph id="HDA1585A4620441AAA44FD48DE6AD930C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28E7E126925844BAAEC2063FA3C04F6A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>when used with respect to any unit of the National Forest System, the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

