<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBD44C1ECF28C4478B8C92BF496D39ECC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1939 IH: U.S. Engagement in Sudanese Peace Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1939</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250306">March 6, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To require the imposition of sanctions with respect to conflict in Sudan, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H13C642701F124565A0BB19687F2BCEBF" style="OLC">
<section id="H847BD6B361BA4B25B47265E1B1CA63FC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title and table of contents</header>
<subsection id="H348740E60C854EF0B63DEC25D1E83272"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>U.S. Engagement in Sudanese Peace Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3A108E0FAC23428B9EAE0D1A835362B8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows: </text>
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded">
<toc-entry idref="H847BD6B361BA4B25B47265E1B1CA63FC" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title and table of contents.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HFE2B0518402B42D199D9865641CD9116" level="section">Sec. 2. Statement of policy.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HC6EE8AE3231E4D4990F1226525142C14" level="section">Sec. 3. Sense of Congress.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H90927149301442CB8AE745751625290B" level="title">Title I—Sanctions authorities</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H08C8A0DCE63C44F69B22AAF8E29AF11C" level="section">Sec. 101. Report on international crimes and blocking humanitarian aid.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HC57C3B6741C34A09B36250D18BAB2C73" level="section">Sec. 102. Report on foreign entities violating the United Nations arms embargo on Darfur.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HF450F8FF64E14DC5BBE7DC2421B8C618" level="section">Sec. 103. Sanctions required.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H3B6FA32F3A3441FBB4D4ED460EA7C278" level="section">Sec. 104. Termination of sanctions.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H42A4367D82B143E7B2F59A923B56DA2C" level="section">Sec. 105. Definitions.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HECCC88CE94D74233B6A93AF71F4E8D2F" level="title">Title II—Other provisions</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H33D7E593E0FB49E0B114A053501D0870" level="section">Sec. 201. Strategy.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HA9D0E53B85574E7282538990FE150D13" level="section">Sec. 202. Special Envoy for Sudan.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HFB28A7D25C5049478BDC21C0E6780CA3" level="section">Sec. 203. Use of United States influence at the United Nations.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HC931D50AACE245C1AE13462522A5DB39" level="section">Sec. 204. Assistance to deploy and sustain a United Nations, African Union, or multinational force.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H58A38AB4EC9F4BD0A655215C1FF358D5" level="section">Sec. 205. Empowering Sudanese women and youth.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H5F80E4A7384F45209B49C440C358CA08" level="section">Sec. 206. Prohibition on sale and licensing of major defense equipment.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H1B0F2D58122345BCBD7573C872B0D0EC" level="section">Sec. 207. Certification and report on non-restriction of United States humanitarian assistance in Sudan.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HCA9B2A74B65649E98EB973D1EBF986AE" level="section">Sec. 208. Report on United States weapons being used in Sudan.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section>
<section id="HFE2B0518402B42D199D9865641CD9116"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text> <paragraph id="HFFC37151F6C84A5AB1CE23E6FBC39292"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to support an inclusive diplomatic process, that meaningfully includes women and youth leaders, and marginalized communities, to establish a cease fire and a sustainable peace agreement in Sudan;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2EBD7D6130184984A9D669DFF3E3F957"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to support justice and accountability for violations of international humanitarian law, genocide, war crimes, crimes against humanity, and other serious human rights abuses by armed actors in Sudan, especially those involved in the conflict that began on April 15, 2023, those who perpetrated the October 25, 2021, coup d’etat, and those who committed human rights abuses during and in the wake of the state of emergency declared by the military junta after the October 25, 2021, coup d’etat; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE676DBFD5D5042ABBA17C67A27258945"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to pursue a strategy on Sudan that includes—</text>
<subparagraph id="HA2EC1F06E023464799582E7A215ABB4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">leading and coordinating international efforts to establish and facilitate a comprehensive and inclusive peace process that meaningfully includes civil society and seeks a sustainable end to the country’s conflicts;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4935E3F97F694B22AAB128E318E8B88F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitating unrestricted delivery of humanitarian aid throughout Sudan, across military lines and across international borders, including through local grassroots organizations;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA0B6DBF7DCD84527AC7EA7715F7BFC51"><enum>(C)</enum><text>developing and advancing a plan for the prevention of mass atrocities and for protecting civilians;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB6D0615BDA5B48AC8371B865FB56C78E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pursuing survivor-centered justice and accountability for violations of international humanitarian law, genocide, war crimes, crimes against humanity, and other serious human rights abuses, including conflict-related sexual and gender-based violence; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H05DDB575C8AD4CAD9B9F168622CCA5D7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>supporting an inclusive dialogue aimed at establishing a civilian-led transition to democracy, including by promoting mechanisms that ensure the meaningful leadership and inclusion of women, youth, and traditionally marginalized communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="HC6EE8AE3231E4D4990F1226525142C14"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text>
<paragraph id="H9BB6836442F04F27BE2FDE8E7342C865"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretary of the Treasury, should—</text> <subparagraph id="H15FDF6FE67C94C20B6F9059C8451D691"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sanction the leadership of the Rapid Support Forces (RSF) and the Sudanese Armed Forces (SAF) responsible for strategic decisions that have directed or enabled the commission of atrocities, including genocide, war crimes, and crimes against humanity;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA70291B3AF364DA79CD6C2CF1A50BED8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sanction adult family members of those in the leadership of the RSF and SAF unless such family member has condemned the sanctionable activity and taken tangible steps to oppose the activity; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H500C7F08E551429AA4E03170B515986D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>designate the RSF for sanctions;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCF45DBE7755A4A78A6B25A167128F489"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United Nations should expand its arms embargo to all of Sudan;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H13FDFEB92B06450FBD4BACDFE78F6382"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United Nations assessed contributions should be used pursuant to United Nations Security Council Resolution 2719 (2023) to fund an African Union force to protect civilians, support ceasefire monitoring, or secure humanitarian operations in Sudan if such a force is authorized; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8F4D5B6C14244F9FACDF0F79DD58FA92"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Department of State and United States Agency for International Development should develop a plan to facilitate greater funding to emergency response rooms and other local mutual aid organizations providing humanitarian assistance in Sudan, including use of market-based assistance.</text></paragraph></section> <title id="H90927149301442CB8AE745751625290B"><enum>I</enum><header>Sanctions authorities</header> <section id="H08C8A0DCE63C44F69B22AAF8E29AF11C"><enum>101.</enum><header>Report on international crimes and blocking humanitarian aid</header> <subsection id="H15C00DEA9C2E4F7F9189D08F988B684A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that identifies each foreign person that has knowingly engaged in any of the following conduct in Sudan since April 2023: </text>
<paragraph id="H072EFD6CE4BE486F85A36DB5CBA0BA88"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Perpetrating, directing, or enabling the commission of genocide, war crimes, or crimes against humanity against civilians.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H22915E828AB6400E9646EC80CA3DEEA1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Systematic blocking of and interference with the delivery of humanitarian aid to civilians.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H44222452AD3946BAA5ADF9DE19345303"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Update</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an update of the report required by subsection (a) for each of the 5 calendar years following the calendar year in which the initial report is submitted.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HC57C3B6741C34A09B36250D18BAB2C73"><enum>102.</enum><header>Report on foreign entities violating the United Nations arms embargo on Darfur</header> <subsection id="HAE5E9BDEDC4A4DE3B822642606DFB529"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that identifies each foreign person determined to be violating the United Nations arms embargo on Darfur imposed pursuant to United Nations Security Council Resolutions 1556 (July 30, 2004) and 1591 (March 29, 2005).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H7189F1A5FDAE4BC0A7469C959D842B62"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Update</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an update of the report required by subsection (a) for each of the 5 calendar years following the calendar year in which the initial report is submitted.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HF450F8FF64E14DC5BBE7DC2421B8C618"><enum>103.</enum><header>Sanctions required</header> <subsection id="HD7281FC173F14729B7ECB542773822AA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the President—</text>
<paragraph id="H1BB938CC31664872A00E84F953869054"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submits the report or update to the report required by section 101, the President shall impose 6 or more of the sanctions described in paragraphs (1) through (7) of subsection (b) on each foreign person identified in the report; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF7094EEC74B840088CABCAB9DCF9043E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submits the report or update to the report required by section 102, the President shall impose 4 or more of the sanctions described in paragraphs (2), (3), (4), (6), and (7) of subsection (b) on each foreign person identified in the report.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H1CA74FCF8C9B4D8F9DA8A12BC180B3F1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text> <paragraph id="HC69BEB7B7B8C4E92B8A97F6C48A03CBD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>), block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of the foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDCA90C7C85E84B4AA27BEDCD6D7C6F82"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Export-import bank assistance for exports to sanctioned persons</header><text>The President shall direct the Export-Import Bank of the United States not to give approval to the issuance of any guarantee, insurance, extension of credit, or participation in the extension of credit in connection with the export of any goods or services to the foreign person. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCAE6CAAB2D2B4EDA98B7D74EDE3C328C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Loans from United States financial institutions</header><text>The President shall prohibit any United States financial institution from making loans or providing credits to the foreign person totaling more than $10,000,000 in any 12-month period unless the person is primarily engaged in activities to relieve human suffering and the loans or credits are provided for such activities.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7023F1FDF4024B03B67EC219353D80B4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Loans from international financial institutions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall direct the United States executive director to each international financial institution to use the voice and vote of the United States to oppose any loan from the international financial institution that would benefit the foreign person.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H097D4A4CA6B249E984789D90D8D57824" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Loans from the International Development Finance Corporation and the United States Trade and Development Agency</header><text>The President shall direct the Chief Executive Officer of the United States International Development Finance Corporation and the Director of the United States Trade and Development Agency to prohibit any loan, loan guarantee, equity investment, project assistance, or any other type of support to a listed foreign person.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDAA8FEA7DCEB44B9B2065C5114CCF4DD"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Procurement sanction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Government may not procure, or enter into any contract for the procurement of, any goods or services from the foreign person. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H40940BF8BE38492488C078B374DA62FD"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Exclusion of foreign individuals</header> <subparagraph id="H34FDDD03F04445CAB38F071A209FED6E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall direct the Secretary of State to deny a visa to, and the Secretary of Homeland Security to exclude from the United States, any individual identified in the report required by subsection (a). </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1783A255DA694845AF98ED9A039E50A2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien who the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) knows, or has reason to believe, is described in subparagraph (A) is—</text> <clause id="H4D6E7B75111B44A3820BD1BA0542301E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States; </text></clause>
<clause id="H4941FC4266C848549F6D8BC67A2C4EB1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible for a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause> <clause id="HBF38BA1A09F446FBAD7C023E2D2E3D32"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>). </text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA14729008B914CB0BCAAF021D190591F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header>
<clause id="H94300EFD0514470FA8D958FAF372A457"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The issuing consular officer, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) shall, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>), revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to an alien described in subparagraph (A) regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is issued.</text></clause> <clause id="H6F9294393A6E4F35897E910E5002C7F4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A revocation under clause (i)—</text>
<subclause id="H39F742D1004144E199ABA46608E82A0A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall take effect immediately; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HAAA72461DABF4F3A949D3A46195401AA"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H1EA52C5F03CE4C39BCFA44C7320C1DF0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header>
<paragraph id="HBDEE54379F0D44DEA40D233F8F07AF6F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exception to comply with international obligations</header><text>Sanctions under subsection (b)(7) shall not apply with respect to the admission of an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5ECC09D295CA4E25AE228E916E6A1308"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception relating to the provision of humanitarian assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sanctions under this section may not be imposed with respect to transactions or the facilitation of transactions for—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1BC5E766D5164ED0B47CA6E03AF65D12"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the sale of agricultural commodities, food, medicine, or medical devices;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D1A7639AE7747C5814AA680EC90FA9A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the provision of humanitarian assistance;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE32A2966D40C458DB47E14C742025EE6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>financial transactions relating to humanitarian assistance; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD9EDC1068AD647609E9450A4F9B4755B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>transporting goods or services that are necessary to carry out operations relating to humanitarian assistance. </text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBEBCF7DC1A2943E9B410C09FD0FBB442"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception for intelligence, law enforcement, and national security activities</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply to any authorized intelligence, law enforcement, or national security activities of the United States. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDDA8E146ACA4A859E13412F529DEC62"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Classified information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any judicial review of a determination made under this section, if the determination was based on classified information (as defined in section 1(a) of the Classified Information Procedures Act) such information may be submitted to the reviewing court ex parte and in camera. This paragraph does not confer or imply any right to judicial review. </text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9C349FBE11F44B42AA50A2513F8B3123"><enum>(d)</enum><header>National interest waiver</header><text>The President may waive the imposition of sanctions under subsection (b) with respect to a person if the President—</text> <paragraph id="H6E872A0471B94FD0968142E1B286FFD6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determines that such a waiver is vital to the national interests of the United States; and </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H001A6F27948641D8B1898C2B9EC6857F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not more than 15 days after issuing the waiver, submits to the appropriate congressional committees a notification of the waiver and the reasons for the waiver. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H3B6FA32F3A3441FBB4D4ED460EA7C278" commented="no"><enum>104.</enum><header>Termination of sanctions</header> <subsection id="H86BF95975F194725B66868C391799D4F" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), the President may terminate the application of sanctions under this section with respect to a person if the President determines and reports to the appropriate congressional committees not later than 15 days before the termination of the sanctions that—</text>
<paragraph id="H95EC02FAB56348E6B148C9F07412B3E7" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>credible information exists that the person did not engage in the activity for which sanctions were imposed;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06EAB9FA9F9A462BBE8E9FFB10045230" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the person has credibly demonstrated a significant change in behavior, has paid an appropriate consequence for the activity for which sanctions were imposed, and has credibly committed to not engage in an activity described in subsection (a) in the future; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H24A0EEEA344D428690F54363CD656E98" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the termination of the sanctions is in the vital national interests of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H27C71C0B68374B17BC1BCB3E683CB86F" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions relating to blocking the provision of humanitarian aid to civilians</header><text>The authority to impose sanctions under section 101(3) shall terminate if a comprehensive agreement to end the conflict is reached and implemented between the warring parties in Sudan. </text></subsection></section>
<section id="H42A4367D82B143E7B2F59A923B56DA2C"><enum>105.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title—</text> <paragraph id="H420FDAF0285041DE962EF8FCA90E1B13"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H9D3803DEE4644503AEF45EE48303DBE4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8D294252389A4E13B8FE27AF3C69B299"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF6DE355293864182BEC03EDAF56D2744"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>foreign person</term> means an individual or entity that is not a United States person; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE457701BC62140728EB10B1172BE9A3F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>United States person</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="HF262105C8EF2417C943EEBAA6D176C28"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H51F2CB9C2BDB4D20895F28A32043B869"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a permanent resident alien of the United States; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB8A3CAD3A29E4B57B7855DF5E57B5DAF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></title> <title id="HECCC88CE94D74233B6A93AF71F4E8D2F"><enum>II</enum><header>Other provisions</header> <section id="H33D7E593E0FB49E0B114A053501D0870"><enum>201.</enum><header>Strategy</header> <subsection id="HF264C01545CD4F1F8A377A8C375619C6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a strategy to support the protection of civilians, the delivery of humanitarian assistance, and progress towards a sustainable peace in Sudan that includes—</text>
<paragraph id="H9EAAA847900F436A8F765446CABE7ABA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>plans for establishing and leading a diplomatic mechanism for negotiations that lead to a comprehensive ceasefire and a sustainable peace;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H05595429D8384117AE583A99C4AAAE17"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">actions in multilateral fora and with regional institutions in support of protection of civilians, sustained and unimpeded humanitarian access, enforcement of the United Nations arms embargo and the expansion of the United Nations arms embargo to include all of Sudan;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H204CA12C991D4E1F989FDB44548F8A13"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">plans to support an inclusive civilian political dialogue, including activities to improve and increase women’s and youth’s meaningful leadership and participation in political negotiations, related to the development of a constitutional framework and a pathway that will lead to civilian rule;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5EC9F7CF45FE4FA4A635F0B16F8863B7"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to support grassroots organizations that are currently providing humanitarian and peacebuilding assistance to the Sudanese people in conflict-affected areas that traditional implementing partners cannot reach, including through the development of mechanisms through which to fund organizations and the facilitation of electronic means and other technology enabling communication;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC4D8C1D5324E401780151A3726AC49A0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>efforts to provide training and other support for doctors, lawyers, and other human rights defenders, as well as those working at the grassroots providing humanitarian assistance, on activities undertaken to—</text> <subparagraph id="H9CC5C41C6BCD467882222BBB16973896"><enum>(A)</enum><text>support accountability for human rights abuses, including gathering witness testimony and preservation of forensic evidence; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA8B8847573A0454CBB2F24BD26176D85"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide psychosocial support for Sudanese civilians who experienced violence, particularly victims of conflict related sexual and gender-based violence;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE26752BB53894B119B0F85CAAD7E5213"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a comprehensive sanctions strategy focused on deterring genocide, war crimes and crimes against humanity, ending hostilities, and supporting accountability by—</text>
<subparagraph id="HA91716A35D2B4F699674BB10E26CFE76"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">targeting actors, both within Sudan and internationally, who are responsible for gross violations of human rights and international humanitarian law and whose actions enable those responsible for such violations; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB1DD7E2F059C42ED84DE94DC98A9B43E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">targeting actors providing arms, material, and financial support to the Rapid Support Forces (RSF) and the Sudanese Armed Forces (SAF) or individuals belonging to or affiliated with these individuals; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB5C1815593244823A36FE4319FC85448"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification of countries supporting the RSF or SAF through provision of materiel or other resources or equipment.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H059F6F04BB1A4B18B4EFBBA8483A7273"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the strategy required by subsection (a) is submitted to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, and every 180 days thereafter for 4 years, the Secretary of State shall submit to such committees a report on implementation of the strategy that includes substantive updates of the matters described in paragraphs (1) through (5) of subsection (a).</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HA9D0E53B85574E7282538990FE150D13"><enum>202.</enum><header>Special Envoy for Sudan</header>
<subsection id="H6643184F77904C0FB46AC5792D45212E" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7204 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/159">Public Law 118–159</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H9E3C3ED0981F4E97B38A0CABF55DB72D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>with the advice and consent of the Senate</quote> and inserting <quote>consistent with section 1(j) of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2651a">22 U.S.C. 2651a(j)</external-xref>)</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE669BDA17C314AA8B4C5FE181DB099DF" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (d), by striking <quote>shall terminate on the date that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act</quote> and inserting <quote>shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAD1E9D59B4114D0CB06166019C6B6A9D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $4,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029 to carry out the amendments made by subsection (a). </text></subsection></section>
<section id="HFB28A7D25C5049478BDC21C0E6780CA3"><enum>203.</enum><header>Use of United States influence at the United Nations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State and the United States Permanent Representative to the United Nations shall use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States at the United Nations and other multilateral bodies to—</text> <paragraph id="H8A6A698DBDA84A53B7AA9DB0C792F6A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>advocate for unimpeded humanitarian access and an immediate end to bureaucratic impediments to humanitarian assistance in Sudan;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H838B09C201714264BB0C4CF3F03661AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support the documentation of atrocities including possible genocide, war crimes, and crimes against humanity; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0033C90F45284D9F8C01EFC2F47F09CD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure development of plans for protection of civilians in Sudan; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H37E5EF9A37924136849F63E2ED80C0CC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>advocate for an end to hostilities in Sudan.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HC931D50AACE245C1AE13462522A5DB39"><enum>204.</enum><header>Assistance to deploy and sustain a United Nations, African Union, or multinational force</header> <subsection id="HABC715DF66A843F1B5642EC893222DC5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, is authorized to provide assistance to deploy and sustain a United Nations, African Union, or multinational force to advance civilian protection, facilitate humanitarian operations, and monitor any prospective ceasefire in Sudan.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H79BD85F6804443CEA62168539A1D08A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conditions</header>
<paragraph id="HD849D4D5954E489F9DD08D0561880D44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Assistance provided under subsection (a) may not be provided until the force has agreed not to transfer title to, or possession of, any such assistance to anyone not an officer, employee or agent of the force, and not to use or to permit the use of such assistance for any purposes other than those for which such assistance was furnished, unless the consent of the President has first been obtained, and written assurances reflecting all of the forgoing have been obtained from the force by the President.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF024E55D16BE4B14A59387B23236D4AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Congressional notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the President consents to the transfer of such assistance to anyone not an officer, employee, or agent of the force, or agrees to permit the use of such assistance for any purposes other than those for which such assistance was furnished, the President shall immediately notify the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate in accordance with the procedures applicable to reprogramming notifications under section 634A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2394-1">22 U.S.C. 2394–1</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA2FE382C049D4941B4FD284AE0AF2BF3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional civilian protection options</header><text>The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Administrator of USAID, shall engage the United Nations, African Union, and other international, regional, and local stakeholders to develop additional civilian protection options in Sudan, including community-based mechanisms, and international monitoring or observation mechanisms. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H7B2579A445C5426286BC76C8C6ABDD7E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of State, the Director of National Intelligence, and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development are authorized to detail or second staff and to provide other technical assistance to the African Union to analyze conditions and plan for the potential establishment of a multinational civilian protection force in Sudan. </text></subsection></section>
<section id="H58A38AB4EC9F4BD0A655215C1FF358D5"><enum>205.</enum><header>Empowering Sudanese women and youth</header>
<subsection id="H096360D4622F411B98DEC540D9A22699"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sudanese women</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consistent with the Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017, the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, in coordination with heads of other relevant Federal agencies and supported by the U.S. Ambassador-at-Large for Global Women’s Issues, should take all available measures to actively facilitate the safe and meaningful leadership and participation of Sudanese women in—</text> <paragraph id="HD54FECB94DE54B32AFAFF83D9EA987F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all formal and informal conflict prevention and conflict resolution processes to address the conflict in Sudan, as well as post-conflict relief, recovery, justice, accountability, and democratic governance efforts;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5020BCDD01D24993AFABA15788BDDCB4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all gender-based violence prevention, mitigation, and response efforts; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65D8E4B1FD8F49CA9FDA1A29AB54F84F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">planning and delivery of humanitarian relief and protection efforts to promote increased safety and access to humanitarian assistance by women and girls.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HCDFEEEF2657D49CB90B8DF91D011D2D2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sudanese youth</header><text>The Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development should actively facilitate the safe and meaningful leadership and participation of Sudanese youth in—</text> <paragraph id="H4E83C567245545A8BA008171475D53E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all conflict prevention and conflict resolution processes to address the conflict in Sudan, as well as post-conflict relief, recovery, justice, accountability, and democratic governance efforts;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA3A5A0152D1A4CFC9862729092C6836A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all gender-based violence prevention, mitigation, and response efforts; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC5ED91215224548BB4D2DAC230275E6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>planning and delivery of humanitarian relief and protection efforts.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H5F80E4A7384F45209B49C440C358CA08"><enum>206.</enum><header>Prohibition on sale and licensing of major defense equipment</header>
<subsection id="HBEE327EE840F47F4815E49D9083A02E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No sale, export, or transfer of major defense equipment (as such term is defined in section 47(6) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2794">22 U.S.C. 2794(6)</external-xref>) may be provided to any country that the President identifies as supporting the Rapid Support Forces (RSF) or the Sudanese Armed Forces (SAF) pursuant to section 201(7).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8121BF280363468AA340C0A441003756"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the prohibition in subsection (a) on a case-by-case basis if the President—</text>
<paragraph id="H9D836CA1A18C44B380EB59C2972B3FDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determines such a waiver is vital to the national interests of the United States; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FDC622109DE4F4A84D8942E3F7BA050"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not more than 15 days after issuing the waiver, submits to the appropriate congressional committees a notification of the waiver and a detailed description and justification for the utilization of the waiver.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H8207AC2CC02D47CBBFF1BA0839692525"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</text> <paragraph id="H8B0B55F16FE54E138420FC916F9E210C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9C0AD5B7A6134FBB8AC1F975FA361699"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H1B0F2D58122345BCBD7573C872B0D0EC"><enum>207.</enum><header>Certification and report on non-restriction of United States humanitarian assistance in Sudan</header> <subsection id="HAAD0BF91FE784612B35CC1ED81905393"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a certification and report consistent with the requirements of section 620I(a) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 describing and assessing the extent to which any country prohibits or otherwise restricts, directly or indirectly, the transport or delivery of United States humanitarian assistance in Sudan, including any United States Government-supported international efforts to provide such humanitarian assistance. </text></subsection>
<subsection id="H1C6EA324D0E64668B6FEC67100F11D9E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of exception</header><text>The certification and report required by subsection (a) shall include a description of any uses of the exercise of the authority described in section 620I(b) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 and the date such waiver was exercised in the continued provision of assistance to such country.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H70D163B57CFE44FEB070147FB6E6B381"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The certification and report required by subsection (a) shall be provided in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex if submitted separately from the unclassified portion.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HCA9B2A74B65649E98EB973D1EBF986AE"><enum>208.</enum><header>Report on United States weapons being used in Sudan</header>
<subsection id="H73EB1EB43B5B4D27B375DF6420218320"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the Director of National Intelligence, shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate a report on United States-origin weapons or military equipment being used by belligerents in Sudan. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H024E9E24276A409DAFA83F90BABEC372"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The report shall include the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H4F91CB3AA16C42E0A8C870E6328AF739"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of whether United States-origin weapons have been or are currently being used by belligerents in Sudan and by which actors.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38189A5F9CE34DDFB137FA8E9EA55596"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A list of the types of United States-origin weapons identified as having been used by belligerents in Sudan.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H40E304DB618445CFBA0F218F9227C2EE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An analysis of the chain of control for any United States-origin weapons identified as having been used by belligerents in Sudan.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H46B1B3F245B14111BDBF24DDCA90CEC7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A summary of actions already taken or steps necessary to prevent any United States-origin weapons from being used by belligerents in Sudan. </text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9C56610BCE5145F38FF2DAA47318D367"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex if submitted separately from the unclassified portion.</text></subsection></section></title> </legis-body> </bill> 

