<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB7FBB105FF054A0585F10D91D9A53F60" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 947 IH: Non-Recognition of Russian Annexation of Ukrainian Territory Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 947</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250204">February 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the United States Government from recognizing the Russian Federation’s claim of sovereignty over any portion of the sovereign territory of Ukraine, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9537AFBB7D444299AFD4C404B154C6A7" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H8C6584EFFF9C4C50B0762718B1C99799"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Non-Recognition of Russian Annexation of Ukrainian Territory Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC2F7EBB7D24547A0A21EC004F63C1BE4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition against United States recognition of the Russian Federation’s claim of sovereignty over any portion of Ukraine</header><subsection id="H743E7A7A89C84BAEA75F38040438EF77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States not to recognize the Russian Federation’s claim of sovereignty over any portion of the internationally recognized territory of Ukraine, including its airspace and its territorial waters.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC2C852A773E547198353F9BCE03ED927"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with subsection (a), no Federal department or agency may take any action or extend any assistance that implies recognition of the Russian Federation’s claim of sovereignty over any portion of the internationally recognized territory of Ukraine, including its airspace and its territorial waters.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

