<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H903E94C5C3484E17AC7ABC003CC3C0D9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5318 IH: Reducing Antiquated Permitting for Infrastructure Deployment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5318</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250911">September 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide that the deployment of a small personal wireless service facility is not subject to requirements to prepare certain environmental or historical preservation reviews, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0C518FFA80AA49039FD9E1F08BFDE43B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H48DD375B08754516A3BBB6EF4DD06C96" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reducing Antiquated Permitting for Infrastructure Deployment Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RAPID Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H94474A3FE5514E7B84C1A188A5E8D7B5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exemptions for small personal wireless service facilities</header> <subsection id="H0049E15AF84645319202003B9A09A0EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>NEPA exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal authorization with respect to a project to deploy a small personal wireless service facility may not be considered a major Federal action under section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE295D80B36694FFCAA8FEE6505005332"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National Historic Preservation Act exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A project to deploy a small personal wireless service facility may not be considered an undertaking under section 300320 of title 54, United States Code.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H81568C7B1BC04A2BB1EFE2E404A11497"><enum>3.</enum><header>Presumption with respect to certain complete FCC forms</header> <subsection id="H9E44FDDEA69D48E8925169A27164258D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Presumption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an Indian Tribe is shown to have received a complete FCC Form 620 or FCC Form 621 (or any successor form), or can be reasonably expected to have received a complete FCC Form 620 or FCC Form 621 (or any successor form), and has not acted on a request contained in such complete form by the date that is 45 days after the date of such receipt or reasonably expected receipt—</text> 
<paragraph id="H014223654F6D47A1A83A41096F396953"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Commission and a court of competent jurisdiction (as the case may be) shall presume the applicant with respect to such complete form has made a good faith effort to provide the information reasonably necessary for such Indian Tribe to ascertain whether historic properties of religious or cultural significance to such Indian Tribe may be affected by the undertaking related to such complete form; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB2F1E7223731405BA7098A06A830E71F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such Indian Tribe shall be presumed to have disclaimed interest in such undertaking.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8FDC69F557B64A4292D49224CCDB5756"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Overcoming presumption</header> 
<paragraph id="HA434FDA4BC08425CBAA57404F1B4C1D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An Indian Tribe may overcome a presumption under subsection (a) upon making, to the Commission or a court of competent jurisdiction, a favorable demonstration with respect to 1 or more of the factors described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A09036D04BF4AEB8C13A7F9D38B1D4A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Factors considered</header><text>In making a determination regarding a presumption under subsection (a), the Commission or court of competent jurisdiction shall give substantial weight to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0F437AFB35174116ACD380BBA869F88A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the applicant with respect to the relevant complete form failed to make a reasonable attempt to follow up with the applicable Indian Tribe not earlier than 30 days, and not later than 50 days, after the applicant submitted a complete FCC Form 620 or FCC Form 621 (as the case may be) to such Indian Tribe; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF96C86AAFDC8419BBBFCA73A3BD21733"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the rules of the Commission, or FCC Form 620 or FCC Form 621, are found to be in violation of a Nationwide Programmatic Agreement of the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6895A310DB184A339025010C50C62EEB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H7BF1247AA31746E78D2A5F3D96DB4744" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Communications Commission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD868BE8E936D4131A9069B8E5DB9EF3C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal authorization</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HEB3E6A6D3DD24C03A480C583B638E486"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any authorization required under Federal law with respect to a project; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H78118EE9F3204F7FA3C4292ED185BAA9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any permits, special use authorizations, certifications, opinions, or other approvals as may be required under Federal law with respect to a project.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB650EF190B84DFDAFC623ABD8DDD20F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Indian tribe</term> in section 102 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5130">25 U.S.C. 5130</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9373D10505594873BA2CB39492064280" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Personal wireless service</header><text>The term <term>personal wireless service</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HDA2475B7ED5F41B08D51D4BDD16369BB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any service described in section 332(c)(7)(C)(i) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/332">47 U.S.C. 332(c)(7)(C)(i)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA2592127624C4854A604F23F4E13B1E1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes commercial mobile data service (as defined in section 6001 of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1401">47 U.S.C. 1401</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H78F1A74531CE431397C3F68DA6BB6AE1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Personal wireless service facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>personal wireless service facility</term> means a facility for the provision of personal wireless service.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC602D031CF704B08992C4E7A57017729"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Small personal wireless service facility</header><text>The term <term>small personal wireless service facility</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H6889ED978EC54B32AE9EB982DDC7CE94"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a personal wireless service facility with respect to which each antenna is not more than 3 cubic feet in volume; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE6DF315BC5BC448B924933A4EF0E7885"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a wireline backhaul facility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E9305A583E44CDFA6261EF33291334D"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Wireline backhaul facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>wireline backhaul facility</term> means an above-ground or underground wireline facility used to transport communications service or other electronic communications from a small personal wireless service facility or its adjacent network interface device to a communications network.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

