<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG25956-VNY-C5-61Y">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1869 IS: Helicopter Operational Versatility and Enhanced Readiness Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 1869</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250522">May 22, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> introduced the following bill;
                which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To require the Secretary of Defense to carry out an operational
            experimentation program to evaluate the military utility of optionally piloted vehicle
            rotary-wing aircraft, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Helicopter Operational Versatility and Enhanced Readiness Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HOVER Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb0079d5447a8486fb8738d46dfe407b5">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Operational experimentation program for optionally piloted vehicle (OPV)
                rotary-wing aircraft</header>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id480683bd6bc24655aaa02732b156236a">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Operational experimentation program</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Army shall establish an operational experimentation program using optionally piloted vehicle (OPV) technology, including such rotary-wing platforms as the Secretary determines suitable—</text>
                <paragraph id="id1c9d333dbfa847bc979e8b4dd13ab247">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>to evaluate the military utility of optionally piloted vehicle aircraft in contested environments;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id7dbfd2035a0d4900997a987736d269fc">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>to assess integration of such aircraft with crewed aircraft in multi-domain operations;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id6b7b68b7f73c462cb740a30e10c10c6e">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>to analyze cost and maintenance benefits of autonomous flight;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id542534a2cad2412f8f3bfa6e0f415655"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>to develop future tactics, techniques, and procedures (TTPs) for Army aviation; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id05fb9b87902e452592acb2c4e8225245">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>to complement and inform ongoing Army science and technology efforts relating to autonomy, such as the Autonomy for Combat Environment Sustainment (ACES), Mission Adaptive Autonomy (MAA), and the ALIAS transition agreement with the Defense Advance Research Projects Agency (DARPA).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5051f2bd1b13408fb5ae04f9d8502adb">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Duration</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall carry out the program required by subsection (a) during the two-year period beginning on the date of the commencement of the program.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0164e32414ba4f8e8bfa652cbfc465a0">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Conversion</header>
 <text>Under the program required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall convert at least three existing rotary-wing aircraft of the Army into optionally piloted vehicles.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id88ffa86b1ff94640b7e839af262097c4">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Special use airspace</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall ensure that all testing and evaluation under the program required by subsection (a) is conducted in special use airspace of the Department of Defense.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id0136cfc9442e48a2846faa76dbd5d795">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Program management</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall carry out the program required by subsection (a) by acting through the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Acquisition, Logistics, and Technology in coordination with the head of the Program Executive Office for Aviation.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idaa662b2924e841ba958c475d6633fe04">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Partnerships</header>
 <text>In carrying out the program required by subsection (a), the Secretary may collaborate with stakeholders in the United States defense industry, universities, and research institutions to advance optionally piloted vehicle technologies and integrate best practices to support rapid prototyping and ensure interoperability with broader Joint All-Domain Operations initiatives.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0c6e2e8922644479a947368f1bc83f83">
                <enum>(g)</enum>
                <header>Report</header>
 <text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives a report detailing—</text>
                <paragraph id="iddba8d601590a41c99637c76efd3079c3">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>progress on the conversion required by subsection (c) and experimentation efforts under the program required by subsection (a);</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id43b7480bcf804bcea090cd1d5ba72565">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>initial findings of the Secretary with respect to the program on operational efficiency, cost savings, and effectiveness; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id1bba2b4460944440a5b709e748632ad1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>recommendations for potential future procurement of optionally piloted vehicle platforms.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id7be144ec053c48a28666c75cfdf0e9e3">
                <enum>(h)</enum>
                <header>Implementation flexibility</header>
 <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the ability of the Secretary to adjust the scope, platform selection, or methodology of experimentation to ensure alignment with existing service priorities and long-term modernization objectives.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

