<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-NEW25122-8KN-M6-5S5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 88 ATS: Designating March 7, 2025, as “National Speech and Debate Education Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 88</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250221" legis-day="20250220">February 21 (legislative day, February 20), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating March 7, 2025, as <quote>National Speech and Debate Education Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas it is essential for youth to learn and practice the art of communicating with and without technology;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas speech and debate education offers students myriad forms of public speaking through which students may develop talent and exercise unique voice and character;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas speech and debate education gives students the 21st century skills of communication, critical thinking, creativity, and collaboration;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas critical analysis and effective communication allow important ideas, texts, and philosophies the opportunity to flourish;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas personal, professional, and civic interactions are enhanced by the ability of the participants in those interactions to listen, concur, question, and dissent with reason and compassion;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas students who participate in speech and debate have chosen a challenging activity that requires regular practice, dedication, and hard work;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas teachers and coaches of speech and debate devote in-school, afterschool, and weekend hours to equip students with life-changing skills and opportunities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas National Speech and Debate Education Day emphasizes the lifelong impact of providing people of the United States with the confidence and preparation to both discern and share views;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas National Speech and Debate Education Day acknowledges that most achievements, celebrations, commemorations, and pivotal moments in modern history begin, end, or are crystallized with public address;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas National Speech and Debate Education Day recognizes that learning to research, construct, and present an argument is integral to personal advocacy, social movements, and the making of public policy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the National Speech &amp; Debate Association, in conjunction with national and local partners, honors and celebrates the importance of speech and debate through National Speech and Debate Education Day; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas National Speech and Debate Education Day emphasizes the importance of speech and debate education and the integration of speech and debate education across grade levels and disciplines: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id9d8d715a6b2b493f8d0e6c06809a200b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates March 7, 2025, as <quote>National Speech and Debate Education Day</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfdcbd24c0da1470c92e7c91bf82d5277"><enum>(2)</enum><text>strongly affirms the purposes of National Speech and Debate Education Day; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id68a5a7c6c899403b8c917555de7f93f3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages educational institutions, businesses, community and civic associations, and all people of the United States to celebrate and promote National Speech and Debate Education Day.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

