<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAC32500FD01345B69F54A71F6FDF8B72" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 398 IH: Geothermal Cost-Recovery Authority Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 398</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250114">January 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 to provide cost-recovery authority for the Department of the Interior.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2164C9E180664F35B2F81DE36D9D080A" style="OLC"><section id="H6279B4BB1A164768BA5185114ECB3E6C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Geothermal Cost-Recovery Authority Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8ADD48E2F3094476A3A7FE4F19DE99B8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Cost recovery from geothermal leasing, permitting, and inspections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6 of the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1005">30 U.S.C. 1005</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8EC254512878409C8E6905FFB21E46F2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H154477109C63443197F459614A64C630"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Cost recovery</header><paragraph id="H141E29048347495CAB1D85C43B10FEE9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the period that begins on the date of enactment of this subsection and ends September 30, 2032, the Secretary may require an applicant for, or a holder of, a geothermal lease to reimburse the United States for all reasonable administrative and other costs incurred by the United States from—</text><subparagraph id="HF22F2F8C0FD84BB59D604C4AA1404CFF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">processing the application for the geothermal lease, including any application for an operations plan, geothermal drilling permit, utilization plan, site license, facility construction permit, commercial use permit, and any other approval associated with a geothermal lease; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD72A8709598F4897BA91A14359690982" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inspecting and monitoring—</text><clause id="HA6BD411019844040834384A87199D97D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>geophysical exploration activities;</text></clause><clause id="H90B8A75EDEB04C0F8BD0D0FD3B0EA64B" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the drilling, plugging, and abandonment of wells; and</text></clause><clause id="H1E3204E2E7E5494399A4DABF54144970" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the construction, operation, termination, and reclamation of any well site or facility for the utilization of geothermal resources pursuant to the geothermal lease.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD178824A6BAF47B09BDD6E1D6AD88A1F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether to require reimbursement under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consider whether there is in existence a cooperative cost share agreement between the United States and the holder of a geothermal lease.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1865ECFB0C134376B51F6CF9DDF9668B" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Adjustments</header><text>The Secretary may reduce the amount to be reimbursed under paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines—</text><subparagraph id="H4D0C118047EB4BF1AEAE40043A082CEA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that full reimbursement would impose an economic hardship on the applicant; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0133ADFAB884E6E95C896BEFCA4C611" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that a less than full reimbursement is necessary to promote the greatest use of geothermal resources.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1ED46C5C450484989E214F0C4842115" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use</header><text>The amounts reimbursed under this subsection shall be credited to the currently applicable appropriation, account, or fund of the Department of the Interior as discretionary offsetting collections, and shall be available only to the extent provided in advance in appropriations Acts for—</text><subparagraph id="H3EAB0A550C0D417783761128AEC88B78" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">processing the application for geothermal leases, including any application for operations plans, geothermal drilling permits, utilization plans, site licenses, facility construction permits, commercial use permits, and any other approval associated with geothermal leases; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD951848F1E54D3D9867674DBA63D04D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>inspecting and monitoring—</text><clause id="H852F0AF58FF34EDB8D2B4D1B1F02AB12" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>geophysical exploration activities;</text></clause><clause id="H4485FB082922412BA866D5FE78A2854A" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the drilling, plugging, and abandonment of wells; and</text></clause><clause id="HC839A680F0914DE9BDC6F4CF8178BCD4" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the construction, operation, termination, and reclamation of any well site or facility for the utilization of geothermal resources pursuant to geothermal leases.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HC916817C2CD447BF891D87549D8F4FA2" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report</header><subsection id="H6474A5B1F227491091A64208E27F3F22"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the geothermal industry and other stakeholders, shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, and make publicly available on the website of the Department of the Interior, a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="H3528DB8DB45E4E38BD3FC8C3A71EA0B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of how the amendments made by section 2 of this Act affected the Bureau of Land Management’s geothermal program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7985097C5BA047E383B208DBA99DA82E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any recommendations for reauthorization of section 6(j) of the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970, as added by this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H460E5917709B45D3A9833FDBC1A964B0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any other recommendations for updates to such section and the Bureau of Land Management’s geothermal program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H23C18ACD57B14E34AE22C9E22D7B49D7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the report required in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Interior shall solicit facts or information from the geothermal industry and other stakeholders.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

