<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6186DB5735414F499BB0A9A6505C0670" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3893 IH: Employment Abundance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3893</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250610">June 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council to issue regulations that require all Federal contractors to conduct a comprehensive review of job classifications to identify positions for which a college degree is required without a demonstrable occupational necessity.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD7EEAF1BBFF14DE3BB4CD79214F74D34" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H34A7844FA19F432E989E50C433D9AD36" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Employment Abundance Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD87F766D0F6346F5894D358E8A3AE6F5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal contractor job classification review</header> <subsection id="HBA665B1D41F6484FADE6AC06D8F4FA88"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council shall issue regulations that require any Federal contractor that enters into a contract subject to the Federal Acquisition Regulation to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H11FF49DDB7FF4354931298C4BD40CC17"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a comprehensive review of all job classifications within their Federal contract-related workforce;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4CFBAD7D7DE3427F8F41931C9F6AEDAD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify each position that requires a bachelor’s degree or higher as a condition of employment; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7573158EA8EE4D16A01A10E511672EE9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>determine whether such educational requirements are demonstrably necessary for the performance of essential job functions.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1AF49F0924784B9EA8C4B5E8200D2025"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the effective date of the regulations issued pursuant to subsection (a), each Federal contractor shall submit to the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council a report outlining the results of its job classification review, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB74BF91B505F4314BD9151D099EB1FA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of positions where a degree requirement was determined to lack demonstrable occupational necessity; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA04D7AB012AD481F8092CD1DBDB4DD0F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a plan to revise such job classifications, including alternative criteria that may be used, such as relevant work experience, certifications, or skills assessments.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCFE130EC2DD0415B8DF9622ABFB5D5CD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compliance and enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Failure to comply with the requirements under this section may result in administrative actions, including ineligibility for future Federal contracts, subject to regulations issued by the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE1D859006D18494D9DE19441C9611BB3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit Federal contractors from maintaining educational requirements for a case in which such requirements are shown to be necessary for job performance or are mandated by law, regulation, or professional licensure standards.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6F56E18EFB4441F9A519342CA35519AE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section applies with respect to any contract entered into on and after the effective date of the regulations issued pursuant to subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

