<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25172-L33-VD-L84">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1320 IS: Servicewomen and Veterans Menopause Research Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>S. 1320</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title>To direct the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to take certain steps regarding research related to menopause, perimenopause, or mid-life women’s health, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H53C934BDCD66413D85AD7FE92BC11E39">
<section section-type="section-one" id="H8312ED64070945F6B5AF93F0607A990D"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Servicewomen and Veterans Menopause Research Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="idfb56bc4370cb45de9223d37cd71e645a"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0c428e08b9f644838ac0f5e0c8a65553"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered provider</header><text>The term <term>covered provider</term> means a health care provider employed by the Department of Defense or the Department of Veterans Affairs. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id11519ed573b84fe2ba54425e9a665e20" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Menopause</header><text>The term <term>menopause</term> means the stage of a woman’s life—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id24dff10d4595405fb66a11a0c94ef8b1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">when menstrual periods stop permanently and she can no longer get pregnant; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida34c51ab7656498aa7dd339f854f14c1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is not a disease state, but a normal part of aging for women. </text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idb8c9895e8120448fa70a7c826a360f95"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mid-life</header><text>The term <term>mid-life</term> means a life stage that—</text> <subparagraph id="id0ba98821d4054f618761905460269444"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coincides with the menopausal transition in women, which may be physical or emotional;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="ida4d893439ead4604b17eccdfc699edb4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>encompasses the late reproductive age, which can begin at approximately 35 years of age, to the late postmenopausal stages of reproductive aging, which can extend to approximately 65 years of age; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id5b3685677b5e41e89b2ba7be08b2e804"><enum>(C)</enum><text>often marks the onset of many chronic diseases.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="ide50ecfd074ee457aa492bfbac016ce53" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Perimenopause</header><text>The term <term>perimenopause</term> means the time during a woman's life when levels of the hormone estrogen fall unevenly in a woman’s body and is also called the menopausal transition.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id6d002b98acfc4d2d9243dfe98b2c91b6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Postmenopausal</header><text>The term <term>postmenopausal</term> means the stage of a woman's life after a woman has been without a menstrual period for 12 months that lasts for the rest of a woman’s life and reflects a time when women are at increased risk for osteoporosis and heart disease. </text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H67D0A61A9B584DCEB95ADCA1B86E38B6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Evaluation of certain research related to menopause, perimenopause, or mid-life women’s health</header>
<subsection id="H75EF4CE5153840B3B5587B825EC7718D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall evaluate—</text> <paragraph id="H9B96D1DFB9E349C497D7069748CB12B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the results of completed research related to menopause, perimenopause, or mid-life women’s health among women who are members of the Armed Forces or veterans;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H31A9235554674CEE82D6C251140B8104"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the status of such research that is ongoing;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3B05EDBDCF4C45D293E8DC006A6AA239"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any gaps in knowledge and research on—</text>
<subparagraph id="idf48620e892434fe8b60e1a2bd8bec422"><enum>(A)</enum><text>treatments for menopause-related symptoms, including hormone and non-hormone treatments;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCE1BC3538D374AF69D026DAF5EA1F0A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the safety and effectiveness of treatments for menopause-related symptoms;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2A29BFBEE6AF4876A409B73807559BE5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the relation of service in the Armed Forces to perimenopause and menopause and the impact of such service on perimenopause and menopause;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7F7A30122161441F92D309FB5149C94B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effect of combat roles on symptoms relating to perimenopause and menopause, including exposure to burn pits, toxic chemicals, and perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances (commonly known as <quote>PFAS</quote>); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4AEB8BC267964933B95F32FC679972E2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the impact of perimenopause and menopause on the mental health of women who are members of the Armed Forces or veterans;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id89ecac9b27734a849ca391031b687bd5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the availability of and uptake of professional training resources for covered providers relating to mid-life women’s health with respect to the care, treatment, and management of perimenopause and menopausal symptoms, and related support services; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idd917c7f4a6fb4ff4ae2bd279fc46b9e3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the availability of and uptake of treatments for women who are members of the Armed Forces or veterans who are experiencing perimenopause or menopause. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCC48F00D45254D46BA264F856C9BA370"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report; strategic plan</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall each submit to Congress a report containing—</text>
<paragraph id="H1EEC44E565DA4FE98595ED38B11CAE19"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the findings of the evaluation conducted under subsection (a);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id4d97f7375c3848ed9648c63c118fc37b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations for improving professional training resources described in subsection (a)(4) for covered providers; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3DF98B22D9284FC484EE9EE83D27CB44"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a strategic plan that—</text> <subparagraph id="H631D2B7C54E045888DFC5E9FC4FC644E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>resolves the gaps in knowledge and research identified in the report; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD0DED035AC4747A3A39DEF72371744D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies topics in need of further research relating to potential treatments for menopause-related symptoms of women who are members of the Armed Forces or veterans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf9b714a3f0694808b47d2973d7f1ca2e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Nonduplication and supplementation of efforts</header><text>In carrying out activities under this section, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall ensure that such activities minimize duplication and supplement, not supplant, existing information-sharing efforts of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H0B9E160AA4BB4B1BA0BD7F0809F10774"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on additional research related to menopause, perimenopause, or mid-life women’s health</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs should each conduct research related to menopause, perimenopause, or mid-life health regarding women who are members of the Armed Forces or veterans.</text></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

