<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-RIL25106-Y0G-W4-M3N"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 44 IS: Designating the week of January 26 through February 1, 2025, as “National School Choice Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 44</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250129">January 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating the week of January 26 through February 1, 2025, as <quote>National School Choice Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas providing a diversity of choices in K–12 education empowers parents to select education environments that meet the individual needs and strengths of their children;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas high-quality K–12 education environments of all varieties are available in the United States, including traditional public schools, public charter schools, public magnet schools, private schools, online academies, and home schooling;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas talented teachers and school leaders in each of these education environments prepare children to achieve their dreams;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more families than ever before in the United States actively choose the best education for their children;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more public awareness of the issue of parental choice in education can inform additional families of the benefits of proactively choosing challenging, motivating, and effective education environments for their children;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the process by which parents choose schools for their children is nonpolitical, nonpartisan, and deserves the utmost respect; and</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas tens of thousands of events are planned to celebrate the benefits of educational choice during the 14th annual National School Choice Week, held the week of January 26 through February 1, 2025: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id2c52fee505e348e99c666c7cb8beb869"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates the week of January 26 through February 1, 2025, as <quote>National School Choice Week</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id04c9eaf2f1624193bb1180a8ba0f0024"><enum>(2)</enum><text>congratulates students, parents, teachers, and school leaders from kindergarten through grade 12 education environments of all varieties for their persistence, achievements, dedication, and contributions to society in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaa2734c6fb6846e6bc9b358348e5ca75"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages all parents, during National School Choice Week, to learn more about the education options available to them; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc7a098f13adb4ac69ff569428fa19b9f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to hold appropriate programs, events, and activities during National School Choice Week to raise public awareness of the benefits of opportunity in education. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

