<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7AE5270692E64B3B9C105539A2F0EC50" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 609 IH: Expressing support for the designation of August 2026 as Veterans Appreciation Month.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 609</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of August 2026 as Veterans Appreciation Month.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas United States veterans have answered the Nation’s call to serve;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas veterans fought the Nation’s battles in the air, on land, and on sea;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the brave men and women who served in the United States Armed Forces made great sacrifices to protect the freedom and democracy of the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas United States veterans willingly placed the well-being of the Nation above their own;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas given their immense sacrifice and bravery, veterans deserve to be honored during the entire month of August and throughout the year;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas we must recognize the pressing issues faced by veterans and the imperative to ensure that all individuals who have served in the United States Armed Forces are adequately cared for and protected; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the people of the United States are proud of the courageous service of all who served in the United States Armed Forces: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HCD08D1A322674FDFAFE85D1FF1997408"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA1636F10DF7F425DAEBA507E78E12618"><text>That the House of Representatives supports the designation of Veterans Appreciation Month.</text></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

