<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KAT25616-9NM-KJ-J8F"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2554 IS: Alaska Native Landless Equity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2554</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250730">July 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for the recognition of certain Alaska Native communities and the
            settlement of certain claims under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act, and for
 other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section section-type="section-one" id="H8B739381F39A4FC7864C077155F5A965"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Alaska Native Landless Equity Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7890CA1EA1BC4245A4A805DBF685EB5E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to redress the omission of the southeastern Alaska communities of Haines, Ketchikan, Petersburg, Tenakee, and Wrangell from eligibility under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1601">43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>) by authorizing the Alaska Natives enrolled in the communities—</text><paragraph id="H61210BBA6F3D41C9A532BB5262BA2439"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to form Urban Corporations for the communities of Haines, Ketchikan, Petersburg, Tenakee, and Wrangell under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1601">43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H899A4EDC068E43AF8A57215DDA38E432" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to receive certain settlement land pursuant to that Act.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H248D0F1440D44B05AF891BACBD0F1ED7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of additional native corporations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 16 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1615">43 U.S.C. 1615</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H62DACB4D4B7749DDB77DAEBC928E0291" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><subsection id="HE2B8820431664FD496B2BF10351BB03F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Native villages of haines, ketchikan, petersburg, tenakee, and wrangell,
 Alaska</header><paragraph id="H7ACD8E4EF6904CC39155895BDB76C4D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Native residents of each of the Native Villages of Haines, Ketchikan, Petersburg, Tenakee, and Wrangell, Alaska, may organize as Urban Corporations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE77F3AF7A4234D799323DF782A176A04" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect on entitlement to land</header><text>Nothing in this subsection affects any entitlement to land of any Native Corporation established before the date of enactment of this subsection pursuant to this Act or any other provision of law.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H86CD7BB2DB734870AB9205CFA14F0CA7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Shareholder eligibility</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1607">43 U.S.C. 1607</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H79AB75C626984D56954E8CFB512E6B0D" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><subsection id="H832069A4BC2047C1B94C646EB5B389C5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Native villages of haines, ketchikan, petersburg, tenakee, and
 wrangell</header><paragraph id="H8E6C2D3AA4124B8889366BF02E765313"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall enroll to each of the Urban Corporations for Haines, Ketchikan, Petersburg, Tenakee, or Wrangell those individual Natives who enrolled under this Act to the Native Villages of Haines, Ketchikan, Petersburg, Tenakee, or Wrangell, respectively.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H703DA1DEB7894DE5931A75861FE93436"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Number of shares</header><text>Each Native who is enrolled to an Urban Corporation for Haines, Ketchikan, Petersburg, Tenakee, or Wrangell pursuant to paragraph (1) and who was enrolled as a shareholder of the Regional Corporation for Southeast Alaska shall receive 100 shares of Settlement Common Stock in the respective Urban Corporation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C5D7CE64AB3414B910F428FC2F6EC54"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Natives receiving shares through inheritance</header><text>If a Native received shares of stock in the Regional Corporation for Southeast Alaska through inheritance from a decedent Native who originally enrolled to the Native Village of Haines, Ketchikan, Petersburg, Tenakee, or Wrangell and the decedent Native was not a shareholder in a Village Corporation or Urban Corporation, the Native shall receive the identical number of shares of Settlement Common Stock in the Urban Corporation for Haines, Ketchikan, Petersburg, Tenakee, or Wrangell as the number of shares inherited by that Native from the decedent Native who would have been eligible to be enrolled to the respective Urban Corporation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8314549E549148ADB14B35B3CEA367E6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Effect on entitlement to land</header><text>Nothing in this subsection affects any previous or future allocation of acreage to any Regional Corporation pursuant to section 12(b) or 14(h)(8).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HED57E0061106491BB33DD35A758A2E3C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Distribution rights</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1606">43 U.S.C. 1606</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H7AE4ACDA2C9349AFA390111552217A56"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (j)—</text><subparagraph id="HE5E836D82E5E4DF395F893115C426E1F" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the third sentence, by striking <quote>In the case</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H0B1C49BE6889407FA80E31D380C6F503" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H5902C1D8098D4961BE5EB515234BA618"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Thirteenth regional corporation</header><text>In the case</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97FF2896D6EF472B8D0D5252055A5E71"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by striking <quote>Not less</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBEC22CA9022D4121A1F69D8D49549829"><paragraph id="H1A42868A7CE64A2E875993F2D000630A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum allocation</header><text>Not less</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF26AD83A32594F2082021C38ECF729B4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(j) During</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H43A080560ED44F39958622BCB28D7973" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><subsection id="HCC3344D4B6B547779D705954CCC144E1"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Distribution of corporate funds and other net income</header><paragraph id="H7E8EE755AA254D06B1148FE88653C64F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H945439506AB34D20AF7BEA58B47DA9DA" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HFCE891D5CF064A7E98A925585FB63C1A" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H2450582ACFDA4D179A2260BDA7C9EDB7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Native villages of haines, ketchikan, petersburg, tenakee, and wrangell</header><text>Native members of the Native Villages of Haines, Ketchikan, Petersburg, Tenakee, and Wrangell who become shareholders in an Urban Corporation for such a Native Village shall continue to be eligible to receive distributions under this subsection as at-large shareholders of the Regional Corporation for Southeast Alaska.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E766ECE6CB5491494E0317848D61B2A" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H444E943E9D0B4CA3946C0733B87A5AE3"><subsection commented="no" id="H333FFEA52FF8475F80E30E0B46F92EE1"><enum>(s)</enum><header>Effect of amendatory Act</header><text>The <short-title>Alaska Native Landless Equity Act</short-title> and the amendments made by that Act shall not affect—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H90CF20FDE7054BA8B5C4FE5FBD8FCA3B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the ratio for determination of revenue distribution among Native Corporations under this section; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H09960D7B64384195B85F514D2BF4E5DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the settlement agreement among Regional Corporations or Village Corporations or other provisions of subsection (i) or (j).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HEB21A6F022EC4B3496F0E7F5548986D1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Compensation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1601">43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H2EC88872EA13458B820F827F0515CBBC" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><section id="HFFD9C0863A83470884A03E4FAB0D14FA"><enum>43.</enum><header>Urban corporations for haines, ketchikan, petersburg, tenakee, and
 wrangell</header><subsection id="H442922FE1F8D47AC912277A76B8771AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of urban corporation</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Urban Corporation</term> means each of the Urban Corporations for Haines, Ketchikan, Petersburg, Tenakee, and Wrangell.</text></subsection><subsection id="H498720784F834FDC913447A472D34C19"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conveyances of land</header><paragraph id="H2BCCE872E3974BBB95733AC72930BE04"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization</header><subparagraph id="H8F56BA684C9849349EA1AAC273A3855F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Conveyances to urban corporations</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77c7962830d74129ac17db15117c5bf5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to valid existing rights and paragraphs (3), (4), (5), and (6), the Secretary shall convey—</text><subclause id="HEF1224888DC94AA28888413F2927F7B7"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the Urban Corporation for Haines, in accordance with clause (ii), the surface estate in 13 parcels of Federal land comprising approximately 23,040 acres, as generally depicted on the maps entitled <quote>Haines Selections</quote>, numbered 1 through 3, and dated June 27, 2025;</text></subclause><subclause id="H9BB83A1753D04628B40446A66D21B86A"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the Urban Corporation for Ketchikan, the surface estate in 8 parcels of Federal land comprising approximately 23,040 acres, as generally depicted on the maps entitled <quote>Ketchikan Selections</quote>, numbered 1 through 4, and dated June 27, 2025;</text></subclause><subclause id="H0AF67D1ADE1B4D89AD0AD98BBE3010B1"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the Urban Corporation for Petersburg, the surface estate in 12 parcels of Federal land comprising approximately 23,040 acres, as generally depicted on the maps entitled <quote>Petersburg Selections</quote>, numbered 1 through 3, and dated June 27, 2025;</text></subclause><subclause id="H5CEA5788D1534517878137489F89259E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the Urban Corporation for Tenakee, the surface estate in 15 parcels of Federal land comprising approximately 23,040 acres, as generally depicted on the maps entitled <quote>Tenakee Selections</quote>, numbered 1 through 3, and dated June 27, 2025; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H98F04A8048F247B0B0087326D72C6095"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the Urban Corporation for Wrangell, the surface estate in 13 parcels of Federal land comprising approximately 23,040 acres, as generally depicted on the maps entitled <quote>Wrangell Selections</quote>, numbered 1 through 5, and dated June 27, 2025.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2d8bfb6c7a8a40fb911eb0f6c07be90d"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Haines phases; conditions</header><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddda20fa407fb47318a3261e6885ce2e6"><enum>(I)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conveyance
 phases</header><text>The conveyance to the Urban Corporation for Haines under clause (i)(I) in the selection area at Slate Creek, Berners Bay, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Haines Selections</quote>, map 2 of 3, and dated June 27, 2025 (referred to in this subclause as the <term>Map</term>), shall be completed in the following 2 phases:</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb7ea1358e6c24d14b151fa4ae4f25d36"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Phase 1</header><text>The Secretary shall convey to the Urban Corporation for Haines the parcel of Federal land comprising approximately 81 acres, as generally depicted on the Map as <quote>Slate Ck. West Shore</quote>.</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8648f24dbefa46d7bb7f312c1026d2ef"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Phase 2</header><text>Subject to the conditions described in subclause (II), and on an application for conveyance by the Urban Corporation for Haines, the Secretary shall convey to the Urban Corporation for Haines—</text><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id615ac14070a941bc8eefa20fcbb29aff"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the parcel of Federal land comprising approximately 37 acres, as generally depicted on the Map as <quote>Slate Ck. West Shore North</quote>; and</text></subitem><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide2f34156f0434fd4a340a034d86e9c1b"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the parcel of Federal land comprising approximately 55 acres, as generally depicted on the Map as <quote>Slate Ck. East Shore</quote>.</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="id2149660301fa44bd984c7376ba9e709e"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Phase 2 conditions</header><text>The phase 2 conveyance described in subclause (I)(bb) shall occur on the earliest of the date on which—</text><item id="id5605786fb56844f69b8f5eec5df59018"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the Federal mining claims underlying the Federal land described in that subclause are relinquished;</text></item><item id="id0de138d03373420fa3a4dd372be86b29"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the Federal mining claims underlying the Federal land described in that subclause are abandoned, on a determination by the Secretary that the Federal mining claims are void and forfeited; and</text></item><item id="id10bcad3d80ea43f0b1ae73617e61bc15"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>Coeur Mining (or a successor in interest) consents that the Federal land described in that subclause can be conveyed prior to any relinquishment or abandonment of the Federal mining claims underlying that land.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7BCEADBE96F499791D4E5949B8EB886"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Conveyances to regional corporation for southeast
 Alaska</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, on the applicable date on which the surface estate in land is conveyed to an Urban Corporation under subparagraph (A)(i), the Secretary shall convey to the Regional Corporation for Southeast Alaska the subsurface estate for that land.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfb7ea249522a4e5280abd3214fcb18b4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Congressional intent</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4191c34851d849bc951aecc1e58180fe"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to clause (ii), it is the intent of Congress that the Secretary complete the interim conveyance of the surface estate in land to an Urban Corporation under subparagraph (A)(i) not later than the date that is 2 years after the applicable date of incorporation of the Urban Corporation under section 16(e)(1).</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida5caceb12fd44c75b9e59472e3dba82b"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As the Secretary determines to be necessary, the Secretary may extend the 2-year deadline established by clause (i) by not more than 1 year for any individual parcel of land to allow for the conclusion of any pending appeal of a public easement decision for the applicable parcel pursuant to section 17(b), subject to the requirement that the final conveyance of the surface estate with respect to the applicable parcel shall be completed as soon as practicable after the date on which the appeal is concluded.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf49186b34a694aa2adadbe50c801daec"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Finalization of entitlement</header><clause id="idc89ab723d6624da3ae2ed4f33b5bd3d1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The conveyances under subparagraph (A)(i) shall be considered to be the full and final satisfaction of the entitlement of the southeastern Alaska communities of Haines, Ketchikan, Petersburg, Tenakee, and Wrangell under this Act, notwithstanding whether the surveyed acreage of the parcels of land described in subclauses (I) through (V) of that subparagraph is less than or more than 23,040 acres in the case of each Urban Corporation, subject to the requirement that the surveyed acreage shall be not less than 23,020 acres and not more than 23,060 acres.</text></clause><clause id="id0b5658f3bf654a19ae1b3cd91eb83c25"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Adjustments</header><text>If the total surveyed acreage of land conveyed to an Urban Corporation under subparagraph (A)(i) is less than 23,020 acres or more than 23,060 acres, the Secretary, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Urban Corporation shall negotiate in good faith to make a mutually agreeable adjustment to the parcels of Federal land described in subclauses (I) through (V) of that subparagraph to ensure that not less than and not more than 23,040 acres of land is conveyed to the Urban Corporation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H19FB1FF0C9C24EC0988BD95FBF2C67F2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><subparagraph id="H14008064157B403791885E1A4055959F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Federal land described in paragraph (1) is withdrawn from all forms of—</text><clause id="HAA1B804A1D334EAA8859960136179AAF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text></clause><clause id="HBB751CFFC587477FA25EA1BB297B78E2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text></clause><clause id="HF70EEBD11036433FBC24EC7339D44BB0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA0829E50094487C98183955B8E32868"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The withdrawal under subparagraph (A) shall remain in effect until the date on which the Federal land is conveyed under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0586E39AA86A40BDBC71239F3E7B946B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment of land conveyed</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, any land conveyed to an Urban Corporation under paragraph (1)(A)(i)—</text><subparagraph id="HB70F04C517AF447F91C0806AAC66FF31"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idc7875e4ae39f472cba4ee97f49babfbf"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be considered to be land conveyed by the Secretary under paragraph (3) of section 14(h); but</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf393bdc31f3143cf85fea5b98a155869" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be subject to the requirements under that section that the land be vacant, unappropriated, and unreserved; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF625A7AE8954A1E98EA79B31A4C55C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be subject to all laws (including regulations) applicable to entitlements under section 14(h)(3), including section 907(d) of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1636">43 U.S.C. 1636(d)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA3140769CC44AFDAACA9F2966A6C7AC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public easements</header><subparagraph id="idac580b6019124d5b82b635b439c0d05c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (C), the conveyance and patents for the land under paragraph (1)(A)(i) shall be subject to the reservation before the conveyance of public easements under section 17(b).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbf36e3591e344846b0ce51a053198041"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>No public easement reserved on land conveyed under paragraph (1)(A)(i) shall be terminated by the Secretary without publication of notice of the proposed termination in the Federal Register.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0fe66b18bc684405a804a0294fcd3cdb"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Reservation of easements</header><text>In the conveyance and patent for any parcel of land under paragraph (1)(A)(i) for which the easement reservation process has not been completed by the date that is 2 years after the applicable date of incorporation of the Urban Corporation under section 16(e)(1), or, in the case of an appeal of a public easement under section 17(b), by the date that is 3 years after the applicable date of incorporation, the Secretary shall—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id86531c3eb394414e8fa27bae735f3066"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">convey the parcel of land; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6d7b14d7f8d24dffb555974b6a513fa7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as part of the conveyance and patent for the parcel of land under clause (i), reserve the right of the Secretary to amend the conveyance and patent to include reservations of public easements under section 17(b) until the date of completion of the easement reservation process.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6acf54b13348483297c0d05cec4b3939"><enum>(D)</enum><header>State of Alaska easements</header><text>Nothing in this Act modifies, changes, or terminates the rights-of-way granted to the State under—</text><clause id="idEF2D003FD4BE4826836EAC81F1741EDD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>section 4407 of the SAFETEA–LU (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/59">Public Law 109–59</external-xref>; 119 Stat. 1777); or</text></clause><clause id="idEE22BF33A10A4B35BBE051C0E8CFDB48"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the 2006 memorandum of understanding between the State and the Forest Service to implement that section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H308C7C95331B4445ABA102F6ABB3457C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Hunting, fishing, recreation, and access</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBE268353315644AEBD05F295E7D5715D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any land conveyed under paragraph (1)(A)(i), including access to the land through roadways, trails, and forest roads, shall remain open and available to subsistence uses, noncommercial recreational hunting and fishing, and other noncommercial recreational uses by the public under applicable law—</text><clause commented="no" id="HB2E956BE7E884EEAA50DD58953056A15"><enum>(i)</enum><text>without liability on the part of the Urban Corporation, except for willful acts of the Urban Corporation, to any user as a result of the use; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H22058093BB5441BF9CDBEA85538E96F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subject to—</text><subclause commented="no" id="HC09DCD5B9F104971984EC83718050DA0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any reasonable restrictions that may be imposed by the Urban Corporation on the public use—</text><item commented="no" id="HB5235B80658A430FBAB38DD72965D24B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>to ensure public safety;</text></item><item commented="no" id="HB76946FFEB664CDA99503B24DC1FE6FC"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to minimize conflicts between recreational and commercial uses;</text></item><item commented="no" id="H38ACEBD40C1E48F2A04A133FF84E3454"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>to protect cultural resources;</text></item><item commented="no" id="H2885FE34A71E4B8B9AE1921D6598A3FC"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>to conduct scientific research; or</text></item><item commented="no" id="H62DFBE7E96C14D17ADE9A1857F4BA94B"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>to provide environmental protection; and</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HEB5ABDCA609545F397F85352EA34C2DD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the condition that the Urban Corporation post on any applicable property, in accordance with State law, notices of the restrictions on use.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H672298F0A5BA4B0DB08F8AB2CBB23E75"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Access provided to any individual or entity under subparagraph (A) shall not—</text><clause commented="no" id="H84D76D4750234ACD9077E6B0B1F8EBA8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>create an interest in any third party in the land conveyed under paragraph (1)(A)(i); or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H3439210A8882401EA08983A847BA4BFD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide standing to any third party in any review of, or challenge to, any determination by the Urban Corporation with respect to the management or development of the land conveyed under paragraph (1)(A)(i), except as against the Urban Corporation for the management of public access under subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D1264F784F24B1AB9AD731475A6BFD8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Miscellaneous</header><subparagraph id="HBF59FD921CF940D0A56AD471B330FCA1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Special use authorizations</header><clause id="HAE226E3A90194772AEBAA757D6F04A39"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On the conveyance of land to an Urban Corporation under paragraph (1)(A)(i)—</text><subclause id="H22B3F11A99084E6BB5F68916D4F8D82F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any guiding or outfitting special use authorization issued by the Forest Service for the use of the conveyed land shall terminate; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H22726DAD42174269BEABFDBCC2E4B16D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>as a condition of the conveyance and consistent with section 14(g), the Urban Corporation shall issue the holder of the special use authorization terminated under subclause (I) an authorization to continue the authorized use, subject to the terms and conditions that were in the special use authorization issued by the Forest Service, for—</text><item id="HB8FE717C4F764F0D9CB136EB42564144"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the remainder of the term of the authorization; and</text></item><item id="H72ED804E28BC45EFA4CACE8210952E8A"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>1 additional consecutive 10-year renewal period.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H0E56DED8057A4FAFB44D61E97E9E9A18"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Notice of commercial activities</header><text>The Urban Corporation, and any holder of a guiding or outfitting authorization under this subparagraph, shall have a mutual obligation, subject to the guiding or outfitting authorization, to inform the other party of any commercial activities prior to engaging in the activities on the land conveyed to the Urban Corporation under paragraph (1)(A)(i).</text></clause><clause id="HAE0278C1EFA14595B6B03103F4C76123"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Negotiation of new terms</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph precludes the Urban Corporation and the holder of a guiding or outfitting authorization from negotiating a new mutually agreeable guiding or outfitting authorization.</text></clause><clause id="H04F6C083B1EB4A37BE8D40F41A0A0773"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Liability</header><text>Neither the Urban Corporation nor the United States shall bear any liability, except for willful acts of the Urban Corporation or the United States, regarding the use and occupancy of any land conveyed to the Urban Corporation under paragraph (1)(A)(i), as provided in any outfitting or guiding authorization under this paragraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id69329d36611647c794854d7b94231766"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Mutual use agreement for roads and facilities</header><clause id="id8bb144ccb8eb4696b04046b2798fbf40"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall seek to enter into a binding mutual use agreement for—</text><subclause id="id219425b1efbc42f5afbce0ccff3d1bbe"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the use of National Forest System roads and related transportation facilities (including marine access facilities, log transfer facilities, sort yards, and associated log rafting and storage areas) in the Tongass National Forest by the Urban Corporation and designees of the Urban Corporation; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idfaf08cc4cd2c45c8b96c7a3dd0c643cb"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the use of the roads and related transportation facilities (including marine access facilities, log transfer facilities, sort yards, and associated log rafting and storage areas) of the Urban Corporation by the Forest Service and designees of the Forest Service.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id19a015da4a8344e8bb3b3c9f16b657ce"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text>The binding mutual use agreement under clause (i)—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf71d28ab273d45dfb077480dd233eaf0"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall provide that the use of road and transportation facilities infrastructure by a third party shall not begin until the date on which the third party signs a mutual use agreement entered into with the Urban Corporation;</text></subclause><subclause id="idd3ead909a97d4ee883898c7ab3089c64"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall provide that the State (including entities and designees of the State) shall be authorized to use the roads and related transportation facilities of the Urban Corporation on substantially similar terms as are provided by the Urban Corporation to the Forest Service;</text></subclause><subclause id="idc71c781dc5f14dc9b1ede429185ddf93"><enum>(III)</enum><text>shall include restrictions on, and fees for, the use of the National Forest System roads and related transportation facilities in existence as of the date of enactment of this section, as necessary, that are reasonable and comparable to the restrictions and fees imposed by the Forest Service for the use of the roads and related transportation facilities;</text></subclause><subclause id="idef55be31c5e7471a9c4e7efce21956b6"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>shall not restrict or limit any access to the roads and related transportation facilities of the Urban Corporation or the Forest Service that may be otherwise provided by valid existing rights and agreements in existence as of the date of enactment of this section; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id8c5faaa04b8f4d8ba14af94a18d1dae4"><enum>(V)</enum><text>shall provide for periodic updates to the mutual use agreement if the terms and conditions of the updated mutual use agreement are consistent with the terms and conditions described in subclauses (I) through (IV).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id951cde83177f468c9dab85a88a7872a1"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Intent of congress</header><text>It is the intent of Congress that the mutual use agreement under clause (i) shall be entered into as soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this section and in any case by not later than 1 year after the date of incorporation of the Urban Corporation.</text></clause><clause id="id450a6c9c0fc94f51ac1531900f90f20f"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Continued access</header><text>Beginning on the date on which the land is conveyed to the Urban Corporation under paragraph (1)(A)(i) and ending on the effective date of a binding mutual use agreement entered into under clause (i), the Urban Corporation shall provide and allow administrative access to roads and related transportation facilities on the land under substantially similar terms as are provided by the Forest Service as of the date of enactment of this section.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F8F40A88B704BE68D87C10429E9BF02"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effect on other laws</header><clause id="H1512A4C6CB1546EE9F79A9B38F05DADB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this section delays the duty of the Secretary to convey land to—</text><subclause id="HC9FD382AB81E4768BCD26CA65E5A988F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the State under <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/85/508">Public Law 85–508</external-xref> (commonly known as the <quote>Alaska Statehood Act</quote>) (48 U.S.C. note prec. 21); or</text></subclause><subclause id="HA1D1AEE2CC444591A3476D8FD8CE3E45"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a Native Corporation under—</text><item id="HB809B6C3CFD64B11A9B789DF0862976D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>this Act; or</text></item><item id="H2C81790B5B9D4E8289E04B8DDDD3733F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the Alaska Land Transfer Acceleration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1611">43 U.S.C. 1611</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/452">Public Law 108–452</external-xref>).</text></item></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H9C16E8869D874F819DF3515104DDF8B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Statehood entitlement</header><subclause commented="no" id="HFED2E6BE7F244EEBAA22DEDD08459D27"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Statehood selections under <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/85/508">Public Law 85–508</external-xref> (commonly known as the <quote>Alaska Statehood Act</quote>) (48 U.S.C. note prec. 21) are not displaced by the parcels of land described in subclauses (I) through (V) of paragraph (1)(A)(i).</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H0016F848940A40C3AEF8C81460D7B0E1"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Boundary adjustments</header><text>In the event of a dispute between an area selected as a Statehood selection and a parcel of land referred to in subclause (I), the Secretary shall work with the Urban Corporation and the State in good faith to adjust the boundary of the parcel to exclude any area selected as a Statehood selection.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H1342FE9533754A1CADCBE05FD4D36773"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Conveyances</header><text>The Secretary shall promptly proceed with the conveyance of all land necessary to fulfill the final entitlement of all Native Corporations in accordance with—</text><subclause id="H4C89621F5D0746A89300CA0D62526552"><enum>(I)</enum><text>this Act; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H6D9EB20DFC0C483698B6B06456A8815D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Alaska Land Transfer Acceleration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1611">43 U.S.C. 1611</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/452">Public Law 108–452</external-xref>).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6C57FA6338D645C0B1E865E07B0763B4"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Fish and wildlife</header><text>Nothing in this section enlarges or diminishes the responsibility and authority of the State with respect to the management of fish and wildlife on public land in the State.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2BA01C3733D42E4A613212F48F62662"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Maps</header><clause id="H464EEC85CB2C43A19D85C747C2C54973"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Each map referred to in paragraph (1)(A)(i) shall be available in the appropriate offices of the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></clause><clause id="HF1F5FFDB817047B4BFED4BC715A2B2E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Corrections</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, may make any necessary correction to a clerical or typographical error in a map referred to in paragraph (1)(A)(i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfa864cb67efc4f19beff4e5104f4850b"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Escrow funds</header><text>Beginning on the date of enactment of this section, the escrow requirements of section 2 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/204">Public Law 94–204</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1613">43 U.S.C. 1613</external-xref> note) shall apply to proceeds (including interest) derived from the land withdrawn under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H910ED114C5CD4C56AECA155A40F027DC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conveyance of roads, trails, log transfer facilities, leases, and
 appurtenances</header><paragraph id="id4389deeec6ae44a49f629297e1547065"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The land conveyed to an Urban Corporation under subsection (b)(1)(A)(i) shall include all right, title, and interest of the United States in all roads, trails, log transfer facilities, leases, and appurtenances on or related to the land conveyed to the Urban Corporation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfc9adafa8bb9430fabf10ee72e814b91"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>The land conveyed to an Urban Corporation under subsection (b)(1)(A)(i) shall be subject to all valid existing rights in accordance with section 14(g), including any reciprocal rights-of-way, easements, or agreements for the use of the roads, trails, log transfer facilities, leases, and appurtenances conveyed under subsection (b)(1)(A)(i).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2148EDDF0514B1393899D4BCAD1FACD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Continuation of agreements</header><subparagraph id="H82068CB5E3234FE18CD014088462A0BD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On or before the date on which land is conveyed to an Urban Corporation under subsection (b)(1)(A)(i), the Secretary shall provide to the Urban Corporation notice of all reciprocal rights-of-way, easements, and agreements for use of the roads, trails, log transfer facilities, leases, and appurtenances on or related to the land in existence as of the date of enactment of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7A3503E36BC4557914C780FCD2D0EDC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>In accordance with section 14(g), any right-of-way, easement, or agreement described in subparagraph (A) shall continue unless the right-of-way, easement, or agreement—</text><clause id="HCDD76E01551A41E6B51368AFA868E0AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>expires under its own terms; or</text></clause><clause id="HDF28AA25019549D5A8B28818EBFFC1F5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is mutually renegotiated.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H770FAAF750424794B7B28DF477B7C052"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Settlement trust</header><paragraph commented="no" id="HB29D946A513A48CCB34DB4ADE66371DB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each Urban Corporation may establish a settlement trust in accordance with section 39 for the purposes of promoting the health, education, and welfare of the trust beneficiaries, and preserving the Native heritage and culture, of the community of Haines, Ketchikan, Petersburg, Tenakee, or Wrangell, as applicable.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE1360F373A754428AE244567B29D85EB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Proceeds and income</header><text>The proceeds and income from the principal of a trust established under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H38EE19F261284D0AA9A8F983FE15955F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>first be applied to the support of those enrollees, and the descendants of the enrollees, who are elders or minor children; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5A0207599F484874B5F0AD3A3F5089DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>thereafter to the support of all other enrollees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6E44D9CBB7DA47FEA6E9BBF065BE8520" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $12,500,000, to be used by the Secretary to provide 5 grants in the amount of $2,500,000 each, to be used only for activities that support the implementation of this section, including planning and development.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

