<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-BIN25093-T49-W8-NKR"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 329 ATS: Congratulating Louisiana State University on their victory in the 2025 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I College World Series.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 329</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250721">July 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S389">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating Louisiana State University on their victory in the 2025 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I College World Series.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on Sunday, June 22, 2025, the Louisiana State University (referred to in this preamble as <quote>LSU</quote>) Fighting Tigers baseball team won the 2025 National Collegiate Athletic Association (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>NCAA</quote>) Division I College World Series, defeating Coastal Carolina University by a score of 5 to 3;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the LSU Fighting Tigers were undefeated in the College World Series, played in Omaha, Nebraska;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the LSU Fighting Tigers scored 6 runs on 16 hits in the championship series;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the LSU Fighting Tigers won their eighth NCAA Division I Baseball Championship, the second-most baseball championship wins by one team in NCAA history; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas head coach Jay Johnson won 2 national championships in 4 seasons, becoming the fastest coach to win multiple national titles at a school in NCAA history;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Kade Anderson was named the Most Outstanding Player of the College World Series, after pitching a complete game shutout in Game 1 of the championship series against Coastal Carolina University;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 2025 LSU Fighting Tigers baseball team was comprised of some of the best players in the Southeastern Conference (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>SEC</quote>) with Kade Anderson and Zac Cowan named to the First Team All-SEC Team, Jared Jones, Daniel Dickinson, Derek Curiel, and Anthony Eyanson named to the Second Team All-SEC Team, and Derek Curiel and Casan Evans named to the Freshman All-SEC Baseball Team;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 2025 LSU Fighting Tigers baseball team was comprised of some of the best players in the United States, with Kade Anderson named to the First Team All-American Baseball Team and Jared Jones, Derek Curiel, and Anthony Eyanson named to the Second Team All-American Baseball Team; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the LSU Fighting Tigers finished the season with 53 wins and 15 losses: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idf9d08ea2e12b4b3090df916c679ff7fc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the Louisiana State University Fighting Tigers for winning the 2025 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I College World Series;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd629968f3c3f41e98ec3b4ec740daceb"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the achievements, teamwork, and tenacity of the coaches, players, and staff of the Louisiana State University baseball team;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3d927aaa6f2b4d7b98ad36cb6f20ed96"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the fans of Louisiana State University and the entire State of Louisiana for their dedication and support; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9d9668b0c3684bcc818c6b39d7c0e469"><enum>(4)</enum><text>respectfully requests that the Secretary of the Senate transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text><subparagraph id="idf59b399798d145a1ae85b939557af8da"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the head coach of the Louisiana State University baseball team, Jay Johnson;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida22eea96e542408e87aa2cf4e00dfe8b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Office of the President of Louisiana State University; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf08c6dc9eaac492b922fc87ff90f383e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the athletic director of Louisiana State University, Scott Woodward.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

