<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD819AFB5551E4F48B882A60C52E76DEA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3688 IH: Protecting Children from Experimentation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3688</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250603">June 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000375">Mr. Arrington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000609">Mr. Palmer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/110">chapter 110</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, to prohibit gender transition procedures on minors, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD7A13D6CA9074F838BD756C5A1A03C46" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6E9CA989A69B42A2AD3D5ADD09CB4304" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Children from Experimentation Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2EBC2FDCE1D64028ABFB0CD0C6B43B54"><enum>2.</enum><header>Gender transition procedures on minors prohibited</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/110">Chapter 110</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFAE6B718A8E24360BCE29964DBDE776E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H527ADCF69E434E33BADCC8AA02010290" style="USC"> <section id="HD46AC315547B4E2FA37D7AE6CBF50601"><enum>2260B.</enum><header>Gender transition procedures on minors</header> <subsection id="H1805ECBD7B5C4FCD8216391F3707B9CE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any physical or mental health care professional who, under the circumstances described in subsection (d), knowingly performs or otherwise aids and abets the performance of a gender transition procedure on a minor shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE893C4D7D23D4A0BA231D8A973AA2F3C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on prosecution of person on whom procedures are performed</header><text>No person on whom the gender transition procedure under subsection (a) is performed may be arrested or prosecuted for an offense under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H90FD4A424AE34685A158D5803548289C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil action</header><text>A person on whom a gender transition procedure is performed under this section may bring a civil action for appropriate relief against each person who performed the gender transition procedure.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7A974B73AD344E988D68CA666D7BD5C6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Circumstances described</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the circumstances described in this subsection are that—</text> <paragraph id="H2053325862DC45EC94BDDB8D56033D82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the defendant or minor traveled in interstate or foreign commerce, or traveled using a means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce, in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC7C82E64D6D540358FE503CF96AB3DAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the defendant used a means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD75F44193CAB447A94D831586BA4067B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any payment of any kind was made, directly or indirectly, in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (a) using any means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce or in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5DE5F3B5CD3D45FE8379E9A88546AE53"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the defendant transmitted in interstate or foreign commerce any communication relating to or in furtherance of the conduct described in subsection (a) using any means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce or in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce by any means or in manner, including by computer, mail, wire, or electromagnetic transmission;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5877A002FC4443E3A06D890C309B9EF5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any instrument, item, substance, or other object that has traveled in interstate or foreign commerce was used to perform the conduct described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEAC81D0DEF3D4CDDA2FC9F006067BDEF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the conduct described in subsection (a) occurred within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, or any territory or possession of the United States; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FB83EFCA5BD46BF84A07DCE0E06A440"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the conduct described in subsection (a) otherwise occurred in or affected interstate or foreign commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H08C2F355C5384A669C4EF50B867E6C2F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HFB2D453A19B942A790F6EDAF05D11C2D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Female</header><text>The term <quote>female</quote>, when used to refer to a natural person, means an individual who naturally has, had, will have, or would have, but for a congenital anomaly, historical accident, or intentional or unintentional disruption, the reproductive system that at some point produces, transports, and utilizes eggs for fertilization.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF856A5DAC694FC9923A66A0569A59EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Gender transition</header><text>The term <quote>gender transition</quote> means the process in which an individual goes from identifying with or presenting as his or her sex to identifying with or presenting a self-proclaimed identity that does not correspond with or is different from his or her sex, and may be accompanied with social, legal, or physical changes.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBAD7D5B484974289B10A10C47AB03CC1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Gender transition procedure</header> <subparagraph id="HBCD4B8CA772348659B55E70AF1BE8652"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>gender transition procedure</quote> means any hormonal or surgical intervention for the purpose of gender transition, including—</text> 
<clause id="H14C45F55CF3D477EBBD38195DF4E02C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>gonadotropin-releasing hormone (GnRH) agonists or other puberty-blocking or suppressing drugs to stop or delay normal puberty;</text></clause> <clause id="H3CB572A7C5F549499D61EF9F28F6CEA4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>testosterone, estrogen, progesterone, or other androgens to an individual at doses that are supraphysiologic to what would normally be produced endogenously in a healthy individual of the same age and sex;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA04FF37BC69946158ADEFDE7E3F9E7FF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>castration;</text></clause> <clause id="H36C554CFE8B14D3E917432758F0E57CD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>orchiectomy;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB2BC4DBCFFD74CE89A578810395912F2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>scrotoplasty;</text></clause> <clause id="HAE980982743441AB845A4DED9536F558"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>implantation of erection or testicular prostheses;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H251CD092220B4CF5AF014A64A553D019"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>vasectomy;</text></clause> <clause id="H9DD8384B98AB4A2C905B1F9ABF277778"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>hysterectomy;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H25F86F386CEC430EA447378E7B91C9CD"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>oophorectomy;</text></clause> <clause id="HD74B0335A8B447C4857C03D07236896F"><enum>(x)</enum><text>ovariectomy;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3A0B797782FC4840BC95CBDA22F79884"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>reconstruction of the fixed part of the urethra with or without a metoidioplasty or a phalloplasty;</text></clause> <clause id="H91E621216EB744A7812A7CCD4EE14B79"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>metoidioplasty;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE990C19D558E44A68CBB22916C90766D"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>penectomy;</text></clause> <clause id="H3F2CEF46A979445986AB484401304BF4"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>phalloplasty;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB4725517B39A42C392766EC2997C5F7C"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>vaginoplasty;</text></clause> <clause id="H33253479EB044116BAE22A6A702D5641"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text>clitoroplasty;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H077EA1CA3D29487BAAB883E04AB8282C"><enum>(xvii)</enum><text>vaginectomy;</text></clause> <clause id="HB145058F666342AA859023DD9931838D"><enum>(xviii)</enum><text>vulvoplasty;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H77085F3E520447D49951AC6EDED94BB4"><enum>(xix)</enum><text>reduction thyrochondroplasty;</text></clause> <clause id="H39A5C24976B44264BDD311F5D99EC8E5"><enum>(xx)</enum><text>chondrolaryngoplasty;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4E09E3B603324349A0BEAE218355743B"><enum>(xxi)</enum><text>mastectomy;</text></clause> <clause id="H49CD670B8519443E82005DCA3A01D953"><enum>(xxii)</enum><text>tubal ligation;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF022C5B45C7C4EDE9C5710AA6A65E481"><enum>(xxiii)</enum><text>sterilization;</text></clause> <clause id="HDBCA98C17F264A02B89F64651D860D13"><enum>(xxiv)</enum><text>any plastic, cosmetic, or aesthetic surgery that feminizes or masculinizes the facial or other physiological features of an individual;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2973F7A97C40417582C1481AC6C590BE"><enum>(xxv)</enum><text>any placement of chest implants to create feminine breasts;</text></clause> <clause id="H9F740E549AFB4D9F9DB7B81CB9599EE8"><enum>(xxvi)</enum><text>any placement of fat or artificial implants in the gluteal region;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1D28652C101F4B4CB996CE1874E0F562"><enum>(xxvii)</enum><text>augmentation mammoplasty;</text></clause> <clause id="HC61CDA8F8B2944AA8C5B36F9E96DD859"><enum>(xxviii)</enum><text>liposuction;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H77DC271D9F7E49428BAD264177CB7DD3"><enum>(xxix)</enum><text>lipofilling;</text></clause> <clause id="HD1ECAAD2E8574EF99C37DC7C1E817570"><enum>(xxx)</enum><text>voice surgery;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDDA8CBB106704CFFA2B239A314D41380"><enum>(xxxi)</enum><text>hair reconstruction;</text></clause> <clause id="H1B64E46B69E8419988DC28C00A635BAE"><enum>(xxxii)</enum><text>pectoral implants; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCECAA1B711DA4288B88E823E788063F0"><enum>(xxxiii)</enum><text>the removal of any otherwise healthy or non-diseased body part or tissue.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8971FB415EB24007AB1C97F8CA073BB5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <quote>gender transition procedure</quote> does not include the following when furnished to an individual by a health care provider with the consent of such individual or, if applicable, such individual’s parents or legal guardian:</text> 
<clause id="H1CCEDD8A828741BB9BB13A0D96765C4E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Services to individuals born with a medically verifiable disorder of sex development, including an individual with external sex characteristics that are irresolvably ambiguous, such as an individual born with 46 XX chromosomes with virilization, an individual born with 46 XY chromosomes with undervirilization, or an individual born having both ovarian and testicular tissue.</text></clause> <clause id="H57A76E66246F46E28F3C8121176304D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Services provided when a physician has otherwise diagnosed a disorder of sexual development in which the physician has determined through genetic or biochemical testing that the individual does not have normal sex chromosome structure, sex steroid hormone production, or sex steroid hormone action for a healthy individual of the same sex and age.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4D38570900F349018213EA4BA6B16CC8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The treatment of any infection, injury, disease, or disorder that has been caused by or exacerbated by the performance of gender transition procedures, whether or not the gender transition procedure was performed in accordance with State and Federal law or whether or not funding for the gender transition procedure is permissible under this section.</text></clause> <clause id="H2FF46310113F4A65BA75968C465157B3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Any procedure undertaken because the individual suffers from a physical disorder, physical injury, or physical illness (but not mental, behavioral, or emotional distress or a mental, behavioral, or emotional disorder) that would, as certified by a physician, place the individual in imminent danger of death or impairment of major bodily function, unless the procedure is performed.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H873667167E124877A4AFBBD07EC00980"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Puberty suppression or blocking prescription drugs for the purpose of normalizing puberty for a minor experiencing precocious puberty.</text></clause> <clause id="HA72B9B7AA160400D96BF3FCC38FDB9E7"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Male circumcision.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H105B919466B04CB28B5F7EC5C7732453"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Male</header><text>The term <quote>male</quote>, when used to refer to a natural person, means an individual who naturally has, had, will have, or would have, but for a congenital anomaly, historical accident, or intentional or unintentional disruption, the reproductive system that at some point produces, transports, and utilizes sperm for fertilization.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H13F40A1E185F44EB83ECB24A7150765F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Minor</header><text>The term <quote>minor</quote> means an individual under the age of 18.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF5AE3ACAE71E481081C8253D4734F4B9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Sex</header><text>The term <quote>sex</quote>, when referring to an individual’s sex, means to refer to either male or female, as biologically determined.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4431A42B3B3F4209819AF619340FE901"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending the table of sections for such chapter by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HAA8A2607F631484C82C131696CE2CAC0" style="USC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">2260B. Gender transition procedures on minors.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

