<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB0F13FD86B574D84B56E5E71FC3CA561" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1898 IH: Military Helicopter Training Safety Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1898</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250306">March 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to submit to Congress reports on the feasibility of installing traffic alert and collision avoidance systems and automatic dependent surveillance-broadcast IN capabilities in all military rotary-wing aircraft, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEA68A2ECC75A474BB9C83EEEE0B5F69D" style="OLC"><section id="H399E22C9EA8C47169736F721C1A5AFFF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military Helicopter Training Safety Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE02428C28012482E8C5E72F3511AAA38"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on feasibility of installing traffic alert and collision avoidance systems in all military rotary-wing aircraft</header><subsection id="HD02C1682C6F5463EA7858060F3624F93"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report on the feasibility of installing a traffic alert and collision avoidance system in each military rotary-wing aircraft. Such report shall include—</text><paragraph id="HFFE15E1E8B59493F98A54A050A680C86"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the cost associated with installing a traffic alert and collision avoidance system in each military rotary-wing aircraft;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79AF4B3D65AA45C7AE7684A345942BA0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an analysis of the effect of installing such systems in such aircraft on the safety of civilian airspace;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EC1CE11B53441999E91CDC6DCBCB0D5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an identification of any changes to the configuration of the cockpit of such aircraft that would be necessary in order to install such systems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8A0EE7A564548DCA2AB94AA91C32D4C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any implications the installation of such systems would have for combat, training, or domestic security operations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC580392DF56C4697B644B63E8989DBC6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>if the Secretary determines that the installation of such systems in such aircraft is not feasible, recommendations regarding similar systems or capabilities that could be installed instead.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H52E367529F6A4FE6BF8472685A3FFBC4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Traffic alert and collision avoidance system defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>traffic alert and collision avoidance system</quote> means a collision avoidance system in compliance with section 121.356 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</text></subsection></section><section id="H1D7DF637CFA04302ABB26E061C87F63F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on feasibility of installing automatic dependent surveillance–broadcast IN capabilities in all military rotary-wing aircraft</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report on the feasibility of installing automatic dependent surveillance–broadcast IN capability in each military rotary-wing aircraft. Such report shall include—</text><paragraph id="H70064FC398C6481E83C24DE1EBEEA611"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the cost associated with installing automatic dependent surveillance–broadcast IN capability in each military rotary-wing aircraft;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68B25211953D41B58F84A7E0432EF682"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an analysis of the effect of installing such capabilities in such aircraft on the safety of civilian airspace;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDB8E97963AF49DFA5EDC57806D7B2A1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an identification of any changes to the configuration of the cockpit of such aircraft that would be necessary in order to install such capabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B1C0F7E216F47B58F9FCE448E66594D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any implications the installation of such capabilities would have for combat, training, or domestic security operations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE5A5F3D386241298155664EA4D9439E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>if the Secretary determines that the installation of such capabilities in such aircraft is not feasible, recommendations regarding similar systems or capabilities that could be installed instead.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

