<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4465 IH: To amend chapters 4, 10, and 131 of title 5, United States Code, as necessary to keep those chapters current and to correct related technical errors.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4465</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20250716">July 16, 2025</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend chapters 4, 10, and 131 of title 5, United States Code, as necessary to keep those chapters current and to correct related technical errors.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H8B5EC8535449488B871FD8EA0D1873EE"> 
<section id="id15bbda72-67c8-40ed-bbda-7267c840ed60" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> <toc> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1. Table of contents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2. Purpose; effect on existing law.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 3. Amendments to chapters 4, 10, and 131 of title 5, United States Code.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 4. Subsequent amendments.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 5. Conforming amendments.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 6. Transitional and savings provisions.</toc-entry></toc></section> <section id="id22244e1a-f02a-477c-a44e-1af02a677c4e"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose; EFFECT ON existing law</header> <subsection id="idbe7a6d3f-2c6e-4033-ba6d-3f2c6e1033df"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to amend chapters 4, 10, and 131 of title 5, United States Code, as necessary—</text> 
<paragraph id="iduyktaewz-2jki-92qj-lpmw-gvj210i001c8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to keep those chapters current by incorporating laws enacted after October 19, 2021, that are deemed to amend or repeal provisions of those chapters pursuant to section 5 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/286">Public Law 117–286</external-xref> (136 Stat. 4360); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id31g1zr0e-isqg-84fp-a3w0-dbbo2hl5vyuw"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to correct related technical errors.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="idb3518503-1e57-48e7-9185-031e5728e764"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect on Existing Law</header><text>The amendments made by this Act do not change the meaning or effect of the existing law. The amendments only incorporate laws as described in subsection (a) to reflect existing law in chapters 4, 10, and 131 of title 5, United States Code, and correct related technical errors. </text></subsection></section> <section id="idd40w8p3g-gwu7-6mg0-olg8-fn02qn7971zv"><enum>3.</enum><header>Amendments to chapters 4, 10, and 131 of title 5, united states code</header> <subsection id="idhlpmpf7t-szlw-3176-n4tc-carlb2nc7tgk"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Chapter 4 of Title 5, United States Code</header> <paragraph id="idvaqqqp4b-umjd-7h5a-9gin-eozilk74bvfr"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Section 401</header> <subparagraph id="idyu193jzd-w1c1-oqjm-nouy-frwb2r3gm9fj"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 401 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<clause id="idklrqjcql-1mzo-fjzd-pr3t-kruh2so5nt67"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (4), and (5) as paragraphs (2), (3), (4), (5), and (6), respectively; and </text></clause> <clause id="idibo5vebv-hlva-sv3i-5ga4-na1m0t0eqrf5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (2), as redesignated, the following new paragraph (1):</text> 
<quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e105" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> 
<paragraph id="idhgd2z6ik-4v48-c94a-ufsz-ycol3hkp6w90"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="idr3zzeeoq-h22j-kv57-o0a1-ysvmvpki76u4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id27l6wwbz-9nzt-ma8j-bohp-ficn7ztu87o6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Oversight and Accountability of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idgs1jgzu9-zz10-3tmn-y8vq-d9ec8uvi73dm"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other relevant congressional committee or subcommittee of jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idwjpm67ec-2tok-uns7-cog6-0dzbocjrhk8n"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 401(5) of title 5, United States Code, as redesignated by subparagraph (A), is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e129" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> <paragraph id="idoejfhqe5-t1ia-hz05-08cy-a1w4b5qr65nl"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Inspector general</header><text>Except as otherwise expressly provided, the term <term>Inspector General</term> means the Inspector General of an establishment.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idratedv64-pbwg-oinu-4dup-dq99k6witfry"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Section 403</header> 
<subparagraph id="idua5yfcic-d0u6-hzm5-e26b-wzqcui4k78re"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 403(b) of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e144" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> <subsection id="idhn43qjp7-hn24-rlo2-uezs-d5g599c2y5sm"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Removal or Transfer</header> <paragraph id="idn83z1lbt-r736-as5t-zaln-1kkvbatj99uj"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority of president; written communication</header> <subparagraph id="idv3jyt4r0-wez9-jquq-0ijd-auzt8vsglceb"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An Inspector General may be removed from office by the President. If an Inspector General is removed from office or is transferred to another position or location within an establishment, the President shall communicate in writing the substantive rationale, including detailed and case-specific reasons, for any such removal or transfer to both Houses of Congress (including to the appropriate congressional committees), not later than 30 days before the removal or transfer. Nothing in this subsection shall prohibit a personnel action otherwise authorized by law, other than transfer or removal.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="iddp1hk4gz-4ae8-uw3z-3gkb-39ri70tortw1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Written communication requirements in case of open or completed inquiry</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If there is an open or completed inquiry into an Inspector General that relates to the removal or transfer of the Inspector General under subparagraph (A), the written communication required under that subparagraph shall—</text> <clause id="idw84c5rjs-qmzc-iy3p-65q2-qzcsmboduz6o"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identify each entity that is conducting, or that conducted, the inquiry; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idis2ohp74-84sq-1v4j-we0o-l1q1jvv26n14"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a completed inquiry, contain the findings made during the inquiry.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id1jamee3k-b8i4-q9ec-nl9c-z1gdn6ua5a3z"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Placement on non-duty status</header> <subparagraph id="id9hmtz2jl-v2wy-e1mh-70y3-9fw6ulze4a70"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definition of inspector general; certain references</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph:</text> 
<clause id="idylu4d992-qjkd-huab-obs2-rtu39nh1wypt"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Inspector general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Inspector General</term>—</text> <subclause id="idpo5p0zhl-bftz-ludz-20nf-l4mmu2ggwemt"><enum>(I)</enum><text>means an Inspector General who was appointed by the President, without regard to whether the Senate provided advice and consent with respect to that appointment; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="id5f4ka71e-lvfl-0z20-iem6-fgza8hh3qlwe"><enum>(II)</enum><text>includes the Inspector General of an establishment, the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, the Special Inspector General for the Troubled Asset Relief Program, and the Special Inspector General for Pandemic Recovery.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="id2ebhwdgu-viba-iog4-z487-40hi7uow0fn1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Certain references relating to removal or transfer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A reference to the removal or transfer of an Inspector General under paragraph (1), or to the written communication described in that paragraph, shall be considered to be—</text> 
<subclause id="idf80fpogn-vc2f-nehr-lfqk-u7tlwc9g3usc"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, a reference to section 1229(c)(6) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/181">Public Law 110–181</external-xref>, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/415">5 U.S.C. 415</external-xref> note);</text></subclause> <subclause id="id3dad3s87-5ra5-nhd2-3zga-05fhm5os7gp7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of the Special Inspector General for the Troubled Asset Relief Program, a reference to section 121(b)(4) of the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5231">12 U.S.C. 5231(b)(4)</external-xref>); and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="id3omq87yt-gdiz-9djj-yle6-rsuld8pl9gpj"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in the case of the Special Inspector General for Pandemic Recovery, a reference to section 4018(b)(3) of the Coronavirus Economic Stabilization Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9053">15 U.S.C. 9053(b)(3)</external-xref>).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idfzoh8yti-5wo6-flmw-79b8-nvjgd80d5ne7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authority of president</header><text>Subject to the other provisions of this paragraph, only the President may place an Inspector General on non-duty status.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idtti04ef3-klvs-zd34-gb6t-v41ja2vulesz"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Written communication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the President places an Inspector General on non-duty status, the President shall communicate in writing the substantive rationale, including detailed and case-specific reasons, for the change in status to both Houses of Congress (including to the appropriate congressional committees) not later than 15 days before the date on which the change in status takes effect, except that the President may submit that communication not later than the date on which the change in status takes effect if—</text> <clause id="idnhnjbp59-wztq-i38b-38aq-6bazm42qpc41"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the President has made a determination that the continued presence of the Inspector General in the workplace poses a threat described in any of clauses (i) through (iv) of section 6329b(b)(2)(A) of this title; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="id444sz3bt-kuih-57gk-12bd-mqdj00pn2yzo"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the communication, the President includes a report on the determination described in clause (i), which shall include—</text> <subclause id="idaz59wedl-qqth-9ahy-6380-g5bbbn82k088"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a specification of which clause of section 6329b(b)(2)(A) of this title the President has determined applies under clause (i) of this subparagraph;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idylkkcoz3-o2tm-f9oe-bmyk-24uyeynkt7il"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the substantive rationale, including detailed and case-specific reasons, for the determination made under clause (i);</text></subclause> <subclause id="idna2qispc-6b6q-wo7d-tbzc-6suyort9ijwn"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an identification of each entity that is conducting, or that conducted, any inquiry upon which the determination under clause (i) was made; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idzojn5z9h-dydw-uzo2-tcbh-5cfwb7btqmqc"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>in the case of an inquiry described in subclause (III) that is completed, the findings made during that inquiry.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id56z3azko-7qaz-zp0c-bqt2-68akgoyyelzz"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Placing inspector general on non-duty status during specified period before removal or transfer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may not place an Inspector General on non-duty status during the 30-day period preceding the date on which the Inspector General is removed or transferred under paragraph (1)(A) unless the President—</text> 
<clause id="idlhwfws4y-59oz-jr2w-z7d7-80bwhqu67wk4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has made a determination that the continued presence of the Inspector General in the workplace poses a threat described in any of clauses (i) through (iv) of section 6329b(b)(2)(A) of this title; and</text></clause> <clause id="idfoiqs3vt-lf7b-w5oa-zjqe-ysf61k4lakzg"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not later than the date on which the change in status takes effect, submits to both Houses of Congress (including to the appropriate congressional committees) a written communication that contains the information required under subparagraph (C), including the report required under clause (ii) of that subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idglqttnpb-yrz5-z9q7-z6a3-tcc2vyglgdjz"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 403(d)(1)(C) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <clause id="idamp6ad95-69uj-2fjc-j56d-eiebbr764zcm"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i), in the matter before subclause (I), by inserting <quote>, including employees of that Office of Inspector General</quote> after <quote>employees</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idzd65lctu-bayk-qf4q-55o2-ligzye1n0akz"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by inserting <quote>(including the Integrity Committee of that Council)</quote> after <quote>and Efficiency</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id4uwljwin-yz71-wv59-okia-u0g4ninitrgz"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 403 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e281" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> 
<subsection id="idfr7qc1zh-0n2n-1zw4-tb22-bsach22l1oiv"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Vacancy in Position of Inspector General</header> 
<paragraph id="idtkfjbtay-z6yv-z67f-6473-nzj0mhorifp4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="idvorvmny6-jqdw-rzpm-3q1p-fth7b8n821n2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>First assistant to the position of inspector general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>first assistant to the position of Inspector General</term> means, with respect to an Office of Inspector General—</text> 
<clause id="id2rde7mp4-2nb4-uhoq-89y2-2mldzgwr01vb"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individual who, as of the day before the date on which the Inspector General dies, resigns, or otherwise becomes unable to perform the functions and duties of that position—</text> <subclause id="idoqzvnnj8-3aw0-bsdw-kko4-2r6h2z8qcl9z"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is serving in a position in that Office; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idj04v7sqi-n2eg-e923-smmy-6p7j30jllcoz"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has been designated in writing by the Inspector General, through an order of succession or otherwise, as the first assistant to the position of Inspector General; or</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="idlik1ej18-vh1l-i128-y0k3-3s67eoovwij1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the Inspector General has not made a designation described in clause (i)(II)—</text> 
<subclause id="ide0kpy46g-z270-f8re-zs2z-pkz71p8mmv5e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Principal Deputy Inspector General of that Office, as of the day before the date on which the Inspector General dies, resigns, or otherwise becomes unable to perform the functions and duties of that position; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="idtj9dzsvu-31wo-2luc-6qz7-yj8mocmuk2cr"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if there is no Principal Deputy Inspector General of that Office, the Deputy Inspector General of that Office, as of the day before the date on which the Inspector General dies, resigns, or otherwise becomes unable to perform the functions and duties of that position.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idrutlhdi9-vh3b-wg65-92sk-7m5csoe5zmg4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inspector general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Inspector General</term>—</text> <clause id="idt7ys0gpl-plyw-juyw-zw1a-c9sehcw3p754"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means an Inspector General who is appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idhuactko7-ae23-m8kf-myrg-4q82z1g6suyb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes the Inspector General of an establishment, the Special Inspector General for the Troubled Asset Relief Program, and the Special Inspector General for Pandemic Recovery.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id1q3zjzsz-upv6-yqn9-k94e-nalvaiqsqpk2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Death, resignation, or inability to perform functions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an Inspector General dies, resigns, or is otherwise unable to perform the functions and duties of the position—</text> 
<subparagraph id="idzj07z5m1-ad4d-4a88-fe4g-ugmvv84i0gg7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 3345(a) of this title and section 103(e) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3025">50 U.S.C. 3025(e)</external-xref>) shall not apply;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idwpy2k1ju-jtyh-6dk2-if8d-zqhngbssqq57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to paragraph (4), the first assistant to the position of Inspector General shall perform the functions and duties of the Inspector General temporarily in an acting capacity subject to the time limitations of section 3346 of this title; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idv42nw1oc-b0a0-migv-h13f-zza6i2y8l5h6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding subparagraph (B), and subject to paragraphs (4) and (5), the President (and only the President) may direct an officer or employee of any Office of an Inspector General to perform the functions and duties of the Inspector General temporarily in an acting capacity subject to the time limitations of section 3346 of this title only if—</text> <clause id="idlsqct830-0ifs-wr58-waic-ngejm058yc6n"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">during the 365-day period preceding the date of death, resignation, or beginning of inability to serve of the Inspector General, the officer or employee served in a position in an Office of an Inspector General for not less than 90 days, except that—</text> 
<subclause id="idjmh1al97-z928-3umj-i8ju-eotuolwoycv4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the requirement under this clause shall not apply if the officer is an Inspector General; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="idg38jilt6-7uot-lv2c-felv-bhhm2zwjp8t9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for the purposes of this subparagraph, performing the functions and duties of an Inspector General temporarily in an acting capacity does not qualify as service in a position in an Office of an Inspector General;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="id1g2qldk3-2cr3-9y3a-5nm6-zdjit1ay184v"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the rate of pay for the position of the officer or employee described in clause (i) is equal to or greater than the minimum rate of pay payable for a position at GS-15 of the General Schedule;</text></clause> <clause id="id35qvudcr-6d7a-4qdj-19fk-ljvzk2vbzbii"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the officer or employee has demonstrated ability in accounting, auditing, financial analysis, law, management analysis, public administration, or investigations; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idb2vmqazi-eiyv-m4dw-67is-rcpzk0dsiins"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>not later than 30 days before the date on which the direction takes effect, the President communicates in writing to both Houses of Congress (including to the appropriate congressional committees) the substantive rationale, including the detailed and case-specific reasons, for the direction, including the reason for the direction that someone other than the individual who is performing the functions and duties of the Inspector General temporarily in an acting capacity (as of the date on which the President issues that direction) perform those functions and duties temporarily in an acting capacity.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id3494orz4-gqmq-506p-b97n-1azjnkwa2yd7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Non-duty status</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 3345(a) of this title, and subparagraphs (B) and (C) of paragraph (2), and subject to paragraph (4), during any period in which an Inspector General is on non-duty status—</text> 
<subparagraph id="idjsjzpybf-it7k-ev14-3ou4-hab93wq162rz"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the first assistant to the position of Inspector General shall perform the functions and duties of the position temporarily in an acting capacity subject to the time limitations of section 3346 of this title; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="ido9dt20fs-vvj8-84ab-ihk2-h9stvzqto5i5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the first assistant described in subparagraph (A) dies, resigns, or becomes otherwise unable to perform those functions and duties, the President (and only the President) may direct an officer or employee in that Office of Inspector General to perform those functions and duties temporarily in an acting capacity, subject to the time limitations of section 3346 of this title, if—</text> 
<clause id="idjmtsuc2k-jy6k-8avr-v9d3-je3saela879w"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that direction satisfies the requirements under clauses (ii), (iii), and (iv) of paragraph (2)(C); and</text></clause> <clause id="idjtblrtcq-mm6u-g9ph-jh7a-5f6izdy2y6nr"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that officer or employee served in a position in that Office of Inspector General for not fewer than 90 of the 365 days preceding the date on which the President makes that direction.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idmhlwvuhh-qi89-4j2o-37m9-rgef7tc2lr57"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Acting capacity for 1 inspector general position at a time</header><text>An individual may perform the functions and duties of an Inspector General temporarily and in an acting capacity under subparagraph (B) or (C) of paragraph (2), or under paragraph (3), with respect to only 1 Inspector General position at any given time.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idlirq80ik-9zcl-ivgl-0ayb-11w5c7o1j5re"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Thirty-day period before president’s direction takes effect</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the President makes a direction under paragraph (2)(C), during the 30-day period preceding the date on which the direction of the President takes effect, the functions and duties of the position of the applicable Inspector General shall be performed by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="idov6w9jbf-rm85-wy86-yofl-nizolbzvgpon"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the first assistant to the position of Inspector General; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="ida2oc8knb-2oui-qi6i-ok0i-lv30gjj1zu1n"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the individual performing those functions and duties temporarily in an acting capacity, as of the date on which the President issues that direction, if that individual is an individual other than the first assistant to the position of Inspector General.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id8fcjnv5t-b449-qtjo-inss-entm32qtmo7b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Section 404</header> 
<subparagraph id="id57c92qoz-ik9u-n42e-z2t1-jrpkc1ctlogz"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 404(a)(2) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <clause id="idcz5saeoa-zoa8-mvsy-1bsa-z0tvdarc67j7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, including’’ after ‘‘to make recommendations</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idqo0gwvan-d3uf-abjy-g5lb-ks30gwch0h6d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting a comma after <quote>section 405(b) of this title</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idf711amuy-83rz-je09-kz2c-65l7u34jezrk"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 404(b)(1)(C) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>paragraph (1)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (A)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id9hutjite-yol0-7a3n-zi5i-tfjrnagn8qdk"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Section 405</header><text>Section 405 of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e451" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> <section id="idwvkjcsja-s5yh-jg3j-q45z-rywcszf2gity"><enum>405.</enum><header>Reports</header> <subsection id="idd36cdwev-nng9-npzm-qew4-qv0ozed5e1s5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="id0c6cro5r-flpo-r2ot-w1yz-wti5b7y1p23j"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disallowed costs</header><text>The term <term>disallowed cost</term> means a questioned cost that management, in a management decision, has sustained or agreed should not be charged to the Government.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id0vdhl8yu-b876-mzzf-3t6f-puwicehrf1ln"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>final action</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="idi4aszpjk-vqk0-8col-ttq4-jcz0w0lwm9jc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the completion of all actions that the management of an establishment has concluded, in its management decision, are necessary with respect to the findings and recommendations included in an audit report; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id80tg9ego-m4ta-ss6p-htsj-gj39d214r0de"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the event that the management of an establishment concludes no action is necessary, final action occurs when a management decision has been made.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idn4rd3nwh-36hf-gy93-yerv-zrwvz4jobpv7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Management decision</header><text>The term <term>management decision</term> means the evaluation by the management of an establishment of the findings and recommendations included in an audit report and the issuance of a final decision by management concerning its response to the findings and recommendations, including actions concluded to be necessary.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id6mzkq6j4-q3zz-iejo-1t9r-plzm90obro28"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Questioned cost</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>questioned cost</term> means a cost that is questioned by the Office because of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="idfvkbb73d-5u04-zlun-as5q-eatpzcsaajy5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an alleged violation of a provision of a law, regulation, contract, grant, cooperative agreement, or other agreement or document governing the expenditure of funds;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idfv9dee4k-f9cm-u2he-7wzb-pje6udw73kno"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a finding that, at the time of the audit, the cost is not supported by adequate documentation; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idi152s9p0-2bd4-83ab-svf3-o2cv8nu7m76i"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a finding that the expenditure of funds for the intended purpose is unnecessary or unreasonable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id5m9wzzal-v4iu-96zn-b64u-zbplups6djht"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Recommendation that funds be put to better use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>recommendation that funds be put to better use</term> means a recommendation by the Office that funds could be used more efficiently if management of an establishment took actions to implement and complete the recommendation, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="idzzu0yl6j-aps2-668e-i9ra-zp39mr1piaj5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reductions in outlays;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idsuwznd57-76gg-pp59-ko4k-qgozru9k8kto"><enum>(B)</enum><text>deobligation of funds from programs or operations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idz7nfii9k-v78s-vz5h-bz5h-75gc1taueozo"><enum>(C)</enum><text>withdrawal of interest subsidy costs on loans or loan guarantees, insurance, or bonds;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idadgty7c2-g5dc-gp3k-fgu9-m8zvr8yz3b78"><enum>(D)</enum><text>costs not incurred by implementing recommended improvements related to the operations of the establishment, a contractor, or grantee;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idi4vjkftq-6pzf-05vv-aee1-zippqumc6h2l"><enum>(E)</enum><text>avoidance of unnecessary expenditures noted in preaward reviews of contract or grant agreements; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idn8gwnbh4-dfel-d0p5-0diq-y2c5bkal4utr"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other savings which are specifically identified.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idwf2dm4jv-tjk7-acaj-lmzb-4latz5g0gsog"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Senior government employee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>senior Government employee</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="idc8rth6bk-1o47-tb1k-j6l8-zdd9erj7ovzc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an officer or employee in the executive branch (including a special Government employee as defined in section 202 of title 18) who occupies a position classified at or above GS–15 of the General Schedule or, in the case of positions not under the General Schedule, for which the rate of basic pay is equal to or greater than 120 percent of the minimum rate of basic pay payable for GS–15 of the General Schedule; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idj7y6avw7-iksn-81p1-5fo3-mpvgk4c23wn2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any commissioned officer in the Armed Forces in pay grades O–6 and above.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id1fvizdqj-0m8d-zmtv-59v3-ncp2a5l068vt"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Unsupported cost</header><text>The term <term>unsupported cost</term> means a cost that is questioned by the Office because the Office found that, at the time of the audit, such cost is not supported by adequate documentation.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="ido6ll4c48-9gt9-zg0g-wgmv-5zcwc8isezjg"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Semiannual Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Inspector General shall, not later than April 30 and October 31 of each year, prepare semiannual reports summarizing the activities of the Office during the immediately preceding 6-month periods ending March 31 and September 30. The reports shall include, but need not be limited to—</text> <paragraph id="id7zrebivj-yc2o-g34z-c5e3-wc48wydgg374"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of significant problems, abuses, and deficiencies relating to the administration of programs and operations of the establishment and associated reports and recommendations for corrective action made by the Office;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idr1rguwd8-gv0u-c2wr-8oc7-pvpyr4hbnesq"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an identification of each recommendation made before the reporting period, for which corrective action has not been completed, including the potential costs savings associated with the recommendation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idrz6j93s3-rtyh-0kuq-h200-regltqfd44i5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a summary of significant investigations closed during the reporting period;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idhpqviv6j-oshw-mbqt-5vlv-lpir95yh0q11"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an identification of the total number of convictions during the reporting period resulting from investigations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id13ezv6ju-azol-15fh-d48w-41p3iut9wfz9"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information regarding each audit, inspection, or evaluation report issued during the reporting period, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="id6m4aq2z6-l2qb-amp3-1he8-tajupooasui3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a listing of each audit, inspection, or evaluation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idbazwwsok-os4h-5jtv-i2v8-dl6brt5ogpzo"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if applicable, the total dollar value of questioned costs (including a separate category for the dollar value of unsupported costs) and the dollar value of recommendations that funds be put to better use, including whether a management decision had been made by the end of the reporting period;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idpotrowas-6nth-uec9-sezg-u4ny5wouz5iy"><enum>(6)</enum><text>information regarding any management decision made during the reporting period with respect to any audit, inspection, or evaluation issued during a previous reporting period;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idjrzlkkpl-nvl0-2wba-anqg-aw8b7u5skzwb"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the information described under section 804(b) of the Federal Financial Management Improvement Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/208">Public Law 104–208</external-xref>, §101(f) [title VIII], <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3512">31 U.S.C. 3512</external-xref> note);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id5orj4tv3-yppn-yb92-v5dc-zh2wle6dsy8g"><enum>(8)</enum> 
<subparagraph id="id2yz8o21e-hk9j-ww38-03rk-0ij60t8ygfnz" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an appendix containing the results of any peer review conducted by another Office of Inspector General during the reporting period; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idtkw64z6m-ducq-o9yz-kfue-2btonl2ui7d7" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if no peer review was conducted within that reporting period, a statement identifying the date of the last peer review conducted by another Office of Inspector General;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id5g4girdz-5ctp-8s26-tyng-csf3sdrbtjy0"><enum>(9)</enum><text>a list of any outstanding recommendations from any peer review conducted by another Office of Inspector General that have not been fully implemented, including a statement describing the status of the implementation and why implementation is not complete;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id6dnr2ypn-5gls-mhi5-ayla-zjk1rrvf2qjz"><enum>(10)</enum><text>a list of any peer reviews conducted by the Inspector General of another Office of the Inspector General during the reporting period, including a list of any outstanding recommendations made from any previous peer review (including any peer review conducted before the reporting period) that remain outstanding or have not been fully implemented;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id69ejvrep-4m4p-dycl-2qqn-zzpuh5zbv79z"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">statistical tables showing—</text> <subparagraph id="idd8ou61wj-jfsq-2i74-d00c-48bq0yv0h5z7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total number of investigative reports issued during the reporting period;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idtzq2f2wp-8c2m-d1co-syfi-ul7gs7rzwwy1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total number of persons referred to the Department of Justice for criminal prosecution during the reporting period;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id0h9qy7l7-iq4h-i4yc-91eo-zdyntlqkzzdp"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the total number of persons referred to State and local prosecuting authorities for criminal prosecution during the reporting period; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id6hsbpl80-ufaq-dabr-ofru-brspmz0phf2q"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the total number of indictments and criminal informations during the reporting period that resulted from any prior referral to prosecuting authorities;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="idc50qbozz-aqgl-jo22-suoz-1yps6rsot43s"><enum>(12)</enum><text>a description of the metrics used for developing the data for the statistical tables under paragraph (11);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idl88z4mt8-c1t0-ptwa-nzwu-rljrq9198s59"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a report on each investigation conducted by the Office where allegations of misconduct were substantiated involving a senior Government employee or senior official (as defined by the Office) if the establishment does not have senior Government employees, which shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="idm2ms1ar2-1vjf-45bp-msdw-646vdvvujj0d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name of the senior Government employee, if already made public by the Office; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id45ypc6i0-mhkk-s946-lfol-blh40mwz1zwz"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detailed description of—</text> <clause id="ide74fj36z-8s7a-zo00-kufr-6dcio5vzi2ed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the facts and circumstances of the investigation; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idrw56qo1b-njk2-k5v2-72l6-edsjb1tunzqa"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the status and disposition of the matter, including—</text> <subclause id="idmbjk24dy-bwck-z3to-zpoz-k06z912veusy"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if the matter was referred to the Department of Justice, the date of the referral; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idmrcz062y-zslu-vht4-u8wn-u7gruwj9ui5j"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the Department of Justice declined the referral, the date of the declination;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="idjbp09sfz-6yw2-kz9u-iehj-umzr3um6o8zt"><enum>(14)</enum> <subparagraph id="id0kf459ry-3mzu-2hkz-o00t-fqw88edc0grw" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a detailed description of any instance of whistleblower retaliation, including information about the official found to have engaged in retaliation; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idmmn1f000-o6ld-ybdu-yqa7-ytuo7fc2t5sp" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>what, if any, consequences the establishment actually imposed to hold the official described in subparagraph (A) accountable;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="iddnwztsw7-wbfg-p19w-nfqv-fzvd2av8l8iu"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information related to interference by the establishment, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="idg8vozu5o-za8m-l2qf-v9kb-1vge99l2o0ij"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detailed description of any attempt by the establishment to interfere with the independence of the Office, including—</text> <clause id="idr6npq2lo-zpvb-jwzz-vv8t-sho9ci310z7t"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with budget constraints designed to limit the capabilities of the Office; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idjqg67459-8tty-606j-raj6-jap8tehflkls"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>incidents where the establishment has resisted or objected to oversight activities of the Office or restricted or significantly delayed access to information, including the justification of the establishment for such action; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idddk62ec4-pclw-gzmg-rlre-yd2bcu6ldh6v"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a summary of each report made to the head of the establishment under section 406(c)(2) of this title during the reporting period; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idtbnp7pwe-69hh-zne8-zprw-2navllge6m9g"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">detailed descriptions of the particular circumstances of each—</text> <subparagraph id="id78cl3ucu-e52d-3oyg-p5er-82spa0y2ifvl"><enum>(A)</enum><text>inspection, evaluation, and audit conducted by the Office that is closed and was not disclosed to the public; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id9ejz1mjv-tfm7-otmb-cqd3-c3wnwcqwp9zj"><enum>(B)</enum><text>investigation conducted by the Office involving a senior Government employee that is closed and was not disclosed to the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="idcfphb4wy-22jw-07v6-afik-oerrkav0zufv"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Furnishing Semiannual Reports to Head of Establishment and Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Semiannual reports of each Inspector General shall be furnished to the head of the establishment involved not later than April 30 and October 31 of each year and shall be transmitted by the head of the establishment to the appropriate congressional committees within 30 days after receipt of the report, together with a report by the head of the establishment containing—</text> 
<paragraph id="idaunosb6j-qf1r-go7o-1rgd-6h8zilzi3u9i"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any comments the head of the establishment determines appropriate;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idrb5i8ndz-28oc-ae2r-mm0j-a0nw6y9meeb5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">where final action on audit, inspection, and evaluation reports had not been taken before the commencement of the reporting period, statistical tables showing—</text> 
<subparagraph id="idkkr0cdr0-2z7o-0huz-d9r5-r6emlea25w24"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to management decisions—</text> <clause id="idims1pirb-zylq-scg9-gqb5-23yp71i2spiu"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for each report, whether a management decision was made during the reporting period;</text></clause> 
<clause id="id3m63u2gt-mk70-dki3-47ns-hd42dejs0qh0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if a management decision was made during the reporting period, the dollar value of disallowed costs and funds to be put to better use as agreed to in the management decision; and</text></clause> <clause id="idwci777rv-fug5-5yyw-yv3u-aqe2nc8gl8in"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the total number of reports where a management decision was made during the reporting period and the total corresponding dollar value of disallowed costs and funds to be put to better use as agreed to in the management decision; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idaoln0rw4-us4h-aq9s-l1po-5yr4or6bum5t"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to final actions—</text> <clause id="idnpevei4v-nesm-p37l-adry-qsgjpqynw3ch"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whether, if a management decision was made before the end of the reporting period, final action was taken during the reporting period;</text></clause> 
<clause id="idnh4l5f30-8me7-u5th-zsy0-ft1wd9jsz51q"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if final action was taken, the dollar value of—</text> <subclause id="id4lee3oyr-bgh2-0uyq-ej4q-9yy5gtdshzll"><enum>(I)</enum><text>disallowed costs that were recovered by management through collection, offset, property in lieu of cash, or otherwise;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idoyeogej5-zvr4-23vr-yl1n-vczv6h7o37ff"><enum>(II)</enum><text>disallowed costs that were written off by management;</text></subclause> <subclause id="id798jh8rz-375m-1wnb-vhbg-u7gf4zki9m6w"><enum>(III)</enum><text>disallowed costs and funds to be put to better use not yet recovered or written off by management;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idfdh6hvt9-iew1-o1fz-w0tk-6qvywo8w5lel"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>recommendations that were completed; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="idocv1ojkn-8ly5-602k-bnm9-j1guqzs0z8i4"><enum>(V)</enum><text>recommendations that management has subsequently concluded should not or could not be implemented or completed; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="ida2a3zrc5-6zim-9qeg-6lh8-nnpecfdr4zv5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the total number of reports where final action was not taken and the total number of reports where final action was taken, including the total corresponding dollar value of disallowed costs and funds to be put to better use as agreed to in the management decisions;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="idgm3sf9u4-jdni-k7ig-5nr7-vadwzbz33mu6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>whether the establishment entered into a settlement agreement with the official described in subsection (b)(14)(A), which shall be reported regardless of any confidentiality agreement relating to the settlement agreement; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id4w4rmuor-t2mw-8shk-e2m3-hug6b8bndszo"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a statement explaining why final action has not been taken with respect to each audit, inspection, and evaluation report in which a management decision has been made but final action has not yet been taken, except that such statement—</text> <subparagraph id="idhc8z2pdp-8wl5-ad11-enlz-vmpmri1z1efv"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may exclude reports if—</text> 
<clause id="ids76sept1-9wdi-fofa-a5r3-rr43type1aoc"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a management decision was made within the preceding year; or</text></clause> <clause id="iduqi7vynj-ehsy-ewr6-rod4-vdg2s2v4yw4q"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the report is under formal administrative or judicial appeal or management of the establishment has agreed to pursue a legislative solution; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idk8lvi3fv-2uoz-1v8v-crnf-ejzvmg2yrl8a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall identify the number of reports in each category so excluded.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="id9bb0krmm-b2r4-69oz-cdnz-5a46tl1thkd4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports Available to Public</header><text>Within 60 days of the transmission of the semiannual reports of each Inspector General to Congress, the head of each establishment shall make copies of the report available to the public upon request and at a reasonable cost. Within 60 days after the transmission of the semiannual reports of each establishment head to Congress, the head of each establishment shall make copies of the report available to the public upon request and at a reasonable cost.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="idgpoigk1d-g0vu-ftqs-m9v1-130dfkbw0s0f"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting Serious Problems, Abuses, or Deficiencies</header><text>Each Inspector General shall report immediately to the head of the establishment involved whenever the Inspector General becomes aware of particularly serious or flagrant problems, abuses, or deficiencies relating to the administration of programs and operations of the establishment. The head of the establishment shall transmit any such report to the appropriate congressional committees within 7 calendar days, together with a report by the head of the establishment containing any comments the establishment head deems appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="idh4ikhp5h-oavc-te3b-n1uu-mzwr8h9jizge"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Additional Reports Relating to Serious Problems, Abuses, or Deficiencies</header> <paragraph id="ido7gli7rr-93em-uccu-zyno-1585ry88bgzz"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report to inspector general</header><text>The Chairperson of the Integrity Committee of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency shall, immediately whenever the Chairperson of the Integrity Committee becomes aware of particularly serious or flagrant problems, abuses, or deficiencies relating to the administration of programs and operations of an Office of Inspector General for which the Integrity Committee may receive, review, and refer for investigation allegations of wrongdoing under section 424(d) of this title, submit a report to the Inspector General who leads the Office at which the serious or flagrant problems, abuses, or deficiencies were alleged.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idgslt57ee-zeqq-s5hy-zq2c-48ar1wfdpw93"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to president, congress, and the establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 7 days after the date on which an Inspector General receives a report submitted under paragraph (1), the Inspector General shall submit to the President, the appropriate congressional committees, and the head of the establishment—</text> <subparagraph id="idjrdzzama-pmzt-p6te-l3uu-i4q6j8t2lzzp"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the report received under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idudfuu9hc-n1vc-vrlq-3l4v-vwkduk3kj17s"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a report by the Inspector General containing any comments the Inspector General determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="idlrqzae8v-zyna-izr1-mncn-59ji486f4cm1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Submission of Information on Work Being Conducted by the Office When There Is Change in Status of Inspector General</header> <paragraph id="idl404zwce-idop-y0gn-qob0-8d3llg09fzn8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), not later than 15 days after an Inspector General is removed, placed on paid or unpaid nonduty status, or transferred to another position or location within an establishment, the officer or employee performing the functions and duties of the Inspector General temporarily in an acting capacity shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees information regarding work being conducted by the Office as of the date on which the Inspector General was removed, placed on paid or unpaid non-duty status, or transferred, which shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="idwizu8wa0-6ayk-t6vi-lezi-7nyo8haqbzfj"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each investigation—</text> <clause id="idu7gzjg4y-gt0c-gjrv-beyl-1uecvja6zk3j"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the type of alleged offense;</text></clause> 
<clause id="idipzu8rs9-7pj5-ovof-gh1s-igqckk2tzaa0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the fiscal quarter in which the Office initiated the investigation;</text></clause> <clause id="id18utcebp-tkzj-udzz-psbo-ymwzziydmz02"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the relevant Federal agency, including the relevant component of that Federal agency for any Federal agency listed in section 901(b) of title 31, under investigation or affiliated with the individual or entity under investigation; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="id3npyis51-zveh-sd7a-qfak-cg45ll5wsn9i"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>whether the investigation is administrative, civil, criminal, or a combination thereof, if known; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idmzf2iygd-scda-qjtj-64sc-e2bm0699hlde"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for any work not described in subparagraph (A)—</text> 
<clause id="id7s38h2vw-zgqg-c67p-ansd-8rb32tlcbuua"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the subject matter and scope;</text></clause> <clause id="idzj0lzzhf-hvsn-k89k-gq0e-61fd87vz92iu"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the relevant agency, including the relevant component of that Federal agency, under review;</text></clause> 
<clause id="idtskv65y9-v6e0-ui8q-nwck-rl2yl0ug0uzz"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the date on which the Office initiated the work; and</text></clause> <clause id="id2hmjs7qh-t44b-uqwr-z41h-j8khvidvj9i4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the expected time frame for completion.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idevg3odd9-ewks-91ol-kilt-z7ttc2bp3vgz"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Intelligence community</header><text>With respect to an inspector general of an element of the intelligence community specified in section 415(d)(2) of this title, the submission required by paragraph (1) shall only be made to the committees of Congress specified in section 415(d)(2)(E) of this title.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="idgketr81u-29f9-t76j-j3ah-k89omw5iu5oi"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Limitation on Public Disclosure of Information</header> <paragraph id="idwfpn0nz6-ezvk-rora-tiqc-vc4wvz0cv55o"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the public disclosure of information that is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="idklvfkjqi-fdi8-sl1v-u0i7-v7imw4uzzw19"><enum>(A)</enum><text>specifically prohibited from disclosure by any other provision of law;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idechf163m-elzw-j7qs-jrp7-jkzy87qjasj9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specifically required by Executive order to be protected from disclosure in the interest of national defense or national security or in the conduct of foreign affairs; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idvu2ls83w-2oot-m7mz-3d0v-ss683q5izk4z"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a part of an ongoing criminal investigation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="idtejzvz7l-zin1-zp2v-71kz-eq0tmler4l0e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criminal investigation information in public records</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1)(C), any report under this section may be disclosed to the public in a form which includes information with respect to a part of an ongoing criminal investigation if such information has been included in a public record.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id0aqs5wq4-fz6v-u3gu-wfqs-5h4u0e865gwo"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disclosures to congress</header><text>Except to the extent and in the manner provided under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103(f)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">26 U.S.C. 6103(f)</external-xref>), nothing in this section or in any other provision of this chapter shall be construed to authorize or permit the withholding of information from Congress, or from any committee or subcommittee of Congress.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id8y3oyfpr-yzb5-gtt1-2l95-ir8uovl23ty9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Provision of information to members of congress</header><text>Subject to any other provision of law that would otherwise prohibit disclosure of such information, the information described in paragraph (1) may be provided to any member of Congress upon request.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idon2dsmc6-gggt-21dh-pbu6-pu60a1p7brq2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Protection of personally identifiable information of whistleblowers</header><text>An Office may not provide to Congress or the public any information that reveals the personally identifiable information of a whistleblower under this section unless the Office first obtains the consent of the whistleblower.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id2nuz282t-tzic-nbsl-95e1-s8zfzogv6n1m"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Notification of, and submission of written response by, non-governmental organizations and business entities identified in reports</header> <subparagraph id="idrsb6mf89-uhyr-4nz3-dyeq-7utc8lbtuz13"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), if an audit, evaluation, inspection, or other non-investigative report prepared by an Inspector General specifically identifies a specific non-governmental organization or business entity, whether or not the non-governmental organization or business entity is the subject of that audit, evaluation, inspection, or non-investigative report—</text> 
<clause id="id10tmb24w-ut14-ij90-btq7-16c6hl233ewz"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Inspector General shall notify the non-governmental organization or business entity;</text></clause> <clause id="idkh3bfk45-u4br-jbbw-6u0b-kcpw0l9dgaz9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the non-governmental organization or business entity shall have—</text> 
<subclause id="id4zoskrq0-nrzc-8pn6-hted-1yf6gv383r0i"><enum>(I)</enum><text>30 days to review the audit, evaluation, inspection, or non-investigative report beginning on the date of publication of the audit, evaluation, inspection, or non-investigative report; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="iday3on2hl-yjm5-zp0s-zyqm-m7w4vj38hw0o"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the opportunity to submit a written response for the purpose of clarifying or providing additional context as it directly relates to each instance wherein an audit, evaluation, inspection, or non-investigative report specifically identifies that non-governmental organization or business entity; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="id41yq5fig-bawk-9u2z-z31y-onurnp5sjfkz"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if a written response is submitted under clause (ii)(II) within the 30-day period described in clause (ii)(I)—</text> <subclause id="iduil99icz-0mo8-m821-8u98-68hjopfbjzdh"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the written response shall be attached to the audit, evaluation, inspection, or non-investigative report; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="id9fmgfzmb-2g9f-0aez-gz7t-tsp72pm6ssn4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in every instance where the report may appear on the public-facing website of the Inspector General, the website shall be updated in order to access a version of the audit, evaluation, inspection, or non-investigative report that includes the written response.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idlzqic4wb-gzsz-osl3-299l-w7wf15zulu36"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inapplicability to non-governmental organization and business entities that refused to provide assistance</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to a non-governmental organization or business entity that refused to provide information or assistance sought by an Inspector General during the creation of the audit, evaluation, inspection, or non-investigative report.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idvv11gl5y-aq5a-gcwn-0bub-kfitjhzn80lg"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Review of written response</header><text>An Inspector General shall review any written response received under subparagraph (A) for the purpose of preventing the improper disclosure of classified information or other non-public information, consistent with applicable laws, rules, and regulations, and, if necessary, redact such information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="id0h7koj83-saoe-ijmm-7e5s-nsnaqdz5a75n"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Online Publication; Links</header><text>If an Office has published any portion of the report or information required under subsection (b) to the website of the Office or on oversight.gov, the Office may elect to provide links to the relevant webpage or website in the report of the Office under subsection (b) in lieu of including the information in that report.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id86z3mr5c-61eu-486s-tl7z-kgwqczqe98qq"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Section 406</header> 
<subparagraph id="idhzj8t24z-03da-8hta-h3tk-f9t1poimu18g"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 406(c) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1010" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> <paragraph id="iduk2fl0j8-anze-8ado-jfuy-50ufsmrik94w"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice to congressional committees</header><text>If the information or assistance that is the subject of a report under paragraph (2) is not provided to the Inspector General by the date that is 30 days after the report is made, the Inspector General shall submit a notice that the information or assistance requested has not been provided by the head of the establishment involved or the head of the Federal agency involved, as applicable, to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idgit86ara-44bt-vhg8-y9y1-c0469gpcq98j"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 406(f)(3) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>Veterans’</quote> and inserting <quote>Veterans</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idlyv8sb22-nf88-nutj-macw-i20hovly4sim"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Subparagraphs (B) and (C) of section 406(h)(4) of title 5, United States Code, are amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1025" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> 
<subparagraph id="idhwuw9cbj-f145-n203-y7so-l9zzj5ody0sf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Committee on Oversight and Accountability, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idnagdpn0m-vayh-vnz3-z1z4-c8fnp8kaosb4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any other relevant congressional committee or subcommittee of jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idj9wboy17-otg4-nla5-qgtt-zcs5zlpudl1p"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 406(j) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <clause id="id0i882pzf-3lzj-gdza-z4r7-im1m3bz5vzgw"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>section 552a(a) of title 5</quote> and inserting <quote>section 552a(a) of this title</quote>; and </text></clause> 
<clause id="idkoe46n0d-i9ew-3hqz-izck-bm566l931lfj"><enum>(ii)</enum><text> by striking <quote>section 552a of title 5</quote> and inserting <quote>section 552a of this title</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="idylqhmalw-8ftm-tbgz-d24w-rql5046rgigv"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Section 408</header> <subparagraph id="idu2r0qcs1-kvtn-zznj-iu5e-0ghff89doad1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 408(b)(3) of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1056" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> 
<paragraph id="ide6paw4r3-qck7-9duo-0obf-ffnsurv76i5c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Statement concerning exercise of power</header><text>If the Secretary of Defense exercises any power under paragraph (1) or (2), the Inspector General shall submit a statement concerning that exercise of power within 30 days to the appropriate congressional committees, including the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idltfua76z-kjn0-nuuf-uliz-o457ioagtjci"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 408(b)(4) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>and to other appropriate committees or subcommittees</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id7y0a4z1j-ug2a-gscb-yteb-rc67qe1yuuhc"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 408(f)(1) (matter before subparagraph (A)) of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1071" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> <paragraph id="id7mj024bc-4zwr-ozv9-juud-0nznctvlt0ok"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports transmitted to congressional committees</header><text>Each semiannual report prepared by the Inspector General of the Department of Defense under section 405(b) of this title shall be transmitted by the Secretary of Defense to the appropriate congressional committees, including the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives. Each report shall include—</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id81mmkrjl-bzjh-4fry-2zib-hfykhv603ult"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Section 408(f)(2) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>committees or subcommittees of the Congress</quote> and inserting <quote>congressional committees</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id1ovbb4hi-oa1z-v7sp-vlo9-q3miuomzc44q"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Section 412</header> <subparagraph id="id968k2ucj-cw2e-30vn-1aqe-wid8z7iv53w1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 412(a)(3) of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1092" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> 
<paragraph id="idmeqplrfu-1yi5-51y7-owf9-mmza1982i3ip"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notification and statement of reasons for exercise of power</header><text>If the Secretary of the Treasury exercises any power under paragraph (1) or (2), the Secretary of the Treasury shall notify the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury in writing, stating the reasons for such exercise. Within 30 days after receipt of any such notice, the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury shall transmit a copy of such notice to the appropriate congressional committees, including the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id6lbij134-aap9-5dle-a67l-wr9tw65r77zz"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 412(g)(1) of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1103" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> 
<paragraph id="idzf2i5udw-1218-cqnt-zsm8-37ircopu6ivv"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports to congressional committees</header><text>Any report required to be transmitted by the Secretary of the Treasury to the appropriate congressional committees under section 405(e) of this title shall also be transmitted, within the 7-day period specified under such section, to the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id6zziyvzf-a7k4-kuot-9wf5-cz51bcgv8fdu"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 412(g)(2) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>committees or subcommittees of Congress</quote> and inserting <quote>congressional committees</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idtph9zyvz-om1p-wapm-we6z-nz3lbd9flj6p"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 412(j) (matter before paragraph (1)) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <clause id="id73lgzv28-8rsr-yazk-64sw-o5g360tw8qcs"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 403(d)(1)(B)(i) of this title (or, effective November 27, 2017, section 403(d)(2)(B)(i) of this title)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 403(d)(1)(A) of this title</quote>; and </text></clause> 
<clause id="idszss7zzd-v3pv-n9ur-0tro-kph081p2utyg"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 403(d)(1)(B)(ii) of this title (or, effective November 27, 2017, section 403(d)(2)(B)(ii) of this title)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 403(d)(1)(B) of this title</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="idmm4jamne-h8z6-gvb4-82pu-ndqv9ohz89t8"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Section 413</header> <subparagraph id="id0zmtju6g-8hi7-fnza-i135-meqnvz81j3ui"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 413(a)(3) of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1135" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> 
<paragraph id="id3500e4u1-hmfy-tdi5-y0v2-u8yzz77dbos5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notification and statement of reasons for exercise of power</header><text>If the Attorney General exercises any power under paragraph (1) or (2), the Attorney General shall notify the Inspector General in writing, stating the reasons for such exercise. Within 30 days after receipt of any such notice, the Inspector General shall transmit a copy of such notice to the appropriate congressional committees, including the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idnnewzww0-617z-jive-4f56-3rq8grltregu"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 413(c) of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1147" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> 
<subsection id="id4j0779do-h1kv-zyr6-jw8a-nwtgrqfkajdk"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Any report required to be transmitted by the Attorney General to the appropriate congressional committees under section 405(e) of this title shall also be transmitted, within the 7-day period specified under that section, to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id0i9qb9yn-alia-o4vt-3z4r-iq0bbfhqwtyz"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Section 415</header> <subparagraph id="idop9e3zst-4mzm-u7p8-i4ab-jr9isov20kp2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 415(a)(1)(A) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>the Postal Regulatory Commission,</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idfo56mcfz-oa0z-aalv-vuut-zdpvl3jdc8gp"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 415(e) of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1166" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> <subsection id="idj3jakurz-ehlo-fg0e-t33t-b6k4sqvfhaqz"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Removal</header> <paragraph id="id0zlc7lsg-7va9-qqmi-s5ez-1hkhkbtztpzk"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Board, chairman of committee, or commission is head of designated federal entity</header><text>In the case of a designated Federal entity for which a board, chairman of a committee, or commission is the head of the designated Federal entity, a removal or placement on non-duty status under this subsection may only be made upon the written concurrence of a 2/3 majority of the board, committee, or commission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idml6583tc-qvon-egh4-4nzy-yzdzaeg7cnhe"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inspector general removed or transferred</header> 
<subparagraph id="idw1vuee8b-5azz-8ore-3wgp-1wh2qcwppbrr"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If an Inspector General is removed from office or is transferred to another position or location within a designated Federal entity, the head of the designated Federal entity shall communicate in writing the substantive rationale, including detailed and case-specific reasons, for any such removal or transfer to both Houses of Congress (including to the appropriate congressional committees), not later than 30 days before the removal or transfer. Nothing in this subsection shall prohibit a personnel action otherwise authorized by law, other than transfer or removal.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id34liofbm-vzrv-du10-zpva-va7fc8a6homp"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Written communication requirements in case of open or completed inquiry</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If there is an open or completed inquiry into an Inspector General that relates to the removal or transfer of the Inspector General under subparagraph (A), the written communication required under that subparagraph shall—</text> 
<clause id="idhdf09cli-cza3-whif-eqtz-yszf9tn6ubi8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identify each entity that is conducting, or that conducted, the inquiry; and</text></clause> <clause id="idrqwz73qj-ddjh-y8n8-uh1p-vov0cegy1qal"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a completed inquiry, contain the findings made during the inquiry.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="iddt9a4yf0-ggr9-77zt-eoky-y34olnab3izt"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inspector general placement on non-duty status</header> 
<subparagraph id="ida8622zgd-03ls-7snl-ekvc-67hz3zqwram8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authority of covered official</header><text>Subject to the other provisions of this paragraph, only the head of the applicable designated Federal entity (referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>covered official</quote>) may place an Inspector General on non-duty status.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idr1ahy5qn-ihcs-cewz-tz34-q3dz8l1uqrbs"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Written communication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a covered official places an Inspector General on non-duty status, the covered official shall communicate in writing the substantive rationale, including detailed and case-specific reasons, for the change in status to both Houses of Congress (including to the appropriate congressional committees) not later than 15 days before the date on which the change in status takes effect, except that the covered official may submit that communication not later than the date on which the change in status takes effect if—</text> 
<clause id="idpvh6dpc5-zvy8-gaka-2g8w-0a9flqzm4rsm"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the covered official has made a determination that the continued presence of the Inspector General in the workplace poses a threat described in any of clauses (i) through (iv) of section 6329b(b)(2)(A) of this title; and</text></clause> <clause id="idg1z1ug1o-idgi-shs3-59wa-9whpc7vkmmy2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the communication, the covered official includes a report on the determination described in clause (i), which shall include—</text> 
<subclause id="id5qk2iko2-m7z6-l6q2-ic1u-02cdd4ap5fws"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a specification of which clause of section 6329b(b)(2)(A) of this title the covered official has determined applies under clause (i) of this subparagraph;</text></subclause> <subclause id="idlh8hdc8z-i00q-9zm1-1037-duzazerwn51g"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the substantive rationale, including detailed and case-specific reasons, for the determination made under clause (i);</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idljooiqkj-p3if-go5s-jh0k-5fs8ssp5akch"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an identification of each entity that is conducting, or that conducted, any inquiry upon which the determination under clause (i) was made; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="idgrf6rt7q-zz7c-g6zo-dggz-nhb2z3jezbqz"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>in the case of an inquiry described in subclause (III) that is completed, the findings made during that inquiry.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idnhb6lk7o-hbcm-3trg-dgi6-2tiqzhtpvs9z"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Placing inspector general on non-duty status during specified period before removal or transfer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered official may not place an Inspector General on non-duty status during the 30-day period preceding the date on which the Inspector General is removed or transferred under paragraph (2)(A) unless the covered official—</text> <clause id="id9fj4jiag-twdl-a3r9-tlra-k862p2zcfew1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has made a determination that the continued presence of the Inspector General in the workplace poses a threat described in any of clauses (i) through (iv) of section 6329b(b)(2)(A) of this title; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idavrsengn-47i6-n9ze-dngt-iqias5zlpz1v"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not later than the date on which the change in status takes effect, submits to both Houses of Congress (including to the appropriate congressional committees) a written communication that contains the information required under subparagraph (B), including the report required under clause (ii) of that subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idcjb6niuu-6vq8-l356-n10k-wehfo6gf50sw"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Construction relating to protections and authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to limit or otherwise modify—</text> 
<clause id="id9y0twj0r-tzq0-367k-kyo1-8i9zl32nrtl8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any statutory protection that is afforded to an Inspector General; or</text></clause> <clause id="id59zw8ner-3r1m-nwjy-s995-ga9bgrh0yzah"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other action that a covered official may take under law with respect to an Inspector General.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idgd5v5ton-4j8q-39k7-fz6j-8tvl5njb88zl"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 415(f)(2) of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1275" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> <paragraph id="id41z6mwz6-yiw8-6cgc-w1jb-kazoszrkfnmj"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Oversight responsibilities of inspector general</header> <subparagraph id="idwv79tovo-o7dq-gejc-6mh9-pfqtwuzua4vp"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Postal inspection service</header><text>In carrying out the duties and responsibilities specified in this chapter, the Inspector General of the United States Postal Service (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Inspector General</quote>) shall have oversight responsibility for all activities of the Postal Inspection Service, including any internal investigation performed by the Postal Inspection Service. The Chief Postal Inspector shall promptly report the significant activities being carried out by the Postal Inspection Service to such Inspector General.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idpqpkfke5-mntk-o68h-1h8f-mq2berc7ltef"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Postal regulatory commission</header><text>In carrying out the duties and responsibilities specified in this chapter, the Inspector General shall function as the Inspector General for the Postal Regulatory Commission, and shall have equal responsibility over the United States Postal Service and the Postal Regulatory Commission. The Postal Regulatory Commission shall comply with the Inspector General’s oversight as if the Postal Regulatory Commission were a designated Federal entity under subsection (a)(1) and as if the Inspector General were the inspector general of the Postal Regulatory Commission. The Governors of the Postal Service shall not direct oversight activities for the Postal Regulatory Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="ide24cnmpy-50al-agfj-oig2-pn1r038fbgz7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Section 415(f)(3)(A)(i) (matter before subclause (I)) of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1295" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> 
<clause id="idzu9kvf8h-5hsn-kibb-6iz2-875jpwsnzf9z"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Access to sensitive information</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (d), the Inspector General shall be under the authority, direction, and control of the Governors with respect to audits or investigations, or the issuance of subpoenas, pertaining to the United States Postal Service, which audits, investigations, and subpoenas require access to sensitive information concerning—</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idcelow1s9-8tkp-5hd1-35zq-qn3svr8gm9ef"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Section 415(f)(3)(A)(iii) of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1306" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> 
<clause id="idcspztq9u-0rq7-924k-j93h-p426wzfj6yh8"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Notification of reasons for exercise of power</header><text>If the Governors exercise any power under clause (i) or (ii), the Governors shall notify the Inspector General in writing, stating the reasons for such exercise. Within 30 days after receipt of any such notice, the Inspector General shall transmit a copy of such notice to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idvkc0bqvz-g3z5-i6s3-btsy-t1q21yzo9bdv"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Section 415(f)(3)(B)(i) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>and the Postal Regulatory Commission</quote> after <quote>United States Postal Service</quote>. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idons7u0sy-ubgl-tirz-i0bu-hyvuc0k0a24k"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Section 415(f)(3) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking subparagraph (C). </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id068pi9oi-53rq-odpi-3r47-gitqmzuthr9a"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 415(f) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<clause id="iduvlmeo3s-7y4k-hy5c-0tnc-bkgnhcsz6dn0"><enum>(i)</enum><text> by redesignating paragraphs (4), (5), and (6) as paragraphs (5), (6), and (7), respectively; and</text></clause> <clause id="id163b7hm7-1ppl-ntel-zwwr-g7ogzwu6lowd"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1334" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> 
<paragraph id="idkbubuz4q-60r9-tpdj-lcy5-ytg1hues92b6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Applicability to activities pertaining to the postal regulatory commission</header><text>For activities pertaining to the Postal Regulatory Commission, sections 404, 405, 406 (other than subsection (g)), and 407 of this title shall be applied by substituting the term <term>head of the Postal Regulatory Commission</term> for <quote>head of the establishment</quote>.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="idnq4lwzk3-tnrh-2gez-dvhf-d1vz9egi0t4z"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Section 416</header><text>Section 416(a) of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1347" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> 
<subsection id="idi7yq4drf-rf1q-0por-qlg4-cmql4ic9q2sg"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions; Authority To Determine Whether Complaint or Information Is a Matter of Urgent Concern</header> 
<paragraph id="idlfs9k6yy-2qr8-lbvs-m2lv-swk4w88sm083"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <subparagraph id="id57sntzi0-gs1a-1pl2-iazt-07n6nots6gfn"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Intelligence committees</header><text>The term <term>intelligence committees</term> means the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idt8u5phvp-8ekh-orf9-0im7-nwnev41wb662"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Urgent concern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>urgent concern</term> means any of the following:</text> <clause id="id7jbn94vn-azpw-1k7h-1jti-29ylc3gg2fyo"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A serious or flagrant problem, abuse, violation of law or Executive order, or deficiency relating to the funding, administration, or operations of an intelligence activity of the Federal Government that is—</text> 
<subclause id="idtosplkg2-9om9-ktcz-nyuo-p7p9gpz5wyyh"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a matter of national security; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="id2o81mni7-1nws-4oqw-8rr1-jqrr19cnsku6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not a difference of opinion concerning public policy matters.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="idyi9t51ra-o965-d0j4-b1p4-4bhk18giv4n9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A false statement to Congress, or a willful withholding from Congress, on an issue of material fact relating to the funding, administration, or operation of an intelligence activity.</text></clause> <clause id="id3w3uv2z2-wzys-9owg-eua9-4l2zhc8pzzzd"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>An action, including a personnel action described in section 2302(a)(2)(A) of this title constituting reprisal or threat of reprisal prohibited under section 407(c) of this title in response to an employee's reporting an urgent concern in accordance with this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="iddsuu14gw-m36c-jc4y-d0um-lrdyckg4vilm"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority to determine whether complaint or information is a matter of urgent concern</header><text>Within the executive branch, an Inspector General to whom any complaint or information is reported under this section shall have sole authority to determine whether the complaint or information is a matter of urgent concern under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="idplsuzcpy-ze0o-kp0k-r90p-7jtk5g7cbmb0"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Section 417</header> <subparagraph id="idemjo28el-kb6g-b6zl-b49r-ql4lekipgvf1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 417(a)(3) (matter before subparagraph (A)) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>committees and subcommittees of Congress</quote> and inserting <quote>congressional committees</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idkd2jn0n3-76ma-zsbp-ybwu-tnt1h72dr74q"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 417(d) of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1408" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> <subsection id="id7eh3qccn-lm73-9rla-d3pa-y9j7zkziyjv1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Any report required to be transmitted by the Secretary of Homeland Security to the appropriate congressional committees under section 405(e) of this title shall be transmitted, within the 7-day period specified in section 405(e) of this title, to the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and appropriate congressional committees.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id1kd7b562-jes5-iprv-0e5f-mar2ehk85se1"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Section 419</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 419 of title 5, United States Code, is amended as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="idbs3382tw-4e42-6zs9-gsf8-mvvc36hcvpeb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 419(a)(2) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 113(n) of title 10</quote> and inserting <quote>section 113(o) of title 10</quote>. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idsi2vk5bn-sg11-m4z6-vjo2-skeibykzd4yd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 419(d)(1)(A) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>overeas</quote> and inserting <quote>overseas</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idzwg1r7z6-sln3-32w0-pzal-2d6yjal7cedz"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 419(d)(1)(B) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 113(n) of title 10</quote> and inserting <quote>section 113(o) of title 10</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idj86em5ed-qzq2-fkjk-6qkb-ip5jo7fefoc0"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 419(d)(5) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <clause id="id3mp0kwny-hjhu-wkqt-r981-t1ozmcm0fv19"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">Ccompetitive</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">Competitive</header-in-text></quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="idnhruz22z-awff-zitq-2bfi-hv7urdfiuw6g"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>a lead Inspector General for</quote> and inserting <quote>any of the Inspectors General specified in subsection (c) for oversight of</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="idn3yiqik5-yszp-thjv-oiec-ziett7vhoh22"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>December 19, 2019</quote> and inserting <quote>December 20, 2019</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idqp5tbr4b-sugk-rt6u-ds6g-g5irrssu7mml"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Section 421</header><text>Section 421(b) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>committees of Congress</quote> and inserting <quote>congressional committees</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idcmqcyzz5-g8ji-h4sk-wr1n-lekgsevc0rwh"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Section 424</header> <subparagraph id="id94zt2o48-7m8p-6kmm-sj9p-phhpl6awkbua"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 424(b)(3)(B)(viii) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<clause id="idygt3h83v-glmm-zz6p-6yl5-1t5ni5y7lj5l"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking subclauses (III) and (IV);</text></clause> <clause id="id6bbntupw-jwph-ptjo-mib4-oe31ina32nle"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idsbfb08e6-vnig-2js6-rmzi-furrzl59rusq"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by amending subclause (II) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1483" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> <subclause id="idyyjm9v0h-1qf3-4asi-5sre-fb6isc5izmfh"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the appropriate congressional committees.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id1j059n8k-s0mm-55ij-kqt2-ytw9vzv8zlh0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 424(c)(1) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <clause id="idr521digj-c3i3-3s3c-reav-d9mee8t56zmq"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (E) through (I) as subparagraphs (F) through (J), respectively; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="id8fr22k35-n6zh-mcjt-g4mf-cqa8to8pqofl"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (D) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1502" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> <subparagraph id="id5j40d1ju-f6pj-6t5t-iosf-9ag4g35j6n55"><enum>(E)</enum><text>support the professional development of Inspectors General, including by providing training opportunities on the duties, responsibilities, and authorities under this chapter and on topics relevant to Inspectors General and the work of Inspectors General, as identified by Inspectors General and the Council.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idu9zvyjme-81q5-mnmu-ppwk-pgcmj3e7qtjn"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 424(c)(3) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1512" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> <subparagraph id="id6cfp76kk-s5ge-f7l9-2saa-fwj9292cvi9r"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Report on expenditures</header><text>Not later than November 30 of each year, the Chairperson shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees, including the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, a report on the expenditures of the Council for the preceding fiscal year, including from direct appropriations to the Council, interagency funding pursuant to subparagraph (A), a revolving fund pursuant to subparagraph (B), or any other source.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idkvbojzlo-653r-tgzz-pgtj-ss4ssh8p0thz"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Section 424(c)(5)(B) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>, allegations of reprisal,</quote> and inserting <quote>and allegations of reprisal (including the timely and appropriate handling and consideration of protected disclosures and allegations of reprisal that are internal to an Office of Inspector General)</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idjsoe77z6-7p2f-afka-m7vd-7asgowezd7j4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Section 424(d)(5)(B)(ii) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, the length of time the Integrity Committee has been evaluating the allegation of wrongdoing, and a description of any previous written notice provided under this clause with respect to the allegation of wrongdoing, including the description provided for why additional time was needed.</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idtjbz46kv-3izi-m2no-6f3u-r9c948i6azyl"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Section 424(d)(5)(B) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1531" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> <clause id="idpzjqqm6z-pms1-6ue8-euvn-fdzv3ekye21u"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Availability of information to congress on certain allegations of wrongdoing closed without referral</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an allegation of wrongdoing made by a member of Congress that is closed by the Integrity Committee without referral to the Chairperson of the Integrity Committee to initiate an investigation, the Chairperson of the Integrity Committee shall, not later than 60 days after closing the allegation of wrongdoing, provide a written description of the nature of the allegation of wrongdoing and how the Integrity Committee evaluated the allegation of wrongdoing to—</text> 
<subclause id="idc2w2o5ud-hc8r-ucg8-nfqj-ewhzaw7zfh29"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Chair and Ranking Minority Member of the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="id146t0qlk-jmq7-zwpl-ag5b-h3vjoilk3lon"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Chair and Ranking Minority Member of the Committee on Oversight and Accountability of the House of Representatives.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idjjlor47q-opub-yrj3-g5am-8f10us17a70b"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Section 424(d)(7)(B)(i)(V) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>, and that an investigation of an Office of Inspector General of an establishment is conducted by another Office of Inspector General of an establishment</quote> after <quote>size</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idze0kt6zv-so9f-jk9q-svez-11mljfp28h6w"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Section 424(d)(8)(A)(ii) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>or corrective action</quote> after <quote>disciplinary action</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idrq4bajzf-gzqn-jbua-zqpe-dir7z1nam5zm"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Section 424(d)(8)(A)(iii) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>to the</quote> and all that follows through <quote>jurisdiction</quote> and inserting <quote>to the appropriate congressional committees</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idbu65si6v-rjqd-zvmf-t9bt-incrzqv0oh4z"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Section 424(d)(8)(B) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>and the appropriate congressional committees</quote> after <quote>Integrity Committee</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id6c2n5lz2-uwfw-zhna-300h-73njhzanhbed"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Section 424(d)(9) of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1568" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> <paragraph id="ids3lo89yk-ng2b-v7zt-lwsy-2qcdb6ti4wuo"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Semiannual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On or before May 31, 2023, and every 6 months thereafter, the Council shall submit to Congress and the President a report on the activities of the Integrity Committee during the immediately preceding 6-month periods ending March 31 and September 30, which shall include the following with respect to allegations of wrongdoing that are made against Inspectors General and staff members of the various Offices of Inspector General described in paragraph (4)(C):</text> 
<subparagraph id="idftywbodb-yvvp-w5bj-z3jn-vvy7cjyjor9h"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An overview and analysis of the allegations of wrongdoing disposed of by the Integrity Committee, including—</text> <clause id="idr7u0yjoj-ooiv-zgh0-qdbm-wz0gzsshbce7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>analysis of the positions held by individuals against whom allegations were made, including the duties affiliated with such positions;</text></clause> 
<clause id="idbr8j4prg-iq3r-tb8h-2kzl-0szrrv61dur0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>analysis of the categories or types of the allegations of wrongdoing; and</text></clause> <clause id="id0mqbq9w1-vfvq-tn0e-0ahr-y4f9vl4dwkml"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a summary of disposition of all the allegations.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id4vc4uv8j-8ebo-o540-ntze-elwwumc8a2dl"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of allegations received by the Integrity Committee.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id5trqt3lh-gjto-2905-9he3-mzjzh9l6qpwm"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The number of allegations referred to the Department of Justice or the Office of Special Counsel, including the number of allegations referred for criminal investigation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id6ofzie4g-8uff-mz65-nkqn-g8nzzkesa04q"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The number of allegations referred to the Chairperson of the Integrity Committee for investigation, a general description of the status of such investigations, and a summary of the findings of investigations completed.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id810w9zk2-icgl-mfz0-tv1c-ukh305ee7dch"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An overview and analysis of allegations of wrongdoing received by the Integrity Committee during any previous reporting period, but remained pending during some part of the 6 months covered by the report, including—</text> 
<clause id="idry9r3rpp-i95a-by6b-wrhj-e1i9nzaqqze2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>analysis of the positions held by individuals against whom allegations were made, including the duties affiliated with such positions;</text></clause> <clause id="idfbni8y2t-wg0b-tjqb-6meo-ornutsj89puq"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>analysis of the categories or types of the allegations of wrongdoing; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idoqfb9uom-3pbt-7kj2-2ka5-ogdbf7hcjjj3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a summary of disposition of all the allegations.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idvauugq9e-vrc4-sjjs-z5cw-2fdboa27sndm"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The number and category or type of pending investigations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="ids0fjayg8-ujf5-792y-rvpz-7217fftfy8qs"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each allegation received—</text> <clause id="id4jpzp9m6-g3fn-i52r-rutj-z6zp93d1p4gj"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date on which the investigation was opened;</text></clause> 
<clause id="idfa830k34-1nez-a9ac-3c6f-pz8gf22576vp"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date on which the allegation was disposed of, as applicable; and</text></clause> <clause id="idkog1wc3h-nsvt-ppyq-7hvn-3rlos4blrnok"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the case number associated with the allegation.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id51banksn-ez9h-6qhh-buqj-v9jbeknuzfqt"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The nature and number of allegations to the Integrity Committee closed without referral, including the justification for why each allegation was closed without referral.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idh183gpg9-t64n-cs1o-sm2u-oud798h29p7g"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A brief description of any difficulty encountered by the Integrity Committee when receiving, evaluating, investigating, or referring for investigation an allegation received by the Integrity Committee, including a brief description of—</text> 
<clause id="idelrzct6z-9i61-iys7-rq90-pf0w7izwlkp8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any attempt to prevent or hinder an investigation; or</text></clause> <clause id="id9cfgbc66-34op-iciu-7ezr-e8vrpweh3qt2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>concerns about the integrity or operations at an Office of Inspector General.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id4inoaudj-4cz9-95rq-hckf-w9yga9n274n0"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Other matters that the Council considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="idtau505oo-kcs8-h2tc-ooy9-flpone9sau84"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Chapter 10 of Title 5, United States Code</header><text>Section 1013(a)(2)(A) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>Government</quote> and inserting <quote>Government,</quote>. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="id7vhh8wrk-ctzt-6bgy-v1nk-1c5cp5688t7s"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chapter 131 of Title 5, United States Code</header> 
<paragraph id="idcfczz5nt-l6mr-qmwv-y7sg-a0g7i7o8f5zw"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Section 13104</header><text>Section 13104(f)(4)(B)(i)(III) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>paragraphs (3)(C)(iii) and (iv) of this subsection</quote> and inserting <quote>clauses (iii) and (iv) of paragraph (3)(C) of this subsection</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idg3a2j5zs-owme-rch5-z7z4-aa04zvqhgbl6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Section 13105</header> <subparagraph id="idlbvaerk0-wyzf-thqd-k9de-mhfghwre4b02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 13105(l) (matter before paragraph (1)) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting a closing parenthesis after <quote>section 13104(a)(5)(B</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id5cu0vz8m-bkbg-t8bj-6ib7-lderd34b3hfc"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 13105(l) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <clause id="idj4zyqfb3-1ej1-vkcp-4izk-usi9ffm8rmaz"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking <quote>, as defined under section 13101 of this title</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="id4njw1dc4-korw-ive0-kw8c-9pmunkl32h24"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (10)—</text> <subclause id="idbzkhkw6c-7kuy-1y4b-nmz1-hbuqw4j83cva"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the Congress</quote> and inserting <quote>Congress</quote>; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idmy20qoqu-z669-dtio-zndo-zlmq3p5kvn7z"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, as defined under section 13101 of this title</quote>.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id2h566izu-1n9h-1uj4-fomr-29k5npli92oc"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 13105(l) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1712" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> 
<paragraph id="idkfmzubmv-papv-t81f-skw4-qhyk1vy94qda"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Each judicial officer.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idjc67kr8p-irag-hhww-9pw7-3if6aoi1zucj"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Each bankruptcy judge appointed under section 152 of title 28.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idg7hbwbje-9zvr-bk9v-fm39-hmghjq4ysccj"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Each United States magistrate judge appointed under section 631 of title 28.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id0d65trga-hbnv-3ae0-v3ja-qozgm5m3q3fd"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Section 13107</header> <subparagraph id="idnb15gk5a-da6q-3n73-wnyh-dpwfuyf1j3t3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 13107(b)(3)(A) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>described in paragraph (9) or (10) of section 13101 of this title</quote> and inserting <quote>who is a judicial officer or a judicial employee</quote>. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="ida3rhzl75-45h2-njwh-u6fk-rzfrbiuo54ey"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 13107 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <clause id="idh9ieacqf-g0rk-0dgq-m77v-fijfo3zznz0a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) and (d) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idzcvzycbd-j59l-yke7-vke7-avhj088lsje1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text> by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1748" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> <subsection id="idktg086bz-4j1d-it60-0dv2-oeb6cgkl0pmz"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Online Publication of Financial Disclosure Reports of Federal Judges</header> <paragraph id="id5pld2kqj-dmyq-nbfg-9hfk-umuaekm2pmbd"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment of database</header><text>Subject to paragraph (4), not later than 180 days after May 13, 2022, the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall establish a searchable internet database to enable public access to any report required to be filed under this subchapter by a judicial officer, bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idfe75iled-z5t8-hz98-8t92-n61n2zh2jpsl"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which a report is required to be filed under this subchapter by a judicial officer, bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge, the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall make the report available on the database established under paragraph (1) in a full-text searchable, sortable, and downloadable format for access by the public.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="ida9rmv20z-9h3q-b8ze-youy-kgquf3djp7uw"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Redaction</header><text>Any report made available on the database established under paragraph (1) shall not contain any information that is redacted in accordance with subsection (b)(3).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idn7c8h6z5-4y6q-q7r5-r4ua-8s6risdzccl7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Additional time</header> 
<subparagraph id="idd5lwe0ap-nqgl-jffw-uz93-wmemu8as2kaq"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the requirements of this subsection may be implemented after the date described in paragraph (1) if the Administrative Office of the United States Courts identifies in writing to the relevant committees of Congress the additional time needed for that implementation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id7pytzeff-m4kh-b3k7-tlgt-z2f65suduocj"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Publication requirement</header><text>The Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall continue to make the reports described in paragraph (1) available to the public during the period in which the Administrative Office of the United States Courts establishes the database under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id6lqoopj0-60tf-n6us-0jzd-dkjdok3093vi"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Section 13109</header><text>Section 13109(a)(1) of title 5, United States Code, is amended in the last sentence by striking <quote>and (d)</quote> and inserting <quote>and (e)</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="idaf47jc68-4zo8-pke2-lmkj-7rwrtd4zlrez"><enum>4.</enum><header>Subsequent amendments</header> <subsection id="id9wlw54k2-13no-5peo-vloi-01da1tww485g"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Section 405(<enum-in-header>c</enum-in-header>) of Title 5</header> <paragraph id="idzl1zy0tz-cnud-368j-ljh8-43tfd4dbzqgs"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amendments by the Law Enforcement And Victim Support Act of 2024</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 405(c) of title 5, United States Code, as amended by section 3(a)(4), is further amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="idcjj5gkm0-9dgj-spih-gfnw-l67t4el7r22g"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="ide95hfng0-naka-rqzc-cf1h-ow5ttpibka5j"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (5); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idgplpb57h-2o9j-vvwe-kaqj-ojvus51bokzq"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1817" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> <paragraph id="id8zhz6zqm-99dw-pj6p-zvl6-bji9kevubc7t"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information relating to cases under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/38">chapter 38</external-xref> of title 31, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="idyv0k16cw-vo10-k5ja-roh4-isyh6v7ww34a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of reports submitted by investigating officials to reviewing officials under section 3803(a)(1) of title 31;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idge3ajvjg-2k9n-2cpq-aj3a-6ulof272p7vh"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">actions taken in response to reports described in subparagraph (A), which shall include statistical tables showing—</text> 
<clause id="idzubiaztr-ny0i-9pch-5dju-wvt14cay345o"><enum>(i)</enum><text>pending cases;</text></clause> <clause id="idfv3577s4-2z5l-k5be-k4ty-dzldocnd3lgv"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>resolved cases;</text></clause> 
<clause id="idz778zost-wfrn-lphz-72lu-80jz8in5lgbw"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the average length of time to resolve each case;</text></clause> <clause id="id9sa69k93-ecjm-1nmt-7mp8-t14j4n6vhnw7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the number of final agency decisions that were appealed to a district court of the United States or a higher court; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="id5bc9goe0-ooki-uul5-0kf8-ephcb40a2ycd"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the total number of cases in a report is greater than 2—</text> <subclause id="idvkj42ffw-22wj-zihu-ra9b-kwb1wagnlfsw"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of cases that were settled; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idqiuqzi0y-hrry-gqjg-n98e-v5y5co9iaj0f"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the total penalty or assessment amount recovered in each case, including through a settlement or compromise; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idv9aji6v3-y3g9-vny6-wlr3-q0ho85ues4jn"><enum>(C)</enum><text>instances in which the reviewing official declined to proceed on a case reported by an investigating official; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idlvijfn4q-pdnz-13tn-je6g-lmuqb5yby19b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Repeal of similar amendment; effective date</header> 
<subparagraph id="idwn5j8wg5-1vo2-zejy-sztn-y1vbspbs1b77"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Repeal of prior similar amendment</header><text>Effective on December 23, 2024, section 5203(e) of the Law Enforcement And Victim Support Act of 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/159">Public Law 118–159</external-xref>, div. E, title LII, subtitle A, 138 Stat. 2441) is repealed. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="iduphbcmit-l20k-leub-r4qv-t6d36k9z2nkz"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall take effect as if enacted on December 23, 2024.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="id7vdqydwu-84ml-oe47-79v6-rb2fneq6zroz"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Section 413 of Title 5</header> 
<paragraph id="ide85zetye-3wwt-iint-6kim-2o4z7eqwit23"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amendment by the federal prison oversight act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 413 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: </text> <quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e1886" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> <subsection id="idmr7to9ow-u3s8-zefd-um2u-yd7w5pzqpctf"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Inspections Regime</header> <paragraph id="id3zkf2oy6-wzei-bakq-ph7b-vzts3zzi7f5i"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text> 
<subparagraph id="idnpkrdf3h-kegb-zker-7zf5-58ubl6lepo47"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <clause id="id71h0nbvp-0637-2hoe-j8gw-74cloaebm9k6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="id44dfu1cd-6lpt-oj3a-okv3-42hyegw9dgm2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idks2uamm5-zp63-3vo9-nhab-2vomkzs31uta"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Bureau</header><text>The term <term>Bureau</term> means the Bureau of Prisons.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idd6di2v2f-328w-suqk-afsb-zez465gp6z2z"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Covered facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered facility</term>—</text> <clause id="idbzw8w7ij-8p15-n130-f93i-z157ne9d2yp4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means a correctional facility operated by the Bureau; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idlrnd9h3n-yfh5-h4i2-fc5u-puyp9fbyg8ok"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not include a post-incarceration residential reentry center.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idzua1g795-e0cl-ifi8-clo5-36vgkiiz9sfw"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Family advocate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>family advocate</term> includes—</text> 
<clause id="idzzbmn66u-ud7m-nunz-kglz-msra6ktnwsz7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a grandparent, parent, sibling, spouse or domestic partner, child, aunt, uncle, cousin, niece, nephew, grandchild, or any other individual related to an individual by blood, adoption, marriage, civil union, a romantic or fostering relationship; or</text></clause> <clause id="idsmpy7aty-nelt-zoy9-2h1r-bpkdc1ztyyy6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a friend of—</text> 
<subclause id="idq5t0c2wf-q6jz-e13q-m8yk-nzambt5l1bup"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the incarcerated person; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="id13pntbq0-jrqp-ggq5-e07i-7tcgic29z07v"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the family of the incarcerated person.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idd5b5zrf6-0zzn-jhts-79ja-r67phys24nrz"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Inspection general</header><text>The term <term>Inspector General</term> means the Inspector General of the Department of Justice.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idu1ztunnc-c823-9w6d-49wq-rmu3ic85ti0g"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Ombudsman</header><text>The term <term>Ombudsman</term> means the Ombudsman established under paragraph (3)(A).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idfbc2gtk0-zlsl-vyy3-wlar-nhvzhsgudzz9"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Representative of an incarcerated person</header><text>The term <term>representative of an incarcerated person</term> includes paid or unpaid legal counsel or any other person or entity chosen by an incarcerated person to represent the interests of the incarcerated person.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idj5q5n08s-nere-4cf2-8e1z-qg95bz1zyg2v"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Sexual abuse</header><text>The term <term>sexual abuse</term> has the meaning given that term in section 115.6 of title 28, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idu7rbw210-l177-fcl7-qlcu-5qziwucrgs0q"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Staff</header><text>The term <term>staff</term> means employees and contractors of the Bureau.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="idul0yaqsl-8ac6-aaf7-pqpr-vn6aulylbb57"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inspections of covered facilities by the inspector general</header> <subparagraph id="idhpmtdrvo-nm37-vg4c-w8et-vagevwi2ms4r"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment of inspections regime</header> <clause id="idfqhe9msa-veg4-zr3z-4nmz-vmq03bqnk4qr"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Inspector General shall conduct periodic inspections of covered facilities pursuant to the requirements of this subsection.</text></clause> 
<clause id="idana1p3mi-5v4y-w4yh-7r42-68e8s8k5dzh6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Access to covered facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall ensure that the Inspector General has access to—</text> <subclause id="iden41si2p-ofpb-zkie-p4gk-3h5tfw2vgnd5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any covered facility (including the incarcerated people, detainees, staff, and bargaining unit representative organization) in accordance with paragraph (4); and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="id842ubtju-w33z-py6v-jqp9-qtraklhga322"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any other information that the Inspector General determines is necessary to carry out this subsection.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="idipugfzcj-zjio-pl5w-h6lq-bfr3m4nfkbet"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Notice of inspections</header><text>An inspection of a covered facility under this subsection may be announced or unannounced.</text></clause> 
<clause id="idevm08p6s-sece-gggv-waz8-7qdrpcgunlze"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Community input</header><text>In developing the inspections regime under this subsection, the Inspector General is encouraged to consult formerly incarcerated people, family or representatives of incarcerated people, and community advocates.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idb34btv7f-z0hq-zfpn-t6b5-94e4il9v8ta0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inspection criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An inspection of a covered facility under this subsection may include an assessment of the following:</text> 
<clause id="idgp6t2c6g-y1mr-0eqk-t2v0-cip9i9shloj1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The policies, procedures, and administrative guidance of the covered facility.</text></clause> <clause id="idj4q17hz3-2t5z-iro6-v1ug-os9fy7kepnrc"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The conditions of confinement.</text></clause> 
<clause id="idgsc2azq0-5gy9-z0p4-wsd6-8yzbfiu63sc1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Working conditions for staff.</text></clause> <clause id="idvhp81k4l-ikqs-y16a-cffz-i4u4wz7z3twf"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The availability of evidence-based recidivism reduction programs and productive activities, as those terms are defined in section 3635 of title 18, and the application of earned time credits pursuant to section 3632 of title 18.</text></clause> 
<clause id="id56d1zq8c-0o4m-m6p0-3lbi-w74q6rtb1vjn"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The policies and procedures relating to visitation.</text></clause> <clause id="idrwnf3fsn-zl9i-qy9t-m0zt-t6apc8dvgtqz"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The policies and practices relating to classification and housing.</text></clause> 
<clause id="idlggmozz7-25nk-ksgd-lh8m-thtn70wf9myw"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The policies and practices relating to the use of single-cell confinement, administrative segregation, and other forms of restrictive housing.</text></clause> <clause id="idytycsvzs-c11w-y013-wiuz-hc5iyco9hw6w"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The medical facilities and medical and mental health care, programs, procedures, and policies, including the number and qualifications of medical and mental health staff and the availability of sex-specific and trauma-responsive care for incarcerated people.</text></clause> 
<clause id="idk1gedi8i-djjt-5zle-t9te-mu1hih5icwqi"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Medical services and mental health resources for staff.</text></clause> <clause id="idgibeu7b6-a48r-rfcb-0dzw-03bz1njbegib"><enum>(x)</enum><text>Lockdowns at the covered facility.</text></clause> 
<clause id="id9cwrjdb6-mlbb-q6oy-1iz6-tfssives1mz6"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>Credible allegations of incidents involving excessive use of force, completed, attempted, or threatened violence, including sexual abuse, or misconduct committed against incarcerated people.</text></clause> <clause id="idu0fz348k-0k7q-di9r-lqhr-3gjgoeoubq8i"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>Credible allegations of incidents involving completed, attempted, or threatened violence, including sexual violence or sexual abuse, committed against staff.</text></clause> 
<clause id="id3egnfdqg-7n7a-82uf-q0to-hhtslbc5ln3o"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>Adequacy of staffing at the covered facility, including the number and job assignments of staff, the ratio of staff to inmates at the covered facility, the staff position vacancy rate at the covered facility, and the use of overtime, mandatory overtime, and augmentation.</text></clause> <clause id="idkc9zzbz1-kan4-zztr-crrd-68f3uv32rg7w"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>Deaths or serious injuries of incarcerated people or staff that occurred at the covered facility.</text></clause> 
<clause id="id3udm0l52-v36c-yi2v-g644-ke8uq6mdrdkb"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>The existence of contraband that jeopardizes the health or safety of incarcerated people or staff, including incident reports, referrals for criminal prosecution, and confirmed prosecutions.</text></clause> <clause id="idant1ubbl-n5kv-266p-ce1u-bywhyov5hs8n"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Access of incarcerated people to—</text> 
<subclause id="id6gadc9uc-sqbq-4wsz-ygsd-53fj5qq561z8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>legal counsel, including confidential meetings and communications;</text></subclause> <subclause id="idpu27z0r1-50t9-hvv7-93kr-sruz362nviri"><enum>(II)</enum><text>discovery and other case-related legal materials; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="id52zrh8p1-qh8o-wtyy-gvez-y93c5qhzdj9q"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the law library at the covered facility.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="idk7b9wami-w48l-9pqs-h417-et11k7yht5a2"><enum>(xvii)</enum><text>Any aspect of the operation of the covered facility that the Inspector General determines to be necessary over the course of an inspection.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idtgqf8r5w-am67-g69b-y5kb-w14608v7vpod"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Inspection schedule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An inspection of a covered facility under this subsection shall be conducted on a schedule based on the combined risk score of the covered facility as described in subparagraph (E) and the following considerations:</text> <clause id="idrmzkvwyf-11hj-rd33-q60l-5u5vdmzsh89u"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Higher risk covered facilities shall receive more frequent inspections.</text></clause> 
<clause id="id5kh7z7g9-fz2e-scz5-1mbq-izjgb34mfwis"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Inspector General shall reevaluate the combined risk score methodology and inspection schedule periodically and may alter 1 or both to ensure that higher risk covered facilities are identified and receiving the appropriate frequency of inspection.</text></clause> <clause id="idffvuz4vm-u735-otj6-p5ln-5pj8cfa38bfs"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A determination by the Inspector General that 1 or more of the criteria listed in subparagraph (B) should be inspected, with regard to a covered facility or group of covered facilities, shall be considered.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idhjchdhdo-00nc-8wyg-fvqe-krf3r7o2a42k"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<clause id="ide64r2jl0-6git-ct87-klg6-vr8emh4duw4z"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the completion of an inspection of a covered facility under this subsection, or a group of inspections that assess the same or similar issues at more than 1 covered facility, the Inspector General shall submit to the Attorney General, the appropriate congressional committees, employee representative organizations, and the public a final copy of the report that addresses 1 or more of the following topics:</text> <subclause id="id4ndirodn-1ydp-9s3w-qazj-d9tjg071zay8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>A characterization of the conditions of confinement and working conditions, including a summary of the inspection criteria reviewed under clauses (ii) and (iii) of subparagraph (B).</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idtzr9fzlw-9ymp-0zdk-9zmw-hz1h524jtrnn"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Recommendations made to the covered facility to improve safety and conditions within the covered facility, including recommendations regarding staffing.</text></subclause> <subclause id="idnjp8jq16-86y8-4hse-7j51-s0d7zmhcl9bi"><enum>(III)</enum><text>A recommended timeline for the next inspection and assessment, which shall not limit the authority of the Inspector General to perform additional inspections and assessments, announced or unannounced.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idj9phepg4-fd48-3unh-soz6-7o0ncrmmshm5"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Any other issues or matters identified during the inspection of the covered facility or covered facilities.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="idapgkinvk-f86h-9n5v-rd7b-pzshz3q5dh0z"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Consultation with stakeholders</header><text>In developing the recommendations described in clause (i), the Inspector General may consult with stakeholders, including employee representative organizations.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idr3dsaf0i-ssz2-zlka-je4f-0qdzc95z237k"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Risk score</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after July 25, 2024, the Inspector General shall establish methodology and protocols for determining the combined risk score of a covered facility, which—</text> <clause id="id44lms76e-2efw-5wzm-mz1s-2jsik4lcwgok"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be delivered to the appropriate congressional committees; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="ideoiszaim-8i7q-eda3-ldz8-g9ql6aes9c4v"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be based on—</text> <subclause id="id7rse9sqa-aj93-euc3-641b-zrz7mmw5p2wt"><enum>(I)</enum><text>frequency and duration of lockdowns;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idvregrmow-4eoo-m5ys-gt6p-1tj7za2couda"><enum>(II)</enum><text>availability of programming;</text></subclause> <subclause id="idace4wfgo-ns71-5yj6-9iiq-9o8fyqadkhzk"><enum>(III)</enum><text>staffing levels;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idvm18gzt6-kzcz-rsu4-fn1c-5s4nt0y5kc6q"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>access to adequate physical and mental health resources;</text></subclause> <subclause id="id7zbltkje-60ru-1plf-nz0e-hdr4a065tzo5"><enum>(V)</enum><text>incidences of physical assault, neglect, or sexual abuse;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idhf4aam28-wy0z-4kn8-ruc7-y9khoh0hjfov"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>opportunity to maintain family ties through phone calls, video calls, mail, email, and visitation;</text></subclause> <subclause id="idouja7meb-bal6-szrt-bbse-kpbucmyjbazo"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>adequacy of the nutrition provided;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="id2awqkm4m-899a-45hy-7rjj-wv40v1f8sz3m"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>amount or frequency of staff discipline cases;</text></subclause> <subclause id="id6m443si8-v15o-vl88-mluu-vsgb7m4ih1mf"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>amount or frequency of misconduct by people incarcerated at the covered facility;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idoaavf9v1-8qvr-38w8-frao-ye3lthml0hal"><enum>(X)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">access of incarcerated people to—</text> <item id="idup1hlajl-02yq-ywy1-lper-c5zr6714s53y"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>legal counsel, including confidential meetings and communications;</text></item> 
<item id="idtmp2ozou-gy4n-z9qt-jd0p-6u43ezzsurv1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>discovery and other case-related legal materials; and</text></item> <item id="ido22zw6ii-rct9-iz7g-etyz-ciol9g3w19do"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the law library at the covered facility; and</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="id4wl854zl-ze7a-setn-62qj-avnztsalsf66"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>other factors as determined by the Inspector General.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idcydgj16c-yylq-vw7g-uph0-gq6mwypfaigr"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Bureau response to report</header> <clause id="id6kljea9u-gzcp-bf5i-fkm1-nhqn2ezp6q9s"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the Inspector General issues a report under subparagraph (D), the Bureau shall respond in writing to the inspection report, which shall include a corrective action plan.</text></clause> 
<clause id="idjh1j5vgh-kabn-dt2e-nvn0-dc5534rmwnr8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>Each response and action plan described in clause (i) shall be made available to the public on the website of the Inspector General.</text></clause> <clause id="idpvqpznj1-dw6e-ibqn-jl97-hhfc67qc9fjc"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Compliance with corrective action plan</header><text>The Inspector General may conduct additional inspections or investigations, announced or unannounced, to monitor the compliance of the Bureau with a corrective action plan described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idddg3zb5n-0bj5-he4q-wc2z-67lsnm47y5k7"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>The authority in this paragraph is consistent with and does not supersede, conflict with, or otherwise alter the authority provided to the Inspector General under section 406 of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="idl6g8ukpg-6n6r-354y-n8sb-z3cddo1j6sac"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Ombudsman</header> <subparagraph id="idf8zdek0s-eown-vjd3-unfy-uycv5ioiuibf"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after July 25, 2024, the Attorney General shall establish in the Department of Justice an Ombudsman who—</text> 
<clause id="id6urzd5sm-ziv4-hs28-gr7u-2rs1w3e1fkrz"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may receive a complaint from an incarcerated person, a family advocate, a representative of an incarcerated person, staff, a representative of staff, a Member of Congress, or a member of the judicial branch of the Federal Government regarding issues that may adversely affect the health, safety, welfare, or rights of incarcerated people or staff, including—</text> <subclause id="iduzwpq8b9-6jrd-yk87-jr0o-4b02omop0qar"><enum>(I)</enum><text>abuse or neglect;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idpnmuia83-o2av-r1es-ms4z-iqhnkzzwcpva"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the conditions of confinement, including the availability of health care;</text></subclause> <subclause id="idyekpr1q5-6jaw-43kh-7w2m-cd52pg1eovs3"><enum>(III)</enum><text>working conditions of staff;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idccqu32nh-0jzz-2il5-pt4w-24aicqra0oij"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>decisions, administrative actions, or guidance of the Bureau, including those relating to prison staffing;</text></subclause> <subclause id="idp1lzr480-8pqz-wfo8-q9me-ldqtoip86bzk"><enum>(V)</enum><text>inaction or omissions by the Bureau, including failure to consider or respond to complaints or grievances by incarcerated people or staff promptly or appropriately;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idhsbaplyr-vkc7-f0k1-6g17-2n5cy1ciwkz1"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>policies, rules, or procedures of the Bureau, including gross mismanagement; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="iducob49a6-wprb-6c29-z6nu-6z8jkmsf6sdc"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>alleged violations of non-criminal law by staff or incarcerated people that may adversely affect the health, safety, welfare, or rights of any person;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="idhkamkzfy-kker-z7rp-k8b9-q9iznz1r3j25"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may refer a complainant and others to appropriate resources or Federal agencies;</text></clause> <clause id="idt9gs9o59-l4ry-c56r-h5lb-ubien1na5uq2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>may make inquiries and recommend actions to appropriate entities on behalf of a complainant, the Ombudsman, or others; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idqw4n36w3-zcak-fasz-gfkc-petg86ehiho0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>may decline to investigate or take any action with respect to any complaint; and</text></clause> <clause id="idz04v64sd-jp4y-kjok-lrmt-yzm2fc3t82jb"><enum>(v)</enum><text>in any case in which the Ombudsman declines to investigate or take any action under clause (iv), shall notify the complainant in writing of the decision not to investigate or take any action and the reasons for the decision.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="ide0rz34q4-eihv-iplh-51yu-3aohzro6kw6j"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitations on authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Ombudsman—</text> <clause id="idc570r03i-dpzb-rgzm-zjuo-awbsv3amzqcp"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may not levy any fees for the submission or investigation of complaints;</text></clause> 
<clause id="id4istyzo4-903r-lzem-z26f-5fs2mhp4hg7z"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not investigate—</text> <subclause id="idjs8bmqmu-c1l7-aqc6-f2a7-liifgbh9p1yz"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any complaints relating to the underlying criminal conviction of an incarcerated person;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idllzhwy16-zfe8-5l83-i8zj-6cs93tb3hqj2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a complaint from staff that relates to the employment or contractual relationship of the staff member with the Bureau, unless the complaint is related to the health, safety, welfare, working conditions, gross mismanagement of a covered facility, or rehabilitation of incarcerated people; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="idb7kr4tgr-pnar-zpte-9l44-hopnwlmld14h"><enum>(III)</enum><text>subject to clause (iii), any allegation of criminal or administrative misconduct, as described in subsection (b)(2); and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="id28zhhz2w-aubq-bprn-4j5a-hl7vs1svli5g"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to clause (ii)(III), shall refer any matter covered by subsection (b)(2) to the Inspector General, who may, at the discretion of the Inspector General, refer the allegations back to the Ombudsman or the internal affairs office of the appropriate component of the Department of Justice.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="ide5e11czr-k0a9-ibpn-eb5z-gekeez046foi"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Decision on the merits of a complaint</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the conclusion of an investigation of a complaint, the Ombudsman shall—</text> 
<clause id="id101g7zos-f9d3-4g15-rfku-cvfo8lf3yba0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>render a decision on the merits of each complaint;</text></clause> <clause id="id3v91r5wc-8ocb-s6gz-g79j-4ea63bl8njba"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>communicate the decision to the complainant, if any, and to the Bureau; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="id25ud479u-0w0i-ch10-3bzw-0zas30zlikd7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">state the recommendations and reasoning of the Ombudsman if, in the opinion of the Ombudsman, the Bureau or any employee of the Bureau should—</text> <subclause id="idk4pojpce-9e9v-sqzm-7zqb-8sswqzcmd1pl"><enum>(I)</enum><text>consider the matter further;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idjz38ri3l-q65o-w76z-heu7-amnl4gq81mm0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>modify or cancel any action;</text></subclause> <subclause id="id2jl0noti-37jn-3kd0-q776-uscpzhygghjf"><enum>(III)</enum><text>alter a rule, practice, or ruling;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idfz7u1gkn-9le6-s246-gb0o-1ustw29ietj0"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>explain in detail the administrative action in question; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="idjlwwqfpk-o9ll-dzqm-zuwf-hgi92bg8v7wd"><enum>(V)</enum><text>rectify an omission.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idyk6cnz1j-r4th-o8hy-4wmc-u37k93qfv1dw"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Actions following a decision by the ombudsman</header> 
<clause id="id27633q0a-c7v1-jf35-rn3z-7ayvh78nszn2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Request for information about actions taken</header><text>If the Ombudsman so requests, the Bureau shall, within the time specified, respond to any inquiry or request for information from the Ombudsman and inform the Ombudsman about any action taken on the recommendations provided by the Ombudsman or the reasons for not complying with any request for information or recommendations.</text></clause> <clause id="idtqs8vk0i-mhtb-frg5-1o3z-n3z7nm4z3qdz"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reporting of continuing issues</header><text>If the Ombudsman believes, based on an investigation conducted by the Ombudsman, that there has been or continues to be a significant health, safety, welfare, working conditions, or rehabilitation issue, the Ombudsman shall report the finding to the Attorney General and the appropriate congressional committees.</text></clause> 
<clause id="id7d62q8pb-hmop-gow8-selj-jz7u48j7dhbu"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Monitoring of internal disciplinary actions of the bureau</header><text>In the event that the Bureau conducts an internal disciplinary investigation or review of 1 or more staff members of the Bureau as a result of an investigation by the Ombudsman, the Ombudsman may monitor the internal disciplinary action to ensure a fair and objective process.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="idnyz6zghk-ju3q-dvin-eune-p60620skrjyu"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Inspector general and ombudsman access to bureau of prisons facilities</header> <subparagraph id="id3k9zkuea-wccl-rqd2-7yn9-to88qezyc996"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header> <clause id="idiygi6n6w-9zoz-suzq-mpmg-as3fqwvznqm1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Access to bureau facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in clause (ii), on demand, in person or in writing and with or without prior notice, the Inspector General and the Ombudsman shall be granted access to all Bureau facilities, which shall include—</text> 
<subclause id="idq1o3a2ra-aq3h-4ko4-dzz1-88ihkwiil8oc"><enum>(I)</enum><text>all areas that are used by incarcerated people, all areas that are accessible to incarcerated people, and access to programs for incarcerated people at any time of day; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="idaor8lrqd-jivm-z19u-ogqp-7tcmhvazhqep"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the opportunity to—</text> 
<item id="id93mda1i6-ld75-m2hz-0md2-3fle2g2v5oah"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>conduct private and confidential interviews with any incarcerated person, staff, employee representative organization, or other person; and</text></item> <item id="idc1001jlg-zzi0-m6md-9k9c-bi94zavg8eef"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>communicate privately and confidentially, both formally and informally, with incarcerated people or staff by telephone, mail, electronic communication, and in person, which shall not be monitored or recorded by or conducted in the presence of staff.</text></item></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="idfhuz5cj4-f75e-zbtp-o55d-u10w4ublnq6l"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply in situations where the head of the covered facility provides evidence to the Inspector General or the Ombudsman that there is risk of serious and immediate physical harm to visitors due to an ongoing event that requires restricting access to the facility.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id98gzpet8-s1a2-cj2k-09v6-z2ercs4wjp69"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Purpose of visits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Access to Bureau facilities under subparagraph (A) is for the purposes of—</text> 
<clause id="id8k4owhqo-u1ly-i985-jlcl-yz7l2w9pvcpi"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conducting announced or unannounced inspections by the Inspector General as described in paragraph (2), including inspections to monitor the compliance of the Bureau with a corrective action plan described in paragraph (2)(F)(i);</text></clause> <clause id="idrl756gzy-yry2-yhes-6i3o-7f9d41pjviwd"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>conducting an investigation or other activity by the Ombudsman as described in paragraph (3); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idgo5v6p06-fwg8-mh3l-0bif-7rbg1qkvc3vp"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>inspecting, viewing, photographing, and video recording all areas of the facility that are used by incarcerated people or are accessible to incarcerated people.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id3g4f46lz-rjdz-42sf-699o-zecpp5vgmznj"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Access to documents</header> <clause id="idzuhzqjvb-9eu4-iltd-bmqy-lh4pbh6vf5sv"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header> <subclause id="idzkf5qge0-aesz-cgzw-rzl7-5elw86hdqc6z"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Inspector General and the Ombudsman have the right to access, inspect, and copy all relevant information, records, or documents in the possession or control of the Bureau that the Inspector General or the Ombudsman considers necessary in an inspection, investigation, or other activity.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="id5e7gl92d-35w7-ci89-pqn5-zacrcucibb3y"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Restricted or privileged documents</header><text>The Bureau shall assist the Inspector General and the Ombudsman in obtaining the necessary releases for the information, records, or documents under subclause (I) that are specifically restricted or privileged for use by the Bureau.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="idh1zmh6z6-7oam-yjzu-q8zv-llozj1c8d4cs"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Production of records</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following notification from the Inspector General or the Ombudsman with a written demand for access to Bureau records, the Bureau shall provide access to the requested documentation in a manner consistent with section 552a of this title—</text> 
<subclause id="idme8sy6oz-50nf-z9kv-nljv-4jbnudn8495e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not later than 30 business days after receipt of the written request; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="id72izn1rl-wmna-i6sz-c88a-iz8d1h5our03"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of records pertaining to the death of an incarcerated person or staff, threats of bodily harm including sexual or physical assaults, or the denial or delay of necessary medical treatment, not later than 10 business days after receipt of the written request, unless the Inspector General or the Ombudsman consents to an extension of that time frame.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idt2spd3gs-z2bz-z8qy-0zzm-hey7u9kna273"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Minimize disruption of operations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General and the Ombudsman shall—</text> <clause id="idishaka1p-bd5w-pfaq-7ykm-ncztymzsjlkp"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop procedures—</text> 
<subclause id="idyh1egc0q-pzed-htyp-v7az-znnyn756kzfj"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to ensure that the Inspector General has access to, and the right to review and investigate, any allegations received by the Ombudsman to ensure that the Inspector General may carry out the authorities provided to the Inspector General under this chapter; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="idtcgi6jr9-yd9s-swuh-1mjs-l61eodwf0ww5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that may provide that the Inspector General and the Ombudsman will determine certain categories of allegations that are not necessary for the Inspector General to review prior to the Ombudsman proceeding;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="id9vkzvets-fya9-lvom-p2t1-u1biehcmfczb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>work with the Bureau to minimize disruption to the operations of the Bureau due to inspections, investigations, or other activity;</text></clause> <clause id="idskeryndn-gztf-uwtm-aqwa-38u5hz80esh0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>comply with the security clearance processes of the Bureau, if these processes do not impede the activities described in this subsection; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="ido1lzogoi-cjrn-64kk-jtle-ky99ztduoc7y"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">limit the public release of any photographs or video recordings that would jeopardize—</text> <subclause id="idoosb39vh-d0kg-62zr-n8nb-92tafrfsfq6m"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the safety, security, or good order of a covered facility or the Bureau; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="idv6pz0elq-y9ke-0sdi-i071-f1zfs5wzlrrf"><enum>(II)</enum><text>public safety.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id176y4ql0-bdf0-qhy7-3pqm-mt20nrzcncb6"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>The authority in this paragraph is consistent with and does not supersede, conflict with, or otherwise alter the authority provided to the Inspector General under section 406 of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idrrhe1p9j-afbp-ublm-q847-7q6z1dtew0nc"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header> 
<subparagraph id="idn0hov259-i794-quhs-tdh9-0nrtco7dpn57"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Correspondence and communication with the Inspector General and the Ombudsman, including communication regarding an issue described in section 4051 of title 18, is confidential and shall be protected as privileged correspondence in the same manner as legal correspondence or communications.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idzzlzkrzk-kvj9-r8rf-1k95-g66nu14n5cot"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraph (C), the Inspector General and the Ombudsman shall establish confidentiality procedures for all information maintained by the respective office to ensure that, to the greatest extent practicable, before, during, or after an investigation—</text> 
<clause id="idlkkz77jp-45z3-l4mz-4as9-1990595ytt7e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>staff are not aware of the identity of a complainant; and</text></clause> <clause id="id5bfgjgu4-9k5e-wqjn-y9ic-5bt7qlszvzej"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other incarcerated people are not aware of the identity of a complainant.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idpzgdybtv-tlsk-t7pu-pz5q-w2nanrgpy5pb"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The Inspector General and the Ombudsman may disclose identifying information for the sole purpose of carrying out an investigation and as otherwise authorized under section 407(b) of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="idw1iwuggq-qpiz-d5k0-p6pz-zp8yk0t2aslz"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Filing complaints</header> <subparagraph id="idhwwo14lj-fw62-9ac2-zz2k-4r97hrokyjdp"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Filing complaints on behalf of an incarcerated individual</header> <clause id="idm0uzul4t-bhh2-cjtf-8tju-haw39ncz6fzd"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Online form</header><text>The Ombudsman shall create a secure online form to be made available on the website of the Ombudsman where the family advocates and representatives of incarcerated people can submit complaints and inquiries on issues identified in paragraph (3)(A)(i) on behalf of an individual incarcerated at a covered facility.</text></clause> 
<clause id="idy4zbc6ka-lw58-0za7-1tsn-8tgie5c0ggqy"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Telephone hotline</header><text>The Ombudsman shall create a telephone hotline through which family advocates and representatives of incarcerated people can call to file complaints and inquiries on issues identified in paragraph (3)(A)(i) on behalf of an individual incarcerated at a covered facility.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idp24d5oco-myi2-2kv7-pouz-zjzzvhf1fz4g"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Filing complaints by an incarcerated individual</header> <clause id="idj43ournl-60sh-psby-q7d2-w6vn147fcve0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Internal private submission</header><text>The Bureau shall provide multiple internal ways for incarcerated individuals in covered facilities to privately submit to the Ombudsman complaints and inquiries on issues identified in paragraph (3)(A)(i).</text></clause> 
<clause id="id7db8hzfe-r7eg-4mr1-ugf3-ry2ky1yj4f9b"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Submission via independent entity</header><text>The Bureau shall also provide not less than 1 process for incarcerated individuals in covered facilities to submit complaints and inquiries on issues identified in paragraph (3)(A)(i) to a public or private entity or office that is not part of the Bureau and that is able to receive and immediately forward complaints and inquiries to the Ombudsman, allowing the incarcerated individual to remain anonymous on request.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idemz3ow72-j6pb-bzoi-cwz2-onvuhz1tgkas"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Determination</header> <clause id="idskzoginh-jluh-hy3h-ign3-4h7h1em2845v"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Confirmation of receipt</header><text>Not later than 5 business days after submission of a complaint or inquiry under subparagraph (A) or (B), the Ombudsman shall confirm receipt.</text></clause> 
<clause id="idfw5pkb2c-dt5d-uz55-aopt-m299b02up5c8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>Not later than 15 business days after issuing the confirmation under clause (i), the Ombudsman shall make a determination as to whether any action is warranted and notify the complainant of the determination.</text></clause> <clause id="ids7awkn1v-j63y-jhi8-68rz-hnpmbdkmsa3h"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Statement regarding decision</header><text>If the Ombudsman has determined that action is unwarranted under clause (ii), the Ombudsman shall provide a written statement explaining the decision to the complainant.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idplz9a91r-3dp3-ge27-4r2o-rkkp4kuao18h"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Public education</header><text>The Ombudsman shall coordinate with the Bureau to educate incarcerated people, representatives of incarcerated people, and the public about the existence and functions of the Ombudsman.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="ide4c4e7c2-80c1-o1h8-oi62-zzttn8hg8g90"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Administrative exhaustion</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed as a necessary administrative remedy required for exhaustion under section 7(a) of the Civil Rights of Institutionalized Persons Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1997e">42 U.S.C. 1997e(a)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id80t4irh7-0fvv-kl34-ifmm-97zza5p9niq8"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Prohibition on retaliation</header> 
<subparagraph id="idpug28mbv-gogn-v8iv-lky7-szfyw8fzc79y"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Bureau and staff of the Bureau shall not discharge, retaliate against, or in any manner discriminate against any complainant or any person or entity that has instituted or caused to be instituted any proceeding, investigation, or inspection under or related to this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idoz9ruwik-1ys7-dpzv-lb5q-t3wffvz9evls"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Investigation</header><text>Any alleged discharge of, retaliation against, or discrimination against a complainant, person, or entity because of a complaint, investigation, or inspection may be considered by the Ombudsman as an appropriate subject of an investigation or other activity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idyz9uyzby-enfo-qhdp-nkrw-5l68tfekplh6"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Due process protections</header> 
<subparagraph id="idh1bsopts-y9b0-z1ni-56cf-zu1z2mkrn6sa"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General and the Inspector General shall ensure that implementation of this subsection is consistent with section 552a of this title and all other applicable laws, and respects appropriate due process protections for staff.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idddftgc8h-jz6g-qkpe-cv7o-ktmmh070j6lz"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to modify, supersede, or otherwise affect the authority of the Inspector General to access all records, reports, audits, reviews, documents, papers, recommendations, or other materials, as authorized by section 406(a) of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id444rbdky-fz1o-ztwo-36k6-rep7iqripzw8"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Percentage of annual appropriation for the bureau of prisons</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the amount allocated to the Inspector General and the Ombudsman to carry out the activities described in this subsection should equal an amount between 0.2 percent and 0.5 percent of the annual appropriation for the Bureau.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idnnb55nmu-2ane-ts8n-w5d1-lufje1lyj3lb"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This subsection shall take effect on the date that is 90 days after the date on which appropriations are made available to the Inspector General of the Department of Justice and the Department of Justice for the specific purpose of carrying out this subsection, the Federal Prison Oversight Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/71">Public Law 118–71</external-xref>, 138 Stat. 1492), and the amendments made by that Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block/></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id65nzoerk-wh4w-kujy-htdz-pq7zi0y3pfiu"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Repeal of similar amendment; effective date</header> 
<subparagraph id="idoujliows-416c-4e7i-uv7j-skwadk2fn5kk"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Repeal of prior similar amendment</header><text>Effective on July 25, 2024, section 2(a) of the of the Federal Prison Oversight Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/71">Public Law 118–71</external-xref>, 138 Stat. 1492) is repealed. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idshzv8f5l-bu35-5m78-a2vn-qsr7jzfm5btv"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall take effect as if enacted on July 25, 2024.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="idhs06zof4-8o47-g3uj-1qo7-2iht43kcz456"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Section 416 of Title 5</header> 
<paragraph id="idw4i1kato-q7ny-nh92-p8la-8ud3ra5vczku"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amendments by the intelligence authorization act for fiscal year 2025</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 416(a)(1) of title 5, United States Code, as amended by section 3(a)(10), is further amended—</text> <subparagraph id="id2eat530z-y7lp-zwz6-pwqc-bmqdoec5sdmw"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as subparagraphs (B) and (D), respectively;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idqugstlyg-b9j0-zlaa-5hwm-b3vwum0qbf82"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before subparagraph (B), as redesignated, the following: </text> <quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e2662" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> <subparagraph id="idboeplchq-k2te-o7r6-vht4-jvtfrw1se5u0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Employee</header><text>The term <term>employee</term> includes a former employee or former contractor, if the complaint or information reported pursuant to this section arises from or relates to the period during which the former employee or former contractor was an employee or contractor, as the case may be.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="ido9wjs07h-85d7-o2ym-fiau-v2q6k3m5yr9n"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (B), as redesignated, the following:</text> <quoted-block id="quoted-block-d3e2673" style="other" other-style="codification-quoted"> <subparagraph id="idfq2uurbc-bioo-qf9a-2znn-1wqbsv2ih9lj"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Intelligence community</header><text>The term <term>intelligence community</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id51lplw4u-prya-g8b4-qzrv-hjb5zu4mkjmt"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Repeal of similar amendments; effective date</header> 
<subparagraph id="idw8eueab7-4337-ffdd-oy5w-raidc8d9ls24"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Repeal of prior similar amendments</header><text>Effective on December 23, 2024, sections 6701(c)(1) and 6702(c)(1) of the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2025 (Pub. L. 118–159, div. F, title LXVII, 138 Stat. 2512, 2514) are repealed. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id9a6at28f-6c13-bqys-hfeg-waiaen5z0c8v"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall take effect as if enacted on December 23, 2024.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="idsoiw6ccg-6fjy-02tu-3354-nn4ak0lohukf"><enum>5.</enum><header>conforming amendments</header> 
<subsection id="id3h1teu3j-fzqw-mk4m-qeep-pz61vpf3qlnf"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments To Update References to the Inspector General Act of 1978</header> 
<paragraph id="idczcmn8i7-hqz9-86yq-eiqd-jioqpsvie61l"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Title 2</header> 
<subparagraph id="idjw561bqf-8se8-6a12-wg5z-li69v112zvgj"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Library of Congress Inspector General Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/185">2 U.S.C. 185</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="id6tg34h28-8mgv-mpyu-v8rm-88lob2432obh"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1), by striking <quote>Sections 4, 5 (other than subsection (a)(13)), 6 (other than subsection (a)(7)), and 7 of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Sections 404, 405 (other than subsection (b)(7)), 406 (other than subsection (a)(7)), and 407 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="id34sunb7l-3ae7-7ysu-o6qs-9hvzmuraj88l"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(2)(C), by striking <quote>section 6(a)(8) of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 406(a)(8) of title 5, United States Code</quote>; and </text></clause> <clause id="idqsucieiv-zdhi-pcz3-78sc-zcpzmlem262j"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(3)(C)(i), by striking <quote>section 5 of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.),</quote> and inserting <quote>section 405 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>. </text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="ide9cfia2t-250k-jv5h-r3l8-uleilzdgp2z8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Architect of the Capitol Inspector General Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1808">2 U.S.C. 1808</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="idq0td562o-nst8-39wg-sdie-07wg2gfhcqvz"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(2)(C), by striking <quote>section 6(a)(8) of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 406(a)(8) of title 5, United States Code</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idk7b5uy2g-gz8z-wwa8-jzhg-zulvcv01iq5e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(3)(C)(i), by striking <quote>section 5 of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.),</quote> and inserting <quote>section 405 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id9yyfstpp-vc39-9unz-dfu6-5rewswewkn31"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Title 5</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 15010 of the Emergency Appropriations for Coronavirus Health Response and Agency Operations (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/136">Public Law 116–136</external-xref>, div. B, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/424">5 U.S.C. 424</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="idnsp5asvc-lklv-r7fp-orj7-r81kq1d9q1tn"><enum>(A)</enum><text> in subsection (a)(4), by striking <quote>section 11 of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 424 of title 5, United States Code</quote>; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idcbzz911s-s378-n9mv-157r-2e0bhy9anzm1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(3)(A)(i), by striking <quote>section 6 of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 406 of title 5, United States Code</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idufli3oeq-oavw-600b-n2m0-9zzsqb5p7qm2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(3)(A)(iii), by striking <quote>section 6 of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 406 of title 5, United States Code</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idspsii76r-g3a7-0tty-olst-cfj1tv32c93e"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(3)(B), by striking <quote>section 4(b)(1) of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 404(b)(1) of title 5, United States Code</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idnec6nkz1-z60r-pv1q-vf5c-g4nwgt86dbtn"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(4)(C), by striking <quote>section 6 of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 406 of title 5, United States Code</quote>; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idv7lqgil4-2hgh-zk15-nq97-z7cuwa4sghnz"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in subsection (f)(3), by striking <quote>section 6 of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.),</quote> and inserting <quote>section 406 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idsuo615ss-hygk-zfb2-pyzg-f3ndujlej1lp"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Title 7</header><text>Section 1337 (matter after paragraph (3)) of the Food Stamp and Commodity Distribution Amendments of 1981 (7 U.S.C. 2270 (matter after paragraph (3))) is amended by striking <quote>described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Inspector General Act of 1978 /9">section 9</external-xref> of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/452">Public Law 95–452</external-xref>, 92 Stat. 1107)</quote> and inserting <quote>described in section 422 of title 5, United States Code</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idd5azikjn-ujlo-h6ws-8w4w-6k1d7jmf9fz4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Title 10</header> <subparagraph id="id47hnp6dq-6j3j-dwv1-k8gf-susij3v315mt"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 113(o) of title 10, United States Code, is amended in the subsection heading by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Inspector General Act of 1978</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Chapter 4 of Title 5</header-in-text></quote>. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id4sc8got3-wnlo-86q2-6l47-ul5mfo8cmaq3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 554(a) of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/141">10 U.S.C. 141</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <clause id="id8tw9p2h4-yusd-g9zt-f0cl-bge4pd5abajf"><enum>(i)</enum><text> in paragraph (2), in the matter before subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>the Inspector General Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/452">Public Law 95–452</external-xref>; 5 U.S.C. App.),</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 4 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>; </text></clause> 
<clause id="ideeaaa658-iyqm-u2tp-gyn2-anoe076sozqp"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(B), by striking <quote>section 5 of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)..</quote> and inserting <quote>section 405 of title 5, United States Code.</quote>; and </text></clause> <clause id="idcjkdhe46-hgef-lmoz-ms7e-rqgt1fh9cfbp"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(E), by striking <quote>the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)..</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 4 of title 5, United States Code.</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id18di97lb-ys5h-o4rj-c6m2-janv0912768e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 1034(f)(2)(B) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 5 of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 405 of title 5</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="idc2fae8md-8zue-wlqq-9ys6-wcwsl8p5zvz5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Title 15</header> <subparagraph id="idcchk3smr-63cw-u64f-y7j0-gct78tf13k8a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 1107(a)(3) of the Coronavirus Aid, Relief, and Economic Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9006">15 U.S.C. 9006(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 4 of title 5, United States Code</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id4oprm6ng-25ud-u641-8tpu-485jvd6a0e21"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 2115 of the Relief for Workers Affected by Coronavirus Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9031">15 U.S.C. 9031</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 4 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idqwuik0p0-3g2i-j9rw-epz3-q14726yrnqqr"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4018 of the Coronavirus Economic Stabilization Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9053">15 U.S.C. 9053</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<clause id="idc0p0bu64-o3eb-1owt-kvz2-8ed3l2q1rg2q"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(3), by striking <quote>section 3(b) of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 403(b) of title 5, United States Code</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="idj5qsmkqk-d0ss-tkto-4vbq-85gky6c707yj"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(5), by striking <quote>section 3(e) of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 403(e) of title 5, United States Code</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="idisvl7zrl-d6bs-grjr-29rh-qwi659g8dfw7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1), in the matter before subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>section 4(b)(1) of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.),</quote> and inserting <quote>section 404(b)(1) of title 5, United States Code,</quote>; </text></clause> <clause id="idcgzcm5p5-7yg8-t3n3-5j47-plwjwqr8ggq9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(3), by striking <quote>the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 4 of title 5, United States Code</quote>; </text></clause> 
<clause id="ids6vizhte-4iqu-fny9-8re1-hsap8o3z24zz"><enum>(v)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1), by striking <quote>section 6 of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 406 of title 5, United States Code</quote>; </text></clause> <clause id="id0fryu4mj-tiie-7nms-vrpy-zuj74kayrl0h"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (d)(2)—</text> 
<subclause id="id4ec8owpd-3urj-fukp-qzdy-5l7dladyltot"><enum>(I)</enum><text> by striking <quote>section 6(f)(3) of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 406(f)(3) of title 5, United States Code,</quote>; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="idttspzbsw-w1wg-qdl8-6jcg-zbu7g6c7tr29"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 6(f)(2) of that Act</quote> and inserting <quote>section 406(f)(2) of title 5, United States Code</quote>; and </text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="idvsye9lr4-5h8u-lzer-5uul-spzvmu26vzvs"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>in subsection (i), by striking <quote>section 11 of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 424 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>. </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id8ipjo39e-t7r6-qz4z-dvid-yb7gg4epuj8p"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 501 of division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9058a">15 U.S.C. 9058a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<clause id="iddtyw0ppz-ko00-yj01-c89l-cf1isr17spk3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)(A)(ii), by striking <quote>subsection (a) of this Act</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a) of this section</quote>; </text></clause> <clause id="id21apcddd-duvb-g3y0-hbs0-pd7yv4f58ctl"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (i)(4), by striking <quote>the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 4 of title 5, United States Code.</quote>; and </text></clause> 
<clause id="idoem7mh7m-0wkd-yk3p-bn4p-1wgdl7w1d64a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (k)(3)(A)(i), by striking <quote>has</quote> and inserting <quote>has—</quote>. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id9i009a4w-q0ev-40jw-sknc-0g4nqle9ua7c"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Title 22</header> <subparagraph id="id0z50n93j-69ot-m5yi-ppti-gpqqlonhcu6w"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 5(p)(4) of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2504">22 U.S.C. 2504(p)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.),</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 4 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idk4oenrdw-tqun-i80g-ggzs-b8l43gm3j2dg"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 309A(h)(3) of the United States International Broadcasting Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6208a">22 U.S.C. 6208a(h)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Inspector General Act of 1978</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 4 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id7iwpsint-r1rt-yg1z-n785-b3e6zlstnz4m"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 310A(a) of the United States International Broadcasting Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6209a">22 U.S.C. 6209a(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Inspector General Act of 1978</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 4 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="ido2bu04f1-1w9k-93ki-imfu-rqm5y2vuh2y7"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Title 26</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">Section 6103(l)(13)(D)(i)(II)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">26 U.S.C. 6103(l)(13)(D)(i)(II)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Inspector General Act of 1978,</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 4 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idzma4edng-kkfd-u7ok-rrid-oz3hyfnkrqzk"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Title 31</header> <subparagraph id="idz6sem1gg-icey-70wu-by69-88siybd9902d"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2 of the Good Accounting Obligation in Government Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/414">Public Law 115–414</external-xref>, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/1105">31 U.S.C. 1105</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> 
<clause id="id7j7dqqaz-dwps-59aq-utq9-g5bo61cy5zl5"><enum>(i)</enum><text> in subsection (a)(1), by striking <quote>section 8G(a)(2) of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 415(a)(1) of title 5, United States Code</quote>; </text></clause> <clause id="idz1mz4n32-tijd-rldv-u10b-g8mhy8557pro"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2), by striking <quote>section 12(2) of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 401(1) of title 5, United States Code</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="id92l7r2ib-zp20-f0fv-cmm4-t8yn4b4v8t1f"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(3)(D)(ii), by striking <quote>section 5 of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 405 of title 5, United States Code</quote>. </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idc7k285co-9qzm-hevw-qjzy-zrgjg4fressg"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 3354(d)(4)(B) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 6(j) of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 406(j) of title 5</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idlq57ibdn-6fdo-zzp0-w57l-0cd02sur5h81"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Title 38</header> 
<subparagraph id="idqryvv3h1-6mwy-rcn8-egsa-r12arhsosimw"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 9(a) of the Department of Veterans Affairs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/100/527">Public Law 100–527</external-xref>, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/301">38 U.S.C. 301</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>the Inspector General Act of 1978,</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 4 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id0mz75rr4-3mq9-fnff-telf-bqzaq9qzs9cz"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 312 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<clause id="ididzgt066-4qhf-unze-7vqj-gj3s6cpm7cgm"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>Act</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter</quote>; </text></clause> <clause id="idjpnejp4d-w11p-2zh8-eql3-ti4z7r2zvkty"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1)(A), by striking <quote>the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> in 2 places and inserting <quote>chapter 4 of title 5</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idh3d5ezwn-sviz-rzvl-iuc2-943p6fgfspdt"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(6)(A), by striking <quote>section 5(b) of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/5/5">5 U.S.C. App. 5(b)</external-xref>),</quote> and inserting <quote>section 405(c) of title 5,</quote>. </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idhhd7mgup-4dff-gzw6-q8fi-5r43izib8ddq"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 733(a) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>the Whistleblower Protection Ombudsman designated under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Inspector General Act of 1978 /3">section 3(d)(1)(C)</external-xref> of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.),</quote> and inserting <quote>the Whistleblower Protection Coordinator designated under section 403(d)(1)(C) of title 5,</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idd0f3f8ia-i53l-12ub-p8z4-akkfi1zaw8zo"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Title 42</header> 
<subparagraph id="id1rhrf1wf-nbir-ay5z-hjis-5rl4m9zsyezs"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4004(b)(4) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300jj-52">42 U.S.C. 300jj–52(b)(4)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="idrnd94m7m-3aq5-vwae-t5bd-hkim178zopng"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">inspector general act of 1978</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">chapter 4 of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="id51d3rpk5-aa1v-ond1-qtgz-qgu3zwubyng9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the paragraph text, by striking <quote>section 6 of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 406 of title 5, United States Code</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idnse6nmwg-be2a-uqrb-e944-b08630edzjg3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 601(f)(4) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/801">42 U.S.C. 801(f)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 4 of title 5, United States Code</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idewcp24ki-qim9-u09q-nn5t-mz450s1gp6nc"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Title 44</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3903 of title 44, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="id1rgsiywn-sznt-54zy-swsy-z7zy3dqz8vhc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(3), by striking <quote>section 6(a)(8) of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 406(a)(8) of title 5</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idcpkk5ngw-lwti-ckqg-so4n-ug5f2cimrz1k"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(3)(A), by striking <quote>section 5 of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.),</quote> and inserting <quote>section 405 of title 5,</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id3vk3t2f8-d1vk-6ozc-dbb6-zj2c1tkjlwfn"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Title 49</header><text>The last proviso under the heading <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">salaries and expenses</header-in-text></quote>, under the heading <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Office of Inspector General</header-in-text></quote>, in the Department of Transportation Appropriations Act, 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/235">Public Law 113–235</external-xref>, div. K, title I, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/354">49 U.S.C. 354</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>the Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended,</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 4 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id3grhsntf-qk8h-17g9-zlpw-rcqlo7hvmc2n"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Title 50</header> 
<subparagraph id="idveiypc99-sb11-son3-9vem-m3tky6l9c4z3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 103H(c)(6)(A) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3033">50 U.S.C. 3033(c)(6)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 3 of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 403 of title 5, United States Code</quote>. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idl1ozvfup-4cry-y93y-9mqq-ezwyzri6qh51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 17(b)(8)(A) of the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3517">50 U.S.C. 3517(b)(8)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 3 of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 403 of title 5, United States Code</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="idpt6ko8ja-4f45-5z3z-hzss-04rww8h5zpye"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendments To Update References to the Federal Advisory Committee Act</header> 
<paragraph id="id5vvmrmpy-b79c-ouza-0bm5-a3wvo3kpfzro"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Title 6</header> 
<subparagraph id="idhuzc5snm-1t2q-y15h-rfa7-fa6akot4iz7y"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 102(h) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/112">6 U.S.C. 112(h)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idj9s3b7fv-yadr-edfr-2mqb-5bc20elzz8ob"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 404(f) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/204">6 U.S.C. 204(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<clause id="idyyk90tzj-hwi2-0bkr-8rrq-3img2alqz4ba"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">FACA</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Chapter 10 of Title 5, United States Code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="idsp9wd7q2-qbfa-rgj6-5v2d-fmcg7gc99hro"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the subsection text, by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idy64ma5zw-7s8z-ks71-zz6u-48yntl2jpmto"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 1756(b)(4) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/321o-1">6 U.S.C. 321o–1(b)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.),</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idvezhcczu-ytdw-5481-mhpu-1tpa68scza05"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2(d) of the Protecting Firefighters from Adverse Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/323">6 U.S.C. 323(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<clause id="idfscekvrp-qt0f-ik2j-qn6d-eej9355e9o6i"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">FACA</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Chapter 10 of Title 5, United States Code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="id8fjzv7gq-2lwk-8cl8-ad3u-i243j06zr10i"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the subsection text, by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idj9nuojcg-i6b9-kb2k-8ggu-ehw0b7cl0omm"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3(g)(2) of the K–12 Cybersecurity Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/47">Public Law 117–47</external-xref>, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/652">6 U.S.C. 652</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <clause id="idzvssanyq-c395-3pcn-k50c-nl47paqq00to"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">faca</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">chapter 10 of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idh2zr0f2f-hlhn-rfzz-r7o3-h1ogjy6kv7bj"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the paragraph text, <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id5c92onrp-69pn-dmvy-90kn-ztgeji4b11s1"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 101(c)(2) of the Strenghtening and Enhancing Cyber-capabilities by Utilizing Risk Exposure Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/390">Public Law 115–390</external-xref>, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/663">6 U.S.C. 663</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> 
<clause id="id2ryerth9-hmzy-p2cg-60ze-p0s2nzclw5s7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">faca</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">chapter 10 of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="id34yhwih6-ez4z-ojub-w7li-kfe3adlznzz2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the paragraph text, by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idbmos1bok-356v-smjn-8fow-vcyfzbajj5l6"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2220D(a)(4)(B) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/665k">6 U.S.C. 665k(a)(4)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="idgfi8ao4a-qram-n0io-470h-luo83wviodje"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subparagraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">Federal advisory committee act</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subparagraph">Chapter 10 of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and </text></clause> 
<clause id="idhlpsyufh-mbcm-dnnh-tq98-hhjtfeqzb7ei"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the subparagraph text, by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>. </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idhmd84ywa-ma64-za4g-9tsu-j6pi7fsem6gk"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1927(h) of the TSA Modernization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/254">Public Law 115–254</external-xref>, div. K, title I, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/1116">6 U.S.C. 1116</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> 
<clause id="iddz4yjufk-z7on-8scn-szge-46v0n9aiifu0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Federal Advisory Committee Act</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Chapter 10 of Title 5, United States Code</header-in-text></quote>; and </text></clause> <clause id="idauzkfcde-5hve-fbv6-fak8-4dz8et0ln4bk"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the subsection text, by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="iddksdtyc9-4fky-uafa-twpk-qjw1jzippwy0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Title 7</header> 
<subparagraph id="idoyhrjtga-qpzq-6aup-mzmd-bhwwov0vhcy3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 309(b)(7) of the Federal Crop Insurance Reform and Department of Agriculture Reorganization Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/6921">7 U.S.C. 6921(b)(7)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="id01f1e7ek-dal8-zlwm-q6l0-1d7scya4szk2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">Federal advisory committee act exemption</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">Exemption from <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idl798sroa-6a8y-fgyp-tc8w-qv1f4uqgnwhn"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the paragraph text, by striking <quote>Section 14 of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Section 1013 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id80lrzz7p-sikt-r0yy-q2b6-esnmcp48ku27"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 10409A(b)(5) of the Animal Health Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/8308a">7 U.S.C. 8308a(b)(5)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idagetrlgd-c59c-7cnr-wl5r-sjdndzk7oare"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Title 10</header> 
<subparagraph id="idqmqv8zva-bs7e-oanf-9rwh-7dz5vdgpkvdq"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 833(e)(3) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/81">Public Law 117–81</external-xref>, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/4001">10 U.S.C. 4001</external-xref> note) is amended— </text> <clause id="idtz8qtqe6-ozfz-7al3-7qe7-oe6cjy1zh74e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">FACA non-applicability</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">Inapplicability of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idfhuaotqk-coej-lc1h-pc8p-eimcgspd6v0h"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the paragraph text, by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id6947f38g-3g1f-1ej1-4gej-bb3z9zw4saaf"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 898(k) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>, 10 U.S.C. note prec. 4751) is amended—</text> 
<clause id="id5q2hmz6b-zyfu-q6hi-7kc7-4gatvy5kkt83"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">FACA</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Chapter 10 of Title 5, United States Code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="idb4iy2712-idla-3htr-8818-zzequrkp0y0m"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the subsection text, by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>. </text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idobadf5je-pvoj-8f8b-o0ar-ddzdl2u062lv"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 8933(e) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 14 of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.),</quote> and inserting <quote>section 1013 of title 5,</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="idpz0a22mj-e45b-ga5l-dwjr-fc1500ti9lqw"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Title 15</header> <subparagraph id="idnyt2jtfm-4v2c-z6l1-iq69-nbmlkvvrmipz"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 40(h) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78qq">15 U.S.C. 78qq(h)</external-xref>) is amended— </text> 
<clause id="id8al8dipp-vps5-nsln-p02f-j9ppy6fgtzek"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Federal Advisory Committee Act</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Chapter 10 of Title 5, United States Code</header-in-text></quote>; and </text></clause> <clause id="id4icuvfud-sgpr-uwk5-3b90-pccgr6y50dhd"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the subsection text, by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idkjci2kj6-o7jk-pdi4-iauu-8p4d2f405j48"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 9906(b)(3) of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/4656">15 U.S.C. 4656(b)(3)</external-xref>) is amended— </text> <clause id="iddj7qqbs1-5neq-zt1w-9ojs-9ez4putcw8td"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">FACA exemption</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">Exemption from <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idobkfcsm8-7qbg-y7yo-ewu6-9a4f7zzn9f7p"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the paragraph text, by striking <quote>Section 14 of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) </quote> and inserting <quote>Section 1013 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idp6z7qvu9-3q63-0gsj-09jr-v1js1w6nvmpm"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 104(g) of the National Quantum Initiative Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8814">15 U.S.C. 8814(g)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<clause id="idtcas1r9y-ijc3-mt78-7yoo-qjo5v2iybzvj"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">FACA Exemption</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Exemption From Chapter 10 of Title 5, United States Code</header-in-text></quote>; and </text></clause> <clause id="id8fz0c8qq-0wvr-2tnu-y69u-c6gzoy48u3a0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the subsection text, by striking <quote>section 14 of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 1013 of title 5, United States Code</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idotghcczz-zhsd-jebl-cbz1-d2iin8tqnhrs"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5104(h) of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9414">15 U.S.C. 9414(h)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="idmzu3b9ce-qm6h-tfvb-6k13-aznqw37b05uw"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Faca Exemption</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Exemption From Chapter 10 of Title 5, United States Code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idt5wskcpg-mnmw-uruy-sd7n-ngy250u3c6a9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the subsection text—</text> <subclause id="idlnru8zw0-t2q7-no6f-8det-pdhfu7ira48e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.),</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="id0oo3hl41-uzrq-y40u-jz58-wtny685hc1nw"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 14 of such Act</quote> and inserting <quote>section 1013 of such title</quote>.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idz8f1kcek-z0ad-2h6z-g639-z5ze550nz42n"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Section 100503(c) of the Minority Business Development Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9573">15 U.S.C. 9573(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 14 of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.),</quote> and inserting <quote>section 1013 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idm130kz5b-p9ef-p6jo-ebip-rfgk9rzr389h"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Title 16</header> 
<subparagraph id="idtyibwmer-41fr-4kiv-n8q7-3mo65jz9p2my"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 1223(c)(1) of the John D. Dingell, Jr. Conservation, Management, and Recreation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/460dddd-2">16 U.S.C. 460dddd-2(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id0m4smw21-ejz3-96fc-tokc-s1uy4lf13kdg"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 120(f)(6)(D)(iv) of the Marine Mammal Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1389">16 U.S.C. 1389(f)(6)(D)(iv)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<clause id="idbvgh1n1m-l292-ra9k-n3nj-t3ynm8bbel9t"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the clause heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">faca</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">chapter 10 of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and </text></clause> <clause id="idttfci8y0-wehz-emig-1a1o-22vtwe1pgf9i"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the clause text, by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idzth8di9z-0z9k-q7pf-36yz-4zzmzbj8rnd6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 28001(d) of the Surface Transportation Investment Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>, div. B, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1801">16 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <clause id="idoowf3skz-g5ti-qh2w-33rq-zi746cbiqr7b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idhqkrqaf1-h9cq-hwfu-8zbi-3zwrnwjksubz"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)—</text> <subclause id="idpvumi53v-115r-nw3y-4w57-8pz6md7brk0m"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">FACA</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">Chapter 10 of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and </text></subclause> 
<subclause id="id59hevrob-005s-uw33-utzz-kj836p7af2bq"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the paragraph text, by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idds06qg5m-z5tp-30rh-530y-vkfep262d6qv"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Section 102(d)(1)(C)(iv) of the Ensuring Access to Pacific Fisheries Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/7702">16 U.S.C. 7702(d)(1)(C)(iv)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id6e4oj3wq-g1nw-00bs-1cct-4skvv1ieg5wz"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Section 202(d)(1)(C)(iv) of the Ensuring Access to Pacific Fisheries Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/7802">16 U.S.C. 7802(d)(1)(C)(iv)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idbr9td1c2-vevt-ql74-6dv7-zo29apzrkqcb"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Section 1(b) of the America’s Conservation Enhancement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/188">Public Law 116–188</external-xref>, 134 Stat. 905) is amended, in the table of contents, in the item relating to section 211 under the heading <quote>TITLE II—NATIONAL FISH HABITAT CONSERVATION THROUGH PARTNERSHIPS</quote>, by striking <quote>Nonapplicability of Federal Advisory Committee Act</quote> and inserting <quote>Nonapplicability of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id6ilnu9n9-eic6-47jq-yd25-5j8jmgioapdk"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Section 211 of the America’s Conservation Enhancement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/8211">16 U.S.C. 8211</external-xref>) is amended in the section heading by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">federal advisory committee act</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">chapter 10 of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id2krdwsz8-285z-y178-4qi1-vl6i4hy6vziz"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Title 20</header><text>Section 5(b)(2)(C) of the HBCU Propelling Agency Relationships Towards a New Era of Results for Students Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1063e">20 U.S.C. 1063e(b)(2)(C)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idyi7n9dz1-uvr0-iz8t-iq7z-rno2tivzdzyp"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Title 22</header> 
<subparagraph id="id7ony4zda-yjeo-zpwc-oith-83ow8wf3iwv9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (g) of the Survivors of Human Trafficking Empowerment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7103b">22 U.S.C. 7103b(g)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="idgj827df2-2qmg-sers-1zgr-a7cqgqztj713"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">FACA</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Chapter 10 of Title 5, United States Code</header-in-text></quote>; and </text></clause> 
<clause id="ido8oqag65-27fm-fbjk-q8l2-bn96a09jfj0z"><enum>(ii)</enum><text> by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id5z5or6aj-sf4s-n8ly-tj3w-2n9b1ughjpil"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1413(i)(4) of the Better Utilization of Investments Leading to Development Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9613">22 U.S.C. 9613(i)(4)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<clause id="idt4s3qnsy-5rz2-9m8i-pi4j-e6uj7gdztlmr"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">Federal advisory committee act</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">Chapter 10 of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="idttwz1yr3-fd7k-3jur-4vqi-i1l5pbyqb0m1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the paragraph text, by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idsfb71nq1-9ewh-kov0-pmk5-u22r2w4e02z9"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Title 25</header> 
<subparagraph id="idiwem8md5-cfvn-9gig-rlt4-zkii4jvgm7vn"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 813(g)(5) of the Violence Against Women Act Reauthorization Act of 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1305">25 U.S.C. 1305(g)(5)</external-xref>) is amended— </text> <clause id="idcpzbqhum-u33z-z203-l0yj-00dig4c7q6gl"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">faca</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">chapter 10 of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="id0lkf9mut-yfkt-b3uw-ws34-2cct8zjazqmd"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the paragraph text, by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id8cc10u6k-9i4j-szc4-31yj-i12vlpo2ptdj"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8(e) of the Safeguard Tribal Objects of Patrimony Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/3076">25 U.S.C. 3076(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<clause id="idbt87l7ui-z6v2-dp52-zrdq-eb61yde7hcsw"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Federal Advisory Committee Act</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Chapter 10 of Title 5, United States Code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="id4ifg6ezn-mdht-wv73-hgt3-h55ki0ae7z0v"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the subsection text, by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idltgzjq36-zemq-lz5e-dvz9-vwc748ri7l1f"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Title 31—</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6214(c) of the Anti-Money Laundering Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>, div. F, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/5311">31 U.S.C. 5311</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="idq4jy0ih8-866h-vwjr-275c-0g410iq4b5yr"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Federal Advisory Committee Act</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Chapter 10 of Title 5, United States Code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idqwzrzf6n-jcpy-yjl2-cu8c-5zg20bj45y56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the subsection text, by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="idl2cicz31-if12-i4lf-4ezl-h9hp191atp2i"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Title 33</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 12404(c)(10) of the Federal Ocean Acidification Research And Monitoring Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3703">33 U.S.C. 3703(c)(10)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="id1o8nk72f-40az-e0op-q2lb-usq2lrmzizj7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">Federal advisory committee act</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">Chapter 10 of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idfz4pfzfu-bzzo-59ro-zrvf-hzeukvqe1ca0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the paragraph text, by striking <quote>Section 14 of the Federal Advisory Committee Act</quote> and inserting <quote>Section 1013 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idvseuawe0-09bi-juy7-s5zi-fvvs4g4dv65o"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Title 36</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7(b) of the Women's Suffrage Centennial Commission Act, as enacted by section 431(a)(3) of the Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/31">Public Law 115–31</external-xref>, div. G, 36 U.S.C. note prec. 101) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="id0mf1ij17-3wz3-0ake-ozh0-zmt93iitjmqn"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Federal Advisory Committee Act</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Chapter 10 of Title 5, United States Code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id3crr21i8-6qme-7qt6-8syj-81pq4v1fzyi6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id6n7j64yo-bqfq-4llb-c72v-zcimyije0knw"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>Section 14(a)(2) of such Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Section 1013(a)(2) of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idu68gcjkn-3dn3-mzhm-a786-bkg8dmpftl3w"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Title 38</header> 
<subparagraph id="iddp6vng2j-3qry-k689-4zg0-p6kst42ln7z5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 533(e)(4) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idyuccu21r-z438-lc2s-3e5k-2w70ngw3w23t"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 547(i) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<clause id="idjzbvcit2-l3y3-toqv-w2w7-ebp07zf5em0t"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Federal Advisory Committee Act Exemption</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Exemption From Chapter 10 of Title 5</header-in-text></quote>; and </text></clause> <clause id="id4ljzwicz-pzji-tnou-fvmz-i3edo5abm897"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the subsection text, by striking <quote>Section 14 of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Section 1013 of title 5</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="iduu5hstvo-wiaw-y1d9-55p1-pju9ipv98ep1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5305(f) of the Deborah Sampson Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/315">Public Law 116–315</external-xref>, title V, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1720D">38 U.S.C. 1720D</external-xref> note) is amended— </text> <clause id="idpr0o5twn-833m-r7ct-esmr-fzz63i8ry0w7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">FACA</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Chapter 10 of Title 5, United States Code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="ide8rrkror-mqgj-vei9-sbvq-5bjn5lssy5rv"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the subsection text, by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="idqwl4q0s9-dcpv-vagw-2iso-gneumz26ifcp"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Title 42</header> <subparagraph id="id7c75sr8u-7l44-wcaj-f64g-lyzhrlob0nkw"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 505(d) of the Pandemic and All-Hazards Preparedness and Advancing Innovation Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/22">Public Law 116–22</external-xref>, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247d-5">42 U.S.C. 247d–5</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> 
<clause id="idezf5tz5j-d4a4-ssyi-kczj-o8862837o5ya"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">FACA</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Chapter 10 of Title 5, United States Code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="id7ba1vsaz-jcol-kymd-dohf-z6kky7jnumh8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the subsection text, by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id7956ivrt-2u2c-e525-gkaq-ic5hi85m4ynw"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2062(c)(6) of the 21st Century Cures Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/284s">42 U.S.C. 284s(c)(6)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="idv4gfoq3m-c7dn-89d5-y3eo-5499g5y3zpl6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">faca</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">chapter 10 of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idpm66n347-6to9-lekp-293b-1nwrwq9qdz7w"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the paragraph text, by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idqsdu6lls-0kdl-5tk7-9t3z-wlloz5lqcip9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 2041(a)(1) of the 21st Century Cures Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/255">Public Law 114–255</external-xref>, div. A, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/289a-2">42 U.S.C. 289a–2</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.),</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="ide9akcffb-n9yf-z0zb-qjmd-3smqi4887ekr"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7022(h) of the Substance Use-Disorder Prevention that Promotes Opioid Recovery and Treatment for Patients and Communities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/271">Public Law 115–271</external-xref>, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290aa">42 U.S.C. 290aa</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <clause id="idvw783rcw-0onu-7awc-tld4-zqcd65l6zfey"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Federal Advisory Committee Act</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Chapter 10 of Title 5, United States Code</header-in-text></quote>; and </text></clause> 
<clause id="idwdz8hnif-86gb-urlm-2mle-y6n0rba5st88"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the subsection text—</text> <subclause id="id17y4zwlt-o1b7-56yz-qoow-z5os3um9vntn"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="ideq3v4twv-jjt5-l3rz-tlhz-pffo75wim847"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>such Act</quote> and inserting <quote>such chapter</quote>. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idqrdj2ptc-oulz-8upb-2jl3-z6whwfe1g1bq"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2203(c)(4) of the Water and Waste Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300j-27">42 U.S.C. 300j–27(c)(4)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<clause id="idh0kzkk9o-5vt2-u8jd-zwgu-oj58priq0hrm"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">faca</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">chapter 10 of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="idjkmi5zgr-syzm-nd91-qzqz-r52zels2rq6i"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the paragraph text, by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idhq0317u6-1jp1-z38w-2mc3-wp65y0885y51"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 13103(b)(4) of the Health Information Technology for Economic and Clinical Health Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>, div. A, title XIII, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300jj">42 U.S.C. 300jj</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <clause id="id2eqlqw7l-bvu2-np8r-ney4-708z2ni1nz6r"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">FACA</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">Chapter 10 of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="id39rylrmz-iqz7-sv21-zp23-fumh737bsp4r"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the paragraph text, by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idye9fpaf5-rtly-2dln-p8rt-lgunr93izjqg"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1128C(a)(6)(I) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1320a–7c(a)(6)(I)) is amended—</text> 
<clause id="idsf14tlf6-njpz-zbbv-llws-i11p2ub5sljh"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subparagraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">faca</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">chapter 10 of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="id1envsomi-bqa9-8zce-lbqb-jbffwmwmmha5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the subparagraph text, by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id3taburup-kqf8-dolc-sv7d-4en3lennnhnl"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4(e) of the Recognize, Assist, Include, Support, and Engage Family Caregivers Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/119">Public Law 115–119</external-xref>, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3030s">42 U.S.C. 3030s</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <clause id="idu0sor6wc-ve4p-537w-vzgo-hyclzqpyj9zg"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">FACA</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Chapter 10 of Title 5, United States Code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="id12v2jp8d-71fi-a4qe-lnuo-8hyerzv3whhz"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the subsection text, by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idzat6ijsg-9pbr-84fi-7iaw-o08ntozz8zsn"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Section 41003(a)(1)(D)(ii) of the Fixing America’s Surface Transportation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4370m-2">42 U.S.C. 4370m–2(a)(1)(D)(ii)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code</quote>. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id02j9ibu8-hgnm-cva1-vjrg-zw1f164cvqre"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (c)(5) of the Industries of the Future Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>, div. H, title XCIV, §9412, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6601">42 U.S.C. 6601</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <clause id="idc5ccflts-5w2z-2323-u7i6-wq3r8lzz5b3j"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">faca</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">chapter 10 of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="id41jclcgd-ony8-fjz9-7gh9-vmja6voyzmr3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the paragraph text, by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>. </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idnodee175-5fyy-v4i5-4j8s-nhd4m2zaeziq"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Section 103(g)(6)(B)(vi) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7403">42 U.S.C. 7403(g)(6)(B)(vi)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 14 of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.),</quote> and inserting <quote>section 1013 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idklis18fc-hwyu-9dti-dkzm-sgwiq6fekt2b"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 455(h) of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17114">42 U.S.C. 17114(h)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="idzl98hjy2-8idb-aion-fmio-ndg6yv4lbky8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Federal Advisory Committee Act</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Chapter 10 of Title 5, United States Code</header-in-text></quote>; and </text></clause> 
<clause id="idj7zi9ksa-cq8n-urpo-ihhc-yp7tkjj9hpp0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the subsection text, by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) </quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idpcmfg6vw-prv9-b26b-q9pe-p0nu03cm3uwt"><enum>(M)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 311(c)(4) of the Department of Energy Office of Science Policy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18649">42 U.S.C. 18649(c)(4)</external-xref>) is amended— </text> 
<clause id="idsg0uk1aq-okd6-dh8j-h71r-jhursemciy9r"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">FACA</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">Chapter 10 of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="idwtu8zybt-1q0r-v2w8-8ce9-pqalns2lfs0o"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the paragraph text, by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idw80znpnk-ki03-cc93-gyka-s8m29btt6suq"><enum>(N)</enum><text>Section 10386(a) of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/19106">42 U.S.C. 19106(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id1kgjazqw-9ln4-ohvj-sybm-mkgw4ugo4ljh"><enum>(O)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 10404(d) of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/19134">42 U.S.C. 19134(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<clause id="idy7rsziwz-f9c7-rcq7-750u-mjiwzvjrrwk8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Federal Advisory Committee Act</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Chapter 10 of Title 5, United States Code</header-in-text></quote>; and </text></clause> <clause id="idap6t27q1-7fgh-u9oy-o4tz-9v95t0ov0ngs"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the subsection text, by striking <quote>Section 14 of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Section 1013 of title 5, United States Code,</quote></text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id8h8cseuh-yb1h-m15f-6q6g-inlb8tub58z9"><enum>(P)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 10691(b)(5)(L) of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/19281">42 U.S.C. 19281(b)(5)(L)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="idq8ujrbok-ukkz-epdw-cp20-azbidkmabql5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subparagraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">faca</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">chapter 10 of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idy3yvl275-44f8-t0ij-54gl-sld5i9dcjr3b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the subparagraph text, by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id6whcq1h7-rkpp-j7rl-hzjw-8zcp0g9y578i"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Title 43</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 754 of the Geospatial Data Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2803">43 U.S.C. 2803</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="id6nac47ro-68z3-gnwj-goz2-hrs4obiv0cp7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(3), by striking <quote>section 10(e) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 1009(e) of title 5, United States Code,</quote>; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idj00ie8b5-8gyw-7e87-cbcq-9hfztbg2qtyf"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (h)—</text> 
<clause id="idc1q2kzi4-qlpo-s4ys-vz7z-2rqp586jvht5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">FACA</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Chapter 10 of Title 5, United States Code</header-in-text></quote>; </text></clause> <clause id="idm03dtnz4-00sa-izai-otpb-e27tgiz4u7db"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>; and </text></clause> 
<clause id="id6hnej8e4-r4zm-4foy-jtew-qsnab7ub7ey4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>Section 14(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Section 1013(a)(2) of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="idv34wohws-9cpd-hu7t-b2zu-6vl1vhzzz032"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Title 47</header><text>Section 9202(a)(1)(F)(i) of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/906">47 U.S.C. 906(a)(1)(F)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.),</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="ide346yav7-u3f8-mmwg-adlb-psvt8ahwzspp"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Title 49</header> 
<subparagraph id="idoq7mbc7z-m0uq-6a65-7ok6-t869varrct0v"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1931(b)(3) of the TSA Modernization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/254">Public Law 115–254</external-xref>, div. K, title I, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/114">49 U.S.C. 114</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <clause id="id0784fkcf-8izl-n3eq-8zrj-ziw96zt1z6b2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">faca</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">chapter 10 of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idufy8g3nv-jvpy-umna-j0ec-vad3wfdb1ug8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the paragraph text, by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idzz4m0ly5-3chz-9zpr-prva-p3n8r428pv7g"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 8426(c)(2)(C)(ii) of the Elijah E. Cummings Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>, div. G, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/303a">49 U.S.C. 303a</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idtd3rfc43-gptb-ilcs-yhey-s3pd9o8cauhs"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 513(f) of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/254">Public Law 115–254</external-xref>, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/40101">49 U.S.C. 40101</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>Public Law 92–463</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idl35vrkwn-gfbu-zr5n-l4l9-0s2ei6rn5tk5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Section 202(g)(3) of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/254">Public Law 115–254</external-xref>, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44701">49 U.S.C. 44701</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>Public Law 92–463</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idogenihvi-pm3z-zba8-b8m2-m5lo3obwn447"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Section 333(d)(1) of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/254">Public Law 115–254</external-xref>, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44701">49 U.S.C. 44701</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.),</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idbdp5e26p-4zyr-zups-hyoi-h8bkg2uw7qbg"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Section 103(a)(6)(D) of the Aircraft Certification, Safety, and Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>, div. V, title I, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44736">49 U.S.C. 44736</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>Public Law 92–463</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idis5qhue8-e04o-5tea-ci9b-anklmdkigk99"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Section 213(g) of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/254">Public Law 115–254</external-xref>, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44736">49 U.S.C. 44736</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>Public Law 92–463</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idl332r7es-u63y-sdqj-c8b6-gv8cmylhjnmo"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Section 44810(b)(3) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idellkr4bw-1v46-bqvj-951o-d6afgqvhlhhi"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1916(e) of the TSA Modernization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/254">Public Law 115–254</external-xref>, div. K, title I, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44912">49 U.S.C. 44912</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <clause id="idz3vqizqg-c0f3-6e5u-6qk7-ym64qt0e9llo"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">FACA</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Chapter 10 of Title 5, United States Code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="ide9z5b0bz-c2vo-za45-joqc-j7emo4yqq5ra"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the subsection text, by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idtl19ne0a-gzdf-u6ly-e0vb-cwj61qh6sccj"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1938(f)(3) of the TSA Modernization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/254">Public Law 115–254</external-xref>, div. K, title I, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44919">49 U.S.C. 44919</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> 
<clause id="idfy0kelk7-nsvf-5ub7-6ctc-ab94gi4wl5ge"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">faca</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">chapter 10 of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="id05ou0gy4-kz2s-bzhi-gfp7-0fr6l70qptis"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the paragraph text, by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id6zzod8jj-43o0-mklp-kzap-5u1zawe5mmz6"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Section 44920(h)(1) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.),</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5,</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="idf6nkuke9-7v8f-9t4u-1tsf-8omz84l9ytdj"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Title 50</header> <subparagraph id="idozze4dww-avu1-gmhp-ioa9-2kaoeubuqle5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 106A(d)(7) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3041a">50 U.S.C. 3041a(d)(7)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idsyq5s63u-ry99-izfr-sn8b-dhzk83kev5s5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1034 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3227c">50 U.S.C. 3227c</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="idojcpqkn2-p5er-hot7-yhyb-9p9sednp4gst"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">the federal advisory committee act</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">chapter 10 of title 5, united states code,</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idqp87zzzn-d77l-mzk8-jeqa-33gqif0q7s8v"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the section text, by striking <quote>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idku6eqt8l-3sq9-4dwn-89bt-mvqksbvdk790"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 1754(a)(13) of the Export Controls Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4813">50 U.S.C. 4813(a)(13)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Federal Advisory Committee Act</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idcza3z1oz-2w75-s51b-8gp7-esgmbgpitub5"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1758(f)(5) of the Export Controls Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4817">50 U.S.C. 4817(f)(5)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="id4qnryckb-jadk-zu3c-qsi8-ontkd1faer8k"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">federal advisory committee act</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">chapter 10 of title 5, united states code</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="idjazjd2lr-3n0w-643h-zb96-nkt7k9ncce89"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the paragraph text, by striking <quote>Subsections (a)(1), (a)(3), and (b) of section 10 and sections 11, 13, and 14 of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Subsections (a)(1), (a)(3), and (b) of section 1009 and sections 1010, 1012, and 1013 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="idjvg11wbc-tazi-37id-9jh8-74spuim2n59t"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Title 51</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 60601(d)(4) of title 51, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="idrgpq5cg6-iai8-fjpz-o3et-daz03weq1nz8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">Federal advisory committee act</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">Chapter 10 of title 5</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idch3q33fi-bp76-mr15-z1az-1mms1zhidd61"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the paragraph text, by striking <quote>Section 14 of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>Section 1013 of title 5</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="id213ht5fs-r6ub-7k4z-iks8-pkil182yjchw"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amendments To Update References to the Ethics in Government Act of 1978</header> 
<paragraph id="idinouczy9-hsoc-tz0o-9t5j-lytp05dk8zgj"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Title 2</header> 
<subparagraph id="idoluqwsii-ne1n-wsfk-vz6b-s2mjz960bk4n"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 416(d)(7) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1416">2 U.S.C. 1416(d)(7)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>title I of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App. 101 et seq.)</quote> and inserting <quote>subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/131">chapter 131</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id50lflyns-41je-rq26-15lm-84zjf3e2r6eq"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 114(b)(3)(A) of the Congressional Operations Appropriation Act, 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4576">2 U.S.C. 4576(b)(3)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.),</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 131 of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idf1wzm4ph-70qb-e40p-8a9r-9l33ohp1hbt8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Title 10</header> 
<subparagraph id="idmuw806ut-yaws-d56u-yzqv-mwi2167duzvi"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 988(c)(2) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 102(f)(8) of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 13104(f)(8) of title 5</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idlcgb5fpe-znaa-92eb-mb3n-ohzn8e8zt52o"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 1599g(f)(2)(E) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>the Ethics in Government Act of 1978</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 131 of title 5</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id4uwpl9c7-cju8-64pp-9n30-9fjesj2wj4o7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Title 18</header><text>Section 442(b)(3) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 131 of title 5</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id3p37vvpy-8dt0-4597-2jwk-cp5ptsrkiak6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Title 42</header><text>Section 10691(b)(5)(I)(ii)(II) of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/19281">42 U.S.C. 19281(b)(5)(I)(ii)(II)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 109 of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 13101 of title 5, United States Code</quote>. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idlh6qezy5-wpzm-87fe-apet-1rk44dj0umc9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Title 50</header><text>Section 5306(g)(2)(E) of the Damon Paul Nelson and Matthew Young Pollard Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Years 2018, 2019, and 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3334">50 U.S.C. 3334(g)(2)(E)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)</quote> and inserting <quote>chapter 131 of title 5, United States Code</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="idbaq5klb1-8nc6-wakm-qzf0-yoz7eks9gec7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Other Amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective on the date of enactment of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/286">Public Law 117–286</external-xref> (136 Stat. 4196)—</text> 
<paragraph id="idkmf5l9zt-0e8e-ybnc-6lwy-yje8g4os70ec"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 4(a)(149) of that Act (136 Stat. 4322) is amended, in the matter before subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>Vocational Education Act of 1963</quote> and inserting <quote>Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006</quote>; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id686euj2j-o3d9-d4dq-15qd-d5a1nsffb5oo"><enum>(2)</enum><text>paragraphs (11), (12), (15), and (16) of section 4(c) of that Act (136 Stat. 4354, 4355) are amended by striking <quote>the Stop Trading on Congressional Knowledge Act of 2012</quote> and inserting <quote>the Representative Louise McIntosh Slaughter Stop Trading on Congressional Knowledge Act</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="idb48f9q5m-rgam-5hna-vm2g-4zczpjiayger"><enum>6.</enum><header>Transitional and savings provisions</header> 
<subsection id="id2ktwafvf-hk5p-fcq2-zpa8-01t1gthz28za"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header> 
<paragraph id="idgd838eu1-9c5y-2pf8-edv1-bm2f0zzvrq39"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Incorporated amendment</header><text>The term <term>incorporated amendment</term> means an amendment made by section 3 of this Act as described in subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idgm308saz-wins-wchz-owbu-1lmiudnvzie1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Original amendment</header><text>The term <term>original amendment</term> means an amendment to a source provision enacted after October 19, 2021.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idyeybguyg-h2dl-76dg-rzti-53rqltj9zkuq"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Source provision</header><text>The term <term>source provision</term> has the meaning given the term in section 5(a) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/286">Public Law 117–286</external-xref> (136 Stat. 4360).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="id1n6vtq8n-l2in-b5cs-ycn8-rc9myi65wypc"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope of Section 3 Amendments; Currency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by section 3 of this Act do not affect any law except—</text> 
<paragraph id="id2pein5zc-ypks-debv-cywp-nhtshmwgq1dc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to incorporate original amendments into chapters 4, 10, and 131 of title 5, United States Code, to keep those chapters current through March 15, 2025; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="iddrp39f6y-wrwu-0mp8-972y-3oz6ijey8nl4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to correct related technical errors.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="id918601lq-68jw-qzmu-toc0-s1s4rs4f8kva"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Original Date of Enactment Unchanged</header><text>An incorporated amendment is deemed to have been enacted on the date of enactment of the corresponding original amendment.</text></subsection> <subsection id="idboozp0wi-kaa2-1uhf-etes-tbjqkzqgp4p3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effect of Incorporated Amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An incorporated amendment—</text> 
<paragraph id="idds04tfnv-te00-8pqz-yhze-hf7jf8186tdu"><enum>(1)</enum><text>does not change or affect an original amendment; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="iduspt9co0-wy5n-ov7f-42ls-3k66ync3lg1t"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not change or affect any law that is not otherwise changed or affected by an original amendment.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


