<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H896076B585F841049643419EEF017FC2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5613 IH: It’s About Time Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5613</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250926">September 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">Committee on the Budget</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To change the calendar period of the Federal fiscal year.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H01DF35C9E33C41758043FA2A8766D11C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8B1B619415284C9694F8CCC0BB252593" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>It’s About Time Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8343FAADB77F4D56BD894F03BA2B30C5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Change of fiscal year</header> <subsection id="H9D481AB29B9C49449AAF401CBE537997"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="H6FAA89D2A77F48CB88BBAE97A4A42E45"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Change of calendar period</header><text>Section 1102 of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text>
<subparagraph id="H9924CEB0DD984E3491B734A6C8AC94E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>October 1</quote> and inserting <quote>January 1</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFBECDAACA5F84520A8AF76464181777D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>September 30 of the following year</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31 of that year</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8CA3AA51AAE14DBAA3CFF0C436775895"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by paragraph (1) shall be effective on January 1, 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1916ACE404904487A0BB0A42E7320884"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transition to new fiscal year</header> <paragraph id="H1DEC97A3BB9A477DAE887B8FBCF37DA0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Transition period budget</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable, the President shall prepare and submit to Congress—</text>
<subparagraph id="HA8F4DB5350D8400BA0E4559E1FA1AF21">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>after consultation with the Committees on the Budget and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, budget estimates for the Federal Government for the period commencing October 1, 2026, and ending on December 31, 2026, in such form and detail as the President may determine; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H21D89FB13DD14603B41829E882F89798"><enum>(B)</enum><text>proposed legislation the President considers appropriate with respect to changes in law necessary to provide authorizations of appropriations for that period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H80F6FE5D4CA3493884D353614436BAD4"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Agency transition</header> <text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall provide by regulation, order, or otherwise for the orderly transition by all departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the Federal Government and the Government of the District of Columbia from the use of the fiscal year in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act to the use of the new fiscal year prescribed in subsection (a). The Director shall prepare and submit to Congress such additional proposed legislation as the Director considers necessary to accomplish this objective.</text>
        </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE73BA669E0024993A925E2E15C7FAFAD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conversion of authorizations of appropriations</header><text>Any law providing for an authorization of appropriations commencing on October 1 of a year shall, if that year is any year after 2026, be considered as meaning January 1 of the following year. Any law providing for an authorization of appropriations ending on September 30 of a year shall, if that year is any year after 2026, be considered as meaning December 31 of that year. Any law providing for an authorization of appropriations for the fiscal year 2027 or any fiscal year thereafter shall be construed as referring to that fiscal year ending on December 31 of the calendar year having the same calendar year number as the fiscal year number.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFA5E69C74ACB4A529504FBE5F56BA249"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Title of appropriation Acts</header> <paragraph id="HC0B3541E4A8748608083E178E514731B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 105 of title 1, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>September 30</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H609DAFAD62244A01A2EE24B842AAC745"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by paragraph (1) shall be effective for any fiscal year commencing on or after January 1, 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

