<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H62D725C914934CDAB8A3D8BD28182037" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2305 IH: Corrections Officer Blake Schwarz Suicide Prevention Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2305</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250324">March 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide funding to the Bureau of Prisons, States, and localities to carry out mental health screenings and provide referrals to mental health care providers for certain corrections officers.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0FE89F25D32845B0A67828F692B461D6" style="OLC"><section id="H03630E9BE5E24A2E9805477CB00EF9E9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Corrections Officer Blake Schwarz Suicide Prevention Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF4C6B3242B9744AFA5C6C200C634359A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program</header><subsection id="H4EAF532F89234F369B277583A959DA9C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General is authorized establish a grant program to make grants to States and units of local government to implement and administer mental health screenings to corrections officers at eligible detention centers and refer such individuals to mental health care providers, as applicable. </text></subsection><subsection id="H8715A774C13E413FA1DE924D0D1A4D0A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible entity seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Attorney General an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require, including—</text><paragraph id="HD5DA1F8DC468456A821BE0091BFBD2B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of and a plan for the project under subsection (d) that the entity will carry out; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2796E37FE7754D3EA4D67292E6168BE8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assurance that the entity will hire a mental health liaison staff member to coordinate among eligible detention centers, mental health providers, the Advisory Board, and the outreach team. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8FAA0FB730EE4EBEBE004C229F1A56B0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible projects</header><text>A grant under this section may only be used for the following:</text><paragraph id="HDD324AFFC6034D2AA759E01178A43116"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To develop and administer a brief mental health screening survey as required under subsection (d).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEFEFE28CC2C47DAA7AFD8AD96CF43BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To develop any technology necessary for an eligible detention center to provide the survey under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FC036171F754E1FBDD817AC172E6399"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To hire any staff necessary for an eligible detention center to provide the survey under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27964173A9974C2EA6093246A2816350"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To establish an outreach team pursuant to subsection (e) to refer a correctional officer, if their responses to the survey indicate severe mental illness, to a local mental health care provider for further assessment and outreach, admission (when necessary), and support for that officer in re-establishing ties with a mental health provider.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D694C8324A744B99AAD9C4F89262503"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To pay the salary or overtime pay of an outreach team as established pursuant to subsection (e), including providing direct funding to an eligible detention center to compensate staff members.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3A746B58DBC84DE5A7864319CCA95D0C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Brief mental health screening survey</header><text>A mental health screening survey developed and administered pursuant to a grant under this section shall—</text><paragraph id="H26BB26DBAB0D458CB4A4BDB98CB70C42"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be composed of 5 to 10 questions; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4EB45C3BD014BD6A0E6B3DE8236031F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be based on the questions and content of the Employee Assistance Program standard mental health screening or the Bureau of Prisons initial mental health screening standard; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF86008E5DEA4D66AD3BB1F335A9B9C6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>seek to identify severe mental illnesses, including schizophrenia, bipolar disorder, and major depression;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4917AC5C920248D5A5A88C863F6E41CF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ask individuals about the symptoms of severe mental illness they may be experiencing or have experienced and any prior use of mental health-related medications or inpatient care;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EA87E61356B435E943F33948848FE6F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identify the individual’s place of residence; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H62EF2CECD62A42158AAA24A6C15B5450"><enum>(6)</enum><text>be administered by a trained staff member at the eligible detention center to all corrections officers; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46C353CDF4B44CA0B2B976630C7B5BB2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>be anonymous and confidential.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD3F55D41D3EC4F1D8B82148D0C8AD4BE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Outreach team</header><paragraph id="HBBF4C829D9654F588D9D59F3B76CB26B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A referral to a mental health care provider made pursuant to subsection (d) shall be made by a mental health outreach team that is composed of— </text><subparagraph id="H96820DFA637441A381A832FA844C7763"><enum>(A)</enum><text>mental health care professionals and clinicians from mental health care centers local to the eligible detention center;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64692EDB945C4D70BE1532155A48D3E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>staff from the eligible detention center, when applicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D40CB0F098D496F82A6FB6976F79AA6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a mental health liaison staff member who shall oversee the outreach team.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FF352E6E9F04A888723CCCAD479B11F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alert</header><text>If an individual has been determined to need a referral to a mental health care provider, the mental health outreach team shall be notified immediately by eligible detention center staff and informed, when applicable. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4F277BA913154B1B9C21AB8248B132BF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Bureau of prisons</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall—</text><paragraph id="HDB1AFCFABF8841788F9EA05F464F2AA2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish a program to develop and administer mental heath surveys (as described in subsection (d) of section 2) to corrections officers of the Bureau of Prisons, and establish and maintain an outreach team (as described in subsection (e) of section 2) to refer such corrections officer to mental health care providers, as appropriate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAFDE233AF6F44819E69C781B52F57F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the Advisory Board a plan for the implementation of the program described in paragraph (1). </text></paragraph></section><section id="H5015AFADC0414397BCEE8F96E008BA02"><enum>4.</enum><header>Advisory board on program implementation</header><subsection id="H000856C556A64FB090896A91E43020F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall establish an Advisory Board to manage and administer the grant program under section 2, with the responsibility for the following: </text><paragraph id="HE808990EB99B481684DFFB29A69F6247"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Evaluating and approving the plans submitted by a State or locality as required under section 2 and ensuring that grant funding is used as specified under section 2.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D3FCEF57497431F9B37A2DF86091E07"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Monitoring plans submitted by the Bureau of Prisons and advise the Attorney General on compliance to ensure that funding to the Bureau of Prisons is used as specified under section 3. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A42381348AB4AEFA078C57477091796"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Providing technical assistance to a State or locality to help with the implementation and administration of mental health screening and referral programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9A83AEA4DBF4F359BF54529206B1A89"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Creating a working group of mental health care providers, jail and prison administrators, law enforcement officials, and operators of existing mental health screening and referral programs to share best practices on how to create and implement mental health screening and referral programs that have the largest impact on reducing crime rates and improving employment and wage rates for individuals released from prison or jail. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57F5964810EE4C2AA242D092F391674A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Working in coordination with mental health outreach teams as established under section 2, to ensure that the grant program under such section is operating as required. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81D3FAFA820B47549B38FF0CB541CE22"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Determining if a grant awarded by the Program is not meeting the requirements of the Program and mandate necessary changes and reducing funding if such changes are not made. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E83C6F98439499CAD50534F12922957"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Developing a self-reporting process for mental health assistance that protects the anonymity and privacy of the officer and identifies and neutralizes any impediment to self-reporting, including loss of job and benefits. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H53598A4C487D49149D452C5479E76AAB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Advisory Board shall provide technical assistance to the Bureau of Prisons, States, and localities in setting up and administering the Program and shall identify evidence-backed models for the administration of mental health screening and referral programs that the Bureau of Prisons, States, and localities can look to when designing their own programs. </text></subsection><subsection id="HCFAA4DFDEF7C438DAD7F6256D1E06B21"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="H918F8E5DE01544009D72D6E32B1DDFE6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall appoint members to serve on the Advisory Board established under subsection (a) who have expertise in—</text><subparagraph id="H5CF3984EE80F4413AA8D223EA27FCD30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designing and administering mental health screenings and providing referrals for corrections officers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F14C7391F014E2388E8629A1C491D04"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mental health care within prisons or jails; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AC3C04318A74254BB9F8073EBBF0377"><enum>(C)</enum><text>program evaluation using rigorous experimental and quasi-experimental statistical methods. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0A334C7B78F4746B2D6AB9684F39681"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Number of members</header><text>The Attorney General shall appoint as many members to the Advisory Board established under subsection (a) as the Attorney General determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H563D18D587A04D4EBFAC9952E4EDD389"><enum>5.</enum><header>Funding</header><subsection id="H930DB85D2A114DB6B2DC4F02AEC01654"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Attorney General to carry out this Act—</text><paragraph id="H6826868C45B143488B5D5F177DC27526"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$50,000,000 for fiscal year 2026;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE06F0C418DEC4305B8E8E872EB118531"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$55,000,000 for fiscal year 2027;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCD61DB48EEA4A5CB6B3874E35910147"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$60,000,000 for fiscal year 2028;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDE0932D3929426CBD7948005AC239A7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$65,000,000 for fiscal year 2029; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2133277E4754F5DBB1E67B2E14D5019"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$70,000,000 for fiscal year 2030.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD20F2823839541ACADC0D33D277853B3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distribution of funds</header><text>Of the amounts made available under subsection (a), the Attorney General shall use—</text><paragraph id="HFF6389D4DA8140CF9B150CC0E9E6615F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>90 percent of such amount for a grant program under section 2 and the purposes described under section 3, as applicable, of which— </text><subparagraph id="HD48103A96411491DB0395A31B4487DF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>20 percent shall be for the Bureau of Prisons to carry out the requirements under section 3;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B6DC8E28ECB4DB6963AF47163AF0FBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>20 percent shall be for grants to States under section 2; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61D0164640044BA192691E4762AA3F8C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>50 percent shall be for grants to units of local government under section 2;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD9E6F2F32B74FF5A0C1CC4D7B8E686D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>5 percent of such amount for the Advisory Board to carry out evaluation activities under section 4(a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0126DF0B8C544C7F9C18CF7871F58CA9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>5 percent of such amount for the Advisory Board to carry out the activities under section 4(b). </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6D781536F5014A48AFB539A84AB5FFC8"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H3713B636B5A544E6A4E455B27F71D3F4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDE06B9C16B741CD94FC666324A791BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Locality</header><text>The term <term>locality</term> means any city, county, township, town, borough, parish, village, or other general purpose political subdivision of a State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69CD0ED072024079B0EA38FDE3C3CA4A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mental health care provider</header><text>The term <term>mental health care provider</term> means a fully-licensed professional or group of professionals who diagnose mental health conditions and provide mental health treatment, and who operate near to the relevant jail or prison. Mental health care providers may provide services at hospitals or at private clinics.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A6823A4F62C4FD9904ED201D6860656"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Mental health care center</header><text>The term <term>mental health care center</term> means any facility where one or more mental health care providers offer mental health services, such as a hospital or private clinic.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CADF40D4F724DEF97296D9A6A9B4A24"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Jail or prison administrator</header><text>The term <term>jail or prison administrator</term> means any individual who has been appointed to a supervisory position in a Federal, State, or local incarceration facility by the Federal Government, a State, or a locality. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFE535D4A830480CBC74F7C13D6DE0F9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Law enforcement official</header><text>The term <term>law enforcement official</term> means any officer of an entity administered by a locality, State, or the Federal Government that exists primarily to prevent and detect crime and enforce criminal laws.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43564922B99047F6BE9389C7E17045B8"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Corrections officers</header><text>The term <term>corrections officer</term> means any officer or employee of any prison, jail, or other detention facility, operated by, or under contract to, a Federal governmental agency, whose job responsibilities include providing for the custody of incarcerated individuals. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA15B3F2CEBCF4DDB85C9D1CFE689308F"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Eligible detention center</header><text>The term <term>eligible detention center</term> means any prison or jail administered by the Bureau of Prisons or a State or any jail administered by a State or locality. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1C7B8DBFA474712ACB64B8ECB79F97D"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Severe mental illness</header><text>The term <term>severe mental illness</term> means one or more mental, behavioral, or emotional disorders that results in serious functional impairment and substantially interferes with or limits major life activities.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

