<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELL25418-YP1-TP-CPC"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2079 IS: Enhanced Penalties for Criminal Flag Burners Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2079</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To enhance penalties for the use of incendiary devices, including burning the flag of the United States, in the commission of Federal offenses, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Enhanced Penalties for Criminal Flag Burners Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idb24c8618ffa9492b83937d070b11c7e1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header><subsection id="id049012dfe77d40179a5bba4d652f1494"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id68d4536672114423a124abfbdb3f8bfd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The unauthorized use of incendiary devices and open flames during commission of Federal offenses poses a significant threat to public safety and Federal property.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5672a4ae1c724a6baa0ff2d82f54ea41"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The desecration or destruction of United States symbols, including flags, in connection with Federal crimes or attempts to intimidate public actors amplifies the danger of the underlying crime to the public and to property.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1c4d7fc658c24e0fb1a4c8658d8716f1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The burning of the flag of the United States in furtherance of committing a Federal crime reflects an intent to provoke civic unrest, intimidate officials, or signal violent disruption and is an aggravating factor in the commission of a criminal act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id48246b51f6ee45618334e6965c86b047"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to enhance penalties for the use of incendiary devices, including burning the flag of the United States, in the commission of Federal offenses.</text></subsection></section><section id="ide4e63aacfd0a4998b53cfc8ce6d07452"><enum>3.</enum><header>Enhanced penalties for use of open flames or incendiary devices during commission of Federal offenses</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f231ac773944d0d8f5ad1026e4d349c"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/1">Chapter 1</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf3b087b0f16a45798177b8cc47108943"><section id="id4f9e9434feac4d678778ea7d84523124"><enum>28.</enum><header>Use of open flame or incendiary device during commission of Federal offense involving property damage or public endangerment</header><subsection id="id75371e4b95cc44b88599f901e696d082"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>incendiary device</term> includes any flammable object, accelerant, fire-starting mechanism, or other apparatus intended to ignite fire, whether improvised or commercially manufactured. </text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5dade8b9b6f045c085c4f7b523a95773"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enhanced penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever, in the course of committing a Federal offense involving property damage, obstruction of government operations, or public endangerment, knowingly uses or causes the use of an open flame or incendiary device, including burning the flag of the United States, shall be subject to an enhanced term of imprisonment of not less than 1 year, in addition to any other penalty authorized by law. </text></subsection><subsection id="iddffb1e9e2f084daebb11ecae514caf0e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>This section shall not apply to conduct protected under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, including expressive symbolic conduct not involving criminal acts or threats to public safety.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id81c86587bf8740f98b2ed160331ceeec"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaec304d1758343d2808fd449448bfac0"><toc><toc-entry level="section" bold="off">28. Use of open flame or incendiary device during commission of Federal offense involving property damage or public endangerment.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

