<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-AEG25322-T97-JG-M84"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1811 IS: EDUCATE Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1811</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250520">May 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S389">Mr. Kennedy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to prohibit graduate medical schools from receiving Federal financial assistance if such schools adopt certain policies and requirements relating to diversity, equity, and inclusion.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HBB718ACA976845BAA1FD730DF3EFE6EF"><section id="id1c501091e2374466aba6aa65c2d1da64" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Embracing Anti-Discrimination, Unbiased Curricula, and Advancing Truth in Education Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>EDUCATE Act</quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="HED2A7CBFE9944B9195282862700FB71F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on availability of funds for certain graduate medical schools</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title I of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1011">20 U.S.C. 1011 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2FD8209DA4C745CD930FB50E3525F1F9"><section id="HE84F72D8F25248F6820370B5FCCD1CD5"><enum>124.</enum><header>Limitation on availability of funds for certain graduate medical schools</header><subsection id="H7493550DD298451CB59698A45774C15E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no graduate medical school at an institution of higher education shall be eligible to receive funds or any other form of financial assistance under any Federal program, including participation in any federally funded or guaranteed student loan program, unless the institution submits the following certifications to the Secretary:</text><paragraph id="H577F25A9118949788CA11C6D156C08AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A certification that the institution does not, and will not, do any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H6B7B3F1EB80B49A28DB13BEC3ADC0D48"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Direct or compel faculty, staff, or students of the medical school to personally state, pledge, recite, or otherwise express any of the following tenets as a precondition of receiving any benefit, program access, instruction, privilege, employment, admission, or other such matter:</text><clause id="H1F6441797ABD4819948B5BD7A500F01C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>That any sex, race, ethnicity, religion, color, or national origin makes an individual a member of oppressed or oppressor categories.</text></clause><clause id="HEA9E70AF86954A5EB5B4130DBF8BD483"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>That individuals should be adversely treated on the basis of their sex, race, ethnicity, religion, color, or national origin.</text></clause><clause id="HEF773BE51EF94ABD9F110E249EC84E22"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>That individuals, by virtue of sex, race, ethnicity, religion, color, or national origin, are inherently responsible for actions committed in the past by other members of the same sex, race, ethnicity, religion, color, or national origin.</text></clause><clause id="H083D3B3129424FCA8FE1413618FE51F5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>That America is systemically, structurally, or institutionally racist, or that racism is weaved into the <quote>ordinary business of society</quote>, or that America is an oppressive nation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC2F03B3FF527437AB67C4BBCDF891887"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Take any action that would deprive or tend to deprive a medical student of educational opportunities or otherwise adversely affect their status as a student, on the basis of race, ethnicity, color, or national origin, including—</text><clause commented="no" id="HD76F6B337A94483C80BE6132D7A5A03F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">making a distinction or classification of medical school students on the basis of race, ethnicity, color, or national origin;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H1A377AF921874E78A817520B63ABFCF7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing a privilege or benefit for students solely on the basis of race, ethnicity, color, or national origin;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H26410BB64EDB4C68B80764503371DD58"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing a course of instruction for students solely on the basis of race, ethnicity, color, or national origin; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H45CCFC42B2344803BAD607DAE14A7BFA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">otherwise distinguishing students by race, ethnicity, color, or national origin.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C0A504CF8F34EABB134E0507E06E1BD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Require a course of instruction or unit of study at the medical school directing or otherwise compelling students, faculty, or staff to personally state, pledge, recite, assert, or otherwise adopt any of the tenets specified in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE76589A8591C473DBA88EFD2D55E8F62"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establish, maintain, or contract with a diversity, equity, and inclusion office, or any other functional equivalent of such an office, to serve the medical school.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90D0308967AF4E5688CEC931262DBFB2"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Require or incentivize an individual to complete a diversity statement professing or adhering to diversity, equity, and inclusion as a condition of, or benefit in, admission or employment at such school.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0D7510900304D4B9235438D21FBFC7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A certification that the institution will comply with all applicable civil rights laws, including—</text><subparagraph id="HDBD509551D574ECCBE86D97C78A2EA58"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">titles IV and VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000c">42 U.S.C. 2000c et seq.</external-xref>; 2000d et seq.);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17E782F55B444E80920F73D3302E6FDF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74A8C490ECF14EE993C1B5614DECE9FA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC006110BEE34A85A230C13608B69137"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Age Discrimination Act of 1975 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6101">42 U.S.C. 6101 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0F92794DAD7422198CBA4A0180F5608"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any regulations, guidelines, and standards issued by the Department of Education under any applicable civil rights laws.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFDA5F162266C463F8F344D97362A7503"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HED410B686A06429FA91A2A51A0CAE5EE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Diversity, equity, and inclusion office</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>diversity, equity, and inclusion office</term> means any component of an institution of higher education, including any division, unit, or center of such an institution, that is responsible for directing or compelling faculty, staff, or students to state, pledge, recite, assert, or otherwise express ideas as a precondition of receiving any benefit, program access, instruction, privilege, employment, admission, or other such matter in violation of title IV or title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000c">42 U.S.C. 2000c et seq.</external-xref>; 2000d et seq.).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22C75154E3F94599A09266C12D542335"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Diversity statement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>diversity statement</term> means any written or oral statement that—</text><subparagraph id="HCC9F7C0614EF4BC5B67ECC6096F4819C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>asserts that individuals of any race, sex, ethnicity, color, or national origin are inherently superior or inferior;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60930160BF6C43558F0EE33709B661CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>asserts that individuals should be adversely or advantageously treated on the basis of their race, sex, ethnicity, color, or national origin; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5830A962F7584890BD20207AD20C458A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>asserts that individuals, by virtue of race, sex, ethnicity, color, or national origin, bear collective guilt and are inherently responsible for actions committed in the past by other members of the same race, ethnicity, color, or national origin.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F2B5703ADF84CD1B14E5472C2834C70"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given that term in section 102.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H0A89A96D651E4E3F8E61877FD53A7BD2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Conforming requirements for accrediting agencies and associations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 496(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H7F157979331B4137BD4E8F91B08C3B10"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H819432B6C70844778D1B6927FCD0DDC6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CE5858363E645AC8A5D8901E930D210"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HECEFD169EE5A4AF29518F059F5FB1959"><paragraph id="H1DD65BB9DCB3439BBC499E6596FA8527"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if such agency or association has or seeks to include within its scope of recognition the evaluation of the quality of institutions or programs offering graduate medical education, such agency or association shall, in addition to meeting the other requirements of this subpart, demonstrate to the Secretary that the agency or association does not require an institution or program to adopt any policies or other requirements in contravention of section 124 as a condition of receiving accreditation from the agency or association.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H3C9F9B179EA246EDB05F92971716CD28"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act shall be construed—</text><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6265C069BFA8481A9CF694D18AC76C8B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to prohibit a graduate medical school at an institution of higher education from—</text><subparagraph id="H4630F14B44824F83B7CFD451FDAAC267"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing instruction about unique medical needs or conditions that may be related to an individual’s sex, race, or other characteristics; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04AECB77694F4DE08A978C851CC379BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>collecting and maintaining demographic data on students solely for informational purposes;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC20432CCF9CA42F6BC1D9B89C2D0D36D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an institution with a religious mission, to require or incentivize the institution to take any action that is contrary to the tenets of such religion; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB03285E023C4969A22C7667CF23DFE9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to restrict or prohibit—</text><subparagraph id="H26B360DC4BA14CDD8765EEAEC4C6E06A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the exercise of First Amendment rights by anyone lawfully present on the grounds of an institution of higher education (as defined in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB537494FC3D648FD9E40C55A17AD96F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>academic instruction at such an institution, except to the extent required under section 124(a)(1)(C) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (as added by section 2);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BD7D1BF748149CBAEFEEA7A845091F0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>research operations at such an institution;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88FC1C0039644DA4A5AF21264EFBF01D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the operations of student organizations at such an institution;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2B1326BE7074426921D5EF0A51C2CC1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the invitation of lecturers and other guest speakers to such an institution; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AE3620AFC564B72BE24FAE991FDA309"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the ability of an institution to comply with Federal and State anti-discrimination laws.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H501E730185AE425A9BC386F216744F7C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or an amendment made by this Act is held invalid, the remainder of this Act and the amendments made by this Act shall not be affected thereby.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

