<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HE5FED0C0E631473292D14722C29AE811"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5090 IH: Halting Online Nonconsensual Offenses in the Ranks Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5090</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250902">September 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Uniform Code of Military Justice to expand prohibitions against the wrongful broadcast, distribution, or publication of intimate visual images, including digital forgeries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE1F4798190724E1986EEBA5450247242"><section id="HC689865F98524075852ABAE5D40E24A8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Halting Online Nonconsensual Offenses in the Ranks Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HONOR Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFCA68EB5EC464C6A8A5B32BC1152DC36"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modifications to offense of wrongful broadcast or distribution of intimate visual images under the uniform code of military justice</header></section><section id="HCDCCA6C34D464B9DAC00A2BD7AA024DD" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>Section 917a of title 10, united states code (article 117a of the uniform code of military justice) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="HED08E6E866054DD98104AAC89D6CA80D" style="USC"><section id="H6E7522CD85E04AD7AE7FA1C6FCAEC288"><enum>917a.</enum><header>Art. 117a. Wrongful broadcast, distribution, or publication of intimate visual images</header><subsection id="HD221F269EF4043E18CCBFC387E1CA581"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Any person subject to this chapter—</text><paragraph id="H56EE576A16194535AAD37FC84A4CBE26"><enum>(1)</enum><text>who knowingly broadcasts, distributes, or uses a communication service to publish an authentic intimate visual depiction of an identifiable individual who is not a minor if—</text><subparagraph id="HFCDE42B35BF24910812381360AF5A1F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the intimate visual depiction was obtained or created under circumstances in which the person knew or reasonably should have known the identifiable individual had a reasonable expectation of privacy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BEAF6CC2CED4039B7E69D8CFE73BA8C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the authentic intimate visual depiction was broadcast, distributed, or published without the consent of the identifiable individual;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F8039F5D60E42EF9FA52CD710B33F26"><enum>(C)</enum><text>what is depicted was not voluntarily exposed by the identifiable individual in a public or commercial setting;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44E05A5BBCA948D4ADE9B30C98C1D71E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>what is depicted is not a matter of public concern; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DFA9F532C8A40DD837E9E4298FA1EAC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the broadcast, distribution, or publication of the intimate visual depiction—</text><clause id="H5E9C6EA3063F4406A5DD0FCBEACC4A84"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is intended to cause harm; or</text></clause><clause id="HDA2C133B121C4C0BA413C3C0A3D4660F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>causes harm, including psychological, financial, or reputational harm, to the identifiable individual;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H669C41ACA37C456AB127071160150229"><enum>(2)</enum><text>who knowingly broadcasts, distributes, or uses a communication service to publish an authentic intimate visual depiction of an identifiable individual who is a minor with intent to—</text><subparagraph id="H6551801F142848828017623D8EE26302"><enum>(A)</enum><text>abuse, humiliate, harass, or degrade the minor; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB71D6FF9347D483589966B2D52F3A6DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>arouse or gratify the sexual desire of any person;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H977F9A1880C446C6AFD54B3AAE09BBD8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>who knowingly broadcasts, distributes, or uses a communication service to publish a digital forgery of an identifiable individual who is not a minor if—</text><subparagraph id="HF80117A02A4543BCBB80CB12C344FDDE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the digital forgery was broadcast, distributed, or published without the consent of the identifiable individual;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDC9E284DC23495BAA66324E24E689DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>what is depicted was not voluntarily exposed by the identifiable individual in a public or commercial setting;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5025FBCFC3384907962674ED69E329E0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>what is depicted is not a matter of public concern; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD760D3726004D258F42BB16F348FF09"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the broadcast, distribution, or publication of the digital forgery—</text><clause id="H28D6F179AB764C61978B3BE292944C54"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is intended to cause harm; or</text></clause><clause id="HFEA09DB29D104774A73CA6EF4B2CB3EF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>causes harm, including psychological, financial, or reputational harm, to the identifiable individual; or</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF1B5A9C413F4A75B71400DAC22D205F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>who knowingly broadcasts, distributes, or uses a communication service to publish a digital forgery of an identifiable individual who is a minor with intent to—</text><subparagraph id="HC2D83A69696B45E7804D9AA6E808AACA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>abuse, humiliate, harass, or degrade the minor; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DF157E29739494080D9C569D5A50C77"><enum>(B)</enum><text>arouse or gratify the sexual desire of any person,</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">is guilty of wrongful distribution of intimate visual images or visual images of sexually explicit conduct and shall be punished as a court-martial may direct.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB34AD7E4376942C6B527EB20474AC798"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to—</text><paragraph id="HBBD85809D417451F81C7FB110E2F0D57"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a lawfully authorized investigative, protective, or intelligence activity of—</text><subparagraph id="H25991D1C1F9D4C56BF579F9D30D202D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a law enforcement agency of the United States, a State, or a political subdivision of a State; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H876310FA5FB044ED9DCB59EB14389265"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an intelligence agency of the United States;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE69962CEBA934CD2966BB56C982EA581"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a disclosure made reasonably and in good faith—</text><subparagraph id="H472003D0932D44579E1EB776F85464A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to a law enforcement officer or agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35F939D13BC0413C8F9E90FE62ED065B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as part of a document production or filing associated with a legal proceeding;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DEB3435AC024299AEBD0DB6C5E02AC4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>as part of medical education, diagnosis, or treatment or for a legitimate medical, scientific, or educational purpose;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06BAFC6B37444836BAB2513A350E6667"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in the reporting of unlawful content or unsolicited or unwelcome conduct or in pursuance of a legal, professional, or other lawful obligation; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9187DBCDB8494E4C95CDCCD3F2946C98"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to seek support or help with respect to the receipt of an unsolicited intimate visual depiction;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB50DAE94025B4A93B40EB1D6087161E0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a disclosure reasonably intended to assist the identifiable individual; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H172A82D2AC414443BFE93CCE25F7452E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a person who possesses or publishes an intimate visual depiction of himself or herself engaged in nudity or sexually explicit conduct.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCFAE04C8D74A4BD18A3F4EC8645F507F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consent</header><text>For the purposes of subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="H68DFC2D3528247908D3E969197136E0F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the fact that the depicted individual consented to the creation of the intimate visual depiction shall not establish that the person consented to its disclosure; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H415CA86D21CA4BACA35BE76C27030CB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the fact that the depicted individual disclosed the intimate visual depiction to another person shall not establish that the depicted individual consented to the further disclosure of the intimate visual depiction.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC5314C8BCB424494932F02200A40A46C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H05AC812DB8104F19A09F11F3CA38B23E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consent</header><text>The term <quote>consent</quote> means an affirmative, conscious, and voluntary authorization made by an individual free from force, fraud, duress, misrepresentation, or coercion.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C5555F8253B432BB049F9580CD978CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Digital forgery</header><text>The term <quote>digital forgery</quote> means any intimate visual depiction of an identifiable individual created through the use of software, machine learning, artificial intelligence, or any other computer-generated or technological means, including by adapting, modifying, manipulating, or altering an authentic visual depiction, that, when viewed as a whole by a reasonable person, is indistinguishable from an authentic visual depiction of the individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB68425377332438EB2AB2A8E030C9E99"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Identifiable individual</header><text>The term <quote>identifiable individual</quote> means an individual—</text><subparagraph id="H5B2BEE40DA9F4D4CAAD18C48AE95CF66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who appears in whole or in part in an intimate visual depiction; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC0808854D86476BBBF84D393E40F27F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whose face, likeness, or other distinguishing characteristic (including a unique birthmark or other recognizable feature) is displayed in connection with such intimate visual depiction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C4496C553C54481AA47D1EF615D4674"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Visual depiction</header><text>The term <quote>visual depiction</quote> includes undeveloped film and videotape, data stored on computer disk or by electronic means which is capable of conversion into a visual image, and data which is capable of conversion into a visual image that has been transmitted by any means, whether or not stored in a permanent format.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DA67524BB664ABEBC2E88D7DB22819A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Intimate visual depiction</header><text>The term <quote>intimate visual depiction</quote>—</text><subparagraph id="HD751E770F9ED4CAEB1B9933814F5DCC0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a visual depiction that depicts—</text><clause id="HA63D1B33806540A68D2A5A81558C72DE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the uncovered genitals, pubic area, anus, or female nipple of an identifiable individual; or</text></clause><clause id="H947B4B4E323D4305AB9AD9D92AC99184"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the display or transfer of bodily sexual fluids—</text><subclause id="H45AE046CD1854CBF9D42DC5D379A839E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>on to any part of the body of an identifiable individual;</text></subclause><subclause id="H83FA5E6203264A3C903944202B184FDF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>from the body of an identifiable individual; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H8AB7A957832A4A108249ADD0ECB72FE8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an identifiable individual engaging in sexually explicit conduct; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5E2A87A046B4A02B116940255CD9413"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any visual depictions described in subparagraph (A) produced while the identifiable individual was in a public place only if the individual did not—</text><clause id="HFA8833BAE4144EA8B86607D59EE9C234"><enum>(i)</enum><text>voluntarily display the content depicted; or</text></clause><clause id="H7D5501B06B84452D9127BE9972B4E415"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consent to the sexual conduct depicted.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA336120A900F47958BFA0E04E7B98C35"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Sexually explicit conduct</header><text>The term <quote>sexually explicit conduct</quote> means actual or simulated—</text><subparagraph id="H2BA87791677D4F1292C9D58824D8B56F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sexual intercourse, including genital-genital, oral-genital, anal-genital, or oral-anal, whether between persons of the same or opposite sex;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE4DDE56939B41ECABB409629ACAF3E0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>bestiality;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA6AE83755BC4B46A11848BBAE079D23"><enum>(C)</enum><text>masturbation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BC084117B824DC0B0526AD8DA26EED9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>sadistic or masochistic abuse; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4C138832B294486B081137A67634997"><enum>(E)</enum><text>lascivious exhibition of the genitals or pubic area of any person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA1D8E8CDAE245C0B1DAA0A645699BE5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Minor</header><text>The term <quote>minor</quote> means any individual under the age of 18 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31569B4D8334417BB20DC343C112776E"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Broadcast</header><text>The term <quote>broadcast</quote> means to electronically transmit a visual image with the intent that it be viewed by a person or persons.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AC97325D85F4BD9ABC48AB85406D61D"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Distribute</header><text>The term <quote>distribute</quote> means to deliver to the actual or constructive possession of another person, including transmission by mail or electronic means.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0CD5B68CF444FE6B5EDF2E60CD3CCB4"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Communications service</header><text>The term <quote>communications service</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HFC0A0884598544BA9992498D5F5AA889"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a service provided by a person that is a common carrier;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C3598661C094182BEBE5155DE46C5F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an electronic communication service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77FC52A081234C5C8C869D487DCE0F10"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an information service; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4C034C5B66D4A5C906F205FE3B522B8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an interactive computer service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5BEF51042A74BF4B235B867CA45FAC0"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Common carrier</header><text>The term <quote>common carrier</quote> means any person engaged as a common carrier for hire, in interstate or foreign communication by wire or radio or interstate or foreign radio transmission of energy, but a person engaged in radio broadcasting shall not, insofar as such person is so engaged, be deemed a common carrier.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0D6DF55F6C840CA9D659ED10F015F3B"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Electronic communication service</header><text>The term <quote>electronic communication service</quote> means any service which provides to users thereof the ability to send or receive wire or electronic communications.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FC308B8D31C4E9CB4F6D80C18901588"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Information service</header><text>The term <quote>information service</quote> means the offering of a capability for generating, acquiring, storing, transforming, processing, retrieving, utilizing, or making available information via telecommunications, and includes electronic publishing, but does not include any use of any such capability for the management, control, or operation of a telecommunications system or the management of a telecommunications service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H161A98060DF9450AAAB16CFFCD3E950F"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Interactive computer service</header><text>The term <quote>interactive computer service</quote> means any information service, system, or access software provider that provides or enables computer access by multiple users to a computer server, including specifically a service or system that provides access to the Internet and such systems operated or services offered by libraries or educational institutions.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

