<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7DF2F388C20E44EBA468F70E5B7C1B91" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HR 4427 IH: Syria Sanctions Accountability Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4427</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250716">July 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To review banking restrictions, strengthen anti-money laundering capacity, and update sanctions with respect to the Government of Syria, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H31DBDAA95E3B487A85D3E2B739FE7825" style="OLC"><section id="H9AA3E26C1B2D428AA4A5A0A3AD5FF53C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Syria Sanctions Accountability Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEBD691021BA44ACCBD6F709A27E3C268"><enum>2.</enum><header>Review of exceptive relief for the Commercial Bank of Syria</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 360 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network shall provide a briefing to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate that contains the following:</text><paragraph id="HCCA40E28F1204F118CDD14BCE0C39B8E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation of the impact of the exceptive relief provided by the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network under section 5318(a)(7) of title 31, United States Code, with respect to the Commercial Bank of Syria on May 23, 2025, including an assessment of whether such exceptive relief advanced the national security or foreign policy objectives of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2571EACC1202447AA441D28E9D272343"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A recommendation of whether or not to continue exceptive relief or revise any finding with respect to the Commercial Bank of Syria under section 5318A(a)(1) of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HE58C75A2C1344201B8C553FAF4E0DCE7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Actions at the International Monetary Fund and the World Bank</header><subsection id="H194C34FFA48C4FD9AA2CCC8CD7298C0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Directors at the International Monetary Fund and the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development to use the voice and vote of the United States to support the following:</text><paragraph id="HDDEFA2698574426C8B0CD409D18F3C08"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The restoration of sound data reporting and regular economic monitoring in Syria.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B2C5435BBE44582BBF0F010976F0361"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Technical assistance for the Government of Syria to improve financial connectivity and strengthen measures, consistent with international standards, regarding anti-money laundering, weapons non-proliferation, and anti-corruption.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2629BFFAC4EE483EB3FECEA4474A1C81"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A strategy to address priorities for economic growth in Syria.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC22456C7BD544F09AB8C5F0BFF742021"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Congressional briefings</header><text>Within 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and 1 year thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury shall provide a briefing to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate on the activities described in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H52E19F91C60442D48D3295C8359F0FE2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The preceding provisions of this section shall have no force or effect beginning on the date that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H80E26F4B4AD4434FA7638702A7033C39"><enum>4.</enum><header>Export-Import Bank review of country limitation schedule</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Within 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Chairman of the Export-Import Bank of the United States shall—</text><paragraph id="H486EDE3367BA434093A48BBBF80CF851"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine whether any country limitation applicable to the Bank with respect to Syria is appropriate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC82D7FEEE1004C3B952C1D207530725D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">brief the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate on the determination.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H406A24E4FB4B4807B92BBBDE3E29A095"><enum>5.</enum><header>Modification of sanctions with respect to the Government of Syria</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Caesar Syria Civilian Protection Act of 2019 (title LXXIV of division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/92">Public Law 116–92</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8791">22 U.S.C. 8791</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H8976B7A26AFF4E7ABB0821979F21D276"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 7431(a)—</text><subparagraph id="H31188C297CFE453F94BD96D5ED81522A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>for renewable periods not to exceed 180 days</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB57302CCBC034A6DA6ED32612CBF34E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H58D7A8167435410C9192446EFC8D32A0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HA2B74FDDC90946E88A346BD4225998B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The air space over Syria is not being utilized by the Government of Syria to target civilian populations through the use of incendiary devices, including barrel bombs, chemical weapons, and conventional arms (including air-delivered missiles and explosives).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A45B357B67A485589876648BDA3320E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Areas under the control of the Government of Syria are no longer cut off from international aid and have regular access to humanitarian assistance, freedom of travel, and medical care. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DE7CD380BE34A00B6CCCFB7C3C9F763"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Government of Syria is releasing all political prisoners forcibly held within the prison system of the regime of Bashar al-Assad and the Government of Syria is allowing full access to prison system facilities for investigations by appropriate international human rights organizations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED100F0C369F4552ADE03D91A57987D0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The forces of the Government of Syria are no longer engaged in deliberate targeting of medical facilities, schools, residential areas, and community gathering places, including markets, in violation of international norms.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H678F2F3453F54A6EADBE3CD9D18C73C2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding after paragraph (7) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2DB51CDB8CFE4AB19F08A3A253002B3F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H10E13E037BF74062B391E60310878194"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Government of Syria is taking verifiable steps to combat the illicit production and international illicit proliferation of Captagon.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC669949079DF4F83BBFD8F332A03372B"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Government of Syria is not engaged in the targeting or extrajudicial detention of religious minorities in Syria.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CD3D2874B3E4F7A903FD9F1AD27B04B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 7432—</text><subparagraph id="HBB057078B42941C9B98B20A3E49FF639"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><clause id="H923ED8803B834E30BFEE93332F5B9EF1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subclause id="H0176E0B163EC40E890CB8260D66BFC25"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, for renewable periods not to exceed 180 days,</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HB494D43A89E54D4A873694182AFE5D45"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>with respect to a foreign person</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6DAD1CB7F6034A3FB58F42E198C44CF2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>and every 180 days thereafter while the waiver remains in effect,</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD925A4758640487EBCE0BC05A76A01C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><clause id="H73C02475204642DFAA9DAE20AAADE010"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>, for renewable periods not to exceed 2 years,</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HB866F98269B747C5B2627D8EF4307529"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>and every 180 days thereafter while the waiver remains in effect,</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H419061E95A304E0EA0DDFA304CEBAC99"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 7438 to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1BC9B9C0027540F4B4E28A15FA05FB64" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HEF9F25A3D6AB4E8C87830B884E3B46AF"><enum>7438.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title shall cease to be effective on the earlier of—</text><paragraph id="H99C7F95A78CB42199449DAEC38C6FB4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date that is 30 days after the date that the President reports to Congress that the Government of Syria has met the criteria described in paragraphs (1) through (8) of section 7431(a) for 2 consecutive years; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H161F645858E24B44B59AA7CE23E28613"><enum>(2)</enum><text>December 31, 2029.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

