<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H81526415C39A40D786A825DD15CAACCD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>118 HR 477 IH: Making Advancements in Commercial Hypersonics Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 477</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250116">January 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000480">Mr. Fong</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To advance scientific research and technology development of hypersonic vehicles, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H765102A096D94E3EA8083190954F8885" style="OLC"><section id="HA241E499DD8A4B15A6A80508DBD61A6D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Making Advancements in Commercial Hypersonics Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>MACH Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8CE04F9A47AE4341AAA4CFBA76D9FD30"><enum>2.</enum><header>Making advancements in commercial hypersonics program</header><subsection id="HF70023A72E8C42D4AC4290AD6A5BC58D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In conducting hypersonics research pursuant to section 40112(d) of title 51, United States Code, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (in this section referred to as the <quote>Administrator</quote>) may establish the Making Advancements in Commercial Hypersonics Program (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) to facilitate opportunities for testing of high-speed aircraft and other technologies that advance scientific research and technology development related to hypersonic aircraft.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC99AF21DBD6147E3AB6779DDC3A02D46"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Program may not fund the development of technologies that are supported by the testing described in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H5CA68AADA3F24D4E9898BFFEA2A0DAD7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Strategic plan</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator, acting through the Aeronautics Research Mission Directorate, shall develop a strategic plan for activities under subsection (a) that aligns with the hypersonic research roadmap required under section 603 of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Transition Authorization Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/10">Public Law 115–10</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/51/20302">51 U.S.C. 20302</external-xref> note).</text></subsection><subsection id="HBF75A914841C4B6BB66EEA1448C888C4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination, consultation, and collaboration</header><paragraph id="HA28D9EEC672D4A6C901D1567134A3FD6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Administrator shall ensure coordination between the Aeronautics Research Mission Directorate and other Mission Directorates, as appropriate, to identify technologies eligible for testing opportunities under the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D05DC4B45CC4B2CA513530D5D341997"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation; collaboration</header><text>The Administrator shall consult and seek to collaborate, as appropriate, with the Secretary of Defense and the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration on activities related to the Program, including development, testing, and evaluation of high-speed aircraft and related technologies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC60727920E44F9C9F8C5F472440E313"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate—</text><paragraph id="HC4429BDF8399417D950CC231D6CFA3DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, a report that—</text><subparagraph id="H787B7158D94F46A196F7D51A189E14C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describes activities of the Program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9202856F61B415F830AF779E75FC7EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes the strategic plan required under subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9F01E053B444832829199D65C22ADDB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, a report describing progress in carrying out the Program, including regarding the number and type of testing opportunities carried out in the previous fiscal year and planned for the upcoming fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H554DB88244BD4E9C950F1ADBF2F34629"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Research security</header><text>Nothing in this section authorizes the Administrator to develop, implement, or execute an agreement related to technologies under this section with any entity of concern, a foreign business entity, or a foreign country of concern.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1B0F4EB43D2D43CBA1937EFB05E0AC36"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="H9135B1D481A440F89C09E4954B2D53D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Entity of concern</header><text>The term <quote>entity of concern</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 10114 of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/167">Public Law 117–167</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18912">42 U.S.C. 18912</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFF524A1488743A4989E041F21FD6225"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign business entity</header><text>The term <quote>foreign business entity</quote> means an entity that is majority-owned or majority-controlled (as such term is defined in section 800.208 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, or a successor regulation), or minority owned greater than 25 percent by—</text><subparagraph id="H9D1F830B94974AC79FE3A3AA66A087E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any governmental organization of a foreign country of concern; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H070FDB270F6D43598F49A16CEEBE4BB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other entity that is—</text><clause id="H6FE8DC1B4E7C4CBF9EF8DDB0F34439B3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>known to be owned or controlled by any governmental organization of a foreign country of concern; or</text></clause><clause id="H2F5E80331FDE4A6AB20B7A3CD5AD060A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>organized under, or otherwise subject to, the laws of a foreign country of concern.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C8EBFA48CB84295AA5816F1C52E2580"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign country of concern</header><text>The term <quote>foreign country of concern</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 9901 of title XCIX of division H of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/4651">15 U.S.C. 4651</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E90537A218F4F61BB37DAE42A0A6BEB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>High-speed aircraft</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>high-speed aircraft</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1009 of the Federal Aviation Reauthorization Act of 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/63">Public Law 118–63</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44701">49 U.S.C. 44701</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

