<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Enrolled-Bill" dms-id="H343F0B05628C4BD8A9A3ACFF935169B9" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-joint" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HJ 75 ENR: Providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, Department of Energy relating to “Energy Conservation Program: Energy Conservation Standards for Commercial Refrigerators, Freezers, and Refrigerator-Freezers”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IA</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">One Hundred Nineteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress> 
<session display="yes">At the First Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Friday, the third day of January, two thousand and twenty-five</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 75</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Providing for congressional disapproval under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/8">chapter 8</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, Department of Energy relating to <quote>Energy Conservation Program: Energy Conservation Standards for Commercial Refrigerators, Freezers, and Refrigerator-Freezers</quote>.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="H4D58402092EB4A8793735285A9AD1DDF"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H33B256E6B19C4CBF8F40590FD5669238"><text>That Congress disapproves the rule submitted by the Office of the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, Department of Energy relating to <quote>Energy Conservation Program: Energy Conservation Standards for Commercial Refrigerators, Freezers, and Refrigerator-Freezers</quote> (90 Fed. Reg. 7464; published January 21, 2025) and such rule shall have no force or effect.</text></section> </resolution-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </resolution> 

