<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H613B7282B5284B4DB673A21E8260B42E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2623 IH: Innovative Therapies Centers of Excellence Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2623</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250403">April 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000603">Mr. Luttrell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to designate medical facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs as innovative therapies centers of excellence, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6D4C41CEC3CC437AB8D0C0CD7B985452" style="OLC"><section id="H46B68C6B151A438C89E3371DA824B612" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Innovative Therapies Centers of Excellence Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB3BAE90C5DE548DA9202D4E037565766"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs designation of innovative therapies centers of excellence</header><subsection id="HB75F63CC06214E5582A79E7E56EE8199"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/73">Chapter 73</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7330D">section 7330D</external-xref> the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H6DE99A70CF5541ED93034D2BA3AD9D9B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H4B6EC36B446B4CDB8B1B32E55A73536B"><enum>7330E.</enum><header>Innovative therapies centers of excellence</header><subsection id="HDA21842569694770801CA6E2D8CE2940"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of centers</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE6AEF312B93A43ABA64699B644316A00"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary, upon the recommendation of the Under Secretary for Health, shall designate not less than five Department medical facilities as the locations for innovative therapies centers of excellence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97F5F35FCDC14C80B463F80607C5A4A9" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations for such purpose, the Secretary shall establish and operate innovative therapies centers of excellence at the locations designated pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB0FEC18E1B264A34B435B37279652374"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Geographic distribution of facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In designating Department medical facilities as centers of excellence under subsection (a), the Secretary, upon the recommendation of the Under Secretary for Health, shall assure appropriate geographic distribution of such facilities.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3C188EBAF63E4F1FAB2FB22516F67CB9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements for designation</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8439AA479F0941A3BE1253BC20D6FCED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary may not designate a Department medical facility as a location for a center under subsection (a) unless the peer review panel established under subsection (d) has determined under that subsection that the proposal submitted by such facility as a location for a new center under subsection (a) is among those proposals that meet the highest competitive standards of scientific and clinical merit.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF405948BEB234DA2A1E208DA0D9C890C" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary may not designate a Department medical facility as a location for a center under subsection (a) unless the Secretary, upon the recommendation of the Under Secretary for Health, determines that the facility has, or may reasonably be anticipated to develop, each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H86BDCBBD2F9644B497DFCF719655853E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An arrangement with an—</text><clause id="H854A815D72BF42F7990958C6FBC3B914"><enum>(i)</enum><text>accredited medical school that provides education and training in innovative therapies and with which the Department medical facility is affiliated under which residents receive education and training in use of innovative therapies to treat covered conditions;</text></clause><clause id="H035E003E003D41F3A7F49A6DF7389280"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an accredited school of psychiatry; and</text></clause><clause id="H2463EE34494D4863B0942D4D62DB2786"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an accredited school of social work.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89D9D8C2FA5B41768BBA7C34C873FE4E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The ability to attract the participation of scientists who are capable of ingenuity and creativity in medical research efforts.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H707E3E5CA36C47B3B75DB1296D8055BF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An advisory committee composed of veterans and appropriate medical and research representatives of the Department medical facility and of the affiliated school or schools to advise the directors of such facility and such center on policy matters pertaining to the activities of the center during the period of the operation of such center.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC34A5973FAF4068B5DB0951CB5E80CB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The capability to conduct effectively evaluations of the activities of such center.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H275C259CDE1C4E8B8024A1D17B9773C5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The capability to coordinate (as part of an integrated national system) education, clinical, and research activities within all facilities with such centers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3ECD796C380D44BD9EE709D4B39A330A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The capability to jointly develop a consortium of providers with interest in treating covered conditions with innovative therapies at Department facilities without such centers in order to ensure better access to state-of-the-art diagnosis, care, and education for innovative therapies throughout the medical system of the Department.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9A246D90F074D75BF6510937AA50AF6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The capability to develop a national repository in the medical system of the Department for the collection of data on health services delivered to veterans seeking innovative therapies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B5F5645CC094F44944093B6A08F8D7F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Peer review panel</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE3666D47B682493E878E5867771DD679"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Under Secretary for Health shall establish a panel to assess the scientific and clinical merit of proposals that are submitted to the Secretary for the establishment of centers under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D1E8D5D5AF64C8496AD1C9737108644" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCA1D02814D2E4FB3939C76260D72228A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The membership of the panel shall consist of experts in innovative therapies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF7F6122C20C4DC3B5D8CA8C09711F7B" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Members of the panel shall serve for a period of no longer than two years, except as specified in subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3BBA8BA740E47DB86B32A0F58AF9128" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Of the members first appointed to the panel, one half shall be appointed for a period of three years and one half shall be appointed for a period of two years, as designated by the Under Secretary at the time of appointment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H45DE0EC54713402D9FCD8BA5D0632A5B" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The panel shall review each proposal submitted to the panel by the Under Secretary and shall submit its views on the relative scientific and clinical merit of each such proposal to the Under Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D3FFA808401446FBA159D52657BE150" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The panel shall not be subject to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7ECBF5D0058E495AA714772612146635"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Under Secretary of Health shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report on the activities of the centers of excellence designated under this section during the period covered by the report. Each such report shall include—</text><paragraph id="HF3D233A7FFA848069B4DBEDB13DC3479"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of activities carried out by the centers during such period;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H734FAFF767B342F9A8BDA3B99BA09ABC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an identification of key findings made at such centers during such period;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H92A2B97BDEE94323B3BF1977E7F41A5A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations to improve the delivery of innovative therapies to veterans; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CAC20C9862F48DBABE2E8A6F4E10B15"><enum>(4)</enum><text>such other matters as the Under Secretary determines relevant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H04C67E2E28FB460E9C3BD3303B072838"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated $30,000,000 for each fiscal year for the support of the research and education activities of the centers established pursuant to subsection (a). The Under Secretary for Health shall allocate to such centers from other funds appropriated generally for the Department medical services account and medical and prosthetics research account, as appropriate, such amounts as the Under Secretary for Health determines appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H759DA847D94C49ADB62733D1690AF5B8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section;</text><paragraph id="HDD46B60AE0E6420E85245121208C01CD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered condition</quote> means any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H9924E0FB35484FE59C3316E8B49E6F16"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Anxiety.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46EE8BCEC84E4A84A347F4F003B68F3C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Bipolar disorder.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CBC0D7985EE4908BF6608CB0888148A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Chronic pain.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H889049FB935642F1BA26859CF8CE7C17"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Depression.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4DE557D050D04EF3BBC058C3F9AE26E0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Parkinson’s disease.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43788354787F4911A039A7F6AAA51D1E"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Post-traumatic stress disorder.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14FE46149BF448C08D964C3D998BA684"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Substance use disorder.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74B4C0FAA0E741B297D55D0DDE6C3894"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Such other conditions as may be designated by the Under Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA86CE583C9546EEB99A4821869A4852"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>innovative therapy</quote> means any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H1F32B45BAC874F258EA0B85F3D86F78F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">3,4-Methylenedioxy-methamphetamine.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCF23F019B454A229350E2B605CADA33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>5-Methoxy-N,N-dimethyltryptamine.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9ED5D53ECDF49F0B2D8C7B768A870D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Ibogaine.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A33E23984DC45B48F5410ADEA80DC00"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Ketamine.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDACEB42A0F0541B0B811E4C1799F398E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Psilocybin.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1632829BFAB4A5C9FBF31704A0A06B5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Such other therapies as may be designated by the Under Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HD984CC18D89D4B76816ED048B8A0E712"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 7330D the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H7214DC189EE342BEAE556B14FECC0E5E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">7330E. Innovative therapies centers of excellence.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

