<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9E2961D0566B41EA9680EA3DD38E8FC0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1978 IH: To direct the Secretary of Defense to develop a strategy to treat obesity as a disease and reduce the prevalence of obesity in certain Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1978</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250310">March 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to develop a strategy to treat obesity as a disease and reduce the prevalence of obesity in certain Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9296D28FF6B145C9B5E400146CCEB828" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H26FE63851BD8497DBB83533353300A12" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Combating obesity in certain Armed Forces</header> 
<subsection id="H1DD955DB136E434CA8E962C5E387AFA9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy and educational campaign</header> 
<paragraph id="HA0AD0B0F58014D8DB6590BDD12A95BB7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HE5A2764C856D464BACBEE5730C4F4F6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop a strategy to align the obesity-related programs of the Department of Defense with the classification of obesity as a medically accepted disease; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H48930A44B2D548A1A0797D8F3CAE9245"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conduct an educational campaign to promote awareness, diagnosis, and treatment of obesity as a disease in the covered Armed Forces.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D1AD15FDD5847EEAD4511AB91011769"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements for strategy</header><text>The strategy developed under paragraph (1)(A) shall include the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD2957838FECD4D2395AB4F57BEBA8229"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A plan to coordinate obesity-related programs across the Department of Defense to treat obesity as a disease and reduce the prevalence of obesity in the covered Armed Forces.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2B75F3611F8E4ED6AE374BC7B37B15B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An assessment of the effectiveness of health programs of the Department of Defense that are intended to educate, prevent, or treat obesity among members of the covered Armed Forces, and a plan to modify or update such programs to treat obesity as a disease.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H63CB67BC88234F6CBA3DE40D136FAF27"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the adequacy of nutrition education for physicians and other health care practitioners in the military health system to evaluate and treat obesity as a disease, including the need for any additional education or guidelines for such physicians and other health care practitioners.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCB8EB67361CD47CD8B284B78C81373AC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A strategy to work toward members of the covered Armed Forces with obesity receiving appropriate treatment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7FB99D05D95F4E32959FAF61F46AC8F6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements for educational campaign</header><text>The educational campaign conducted under paragraph (1)(B) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H914E9FF8E85A4408A74AA3AC69A13D75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Information to educate members of the covered Armed Forces regarding best practices to prevent, reduce, or mitigate obesity, and available resources to address the root causes of obesity.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H42A599ECCDF94B498DAD9FCF2C3571AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Information targeted to physicians and other health care practitioners in the military health system to promote diagnosis and treatment of obesity as a disease.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6779BC6F1ADB49D9852144DC335B6EDE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the strategy and educational campaign required by paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense shall consult with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, and other agencies of the Department of Health and Human Services, as determined appropriate by the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0E005F75DBC548239E43ACD88D7A4AED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion of information regarding unmet weight standards in certain reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall include information regarding unmet weight standards in any report submitted by the Secretary to Congress regarding disqualifications for enlistment in, disability incurred in, or medical discharges from, the covered Armed Forces.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H43707214F9F84D128323F204B15B6AEC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional Department of Defense reports</header> <paragraph id="H9F374DB8A95341A8A54A9A2F1A1E0C11"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Effects of obesity on readiness of covered Armed Forces</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report regarding the effects of obesity on the readiness of the covered Armed Forces. Such report shall include legislative recommendations of the Secretary to address such effects.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HACE9B8987D7A4568AAB19165780BD423"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effectiveness of obesity, food, and nutrition-related programs of Department of Defense</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Director of the Defense Health Agency shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the effectiveness of the obesity, food, and nutrition-related programs of the Department of Defense in reducing obesity and improving military readiness.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6657B5AFAF66455B86478B048DCBB41B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>GAO report</header> <paragraph id="H1EECDAC5E3D54B3CA30E5D428B994AF2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report analyzing the existing obesity, food, and nutrition-related programs of the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H134FE55568C4480A903D1377D12B4ACD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HB5848A04578E40A9BB05B70B8343057F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of programs directed to members of the covered Armed Forces.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H32CFAB29FD714449A58F00D7AEE6636B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An assessment of programs directed to health care providers in the military health system.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE78CAB15C2BD453C951FCE2A6B0EDC5A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of the effectiveness of such programs in reducing obesity and the impact of obesity on military readiness.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC44D36F7FD354D16B27C3757A1D4C195"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations to coordinate and improve existing programs to reduce obesity and the impact of obesity on military readiness.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2AF4511506C147558D9404BF8A297433"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H248806B578DE49B2BA64255325C9391A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H6BE508AFEBA24E0CA8AFA0A4DC26EF2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC73BDF8F0BFC45C8803A76A80068626D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3DF629517C4F45398DFE6AA15301AA15"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H873FC558A5C448CF817BC311D761F9CE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB749126B36B549F690481FF440E1B480"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H74ADC08E6DC74C1896384EC787813CEF"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H88F56185232A439EAF5DCCD591A28D13"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H53ABA641EFFF4DC9BD4FE99E8E9CCBF8"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC05741CAE89D49D58BFF54EFDC8568F5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>covered Armed Force</term> means the Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Air Force, or Space Force.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

