<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25B92-FCP-GW-XCM"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>118 S1478 RS: Countering Wrongful Detention Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 94</calendar><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1478</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date date="20250618">June 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</sponsor>, with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide the United States Government with additional tools to deter state and non-state actors from wrongfully detaining United States nationals for political leverage, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4f0a217423af4c4685ca652026e4b122"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Countering Wrongful Detention Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b04ebd477554e3cb20327509b9631b2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows: </text><toc changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><toc-entry level="section" idref="S1">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id386352b19045457ca3ddca492efad7da">TITLE I—Deterring and preventing unlawful or wrongful detention</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id760688eca48847e489c908bcdd19d60d">Sec. 101. Designation of a foreign country as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ida368f83820714619984fa8638ad26ca4">Sec. 102. Required certification regarding international travel advisories.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id0814ec81efbc48eb84793ce092c85adf">TITLE II—Strengthening processes and services for hostages and unlawful or wrongful detainees</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idac403def1fa7456ba0c3e5b03faa29f5">Sec. 201. Advisory Council on Hostage Taking and Unlawful or Wrongful Detention.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id6c6eaa0952fc4126a74f8fe229bae224">Sec. 202. Congressional Report on Components Related to Hostage Affairs and Recovery.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><title id="id386352b19045457ca3ddca492efad7da" style="OLC" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>I</enum><header>Deterring and preventing unlawful or wrongful detention</header><section id="id760688eca48847e489c908bcdd19d60d"><enum>101.</enum><header>Designation of a foreign country as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Robert Levinson Hostage Recovery and Hostage-Taking Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1741">22 U.S.C. 1741 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 306 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id084ef3b4ac304ebdb93469622e25b125" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><section id="id12afa57729a04ecd8679cb60152c4bbd"><enum>306A.</enum><header>Designation of a foreign country as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention</header><subsection id="id1fe85d31d27f480c8152e0d4605c7a71"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the notice requirement of subsection (c)(1)(A), the Secretary of State, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, may designate a foreign country that has provided support for or directly engaged in the unlawful or wrongful detention of a United States national as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention based on any of the following criteria:</text><paragraph id="id2bb40517110e46ebacdc7c29a9d79602"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The unlawful or wrongful detention of a United States national occurs in the foreign country.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id207aed8b723844baaced6bb8f68fc1f5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The government of the foreign country or an entity organized under the laws of a foreign country has failed to release an unlawfully or wrongfully detained United States national within 30 days of being officially notified by the Department of State of the unlawful or wrongful detention.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idde1c4606de6149a3b4fb52f8b9ce9971"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Actions taken by the government of the foreign country indicate that the government is responsible for, complicit in, or materially supports the unlawful or wrongful detention of a United States national, including by acting as described in paragraph (2) after having been notified by the Department of State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id27b6ee9cb8684d4c8cf4949b61975ad7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The actions of a state or nonstate actor in the foreign country, including any previous action relating to unlawful or wrongful detention or hostage taking of a United States national, pose a risk to the safety and security of United States nationals abroad sufficient to warrant designation of the foreign country as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6cf91348b2a1465ab8024f2f8ccc9423"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Termination of designation</header><text>The Secretary of State may terminate the designation of a foreign country under subsection (a) if the Secretary certifies to Congress that the government of the foreign country—</text><paragraph id="id9286147714c34abab3e86e830bdc9782"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has released the United States nationals unlawfully or wrongfully detained within the territory of the foreign country;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbacbc7aa6de04afb9ad15414e83d2067"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has positively contributed to the release of United States nationals taken hostage within the territory of the foreign country or from the custody of a nonstate entity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9bd3649f45c146328d23cb4f08e10253"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has demonstrated changes in leadership or policies with respect to unlawful or wrongful detention and hostage taking; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd01d48bd20834dc98d8a1b79bf8d4759"><enum>(4)</enum><text>has provided assurances that the government of the foreign country will not engage or be complicit in or support acts described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb1f5f22c17ef4770a704aa1c6725d553"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Briefing and reports to Congress; publication</header><paragraph id="id5067fe030d58418fa6ba78c31913db97"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4b843199428443a8b4297297cd5ec900"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 7 days prior to making a designation of a foreign country as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention under subsection (a), the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that notifies the committees of the proposed designation. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55a8e4c7827441c391961b0ec68f4f68"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In each report submitted under subparagraph (A) with respect to the designation of a foreign country as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention, the Secretary shall include—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf8d35b5e2a8740eb97f52c81a7334242"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the justification for the designation; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9c376e36988346cab8ecac0ee0fc9126"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any action taken by the United States Government, including the Secretary of State or the head of any other relevant Federal agency, in response to the designation to deter the unlawful or wrongful detention or hostage-taking of foreign nationals in the country. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf445b75c0462489ebfb3abc95805f9b3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial briefing required</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall brief Congress on the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id63d28a61ce974f65ae4394b8b1a7cb6c"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether any of the following countries should be designated as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention under subsection (a):</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0d34c6439f8b4590898b6858682cb443"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Afghanistan.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id940cfda7a7354c879a1df27dd48610fc"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Eritrea.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id942b28ee519a471f9205579c76c5b952"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Islamic Republic of Iran.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9fc3963a1c5740d8ac1e5859e03a76cb"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The People's Republic of China.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7580bba77bc745f6af513978c5cb8603"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The Russian Federation.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8190e046ed074a229c5c1f8b0fbd887c"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The Syrian Arab Republic or any transitional government therein.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4d4aafba6a9842d08324d34428c07de1"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Venezuela under the regime of Nicolás Maduro.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a90927f3fef46a3bf4569609df5a688"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The Republic of Belarus.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1013f7a4997c4198be24af8c64c98d26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The steps taken by the Secretary and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies to deter the unlawful and wrongful detention of United States nationals and to respond to such detentions, including—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2cd4771d146f4b5c8502fd975af67c8b"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any engagement with private sector companies to optimize the distribution of travel advisories; and</text></clause><clause id="id5430a9f011424d64a0b27f91ef343c49"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any engagement with private companies responsible for promoting travel to foreign countries engaged in the unlawful or wrongful detention of United States nationals.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide608b2b2437f42bca3418dd64658daf8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of a possible expansion of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/97">chapter 97</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Foreign Sovereign Immunities Act of 1976</quote>) to include an exception from asset seizure immunity for State Sponsors of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3649d477ad6c4c529e0a3ecd5de0e576"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A detailed plan on the manner by which a geographic travel restriction could be instituted against State Sponsors of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida351a641aced4796a40bf1ae1cdf8daf"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The progress made in multilateral fora, including the United Nations and other international organizations, to address the unlawful and wrongful detention of United States nationals, in addition to nationals of partners and allies of the United States in foreign countries. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce3a04bc68b1405bbf2bebc86f78ff7f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual briefing</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, and annually thereafter for 5 years, the Assistant Secretary of State for Consular Affairs and the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs shall brief the appropriate committees of Congress with respect to unlawful or wrongful detentions taking place in the countries listed under paragraph (2)(A) and actions taken by the Secretary of State and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies to deter the wrongful detention of United States nationals, including any steps taken in accordance with paragraph (2)(B). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id04b82ddc0bc6454f9e485e87d3b7162b"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Secretary shall make available on a publicly accessible website of the Department of State, and regularly update, a list of foreign countries designated as State Sponsors of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa1e6beb82ca415e823b78cdc00e4819"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Review of available responses to state sponsors of unlawful or wrongful detention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon designation of a foreign country as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention under subsection (a), the Secretary of State, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall conduct a comprehensive review of the use of existing authorities to respond to and deter the unlawful or wrongful detention of United States nationals in the foreign country, including—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb16638e16507485391739536f8ea670d"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sanctions available under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>); </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd7e203ee50f5452f9677a037bac277ae"><enum>(2)</enum><text>visa restrictions available under section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2024 (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182</external-xref> note) or any other provision of Federal law;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idffb1a5070f9840b2a6643b86836d1e65"><enum>(3)</enum><text>sanctions available under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3a92c9aa02ea47a6a81a9418b1c285be"><enum>(4)</enum><text>imposition of a geographic travel restriction on citizens of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28744a33d32d40df8db719c5d1cbcbed"><enum>(5)</enum><text>restrictions on assistance provided to the government of the country under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</external-xref>) or any other provision of Federal law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc1798e9de081461297293634a0c2f78c"><enum>(6)</enum><text>restrictions on the export of certain goods to the country under the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2751">22 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.</external-xref>), the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801 et seq.</external-xref>), or any other Federal law; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida38af936718c4cca8ddf2a3407fdf302"><enum>(7)</enum><text>designating the government of the country as a government that has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism pursuant to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id11d05c57bca04dbf86f6b50190147ef8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 1754(c)(1)(A)(i) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4813">50 U.S.C. 4813(c)(1)(A)(i)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idc6b4331a3bf54443851de5808a2ece59"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2371">22 U.S.C. 2371</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id85f6182d16fb4204942a463a58a5bb1a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>section 40(d) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2780">22 U.S.C. 2780(d)</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id5f64c1ace783491c9c54cf898aadf49f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other provision of law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddb856137678548f7964e1accdf93935f"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress defined</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28e5d3762fec42ec83c9ab417a47c508"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3e455fbb170547e2b49d5269930c8be5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc7886fbbef5646d48e2d93895d0c3c0a"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of Construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to imply that the United States Government formally recognizes any particular country or the government of such country as legitimate.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="ida368f83820714619984fa8638ad26ca4"><enum>102.</enum><header>Required certification regarding international travel advisories</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8b94f978d01e4706980a9a893d6ddc74"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/423">Chapter 423</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5EE119633355467D9C10535D602A23F3" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7243d4b105ef40a99f678f7e9af09ad7"><enum>42309.</enum><header>Required certification regarding international travel advisories</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf6558b24c34b4914a7fb250f9bab2087"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An air carrier, foreign air carrier, or ticket agent who sells, in the United States, a ticket for foreign air transportation of a passenger to a country or other geographic area with a <quote>D</quote> or <quote>K</quote> indicator issued by the Department of State Travel Advisory System shall require the passenger listed on the ticket to certify that the passenger—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23a1230bd5294c84aa96f954629e6169"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has reviewed the travel advisory of the Department of State applicable to such country or other geographic area; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddc5397078b1142e29de093e7ee3b89e2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>understands the risks involved with traveling to such country or other geographic area.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b079202130b4932bb1990639097e96c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf481b00bffcb408c8b12b83923cfdba1"><enum>(1)</enum><header><quote>D</quote> indicator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term><quote>D</quote> indicator</term> means a travel advisory issued by the Department of State that indicates a risk of wrongful detention of a United States national.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7d95f1c8324c463fa19a7b30accb24ed"><enum>(2)</enum><header><quote>K</quote> indicator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term><quote>K</quote> indicator</term> means a travel advisory issued by the Department of State that indicates a criminal or terrorist individual or group has threatened to seize, detain, kill, or injure individuals (or has seized, detained, killed, or injured individuals) to compel a third party (including a governmental organization) to meet certain requirements as a condition of release.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H7C30BC62A400432B854EDF342E7D4657"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/423">chapter 423</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/42308">section 42308</external-xref> the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA7F672A047324FCABF1842D1308AAABC" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><toc-entry level="section">42309. Required certification regarding international travel advisories.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></title><title id="id0814ec81efbc48eb84793ce092c85adf" style="OLC" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>II</enum><header>Strengthening processes and services for hostages and unlawful or wrongful detainees</header><section id="idac403def1fa7456ba0c3e5b03faa29f5"><enum>201.</enum><header>Advisory Council on Hostage-Taking and Unlawful or Wrongful Detention</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Robert Levinson Hostage Recovery and Hostage-Taking Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1741">22 U.S.C. 1741 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by section 101, is further amended by inserting after section 305B the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6a22123e50f34ffb8175bc9a39efd049" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><section id="idd69c5b454e7f4db9afdceae15de089f7"><enum>305C.</enum><header>Advisory Council on Hostage Taking and Unlawful or Wrongful Detention</header><subsection id="id02328f2fb35c4a5f993b880aa8bbc2c5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The President shall establish an advisory council, to be known as the <quote>Advisory Council on Hostage Taking and Unlawful or Wrongful Detention</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Advisory Council</quote>), to advise the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs, the Hostage Response Group, and the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell with respect to Federal policies regarding hostage-taking and unlawful or wrongful detention.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7287727be12e45f2ad73e4d91f053757"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="id0f5d883e1ef247d3898119cae1705d1f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall invite individuals to the Advisory Council, which shall be comprised of—</text><subparagraph id="id18556aa908024d87be0998dff92edb46"><enum>(A)</enum><text>United States nationals who have been unlawfully or wrongfully detained or taken hostage abroad; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idce3ee8813088443e8a9e046e6ca20b31"><enum>(B)</enum><text>family members of such United States nationals; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id62f3b9e4dfe344ddbfe6a663461ee669"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not fewer than 2 experts on areas including hostage-taking, wrongful detention, international relations, rule of law, and counterterrorism who have been recommended by the Secretary of State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id037fb9b6e4224d10a0beab015dc60555"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>The term of a member of the Advisory Council shall be 3 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide802e65d675c4f28ae891476e0d741d4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compensation and travel expenses</header><text>A member of the Advisory Council shall not be considered a Federal employee and shall not be compensated for service on the Advisory Council, but may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7bae0dd0f15e44479c096ca65660cd6b"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Advisory Council shall submit to the President and the appropriate congressional committees a report setting forth the recommendations of the Advisory Council.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id95357bccc73349309c8e673003cc83e2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Council shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id6c6eaa0952fc4126a74f8fe229bae224"><enum>202.</enum><header>Congressional Report on Components Related to Hostage Affairs and Recovery</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbae9f8831e904e0faa3b306b6543da55"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to Congress a report on the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb6e2f07c5c534ba8828b40ba4937bc7f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Hostage Response Group established pursuant to section 305(a) of the Robert Levinson Hostage Recovery and Hostage-Taking Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1741c">22 U.S.C. 1741c(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id244d5e813b0a45b2830ebb27d51d7f44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell established pursuant to section 304(a) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1741b">22 U.S.C. 1741b(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07f1d3b5f1244e9e91700ed6dc22806c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Office of the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs established pursuant to section 303(a) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1741a">22 U.S.C. 1741a(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id21c2e79b6e324d79a50bd172ec536724"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id982737d07a064fb8abee7f074def3a19"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the existing structure of each component listed in subsection (a); </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id66c40115afe44dc58f318114cd309342"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations on how the components can be improved, including through reorganization or consolidation of the components; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2faba53f81b340a4b65493c530a495a2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>cost efficiencies on the components listed in subsection (a), including resources available to eligible former wrongful detainees and hostages and their family members. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></title></legis-body><legis-body display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id0adae890-996d-4ce8-861f-10c0a1b27a71" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id201c017d-5ef3-4f1c-8688-37cafe3c2846"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Countering Wrongful Detention Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided0fbb03-3831-4280-b277-6d31673e3786"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows: </text><toc changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><toc-entry level="section" idref="S1">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" bold="off">Sec. 2. Rule of construction.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id386352b19045457ca3ddca492efad7da">TITLE I—Deterring and preventing unlawful or wrongful detention</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id760688eca48847e489c908bcdd19d60d">Sec. 101. Designation of a foreign country as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ida368f83820714619984fa8638ad26ca4">Sec. 102. Required certification regarding international travel advisories.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id0814ec81efbc48eb84793ce092c85adf">TITLE II—Strengthening processes and services for hostages and unlawful or wrongful detainees</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idac403def1fa7456ba0c3e5b03faa29f5">Sec. 201. Advisory Council on Hostage Taking and Unlawful or Wrongful Detention.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id6c6eaa0952fc4126a74f8fe229bae224">Sec. 202. Congressional Report on Components Related to Hostage Affairs and Recovery.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="id6fbb02e845fd41d295872fc580384482" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act may be construed as preventing the freedom of travel of United States citizens.</text></section><title id="id16cb04cb-17f5-421d-88d0-c2699bc8bbdf" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>I</enum><header>Deterring and preventing unlawful or wrongful detention</header><section id="id878a31cd-d303-4ef7-8f9e-ed2b32f3dad0"><enum>101.</enum><header>Designation of a foreign country as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Robert Levinson Hostage Recovery and Hostage-Taking Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1741">22 U.S.C. 1741 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 306 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79a364f6-409c-446c-a356-f833d4f1da58" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><section id="idd5fab819-ef0c-49f6-80a1-db151d40e6d6"><enum>306A.</enum><header>Designation of a foreign country as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention</header><subsection id="id2dc9894f-5832-47be-bbed-8d469f0deb9e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the notice requirement of subsection (c)(1)(A), the Secretary of State, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, may designate a foreign country that has provided support for or directly engaged in the unlawful or wrongful detention of a United States national as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention based on any of the following criteria:</text><paragraph id="id8ca4dd65-f6c0-4cbb-a58d-8d3b6e0404d1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The unlawful or wrongful detention of a United States national occurs in the foreign country.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id766a8928-08fc-4ce4-89eb-eada429d2175"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The government of the foreign country or an entity organized under the laws of a foreign country has failed to release an unlawfully or wrongfully detained United States national within 30 days of being officially notified by the Department of State of the unlawful or wrongful detention.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5c61aef1-ac93-4afc-bfe3-5f80d4fd6b7c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Actions taken by the government of the foreign country indicate that the government is responsible for, complicit in, or materially supports the unlawful or wrongful detention of a United States national, including by acting as described in paragraph (2) after having been notified by the Department of State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id554af17e-e1ed-4c21-9cdb-78a3363c0f00"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The actions of a state or nonstate actor in the foreign country, including any previous action relating to unlawful or wrongful detention or hostage taking of a United States national, pose a risk to the safety and security of United States nationals abroad sufficient to warrant designation of the foreign country as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id248eb702-35b7-4f84-818f-110eb2456bd0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Termination of designation</header><text>The Secretary of State may terminate the designation of a foreign country under subsection (a) if the Secretary certifies to Congress that the government of the foreign country—</text><paragraph id="id2ff61c0b-e9a8-49ff-88f9-5177f4b2d5b3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has released the United States nationals unlawfully or wrongfully detained within the territory of the foreign country;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb24c0787-3057-4231-8a63-2390dc67c116"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has positively contributed to the release of United States nationals taken hostage within the territory of the foreign country or from the custody of a nonstate entity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2bd1b428-1184-4ccb-bbab-3a4254fa118b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has demonstrated changes in leadership or policies with respect to unlawful or wrongful detention and hostage taking; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id41891e82-cf8e-4aaf-b411-1d9e5d74f7d8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>has provided assurances that the government of the foreign country will not engage or be complicit in or support acts described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idda0a95df-57d5-435c-b196-d4345dcf9dfb"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Briefing and reports to Congress; publication</header><paragraph id="idb1ced975-ae72-4dd2-a5b6-bd036d6e252a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf8e7f4c0-8f6c-4eb1-8c4d-855049c4fad0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 7 days prior to making a designation of a foreign country as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention under subsection (a), the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that notifies the committees of the proposed designation. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf9a9af46-014c-4ccc-a8a7-bf8c1bda0691"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In each report submitted under subparagraph (A) with respect to the designation of a foreign country as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention, the Secretary shall include—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3789b14b-326a-41da-856b-af612233f67f"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the justification for the designation; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0ec73730-ed24-47df-a2b5-d917c1cf195c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any action taken by the United States Government, including the Secretary of State or the head of any other relevant Federal agency, in response to the designation to deter the unlawful or wrongful detention or hostage-taking of foreign nationals in the country. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddf7c7ca2-35b1-4400-8c6b-44432c213a25"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial briefing required</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall brief Congress on the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id36aaadf7-6cef-4319-ad9d-c305303ff835"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether any of the following countries should be designated as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention under subsection (a):</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6750b1c3-4678-4251-a154-defa4e903c40"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Afghanistan.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c012308-e512-44a4-b557-ed911de44bb3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Eritrea.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc9c6c343-9588-48e0-ae6a-0fc5d5d13bb4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Islamic Republic of Iran.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc812fad6-c286-4853-a9df-c91defe6f206"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The People's Republic of China.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id50ad28ee-fbe0-4ec3-802c-5521916e9ed6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The Russian Federation.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddc6ab7a8-34ab-445e-b68b-5ddb7881cd2e"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The Syrian Arab Republic or any transitional government therein.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id679314fd-36f3-4eac-a5bd-ab22fb4db8c0"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Venezuela under the regime of Nicolás Maduro.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6100416b-b783-4460-aa39-ca59a8658f9d"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The Republic of Belarus.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida6a8e77c-c552-4eb6-b8fb-20f021ea661a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The steps taken by the Secretary and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies to deter the unlawful and wrongful detention of United States nationals and to respond to such detentions, including—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id921ab416-3568-40e2-bf43-1b0054ec3ab4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any engagement with private sector companies to optimize the distribution of travel advisories; and</text></clause><clause id="id750649aa-2f81-423b-9e20-500c299067d2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any engagement with private companies responsible for promoting travel to foreign countries engaged in the unlawful or wrongful detention of United States nationals.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4a973e3d-d4e0-4f65-bb91-416a72356000"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of a possible expansion of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/97">chapter 97</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Foreign Sovereign Immunities Act of 1976</quote>) to include an exception from asset seizure immunity for State Sponsors of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idde703b9a-7989-448d-8dc2-c122f859c1f1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A detailed plan on the manner by which a geographic travel restriction could be instituted against State Sponsors of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id080954c1-52d4-49ab-b9fe-7944f28eaf78"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The progress made in multilateral fora, including the United Nations and other international organizations, to address the unlawful and wrongful detention of United States nationals, in addition to nationals of partners and allies of the United States in foreign countries. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id52c95e10-e364-47e8-ae46-bda40a60ee5b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual briefing</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, and annually thereafter for 5 years, the Assistant Secretary of State for Consular Affairs and the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs shall brief the appropriate committees of Congress with respect to unlawful or wrongful detentions taking place in the countries listed under paragraph (2)(A) and actions taken by the Secretary of State and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies to deter the wrongful detention of United States nationals, including any steps taken in accordance with paragraph (2)(B). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3683af05-98d6-47d5-a4aa-af37ea75ca60"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Secretary shall make available on a publicly accessible website of the Department of State, and regularly update, a list of foreign countries designated as State Sponsors of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide7ffd310-dfad-43f6-90f1-931da6101d72"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Review of available responses to state sponsors of unlawful or wrongful detention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon designation of a foreign country as a State Sponsor of Unlawful or Wrongful Detention under subsection (a), the Secretary of State, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall conduct a comprehensive review of the use of existing authorities to respond to and deter the unlawful or wrongful detention of United States nationals in the foreign country, including—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd6f8a4b5-d6d6-4d99-b4cd-895d450c7e50"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sanctions available under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>); </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbf410d9b-d1c0-46b7-b1ce-852b4dab0f18"><enum>(2)</enum><text>visa restrictions available under section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2024 (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182</external-xref> note) or any other provision of Federal law;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6eda86aa-00c4-4372-bafa-a1dab10b2948"><enum>(3)</enum><text>sanctions available under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id87fb3ebc-e04f-40e0-9081-7b4b3c824c78"><enum>(4)</enum><text>imposition of a geographic travel restriction on citizens of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id937727ef-d2a6-4a70-8639-0f3a2a81546c"><enum>(5)</enum><text>restrictions on assistance provided to the government of the country under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</external-xref>) or any other provision of Federal law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0af0fbc8-fa1a-42bd-b516-85138f36ddf0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>restrictions on the export of certain goods to the country under the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2751">22 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.</external-xref>), the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801 et seq.</external-xref>), or any other Federal law; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5343c7a3-40d3-4bb1-bb6c-acdcc5a0eebc"><enum>(7)</enum><text>designating the government of the country as a government that has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism pursuant to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb6757626-43b0-49c7-94a8-62f86e0beb72"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 1754(c)(1)(A)(i) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4813">50 U.S.C. 4813(c)(1)(A)(i)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idef0851d0-78cf-44b0-bfaa-47e4b4fbe8e2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2371">22 U.S.C. 2371</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idabbeb51d-29c7-4b43-961f-20b0f8b99e84"><enum>(C)</enum><text>section 40(d) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2780">22 U.S.C. 2780(d)</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id2d37788c-cdfc-4284-bfb1-38c328b3229b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other provision of law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida4164c70-c1b2-417e-b11c-3048c005784a"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress defined</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9b292c96-21dd-41d8-b97a-2a362b988b70"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idec1b44b5-5388-4851-b59d-b89532fac668"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idab9bfdaa-48f6-4d09-b2a1-787d1c2cf582"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of Construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to imply that the United States Government formally recognizes any particular country or the government of such country as legitimate.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id5c87fe9a-c81b-4cc7-a8ed-751c8f3b749d"><enum>102.</enum><header>Required certification regarding international travel advisories</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida3cba1a6-5fe0-407e-bc01-fd2619f6c33a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/423">Chapter 423</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8899777-6c0a-4443-8b1b-a50f6e37a5ea" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide7649228-a606-45e7-ac0e-b72cf3290fa8"><enum>42309.</enum><header>Required certification regarding international travel advisories</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1122b152-cd20-4e61-ae29-9d5c7a1229dc"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An air carrier, foreign air carrier, or ticket agent who sells, in the United States, a ticket for foreign air transportation of a passenger to a country or other geographic area with a <quote>D</quote> or <quote>K</quote> indicator issued by the Department of State Travel Advisory System shall require the passenger listed on the ticket to certify that the passenger—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd6b9ccc-8516-4023-8da4-2806c455b033"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has reviewed the travel advisory of the Department of State applicable to such country or other geographic area; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc3f15a59-1332-49f7-896c-acdc3a01931c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>understands the risks involved with traveling to such country or other geographic area.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idEEA23D1A090D4C1A89639E1D1FCE4B1E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in subsection (a) may be construed as grounds to inhibit access to consular services by a United States citizen abroad.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idddfbadcb-3621-4858-a58f-bee5f7d821b2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a03629b-3592-45e2-8a3a-f95dd6798243"><enum>(1)</enum><header><quote>D</quote> indicator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term><quote>D</quote> indicator</term> means a travel advisory issued by the Department of State that indicates a risk of wrongful detention of a United States national.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida8f59e8c-ff8e-49dc-8df4-9219453401d2"><enum>(2)</enum><header><quote>K</quote> indicator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term><quote>K</quote> indicator</term> means a travel advisory issued by the Department of State that indicates a criminal or terrorist individual or group has threatened to seize, detain, kill, or injure individuals (or has seized, detained, killed, or injured individuals) to compel a third party (including a governmental organization) to meet certain requirements as a condition of release.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id88b8e0a3-22aa-45f0-8e47-b5d939b68b73"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/423">chapter 423</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/42308">section 42308</external-xref> the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id41bb6d64-4c83-4943-8883-51231f6b0261" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><toc-entry level="section">42309. Required certification regarding international travel advisories.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></title><title id="id97fa2168-4865-445b-9aa9-099cd031464c" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>II</enum><header>Strengthening processes and services for hostages and unlawful or wrongful detainees</header><section id="id101b9b01-221c-42ff-9c84-751bc0b518ff"><enum>201.</enum><header>Advisory Council on Hostage-Taking and Unlawful or Wrongful Detention</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Robert Levinson Hostage Recovery and Hostage-Taking Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1741">22 U.S.C. 1741 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by section 101, is further amended by inserting after section 305B the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddb14afdc-8bc7-47fa-8aa1-4238162d2c86" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><section id="id257f0529-ea10-49c6-bc10-d3f8968e2fd4"><enum>305C.</enum><header>Advisory Council on Hostage Taking and Unlawful or Wrongful Detention</header><subsection id="id7e599913-f733-4df0-a469-342ebe2e4329"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The President shall establish an advisory council, to be known as the <quote>Advisory Council on Hostage Taking and Unlawful or Wrongful Detention</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Advisory Council</quote>), to advise the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs, the Hostage Response Group, and the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell with respect to Federal policies regarding hostage-taking and unlawful or wrongful detention.</text></subsection><subsection id="id31653205-9f21-4f26-9c13-836b37056fa9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="id2bfb0332-1b05-4d96-833e-f97c5aff0586"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall invite individuals to the Advisory Council, which shall be comprised of—</text><subparagraph id="id7a3e75d9-d593-4369-9e96-f7fde8529644"><enum>(A)</enum><text>United States nationals who have been unlawfully or wrongfully detained or taken hostage abroad; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf19db938-0d2b-4fe1-ab49-6ec8dcbb9c02"><enum>(B)</enum><text>family members of such United States nationals; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id74d3520e-035a-48af-93df-dd882926eacb"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not fewer than 2 experts on areas including hostage-taking, wrongful detention, international relations, rule of law, and counterterrorism who have been recommended by the Secretary of State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddde54611-6d9c-4e6c-b341-31ac9b8f8abb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>The term of a member of the Advisory Council shall be 3 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9ef407c8-10e7-44e2-a3fd-5b4bc6fc62fa"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compensation and travel expenses</header><text>A member of the Advisory Council shall not be considered a Federal employee and shall not be compensated for service on the Advisory Council, but may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idad7758a5-6a10-4309-b336-dab584c61d53"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Advisory Council shall submit to the President and the appropriate congressional committees a report setting forth the recommendations of the Advisory Council.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75036cdf-bb36-4804-9483-dcf4788d35c6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Council shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="idee88a4f5-4f69-4201-bb06-fa3bcc38b7f8"><enum>202.</enum><header>Congressional Report on Components Related to Hostage Affairs and Recovery</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7ed60ecc-b7d4-466e-826b-5ef396419e75"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to Congress a report on the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2140c913-91aa-47b6-b7be-37b18973d084"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Hostage Response Group established pursuant to section 305(a) of the Robert Levinson Hostage Recovery and Hostage-Taking Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1741c">22 U.S.C. 1741c(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id13ee34ee-3771-473a-addf-243b3c065429"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell established pursuant to section 304(a) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1741b">22 U.S.C. 1741b(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id09d3cb52-4767-43f3-b919-786e2552fe9b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Office of the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs established pursuant to section 303(a) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1741a">22 U.S.C. 1741a(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id95257fd3-5696-459e-b215-859f91e72095"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3a4cc871-d51d-4d64-a341-4ffbefa77b2d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the existing structure of each component listed in subsection (a); </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id012b6d82-2961-4d60-9037-9a1e7120678a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations on how the components can be improved, including through reorganization or consolidation of the components; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd2e9fcbd-47f7-4d4c-8437-692b466b6693"><enum>(3)</enum><text>cost efficiencies on the components listed in subsection (a), including resources available to eligible former wrongful detainees and hostages and their family members. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></title></legis-body><endorsement><action-date date="20250618">June 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

