<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC464E399571449B7A6C850E51961632D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1413 IH: To amend title 38, United States Code, to require that domiciliary facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs and State homes that provide housing to veterans have resident advocates.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1413</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250218">February 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require that domiciliary facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs and State homes that provide housing to veterans have resident advocates.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDC61BB3DEDA24C7DB55F8AF52AA3A933" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H518DE9C8E5FA47548D66F237F16073E2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Requirement of resident advocate in a domiciliary facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs or State home</header> 
<subsection id="H0DFD31B7153D4967A3229E4E1D149671"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Domiciliary facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section (and conforming the table of sections at the beginning of such chapter accordingly):</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HA37F90C8405A4AF3AA37617A7BB20E94" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="HC3BDC61D55974FE0BE218CE83FB2C1B4"><enum>1720M.</enum><header>Resident advocates in domiciliary facilities of the Department</header> <subsection id="HBAC57BF669CC44029B9FEA5681210FAF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall employ in each domiciliary facility of the Department a resident advocate.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4154ACBC961D4A748F4A398C5564619E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A resident advocate shall have duties that include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H36EEB7BBF7354BB1A8D236B0CD3CA5C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To serve as a liaison between veterans in the domiciliary facility and the Secretary.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0B08186004DE4D1DAC7FA15046187838"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To receive complaints from such veterans, transmit such complaints to the director of such domiciliary facility, and respond to such complaints.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0D4FB3C468154A40AE0FC53253C50482"><enum>(3)</enum><text>When the resident advocate determines it appropriate, to submit such a complaint to the Secretary, the Inspector General of the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H06CE677D99B44DA6BB71A2AC7B6FE5DA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State homes</header><text>Section 1741 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1278E0D13C5842FD9A906A323A008733"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (h); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H447268A04F3B4A50B8E069EDB3CD8F06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting, after subsection (f), the following new subsection (g):</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H087E272018C3449E909AE6FF71E51852" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H53D198A567D240D397ACD1C978DB591C"><enum>(g)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for payment for domiciliary care provided to a veteran in a State home under this section, a State shall employ in such State home a resident advocate. A resident advocate shall have duties that include the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H1C96700C1A084903BBBFCF4F7295B81E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To serve as a liaison between veterans in such State home and the State.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB445F357898C4DC9845398F01CE23073"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To receive complaints from such veterans, transmit such complaints to the director of the State home, and respond to such complaints.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H25DF3791A9D3478A8568B9FC0FAF4C92"><enum>(3)</enum><text>When the resident advocate determines it appropriate, to submit such a complaint to the Secretary, the Inspector General of the Department, or an appropriate State official.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill> 

