<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HAD287414AF4A456ABC9D66021ABB8E6E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3055 RH: Transitioning Retiring And New Service Members to Port Ocean Rail and Truck Jobs Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 200</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3055</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–243, Part I]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250429">April 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250908">September 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="G000602">Ms. Gillen</cosponsor> and <cosponsor name-id="L000590">Ms. Lee of Nevada</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250908">September 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HPW00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250908">September 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs </committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on April 29, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to develop an action plan on members of the Armed Forces eligible for preseparation counseling and veterans becoming supply chain employees, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HPW00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HAF15DEA917F949BD86B5917C542AF6CD"><section id="H6A2ABA2FC77E4830A16E6B72A5D10CA0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transitioning Retiring And New Service Members to Port Ocean Rail and Truck Jobs Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TRANSPORT Jobs Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H7AAE79B78A124A7897CC47ED5601A3BD" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Veteran to supply chain employee action plan</header><subsection id="H6187F2146165445C99BD93FDC02CED48"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and Secretary of Labor, shall develop and make public an action plan to be known as the <quote>Veteran to Supply Chain Employee Action Plan</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H88423257497F41658CA6F2E8C73FF03E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In developing the Veteran to Supply Chain Action Plan, the Secretary of Transportation shall—</text><paragraph id="H48C43C3433DC4EA19D2388C5B1BC591E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify—</text><subparagraph id="HAC3A2C4FBDD646DAB7483B9AA06DF23B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">barriers members of the Armed Forces eligible for preseparation counseling under section 1142 of title 10, United States Code, and veterans face when searching for employment, during the hiring process, or in training to become supply chain employees; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FA535394D2545EE999C40C8B6BEF28A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">challenges supply chain employers face when recruiting, hiring, or retaining members of the Armed Forces eligible for preseparation counseling under section 1142 of title 10, United States Code, and veterans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D6F16FA809C4865A67D8FC97B350F75"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regulatory burdens employers face in the hiring of supply chain employees, especially for employees that are members of the Armed Forces eligible for preseparation counseling under section 1142 of title 10, United States Code, or veterans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF107197D6ABD463091E885433D240DE7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>regions of the United States which have the greatest workforce need for supply chain employees; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A8C89065F954687AA35DE5E4A00E854"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">barriers and industry trends that directly or indirectly discourage members of the Armed Forces eligible for preseparation counseling under section 1142 of title 10, United States Code, and veterans from pursuing, attaining, and remaining in supply chain careers;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85407097B33B42C69270AF6FDDAB64A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>highlight—</text><subparagraph id="H47A33BA3A340420498BE70F26A793E91"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the specific knowledge, skills, and abilities members of the Armed Forces eligible for preseparation counseling under section 1142 of title 10, United States Code, and veterans possess that are critical for supply chain careers and any competency gaps that should be addressed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38BF1797153F4B6D9D8FCF85E2DBE4FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">opportunities to expand or enhance existing initiatives for members of the Armed Forces eligible for preseparation counseling under section 1142 of title 10, United States Code, or veterans to become supply chain employees; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H652F03ED94DC46AF9010AE6F5B646499"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ways to improve supply chain employer outreach programs and enhance existing training, mentorship, education, and advancement programs that would increase the participation and engagement of members of the Armed Forces eligible for preseparation counseling under section 1142 of title 10, United States Code, and veterans in the supply chain workforce; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8273049AA17C47FBB82E22B9184C2928"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommend specific short- and long-term actions the Department of Transportation, the Department of Defense, the Department of Veterans Affairs, or the Department of Labor can take to help members of the Armed Forces eligible for preseparation counseling under section 1142 of title 10, United States Code, and veterans become supply chain employees; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2935B511712A4C8487089BBE3F168985"><enum>(4)</enum><text>consult with the transportation supply chain industry, modal transportation supply chain employers, and organizations representing modal transportation supply chain employees. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2432DCB03F134AB8A2C332463E8ED5E2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Supply chain employee defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>supply chain employee</quote> means an individual directly employed in the facilitation of the movement of goods. </text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20250908">September 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HPW00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc><action-date date="20250908">September 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs </committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

