<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2396397415E341C9A11D7B55C877F591" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2046 IH: To require congressional approval before the sale, disposal, declaration of excess or surplus, transfer, or conveyance of Federal property with historical significance, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2046</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250311">March 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require congressional approval before the sale, disposal, declaration of excess or surplus, transfer, or conveyance of Federal property with historical significance, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAB87006167E74EF1A76D0FDAAB26F8D9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9D917B1075774DFEA1E5109295A70FF4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Congressional approval of sale of Federal property with historical significance</header> 
<subsection id="H4BF05EE9743D4F4C9F0D27395250065F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No specified official may sell, dispose of, declare excess or surplus, transfer, or convey any covered building unless—</text> <paragraph id="HC88B6F226BF84FB6B397FA81908F7449" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the specified official provides to Congress a notice of intent to sell, dispose of, declare excess or surplus, transfer, or convey such covered building; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB0453C1B1802407E8122073983DE8EFD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress passes a joint resolution approving the sale, disposal, declaration of excess or surplus, transfer, or conveyance of the covered building that was the subject of such notice.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFEEA6D09B3F94BCC93948A4EFF3916DD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H1B7C7D0A39274CD8B58A431DE73DF7ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered building</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered building</term> means any land, building, structure, monument, or site—</text> <subparagraph id="H37E33CE5922345EA9DA96525CCA0C174"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is owned by the United States; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD9106DA82DD24FD7A9EA00DC5DD7AF33"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is or has ever been listed on the National Register of Historic Places.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H435C7DADB63D4B0586D78DC8D89E2D08"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specified official</header><text>The term <quote>specified official</quote> means the President, the head of any Federal agency, and any other Federal official. </text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

