<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BON25051-RNM-KT-SYX"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S473 IS: Social Engagement and Network Initiatives for Older Relief Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 473</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250206" legis-day="20250205">February 6 (legislative day, February 5), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Older Americans Act of 1965 to include screening for loneliness and coordination of supportive services and health care to address the negative health effects of loneliness, to require a report on loneliness, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Social Engagement and Network Initiatives for Older Relief Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SENIOR Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id676fc712f61546a685f385a4fb35ac1c"><enum>2.</enum><header>Screening older individuals for loneliness and coordination of supportive services and health care to address loneliness</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 102(14)(N) of the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3002">42 U.S.C. 3002(14)(N)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>and loneliness</quote> after <quote>social isolation</quote> each place it appears.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="PHE273993A41E94ADBBAF3E3541576A7FF"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Report on loneliness</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="PHC727C1CB1B9F4A59A27644C9CFF25D70"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Preparation of report</header><paragraph id="PHAE30AA23EECB49DEAAD54A297D81A5B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall, in carrying out activities under section 206(a) of the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3017">42 U.S.C. 3017(a)</external-xref>), prepare a report—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1d5b422d0c2d489faa068055cf615f13"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on programs authorized by such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3001">42 U.S.C. 3001 et seq.</external-xref>), and supported or funded by the Administration on Aging, that include a focus on addressing the negative health effects associated with loneliness through targeting older individuals identified as being in greatest social need, as appropriate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8aa2d1850a524aba898433888e8d16cc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that examines the relationship between the strength of multigenerational family units and loneliness in older individuals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="PH3E0F019C4B104075B95B6D08844DF912"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Impact</header><text>Such report shall identify— </text><subparagraph id="PH5F02229E90994FB38D00EA68DDF8FDC1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether loneliness is being adequately addressed under the programs described in paragraph (1)(A), including, to the extent practicable— </text><clause id="PHE10C309ED94043829D5A220C37C769DA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the prevalence of loneliness across geographic areas; </text></clause><clause id="PH3FEB665B635148DBA2CCF01C9F9C2B29"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the negative physical and mental health effects associated with loneliness; and </text></clause><clause id="PHF80F6EA5B3A547B9B051A3892FA3308C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the role of preventive measures and services under this Act in addressing the negative health effects associated with loneliness among older individuals; and </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="PH9DE3AB99C29A47FD8D413BE6760E9929"><enum>(B)</enum><text>public awareness of and efforts to address the negative health effects associated with loneliness. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="PHEE20B8A081274069BCCBA018808CB7EC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Types of programs</header><text>Such report shall identify whether programs described in paragraph (1)(A)— </text><subparagraph id="PH3F87C59CEF99425FB31234D393BF79FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>support projects in local communities and involve diverse sectors associated with such communities to decrease the negative health effects associated with loneliness among older individuals and caregivers; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="PH7DC1056B27294D8B9422F3DDB10EDC41"><enum>(B)</enum><text>support outreach activities to screen older individuals for negative health effects associated with loneliness; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="PHB82F0A02B73E48669D0DA43073A1C9C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include a focus on decreasing the negative health effects associated with loneliness. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="PH42F60A76E50B48839BD5B877431B7FF2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>Such report shall, as appropriate, include—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2418f9cb2bc54ea3b68bb1d9970b65a0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for reducing the negative health effects associated with loneliness and to address any negative health effects identified under clauses (ii) and (iii) of subparagraph (A), and subparagraph (B), of paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb8f046a32944983911fc817b7c0d7be"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations for policies or programs that foster strong and stable connections across different generations in a family.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="PH3449D8AFCB1D4E2C9E3DD03C80D3E6D1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission of report</header><paragraph id="PHDC87F72F1CE44A7E979983485D48EF9E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interim status report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit an interim report, to the committees of the Senate and of the House of Representatives with jurisdiction over the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3001">42 U.S.C. 3001 et seq.</external-xref>), and the Special Committee on Aging of the Senate, on the status of the evaluation underway to develop the final report required under this section. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="PH890E46B1C8DB4EF5BF93F71EB8F460F7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit a final report that meets the requirements of this section to the committees of the Senate and of the House of Representatives with jurisdiction over the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3001">42 U.S.C. 3001 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Special Committee on Aging of the Senate. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcbbac9f5dc024b4a8b230e1e017ef702"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section, the terms <term>greatest social need</term>, <term>older individual</term>, and <term>Secretary</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 102 of the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3002">42 U.S.C. 3002</external-xref>). </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

