<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25071-RKJ-F9-7D1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S242 IS: Dignity for Aborted Children Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 242</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250124">January 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To protect the dignity of fetal remains, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Dignity for Aborted Children Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id756A1F61D6754FC3B1C6C1EA9FC6143A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Constitutional authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress enacts the following pursuant to Congress’ power under—</text><paragraph id="H7B7F5ACCD5E441E7A6D98FF9C9A96E57"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Interstate Commerce Clause of section 8 of article I of the Constitution;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3792687C83464A0BB6A2416D0CD1E412"><enum>(2)</enum><text>section 5 of the 14th Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, including the power to enforce the prohibition on government action denying equal protection of the laws; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28FA1C43CD8E48BC91F0FD167CC2F38A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>section 8 of article I of the Constitution of the United States to make all laws necessary and proper for the carrying into execution of powers vested by the Constitution in the Government of the United States. </text></paragraph></section><section id="id749793A951DC4C078A2FD1E5B3281753"><enum>3.</enum><header>Protection of fetal remains</header><subsection id="HAAA16290DF3F4B2697C7C76CFE4EE9D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part H of title IV of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/289">42 U.S.C. 289 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id46EE5ACEA25945389A8B5CBB1BED56F5"><section id="id16755EE005B74674A3E37909FCF93AA6"><enum>498F.</enum><header>Protection of fetal remains</header><subsection id="id3BF27B017B004EB69E61E5E23A361F51"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Consent requirement</header><paragraph id="id8D449530548246DC93395A8D700E4087"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any abortion provider, after performing an abortion, shall provide the patient with an informed consent form, offering the patient the following options for disposal of the human fetal tissue from the abortion:</text><subparagraph id="idFDB747CD3BA54D9EA5FACB533551686A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The patient may take possession of the human fetal tissue and may choose to transfer the tissue to an entity providing interment or cremation services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA349D1FBC92E419A83512C17A406E204"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The patient may elect to release the human fetal tissue to the abortion provider, who shall be subject to the requirements of subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idED76D2DBD89E47809279E1BCF73D2700"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consent requirements</header><text>An abortion provider described in paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="id47046D05B62B421AA438A2B493256356"><enum>(A)</enum><text>obtain a patient signature on each consent form required under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9213A4F3EE9E4EBCAB1575C2A6FFFA5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>retain each such form in the patient's file.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1E3A74D7F5F442268DA774206A3D583E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Provider disposal requirement</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any abortion provider who, after performing an abortion in which the woman on whom the abortion was performed elects, pursuant to subsection (a)(1)(B), to release the human fetal tissue to the abortion provider, to fail to provide for the final disposition of the human fetal tissue through interment or cremation, consistent with State law regarding the disposal of human remains, not later than 7 days after the date on which the abortion procedure was performed. Such final disposition of human fetal tissue may be carried out through interment or cremation of tissue from more than one abortion procedure collectively.</text></subsection><subsection id="id202771CA67364AFB8B12C66E6F7112F5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalties</header><paragraph id="id8C8C6BA558014DC99F89F812A95EA917"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Informed consent violations</header><text>An abortion provider who fails to maintain the documentation required under subsection (a)(2)(B) shall be subject to civil monetary penalties in an amount not to exceed $50,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idF8DF719891CE4ED8A9CA8D06DBDA0E4C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disposal violations</header><text>Any abortion provider who violates subsection (b) shall be fined in accordance with title 18, United States Code, imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7398596C4DB042C984DC04C100880030"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Bar to prosecution</header><text>A patient upon whom an abortion in violation of subsection (b) is performed or attempted may not be prosecuted under, or for a conspiracy to violate, paragraph (1), or for an offense under section 2, 3, or 4 of title 18, United States Code, based on such a violation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3E18550E4B7449A6B766F461E9C80873"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Each abortion provider described in subsection (a)(1) shall submit annual reports to the Secretary indicating, with respect to the reporting period—</text><paragraph id="id34D6662379B14FD6B1AE8CC3A0E38B76"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the aggregate number of abortion procedures performed by such abortion provider;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9418ECF035F94D9CA7389ED7BC289459"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the gestational age at the time of each such procedure; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7B011D7260B44350AF32A5CFB723AF80"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for abortions carried out using an abortion method other than chemical abortion, the aggregate number of fetal remains transferred for interment or cremation and the number released to patients.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idB800034368844182903B99B2E87832BE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual reports by the Secretary</header><text>The Secretary shall submit to Congress an annual report on the number of abortions by State, procedure type, and method of disposal of human fetal tissue.</text></subsection><subsection id="id007663795CCE4BBA84A6D52A0AA5400E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Non-Preemption</header><text>Nothing in this section shall preempt any State requirement that, at a minimum, requires interment or cremation in the same manner that other human remains are required to be treated in such State.</text></subsection><subsection id="idD25021BDA6D14E9196CEC9CA6C40E972"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="id6CC462716F174EE196B8C40EC8646DBE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>abortion</term> means the use or prescription of any instrument, medicine, drug, or any other substance or device—</text><subparagraph id="id8BCC2583FAD54D578A3B2BB6F9BAFFF5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to intentionally kill the unborn child of a woman known to be pregnant; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0830AE3D12954D588479BDA5F907B59E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to intentionally terminate the pregnancy of a woman known to be pregnant, with an intention other than—</text><clause id="id56376225ECBC4682909EA70A1E0F26BF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>after viability to produce a live birth and preserve the life and health of the child born alive; or</text></clause><clause id="id868ED02242064F5BA8B427C48028CD8C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to remove a dead unborn child;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id949D787CAE2849BDA5F516AAB15E6A16"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>abortion provider</term> means an individual or entity that performs abortions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id13E22AEAC0B44B34ACC74DFC2C9FF858"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>human fetal tissue</term> has the meaning given the term in section 498A(g).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

