<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7D3178AB36AF44259FCE0C0F9F991E24" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4531 IH: Barring Adversarial Networks and Notorious Extremist Destabilizers in Latin America Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4531</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001229">Mr. Shreve</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001233">Mr. Messmer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a strategy to counter Iranian and Hezbollah influence operations in Latin America.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9F208BEED07D4F67A00BE9B9B1ACABC0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3A7B498E47014C07B1A677D9F3FEBF8E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Barring Adversarial Networks and Notorious Extremist Destabilizers in Latin America Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BANNED in Latin America Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1B7AB833DAA24812880B2D4FFE5086AE" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Strategy to counter Iranian and Hezbollah influence operations in Latin America</header> <subsection id="HD3C918003BDD4CD78C1840E4404A589D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a comprehensive strategy to counter Iran’s and Hezbollah’s propaganda, missionary networks, and influence operations in Latin America.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFE26266975D24A01A20BC14C11AA5D72"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of strategy</header><text>The strategy required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H3EDCE05F4F224401BFE63673FB2762F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Measures to address the proliferation of Iranian cultural centers in Latin America that promote Iranian ideology, including diplomatic efforts to limit their operations, sanctions on affiliated entities, and public diplomacy to expose their activities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5ED88544251840688F079BF8BBD1D6F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Actions to restrict the travel and activities of Iranian emissaries, including diplomats, cultural attaches, and other agents who facilitate propaganda, radicalization, and terror-supporting networks in Latin America, through visa denials, sanctions, or other travel restrictions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77AA699E230547B0A906DF1CE0245358"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Initiatives to strengthen the capacity of United States intelligence agencies to identify, monitor, and disrupt Iran’s and Hezbollah’s networks, including their cooperation academic institutions and nongovernmental organizations in Latin America.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H890F27DA76644A38BACB98DFBE198C51"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A framework for taking actions, similar to those implemented against Al-Manar and Press TV, to disrupt Iran’s HispanTV and Hezbollah’s Al Mayadeen Espanol platforms, including sanctions, designations, and cooperation with regional partners to limit their broadcasting reach and digital presence.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC4D4FD212037479981F4373A5B5BBECD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A plan to address Iran’s Al Mustafa International University network and its affiliated entities, including their designations as foreign terrorist organizations or specially designated global terrorists, as appropriate, due to their role in radicalization and recruitment for Iran’s ideological and terrorist objectives.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7558AEA1563448A894E0F9862DA66B92"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The strategy required by subsection (a) shall be transmitted in unclassified form and may include a classified annex.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H600CFC3381BF4935BF1033A3701006C9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committee defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF723A522E62946BDA8B581AE43266941"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7984D0A807E14443A290F6682A4FB139"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

