<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROM25051-N2P-6D-LLL"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S332 IS: Holocaust Education and Antisemitism Lessons Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 332</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250130">January 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require a study on Holocaust education efforts of States, local educational agencies, and public elementary and secondary schools, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Holocaust Education and Antisemitism Lessons Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idda3959c2490947bc9f378a9b0adee991"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study and report on Holocaust education</header><subsection id="ida53b50824d6a48ed836f10042f3e093b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Beginning not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the United States Holocaust Memorial Museum (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Director</quote>) shall conduct a study on Holocaust education efforts in States, local educational agencies, and public elementary schools and secondary schools. Such study shall include an examination of—</text><paragraph id="id28ade6d639e24dc897092c76e0a51145"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbf83d706aee1480290525eb33381b70d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a nationally representative sample of local educational agencies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide03b766624e5405d84a39497dcc551b4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a representative sample of public elementary and secondary schools served by the local educational agencies being studied.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id64c732b0b7b1420bb1a0df2a734491c3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>In conducting the study under subsection (a), the Director shall—</text><paragraph id="id7553612b665b41aa92408fe5226fe298"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determine whether States and local educational agencies being studied require Holocaust education as part of the curriculum taught in public elementary schools and secondary schools;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8c12bfaed43f4f9b82eab35a84ccdbcc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify States and local educational agencies being studied that have optional Holocaust education as part of the curriculum taught in public elementary schools and secondary schools;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb84bfb0a2bcf471b8536576285ce3dad"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify each State’s standards and the requirements of the local educational agencies being studied relating to Holocaust education and summarize the status of the implementation of such standards and requirements, including—</text><subparagraph id="id693e10bd8ec5484faf2dcc4b8d39b1b8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the existence of a centralized apparatus at the State or local level that collects and disseminates Holocaust education curricula and materials;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id381b31185e2841038f22291a847642d8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the existence of Holocaust education professional development opportunities for pre-service and in-service teachers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4296631f48a6428c8b546fb732f70c80"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the involvement of informal educational organizations in implementing Holocaust education, including museums and cultural centers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd3fca569a4b046998f2a3a385b566768"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an assessment of the challenges or gaps that may prevent educators from fulfilling Holocaust education requirements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcc8b913f54984970bcddc37494a6dfab"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the identification of training and resources needed to support educators teaching about the Holocaust; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6aea9d8de72f4fbb85fea277b132c9d5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the adoption of United States Holocaust Memorial Museum resources by—</text><clause id="id8e27454722ae4d39a4f7795da559e870"><enum>(i)</enum><text>entities at the State or local level that disseminate Holocaust education curricula; or</text></clause><clause id="id68317aab807b423f9c10004cbc44c2bd"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>local Holocaust museums and centers;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd70e5339fc7a488396ba31402edc4d9a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>determine—</text><subparagraph id="id0c3c4dab42f44fc3bcb3cef6569a8a88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the range of intended outcomes from a Holocaust education unit at the State and local educational agency level; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5545ab8741714b799ae188c056951032"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the methods teachers are using that result in successfully achieving intended learning outcomes, which may include—</text><clause id="idb6e293405abb4f94a8bddaf51b779153"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in-class discussion;</text></clause><clause id="idf72106ea0ea3426abb3924bc6efbb8e8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>educational activities conducted outside the classroom, including homework assignments and experiential learning involving State and local organizations, such as museums and cultural centers;</text></clause><clause id="id8f08a0850bd74e60844d905622aff487"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>project based learning;</text></clause><clause id="ide7ef67a775754f50bfac75fe679f6a24"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>educational materials and activities that are developmentally appropriate and taught through a trauma-informed lens; and</text></clause><clause id="id23839401c6f14d6085c1cf219a49af9c"><enum>(v)</enum><text>integration of lessons from the Holocaust across the curriculum and throughout the school year;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1d1fc74019574af898c2703b4a71b014"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identify the types of instructional materials used to teach students about the Holocaust, including the use of primary source material;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id864886bd8cd84d43bb2bb56ad64d6700"><enum>(6)</enum><text>identify—</text><subparagraph id="idade143620b1d43aeb4a4f19f75a5f5a8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in what disciplines the Holocaust is being taught;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id29e2a4a16b424bcc93de99a4d3a8ecb5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount of time allotted in the required curriculum to teach about the Holocaust; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7325bc85d70e49d88348f8d14c98d367"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the comprehensiveness of the Holocaust education curriculum taught in public elementary schools and secondary schools, as indicated by the extent to which the curriculum addresses all elements and aspects of the Holocaust and is based on reliable educational resources, such as resources provided by the United States Holocaust Memorial Museum; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9f1a5ed1e7154cce8ea82a6ed54c41e9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>identify the approaches used by public elementary schools and secondary schools to assess outcomes using traditional and nontraditional assessments, including assessments of—</text><subparagraph id="id7e8e870ad4674355b59c3cfb99526425"><enum>(A)</enum><text>students’ knowledge of the Holocaust; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id588b4457e4d44badbf976a8c1844fdf0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>students’ ability to identify and analyze antisemitism, bigotry, hate, and genocide in historical and contemporary contexts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4e8fb1d4e2bf425d94b4e3f7df371214"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="id699d8a6d5718435a9edea3ed1ea9b30a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Following the completion of the study under subsection (a), the Director shall prepare and submit to Congress a report on the results of the study.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4ef2e050d6524a9e8e54cfb270a421ff"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline for submittal</header><text>The report under paragraph (1) shall be submitted not later than the earlier of—</text><subparagraph id="id0b7ff81a8ca74c4fb7b932e95c05ae67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>180 days after the completion of the study under subsection (a); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id634ea31fba154fa5913eec61d7e92f4d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>3 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide3a9850336194773a5c6132c8398a03c"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id14da093971664a9b802af15d6fbfbc40"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ESEA terms</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, and <term>State</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id39da00596b96483cbe3dbbad0c69acae"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Holocaust</header><text>The term <term>Holocaust</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the Never Again Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/141">Public Law 116–141</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/36/2301">36 U.S.C. 2301</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb855b995c47843539b5f204f759d6ab0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Holocaust education</header><text>The term <term>Holocaust education</term> means educational activities that are specifically intended—</text><subparagraph id="id2244754bca524da3872631868f8f2bb7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to improve students’ awareness and understanding of the Holocaust;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida81fdfe84a324996ac81a7e360735cd0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to educate students on the lessons of the Holocaust as a means to raise awareness about the importance of preventing genocide, hate, and bigotry against any group of people; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec58b67dfef34842a07d9786b1226c84"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to study the history of antisemitism, its deep historical roots, the use of conspiracy theories and propaganda that target the Jewish people, and the shape-shifting nature of antisemitism over time.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idda8847892cab4f44a0ebdf26f6585436"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Project based learning</header><text>The term <term>project based learning</term> means a teaching method through which students learn by actively engaging in real-world and personally meaningful projects. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

