<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H06521CDA722D4488BC6A5AC8B707E030" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2050 IH: Homeland Heroes Pay Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2050</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250311">March 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000590">Mr. Green of Tennessee</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000594">Ms. De La Cruz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Making continuing appropriations for the salary and expenses of certain excepted employees of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAD83A9543EF546FA92C41FE04EBBECBF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H51950F8CD4D142238C2E34EF23C33571" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Homeland Heroes Pay Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA5450BC6104744D88B8E4469517E7868"><enum>2.</enum><header>Continuing appropriations for certain employees of CBP and ICE</header> <subsection id="H8363F8B701F94A409D38D33B33C7B322"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, such sums as are necessary to pay, during the period of any lapse in discretionary appropriations occurring on or after the date of the enactment of this Act, the salaries and expenses of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8BF7D8517708439EB48873E8C3B128DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">U.S. Customs and Border Protection agents and officers who are performing mission critical functions at United States Southwest, Northern, and maritime border ports of entry, and between such ports of entry, including preventing terrorists, terrorists weapons, illegal aliens, illicit drugs, and other illegal contraband; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C042432B68A4ABC9740300DDA38CB14"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement officers and agents who conduct—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4C13AB250E1F4A918D2B272C062DD227"><enum>(A)</enum><text>immigration enforcement, including detaining and removing aliens (as defined in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H470A12E1D1A14DCFBD1994386D798EE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>investigations of criminal operations and organizations, including—</text> 
<clause id="HF164052F5A1A4ECF9B156254E048F1DB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the illegal trade of contraband such as goods, weapons, and drugs; and</text></clause> <clause id="H318B9225F6374A77AACBCD398D39983D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the smuggling and trafficking of people.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD6253932A17C47CAAB6A98355BBBD531"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>Appropriations and funds made available and authority granted pursuant to this section shall be available until whichever of the following first occurs:</text> <paragraph id="H15AA548DDB944AA89FAD4ADB58EBEB8F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The enactment into law of an appropriation (including a continuing appropriation) for any purpose for which amounts are made available in subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3FF5DDE0BE6340B08D3061B6ED6951B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The enactment into law of the applicable regular or continuing appropriations resolution or other Act without any appropriation for such purpose.</text></paragraph> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

