<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6967308A226347478A57B830D2B257F3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3146 IH: Helping Emergency Responders Overcome Student Debt Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3146</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250501">May 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to include service as a volunteer firefighter or volunteer emergency medical technician as a public service job for purposes of eligibility for the Public Service Loan Forgiveness Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6B5E86E0EA2E4E2FA70ADB6BFF1F610C" style="OLC"><section id="HA0FC3100817E4F57A4036D93883AA8FB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Helping Emergency Responders Overcome Student Debt Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HEROES Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H463CD059EDF248FD9AB5D3EBDBBD459D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Loan forgiveness for volunteer first responders</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 455(m)(3) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(m)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HD232C7F57E95460887BEFB850E7DDD2F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><subparagraph id="H205098E37955467A8022499EEDF73103"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD8F17A2156644D0A87319387CF2E03A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A58D3626F5A4041A3A9C913420C4BF7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H8A3C447FA10F4DF3AFA349998C200CA5" style="OLC"><clause id="H1E57E84097004AF7B882E1F72EC1FBD5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">volunteer work as a qualified volunteer firefighter or qualified volunteer emergency medical technician in accordance with subparagraph (C).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE00F85586DC14EE99649F214CE1EB5A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HA132133B16CA413EBC4647141F22E07D" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HB75F8685530E4EC483B36A8E0888C8B3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Qualified volunteer firefighter; qualified emergency medical technician</header><clause id="HF2A7BE52090D4C88A2C4D82A8F23B57E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The term <term>qualified volunteer firefighter</term> means an individual who—</text><subclause id="H6D48AACEFD1F4E64B46CA0352597B960"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provides firefighting services, fire prevention services, emergency medical services, or other related emergency response services on behalf of a legally recognized fire department or public safety organization; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HC92FE197F59E4C868556C7D38E33E1E0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is not otherwise directly employed on a full-time basis by the same fire department or public safety organization for which they provide such services.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H1BAA8C3DD5DC459DBB6F3708AFE8B2F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The term <term>qualified volunteer emergency medical technician</term> means an individual who—</text><subclause id="H6DB84CA76588456580E0FB9F52D382A7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is trained and certified, licensed, or otherwise authorized under applicable state or local laws to provide emergency medical care, pre-hospital care, or ambulance services in response to medical emergencies;</text></subclause><subclause id="H439661CE3EDB45E48E2F16D85E74FB0F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>performs such care or services on behalf of an ambulance service, fire department, healthcare facility, or public safety organization; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H4AFD11E50F06423FB26226B0176BF2ED"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not otherwise directly employed on a full-time basis by the same ambulance service, fire department, healthcare facility, or public safety organization for which they provide such care or services.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HDD22112D16E84FCDB755D056E2E37851"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Secretary shall—</text><subclause id="H471420AAE05D466EB2C9DD9226B6ACFD"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine the minimum volunteer time required for a qualified volunteer firefighter or a qualified volunteer emergency medical technician to be treated as an individual employed in a full-time job for purposes of this subsection; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HC03727AEBD8E4B678D6A9C04D6FBA3B4"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that such minimum volunteer time is not less than the amount of volunteer time that is required for the qualified volunteer firefighter or a qualified volunteer emergency medical technician to be considered an active member of the relevant ambulance service, fire department, healthcare facility, or public safety organization.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15BC064A2C7D4F71A2C6999F08A34DBF"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Public safety organization</header><text>The term <term>public safety organization</term> means any State, local, or tribal governmental agency or nonprofit organization that has the principal purpose of protecting the safety of life, health, or property.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HAE61D0C4999444B7B37EDB08226AD6C3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Education shall promulgate, after consultation with public safety organizations (which shall include firefighter and emergency responder organizations), regulations to carry out the amendments made by section 2, including regulations relating to—</text><paragraph id="HE584306D4A0B44E1B5013121D917E20C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the minimum volunteer time required for a qualified volunteer firefighter and qualified volunteer emergency medical technician to be treated as an individual employed in a full-time job for purposes of section 455(m) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(m)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF41E3112182649C182A244FE5E9B0BF9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the process of tracking and verifying that volunteer time.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

