<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H81B71AB9875E4341947679D01A00AF89" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3108 IH: Rural Patient Monitoring Access Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3108</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250430">April 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000392">Mr. Kustoff</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001306">Mr. Balderson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act with respect to payment for remote patient monitoring under the Medicare program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7DCAB260388044DF8656F96763D9531D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H40CCF6BE99CC4CA4BB4F265FE9CD8E22" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rural Patient Monitoring Access Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RPM Access Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section>
<section id="HA61A3168D2294493BC157B577E5C32F6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H964117B2B9E7419CB55E69E88D5F56DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Remote patient monitoring (in this section referred to as <quote>RPM</quote>) supports highly coordinated care, improves patient outcomes, and can lower costs to the Medicare program.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H47A9F68E2DD0437B80DCC03C2AE68882"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Three out of five federally designated health professional shortage areas are in rural regions, and rural residents generally must travel farther than urban counterparts to access health care services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB5A37D3ED92643FAB33D8C5083FE063D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Medicare reimbursement for RPM is lowest in States where the prevalence of heart failure, hypertension, and diabetes are well above the national average.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1D331C93F78A44B3A477B2BD9036B078"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The practice expenses and malpractice expenses incurred in the delivery of RPM are not lower in rural areas and do not widely vary by State.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HC07137E9236C4CE48254D27D188CFC5E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Floor for practice expense and malpractice geographic indices for remote patient monitoring</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1848(e)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(e)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC472C6189654B5B9D4ECE86B8B1922D">
<subparagraph id="HD8104E474D8F4B4882FFB29A1DB7820F" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><header>Floor for practice expense and malpractice geographic indices for remote patient monitoring</header><text>For purposes of payment for remote patient monitoring furnished on or after January 1, 2026, after calculating the practice expense and malpractice geographic indices in clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (A) and in subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall increase any such index to 1.00 if such index would otherwise be less than 1.00. The preceding sentence shall not be applied in a budget neutral manner.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HE428568BF62246F3852DE76EFEA76016"><enum>4.</enum><header>Ensuring high-quality remote patient monitoring under Medicare</header> <subsection id="H2BCA8E2817574A22A2330F684A65E0A4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1834 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA0D2D0AD018F48C9A2602A242491A703" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subsection id="H953F21E8154F4A619224B79194A4318D"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Payment for remote patient monitoring</header><text>In the case of remote patient monitoring furnished on or after January 1, 2026, no payment may be made under this part for such monitoring furnished by a provider of services or supplier unless—</text> <paragraph id="H551195A6911E4FD6B48D9445379EA860"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a physician, nurse practitioner, clinical nurse specialist, or physician assistant is available in real time to respond to any physiologic anomaly detected through such monitoring;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H926C53CE82CB4DDF9454D0EABE40254D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such monitoring is furnished through a system that can transmit physiologic data obtained through such monitoring in a format that is compatible with electronic health records, as needed; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E593623D78A4E5B8057AFBF06857C24"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the provider or supplier collects and reports such data as the Secretary may require in order to facilitate the evaluation of cost savings to the program under this title that are generated by the use of remote patient monitoring, except that the Secretary may exempt a provider or supplier under this paragraph if the Secretary determines that such collection and reporting of data would result in unreasonable hardship upon such provider or supplier.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H9A81D280A845465FAD81A075EB3B4A71"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header>
<paragraph id="H0657E0114939449EBDC39496116B22A1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress a report that includes the following information, with respect to the 4-year period beginning January 1, 2026:</text> <subparagraph id="H26AC24C47B4E4685B7CC6D9A82D92BAF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of the estimated savings to the Medicare program resulting from earlier interventions and fewer days of hospitalization among Medicare beneficiaries furnished remote patient monitoring (as such term is used for purposes of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>)) during such period.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8923B01F4C6F459F9D2078D90A199130"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An analysis of the estimated savings to the Medicare program resulting from increased adherence to prescription medications among Medicare beneficiaries furnished remote patient monitoring during such period.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBB89A2BA3F9D4B139422867ADDEA4D64"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An analysis of practice expenses as defined in section 1848(j) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(j)</external-xref>) related to the furnishing of remote patient monitoring during such period, including expenses related to cellular connectivity and other technology platform maintenance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE9E11050F01F49998171A7497329DB14"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H2ED62AF81F2948FC8BD4A39D46C47556"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Medicare beneficiary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Medicare beneficiary</term> means an individual entitled to benefits under part A of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395c">42 U.S.C. 1395c et seq.</external-xref>) or enrolled under part B of such title (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395j">42 U.S.C. 1395j et seq.</external-xref>)</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3E840853EDDD4D5495DBB44DCB3DF5AA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Medicare program</header><text>The term <term>Medicare program</term> means the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

