<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2D776D49933148C78A6E7DA5DC58B3EF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1590 IH: Rural Innovation and Small Business Support Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1590</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250226">February 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require Federal agencies with an SBIR or STTR program to enhance their outreach to rural communities with respect to such programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H701EFE438BB147288E242785B7EF45AE" style="OLC"><section id="HC72F388BB8F34443BF79375F5D713380" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rural Innovation and Small Business Support Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H196B282A3CE047ADA5BF289395E736EA"><enum>2.</enum><header>SBIR and STTR program rural community outreach</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 9 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H7583A85FB5B740DF9AFA614DAB7989FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (j), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H698CEC5B7142405EA2DA759E109B8866" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HEFF815265676456E9896A067392BA71E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Modification relating to rural outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the Administrator shall modify the policy directives issued pursuant to this subsection to require each Federal agency participating in the SBIR program to enhance the outreach efforts of such Federal agency to rural communities to increase the participation of small business concerns located in rural communities in the SBIR program, including by ensuring that such Federal agency conducts outreach efforts with respect to the SBIR program in rural communities.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D76BBDF01C34891AFDDC8AEE217EB8E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (p), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H950097B687724604AF44C4E7D4E0D4BF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H08BAECCDE69A4A928553AB880352E86C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Modification relating to rural outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the Administrator shall modify the policy directives issued pursuant to this subsection to require each Federal agency participating in the STTR program to enhance the outreach efforts of such Federal agency to rural communities to increase the participation of small business concerns located in rural communities in the STTR program, including by ensuring that such Federal agency conducts outreach efforts with respect to the STTR program in rural communities.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

