<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H46A4E8A32B9549948B5527790EF74FFE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4595 IH: Small and Homestead Independent Producers Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4595</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250722">July 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001094">Ms. Hoyle of Oregon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide authority for small cultivators of cannabis and small manufacturers of cannabis products to ship cannabis and cannabis products using the mail, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H46DA2F9265124ACF9854B47E64A9A82E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H229A5ED3A5DB43F5810E84E4D5ABECB6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Small and Homestead Independent Producers Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H43E74637B56E4665A2B04F010694AD8B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authority for small cultivators and manufacturers of cannabis to ship cannabis in the mail</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A small cultivator of cannabis and a small manufacturer of a cannabis product located in a State in which such cultivation or manufacture is lawful by that small cultivator or small manufacturer, as applicable, may ship and sell cannabis or a cannabis product to an individual located in that State or another State in which possession of cannabis or the cannabis product is lawful by that individual, using the United States Postal Service or any private or commercial interstate carrier.</text></section> 
<section id="H849138A2C08D47EE9AA26710163780CB" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Age verification requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Postal Service and any private or commercial interstate carrier that transports cannabis or a cannabis product, as authorized under section 2, may not deliver such cannabis or a cannabis product to an individual who has not attained the age of 21, and shall verify the age of any individual accepting receipt of such a delivery using a reliable online age verification service or by obtaining and examining a copy of a valid, non-expired government-issued identification, including identification issued by an Indian Tribe.</text></section> <section id="H26DF0E108E8F4FE5B0D8876CA272DE47"><enum>4.</enum><header>Preemption</header> <subsection id="HFAA7472BA8B5431D88473E7E32962890"><enum>(a)</enum><header>States in which cannabis is unlawful</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to preempt or supersede any State law that prohibits the manufacture, distribution, or possession of cannabis for all individuals in that State, except for the purpose of permitting the interstate transport of cannabis through that State to a final destination in a State in which possession of cannabis is lawful by the intended recipient.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDDC9758DB381418399F24983F0413B11"><enum>(b)</enum><header>States in which cannabis is lawful</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act preempts the laws of a State that does not prohibit the manufacture, distribution, or possession of cannabis for all individuals in that State (except with respect to age limitations) to the extent that such laws restrict the interstate or intrastate shipment of cannabis or a cannabis product directly to an individual with respect to whom the possession of cannabis or a cannabis product is lawful under the laws of the State.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H36FC0BCFCBC84AAA8F6BFAACA66F37DD"><enum>5.</enum><header>Mailability of cannabis</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1716 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5288E833245A4B5381CA9CF1F19AA8E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (h) through (k) as subsections (i) through (l), respectively; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE33424E3D8584E4881D475040A7837FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (g) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H67A89C2A98FC4D70A0946CFE99A155C7" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H6531432F32DD43249D1B3D540DAF9738"><enum>(h)</enum> 
<paragraph id="H3719EB5B4AF443489FF3AF72F715ABA7" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Postal Service is authorized and directed to permit the transmission in the mails, under regulations to be prescribed by it, of cannabis, to the extent that the mailing is allowable under the Small and Homestead Independent Producers Act of 2025.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H764399451F8044709521902ED66C6E18" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In this section, the term <term>cannabis</term> has the meaning given the term <term>marijuana</term> in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H1B9BF107A9CA49D59E25C9B5D9607022"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H629DE283B4A843E88C4FD9F3A8124ACE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>cannabis</term> has the meaning given the term <term>marijuana</term> in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68129AE94A5A4CE29A5EA5F3AF63AFA0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>small cultivator of cannabis</term> means a person who cultivates one acre or less of mature flowering cannabis plant canopy using outdoor cultivation, 22,000 square feet or less of cannabis plant canopy using greenhouse cultivation, or 5,000 square feet or fewer of mature flowering cannabis plant canopy using indoor cultivation, inclusive of all cannabis cultivated by that person.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDD7FA38BBC254F499C7D401FCFDDF1B1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>small manufacturer of a cannabis product</term> means a person who produces a manufactured cannabis product, including a salve, tincture, edible, or concentrate, with a gross annual revenue of less than $5,000,000, inclusive of all cannabis product manufactured by that person.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBEBB8663CB3F4D8D83A0EBDF363DACE7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>person</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1 of title 1, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HECB168BEE92F43B884C9E0A40F532DC0"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>outdoor cultivation</term> means the cultivation of mature cannabis without the use of artificial lighting or heating in the canopy area at any point in time, and may include the use of light deprivation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H465DAA48DE5E4F3CA29F947312B59104"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <term>light deprivation</term> means the use of any technique to eliminate natural light in order to induce flowering.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDDD3CE898A81400084D82AC24CFCAC4E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The term <term>greenhouse cultivation</term> means the cultivation of mature cannabis in a structure utilizing artificial light at a rate above zero watts per square foot, but no more than six watts per square foot.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF7685CA0B5EC4B0190EACEE7579B1DA3"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The term <term>indoor cultivation</term> means the cultivation of mature cannabis in a structure with the use of artificial light at a rate above six watts per square foot in the canopy area.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A632E933DF74D28A41A53380F1E3AEC"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The term <term>canopy</term> means the area that contains mature cannabis plants at any point in time.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5A59C70A3F404D82A5FED47799887475"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The term <term>mature</term> means, with respect to a cannabis plant, a cannabis plant that is flowering.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H9AB867AD52B949B788F8CBBDE73695E5"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act, and the amendments made by this Act, shall take effect on the date on which cannabis is removed from the list of scheduled substances under the Controlled Substances Act, and Federal criminal penalties for an individual who manufactures, distributes, or possesses cannabis, are eliminated.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

