<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA25067-61T-12-S05"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 49 ATS: Designating the week beginning February 3, 2025, as “National Tribal Colleges and Universities Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 49</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250130">January 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating the week beginning February 3, 2025, as <quote>National Tribal Colleges and Universities Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas there are 34 Tribal Colleges and Universities operating on more than 90 campuses in 16 States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tribal Colleges and Universities are tribally chartered or federally chartered institutions of higher education and therefore have a unique relationship with the Federal Government;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tribal Colleges and Universities serve students from more than 230 federally recognized Indian Tribes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tribal Colleges and Universities offer students access to knowledge and skills grounded in cultural traditions and values, including indigenous languages, which—</text><paragraph id="idad466f29bf994d24a3b9f130b77fd190"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enhances Indian communities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id67508cacef4543c6b66d7c4404679d4a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enriches the United States as a Nation;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tribal Colleges and Universities provide access to high-quality postsecondary educational opportunities for—</text><paragraph id="id96984d4f31db4b11abc568a82dbe7b02"><enum>(1)</enum><text>American Indians;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id464da96234594eb1b3006b4b3b844ea6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Alaska Natives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id39000a90a3bc442dbaa1627789667df2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>other individuals that live in some of the most isolated and economically depressed areas in the United States;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tribal Colleges and Universities are accredited institutions of higher education that prepare students to succeed in the global and highly competitive workforce;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tribal Colleges and Universities have open enrollment policies and enroll Native and non-Native students; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the collective mission and the considerable achievements of Tribal Colleges and Universities deserve national recognition: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id1b0c06e6bc0d47f8895b26d5a4cb2b1d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates the week beginning February 3, 2025, as <quote>National Tribal Colleges and Universities Week</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5ac555405a46432c8f8ffc3ebd827bdc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls on the people of the United States and interested groups to observe National Tribal Colleges and Universities Week with appropriate activities and programs to demonstrate support for Tribal Colleges and Universities. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

