<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8DBC20DBB98548039C55BB074E79A94D" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 376 IH: Expressing support for the designation of May 4, 2025, as a “National Day of Reason” and recognizing the central importance of reason in the betterment of humanity.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 376</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250501">May 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of May 4, 2025, as a <quote>National Day of Reason</quote> and recognizing the central importance of reason in the betterment of humanity.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the application of reason has been the essential precondition for humanity’s extraordinary scientific, medical, technological, and social progress since before the founding of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas reason provides the necessary framework for confronting the crises of today, including—</text><paragraph id="H188792510824494EBE5CBCF21F5E37AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for cultivating our common defense of the rule of law, the separation of church and state, strong democratic institutions, justice, and peace among nations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1287D21ABB2D459F9F464E6C2D9AC8E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for providing an antidote to the fear and disinformation that have fed the rise of authoritarianism in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77EFB57DA53749DAB1D0BAB3D81AA2C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for advancing civil liberties and human rights for all; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C64F06DCB1949DF9AD8DFA9A24740DC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>for confronting the civilizational emergency of climate change;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas America’s Founders insisted upon the primacy of reason and knowledge in public life, and drafted the Constitution to prevent official establishment of religion and to protect freedom of thought, speech, and inquiry in civil society;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Establishment Clause and the Free Exercise Clause, grounded in the principle of reason, protect the rights of people of all religious faiths and of none at all and ensure the United States remains a pluralistic democracy capable of withstanding theocratic threats to secular governance;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas James Madison, author of the First Amendment and fourth President of the United States, stated, <quote>The advancement and diffusion of knowledge is the only guardian of true liberty</quote>, and <quote>Knowledge will forever govern ignorance, and a people who mean to be their own governors, must arm themselves with the power knowledge gives</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Thomas Paine, an American Founding Father and luminary patriot of the Enlightenment and American Revolution, wrote that reason is <quote>the most formidable weapon against errors of every kind</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, today. some of our Nation’s leaders would replace knowledge, facts, and evidence with propaganda, disinformation, and superstition; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas May 4, 2025, would be an appropriate date to designate as a <quote>National Day of Reason</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="HA1983BEF9F5B4427B6BA4F8FB7F59DFC"><section id="H93445164A433443580BFC7044E6A4292" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives— </text><paragraph id="H23759EA92FBB42CB87F203380CBD3365"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of a <quote>National Day of Reason</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB7DDDCB95E345A0A73B86B6429A975A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages all persons in the United States to observe this day and uplift the central importance of reason, critical thought, the scientific method, and free inquiry to resolving social problems and promoting the welfare of humankind.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

