<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF51BFAA4080D48BFB690C9C278B6B4A8" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 97 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the week beginning February 3, 2025, as “National Tribal Colleges and Universities Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 97</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250204">February 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the week beginning February 3, 2025, as <quote>National Tribal Colleges and Universities Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas there are 34 Tribal colleges and universities operating on more than 90 campuses in 16 States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tribal colleges and universities are institutions of higher education that receive Tribal charters or Federal charters and therefore have a unique relationship with the Federal Government;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tribal colleges and universities serve students from more than 230 federally recognized Indian Tribes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tribal colleges and universities offer students access to knowledge and skills grounded in cultural traditions and values, including indigenous languages, which— </text><paragraph id="H346F5A0E76DE4525AD438F19635E4C5B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enhance Indian communities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H83CBBC5258164DFC9CF360E1EB33E001"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enrich the United States as a nation;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tribal colleges and universities provide access to high-quality postsecondary educational opportunities for—</text><paragraph id="H142D4F0A7F794896B27AEFF816D0E851"><enum>(1)</enum><text>American Indians;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7CC5437803D4220B92C6395D0ADC5CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Alaska Natives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FC6CB8DFE914C97B2420B3C766781F0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>other individuals who live in some of the most isolated and economically depressed areas in the United States;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tribal colleges and universities are accredited institutions of higher education that prepare students to succeed in the global and highly competitive workforce;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tribal colleges and universities have open enrollment policies, and approximately 13 percent of the students at Tribal colleges and universities are non-Indian individuals; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the collective mission and the considerable achievements of Tribal colleges and universities deserve national recognition: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H9AE4A93827C44F5398EA0FFFF3897462"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H71C9D27A50A24D8689B3A44091DE2249"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H1245820EEBBC41DDA8CD728DBE514C34"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of <quote>National Tribal Colleges and Universities Week</quote> ; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H862A959A5FA54A99BF25F1005D9C30BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">urges the people of the United States and interested groups to observe National Tribal Colleges and Universities Week with appropriate activities and programs to demonstrate support for Tribal colleges and universities.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

