<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC4700E0B376B488B9A030BEB06955457" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 752 IH: Methane Emissions Mitigation Research and Development Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 752</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250128">January 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for methane emission detection and mitigation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA10A93BBC2954F3587AE43C4C460B5C5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H660696101282402A831B0E1604633BF6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Methane Emissions Mitigation Research and Development Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD23FAC737D074EED831D2CD301D8F82C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Methane emission detection and mitigation</header> <subsection id="HEE38A1E23C354B6A88529F2B9EF6DA6A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subtitle F of title IX of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16291">42 U.S.C. 16291 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H7142F5E136774CCFBEABD39D99D8F588" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF047E6F393694FEB9B96B66DB0235A6A"><enum>969E.</enum><header>Methane leak detection and mitigation</header> 
<subsection id="H139D63E144904A6097614FD8ACB236D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header> 
<paragraph id="H932C06B835F64B5CA67584D397C97079"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Secretary of Commerce, and the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies, shall carry out a program of methane emissions detection and mitigation research, development, and demonstration for technologies and methods that significantly detect, quantify, and mitigate methane emissions. In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H00E7FF65C4694F9585D2BA56CFEC9ADF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enter into cooperative agreements with State or local governments, institutions of higher education, or for-profit entities to provide technical assistance to—</text> 
<clause id="H3B468D802EB74FFD9A1E7C482A9C0A2B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>prevent or respond to methane releases, including prediction, detection, mitigation, quantification, and identification of leaks, vents, and other outflows throughout the natural gas infrastructure (including natural gas storage, pipelines, and natural gas production sites); and</text></clause> <clause id="H2362E7A434384C78BADB354449CEFF9F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>protect public health in the event of a major methane release;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAFD40F4F80B14A329593ADD728CC0F92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in coordination with representatives from private sector entities, State and local governments, and institutions of higher education, establish a publicly accessible resource for best practices in the design, construction, maintenance, performance, monitoring, and incident response for—</text> <clause id="HC49D443EE36545DDBEA1A35EFB04886D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>pipeline systems, including compressor stations;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3D93618D07BE4F9E94B632167835505A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>production wells;</text></clause> <clause id="H52BE792C77C6497291FCE42DFDE04607"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>storage facilities; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5934CCA4F59445B49BF7B5FC538BCB80"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>other vulnerable infrastructure;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBF8B3EC34D884159ACE41773D53F4D4B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in coordination with representatives from private sector entities, State and local governments, and institutions of higher education, establish a publicly accessible resource for best practices in evaluation and incorporation of emission reduction technologies, including—</text> 
<clause id="H21F990AA36C34E35BD1AE59BBB0B694F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>metrics for performance evaluation; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA5DC7BF817944F10A0D25D319078202D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">principles for selection and integration of emission reduction technologies that are best suited for the project or entity concerned;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H664C5A54FF414A2DA2F5D6B234ED281B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>support research of technologies to more accurately quantify emissions, including—</text> <clause id="HDDB45FB7FCDD461288193E3AFA8BE657"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the ability to accurately characterize and measure methane emissions through various atmospheric conditions such as wind, rain, fog, and dust;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCEB60F575E24437BA721B7278DADE0A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improvements to data analytics and machine learning platforms;</text></clause> <clause id="H0F2446D0046A471CA1F0CF929F557838"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the ability to characterize temporal patterns in emissions, such as through continuous monitoring or multitiered system practices;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H68392348AD4B414E8E892435DD69F613"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>improvements to high-resolution spectroscopic databases of methane;</text></clause> <clause id="HFE246F07155A4CF1AB6D12B458DA236C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the ability to remotely detect carbon and ethane isotopes to facilitate attribution of sources of methane emissions; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEED04C2D30094EC8872620F8215E88C2"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improvements to Lidar detection technologies;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7B875F57A3EC409D8D9170A92678232B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>identify high-risk characteristics of pipelines, wells, storage facilities, and materials, geologic risk factors, or other key factors that increase the likelihood or intensity of methane emissions leaks;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8DF630FB89A8460CB086F8E62754DF11"><enum>(F)</enum><text>identify methane mitigation methods and technologies in coal mines; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3D28C14D40354BF49FAF1DCC5AF0D5B1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>in collaboration with private sector entities and institutions of higher education, quantify and map significant geologic methane seeps and other sources of natural emissions across the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1E9836C51168412780E257BBB50E82D0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In carrying out the program under this section, the Secretary shall consider the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H6A72936FBE32492982254AEB495AACE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Historical data of methane emissions.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8197BFDB65434689839DEE0C81415CE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Public health consequences.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBCC3F4D540D64D7EBD0D95EC0DFED52E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Public safety.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2E275E8F30684A0AB0D725B6A41C7BCA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Novel materials and designs for pipelines, compressor stations, components, and wells (including casing, cement, and wellhead).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF596C67C381948FF847FC3C739F31B6D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Regional geologic traits.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H15BBD344F51147B9A871C0DD3DF09247"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Induced and natural seismicity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9AAA02D20E3641CDAE30CA2FE66418E8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Methane leak detection consortium</header> <paragraph id="H5D52792EDD43437D927FB061ECE1FB47"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall establish and operate a Methane Emissions Measurement and Mitigation Research Consortium (in this section referred to as the <quote>Consortium</quote>) for the purpose of supporting, to the maximum extent practicable, data sharing, research prioritization, and researching cooperative leak detection and repair strategies pertaining to methane emissions detection, quantification, and mitigation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2D00429F0405419594CE984DCF078B1E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The members of the Consortium shall be representatives from the National Institute of Standards and Technology, other relevant Federal agencies, National Laboratories, oil and gas operators and industry groups, vendors of methane detection and quantification technologies, institutions of higher education, community organizations, relevant nongovernmental organizations, and other entities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0AAE9EF2C5164252B1124DF336BC39C7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The Consortium shall develop and implement a multiyear plan that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA41FBEDE5E474B4984A4ECEBF5BC2D41"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifies technical goals and milestones for the Consortium; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H67D717AC427341EB9A65BADA0A8E06E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitates data sharing for the purposes of—</text> 
<clause id="H8D469F5C2AB44AC9A3023F5A80A729F8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>bettering the understanding of methane emissions from the oil and gas sector;</text></clause> <clause id="H61980AC479DF46AE936133C627AB725C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving emissions detection, measurement, and mitigation capabilities, including assessing multi-tiered atmospheric measurements; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H49EFE0AB8B494D7EB9AB1E46A781D2AF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>improving the understanding of methane quantification data analytics and machine learning platforms, including for calibration of measurements.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00BFC9E1EFF34BA9AF36FB3CDC987FE3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reporting</header> <subparagraph id="HCE5D5112421A40C7A463D538D48DF917"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall report on the Consortium’s activities to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3E67B12C061C4CAE9A2728E304A9B9F0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report summarizing the activities, findings, and progress of the program under this section. The report shall include the following:</text> <clause id="H9EC0FA83D8FA4AEC933DE8429C5347BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A review of LDAR technologies available to the oil and gas sector for the purpose of methane emissions measurement and mitigation.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC029CEBE6EBC4F4F8DC1882717D0F310"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A summary of research gaps and priorities related to methane emissions detection, measurement, and mitigation capabilities.</text></clause> <clause id="HBC1DBBF82783400A8061C0BE5CC24D90"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A description of the data sharing and cooperative activities that have been initiated pursuant to paragraph (3)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6966DA014B4045969D4AB9591EA62B1E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the report under subparagraph (B) is submitted and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report summarizing the activities, findings, and progress of the program under this section. The report shall include the following:</text> <clause id="H19E440E7687647B5BCFEDEB9BFF49EE8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An updated review of LDAR technologies available to oil and gas operators for the purpose of methane emissions measurement and mitigation.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE46AC32F1B72445FB42EC378CC05D8A3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A description of the state of methane emissions detection and measurement capabilities.</text></clause> <clause id="H5041442F02E74F5EAEA5F08D3E94CA1E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A summary of research priorities relating to methane emissions detection, measurement, and mitigation.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB56C2602582340C093C9411C191E32DD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>An update on the data sharing and cooperative activities undertaken by members of the Consortium.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA302895C847547DE9026CBF4D76382CF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Sunset; termination</header> <subparagraph id="H61CDCEE7D49C4952BB9D577CCD54D991"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may provide support to the Consortium for a period of not more than ten years, subject to the availability of appropriations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H919EF2CC28E348C0AEC3BDC0F94C4119"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Merit review</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date on which the Consortium is established, the Secretary shall conduct a review to determine whether the Consortium has achieved the technical goals and milestones identified under paragraph (3)(A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA3603AF220B5419086F0399A7AF15B01"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0AF42F628B0A45269342E3B8E71582AB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF1272DE2A13745F89AD5E0349BF1A434"><enum>(B)</enum><header>LDAR</header><text>The term <quote>LDAR</quote> means a technology, program, or activity that is intended to monitor, detect, measure, or repair methane leaks.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0BFCEAAA6A784DC3BC1595B6FD6D966B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7D7AA1F74184B8C8730B7C90776F18E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC7FDB006A60244F59742AA0479DF5DF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$36,000,000 for fiscal year 2026.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBA9BEE869C644D989B2BDA4CA2469517"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$38,000,000 for fiscal year 2027.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HED98409255714DF8AF5AECD349344C81"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$40,000,000 for fiscal year 2028.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H02B063415B9442D8BF2C718006508245"><enum>(D)</enum><text>$42,000,000 for fiscal year 2029.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE92B758FB73B4AFD9443146420617792"><enum>(E)</enum><text>$44,000,000 for fiscal year 2030.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HBB7157F69CF04AB8B326BC1AA82E6E5E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 is amended by adding at the end of the items relating to subtitle F of title IX of such Act the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HC102335E7349462691C9979C8CE5AE09" style="OLC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 969E. Methane leak detection and mitigation.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC6E34C57519A477D9E25152A004AEA7C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>National facilities for testing and intercalibration program relating to methane</header> 
<paragraph id="H58B137993E364A7BAC8F83E7392361E1" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act and subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall establish a program through the National Institute of Standards and Technology’s Center for Greenhouse Gas Measurements, Standards, and Information established pursuant to section 10222 of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/167">Public Law 117–167</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18932">42 U.S.C. 18932</external-xref>) that establishes national facilities to advance methane detection, quantification, and relevant standards and supporting methods for testing and intercalibration of methane measurements and the publication and maintenance of standards for such measurements.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCDA7448B0FDB47C48D6F145811ADEE07"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The facilities established under paragraph (1) shall facilitate detection and quantification of carbon, carbon isotopes, methane, ethane, and gases associated with such sources, provide high-resolution spectroscopic reference data advancing accuracy of remote sensing technologies, develop methods relating methane concentration observations to the associated emission fluxes, and facilitate the rapid performance testing of existing and new technologies for the measurement of methane emissions, including testing conditions with a wide range of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD47B48378C9643A284FAFC294D438C1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sizes and extents of emission sources.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3DFF09BD960145E38A3B68CC36AB86F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Geographic diversity.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA569A84FA5FB4ED793A6E3383329C018"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Temporal characteristics.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8D6078B28D4543AB9C5B0EC223BB1A45"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Diversity of atmospheric conditions, such as wind, rain, fog, clouds, and dust.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC9571B34C97E4574A7B37459320391BC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Diversity of observing platforms.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3FF1FE75A5B74CCD80630C926BF46CB3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Quantification of atmospheric emission plumes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8E5DD60186974D218FD3730B32E2BCED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Commerce shall submit to Congress a report summarizing the activities, findings, and progress of the program established under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1CC41733EB949DB8EF176CE2C888DCF" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Commerce to carry out this section the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H12CB3E04A5AC4C1DA3DB6874A91694C2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$15,000,000 for fiscal year 2026.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFF63A6737CF44571A9349D96895A9E4B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$17,000,000 for fiscal year 2027.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6D565B0F04564F0695A16832A45AC44D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$19,000,000 for fiscal year 2028.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H351833EF219D4490A2EAD7B442FE3278" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>$21,000,000 for fiscal year 2029.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H472D666FC9364862BF418DFF2EFBAE29" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>$23,000,000 for fiscal year 2030 and each fiscal year thereafter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

