<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H16F52369EBD04AD78BB0EE9AD88BC26C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4377 IH: Tribal Access to Clean Water Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4377</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250714">July 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide access to reliable, clean, and drinkable water on Tribal lands, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8CCB20A3C8B145E3893624D9A66A2EDE" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H809BF26880C5494AA9024917DE2A8E77"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tribal Access to Clean Water Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCCAC016B8DC74BDA9A92E0709D691338"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE0368A9D585D49A283BE40370BC9C944"><enum>(1)</enum><text>access to reliable, clean, and drinkable water is an essential human need and critical to the public health, well-being, educational attainment, and economic development of all communities in the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA058845E6D704CEE81748399C88DD2D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>many countries, along with the United Nations, have recognized the urgency of the need to access reliable, clean, and drinkable water by passing laws or resolutions relating to the human right to water and sanitation, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H349866CFAC92420E88FBED94D54F3246"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recognizing these water and sanitation needs exist among indigenous peoples; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4D551FD1487E40D0902038BFC9B53E35"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishing aggressive targets for achieving universal access to those basic services;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F1D70DE920749B4A49091019996E98A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the United States, access to reliable, clean, and drinkable water has long been a significant problem in many communities on Tribal lands, such that nearly half of all households on Tribal lands do not have access to reliable water sources, clean drinking water, or basic sanitation, and are significantly more likely than other households in the United States to lack indoor plumbing;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H54F37C2946864765A261BDE0F6DA320A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the first of the 5 pillars announced on February 4, 2025, by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency Lee Zeldin that will guide the work of the Environmental Protection Agency under the Powering the Great American Comeback Initiative is the principle that <quote>every American should have access to clean air, land, and water</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H01C8332762034D9FB408B579D2EE761E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the trust responsibility of the Federal Government to Indian Tribes and the Native Hawaiian Community requires the Federal Government to ensure the survival and welfare of Indian Tribes and the Native Hawaiian Community, and the failure to provide basic water service cannot be reconciled with that trust responsibility;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H78BFB46D76554D33B961DBDC6DE2300C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the public health of Indian Tribes and the Native Hawaiian Community lags behind other communities in the United States at least in part as a result of lack of public health infrastructure, including access to running water;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2C35EA83BFA54319A94D7B37B5C6FB4A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>through the bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>; 135 Stat. 429), Congress provided funding for the Indian Health Service and the Environmental Protection Agency to support the construction and repair of Tribal clean water infrastructure, but—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF007888A42C845F4AA283F259F87E4BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inadequate resources are available to Indian Tribes to assist with accessing those construction and repair funding programs and to support the operation and maintenance of water infrastructure; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF372F540EE654BB3AC153AE3EC5827E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>much of that funding is unavailable to the Native Hawaiian Community;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFEEA420BDFD84EE7B829A3F900E60E80"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">filling the gaps in funding described in paragraph (7) is necessary for efficient implementation of the historic investment in clean water infrastructure for Indian Tribes and the Native Hawaiian Community;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCB78F1179931463B85828FE53EAEB7F9"><enum>(9)</enum><text>technical assistance to Indian Tribes and Native Hawaiian organizations is necessary to ensure that Indian Tribes and the Native Hawaiian Community are able—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94D87BB10A5744BCAC81BDBFF795BBB6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to access and take advantage of the new funding described in paragraph (7);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED6746DD0FA34F1DB393AF66CD499C29"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop the managerial, financial, and regulatory framework necessary for a fully functional and self-sustaining utility; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5D14A9EE1D134B89A245CE53BEFF535E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to engage appropriate outside consultants to assist as needed;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA88466031A034841AD593F36273AD073"><enum>(10)</enum><text>advances in water technology, including treatment, sensors, and innovative pipeline materials, can assist in—</text> <subparagraph id="H208CA9CBCDA3448FA8AB92FB27AAAC0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>accelerating efforts to provide universal access to reliable, clean, and drinkable water on Tribal lands; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7291AA263F1C45FF86FBF02F52450E38"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enhancing resilience in the face of extreme weather events;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE2275908B344A94807EA24AD346A6CA"><enum>(11)</enum><text>past epidemics of communicable diseases and the threat of future such occurrences are stark reminders that access to reliable, clean, and drinkable water to support basic health is a matter of life or death for all individuals in the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB0A426014A894C42B20F4E52269931C8"><enum>(12)</enum><text>it is in the interest of the United States, and it is the policy of the United States, that all Tribal lands be provided with safe and adequate water supply systems as soon as practicable; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H071172A4778A4EBFBA9A4B2C9950F022"><enum>(13)</enum><text>both appropriate funding at the level of unmet need and a <quote>whole of government</quote> approach among all Federal agencies are essential to provide a meaningful solution to the lack of access to clean water on Tribal lands.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H6A4C8C64538C49D0968F4DB092A74CA0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H84FF58727E8E4059807B51F1A9535512"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H410098DFE4C84123BD3E88F231B36913"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Native Hawaiian community</header> <text>The term <term>Native Hawaiian Community</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Native Hawaiian community</term> in section 50.4 of title 43, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HB94129E197694EE198810A7D573E2B0D"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Native Hawaiian organization</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H75885F5DBBC54AA0A947A091607F0FEB"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Native Hawaiian organization</term> has the meaning given the term in section 6207 of the Native Hawaiian Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7517">20 U.S.C. 7517</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2BBE3222C2FF4C45A1F590B027B6E2EF"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Inclusion</header> <text>The term <term>Native Hawaiian organization</term> includes the Department of Hawaiian Home Lands (as defined in section 801 of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4221">25 U.S.C. 4221</external-xref>)).</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H0D47BE02906F46E982C2B6FD542353D7"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Technical assistance</header> <text>The term <term>technical assistance</term> means any expertise provided, whether through direct service, grant, contract, or cooperative agreement—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H737DEC8E2B6A4ECB9E2DADCF06C626C7"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to facilitate access by Indian Tribes and Native Hawaiian organizations to repair and construction funding for drinking water and sanitation facilities made available through—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6DFE737DDAFA4C19BE17B93E9E3A3A86"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>; 135 Stat. 429);</text> </clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F4727A03238494B86590C68A479AA4D"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the rural development mission area of the Department of Agriculture; or</text> </clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H87F94086CBDD40CBB4E4B252DABF6019"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other funding source, the purpose of which is to provide funding to repair and construct drinking water and sanitation facilities; and</text> </clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28C498F3C3B9482DAA21F163B0A7BC9C"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to support Indian Tribes and Native Hawaiian organizations in developing the managerial, financial, and regulatory capacity necessary to build, operate, and maintain drinking water and sanitation infrastructure on Tribal land.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC2F0839645CA494BA7C8D371A5629439"> <enum>(5)</enum> <header>Tribal land</header> <text>The term <term>Tribal land</term> has the meaning given the term in section 905(a) of division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1705">47 U.S.C. 1705(a)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> </section> 
<section id="H3C62C577D717430499E4C27CF8D8BDE6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Department of Agriculture rural development</header> 
<subsection id="HF77174A5EE1E4544801DCD8EA7EB348B" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Water and waste facility loans and grants To
          alleviate health risks</header>
 <text>Section 306C(a) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1926c">7 U.S.C. 1926c(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
        <paragraph id="HD2FE0810F99A47558867C6B72FDF0D6D" commented="no"
          display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), in the first sentence of the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>Native Hawaiian organizations (as defined in section 6207 of the Native Hawaiian Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7517">20 U.S.C. 7517</external-xref>)), including the Department of Hawaiian Home Lands (as defined in section 801 of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4221">25 U.S.C. 4221</external-xref>)),</quote> after <quote>other federally recognized Indian tribes,</quote>; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H5BE07CF9061C457BBD54370E83AC9278">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (2), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0D6472113EE042E98F89CA8F63016867"> <subparagraph id="H59D64CE3BA1A44FE9E3BFFC430CB97B8" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(C)</enum> <header>Tribal residents</header> <text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), loans and grants under paragraph (1) may also be made if the loan or grant funds will be used primarily to provide water or waste services, or both, to residents on Tribal land (as defined in section 905(a) of division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1705">47 U.S.C. 1705(a)</external-xref>)).</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HCC283D99146F47CAA6F0D5CF0EB54B12"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Extension of authority for grants and loans</header><text>In addition to the purposes for which grants and loans may be provided under sections 306C and 306D of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1926c">7 U.S.C. 1926c</external-xref>, 1926d), the Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this section as the <term>Secretary</term>) may make or insure loans to, make grants to, or enter into cooperative agreements or contracts with, eligible entities described in subsection (d) for technical assistance.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA069B6D7DFB14A37BF96829F6AEE3DE5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise available, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030—</text> 
<paragraph id="H32271505646B41AF8278FA58236C930B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$100,000,000, to remain available until expended, to make or insure loans and make grants under sections 306C and 306D of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1926c">7 U.S.C. 1926c</external-xref>, 1926d), and for the additional purposes described in subsection (b), to eligible entities described in subsection (d) to provide for the development, use, and control of water (including the extension or improvement of existing water supply systems); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC5363E0543834E899991D8BDCBBB9B85"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$30,000,000, to remain available until expended, for eligible entities described in subsection (d) to obtain or contract for technical assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8A1C3D0DD0C341D8A6A15D3C492D279A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>An entity eligible to receive a grant or an award of financial or technical assistance using amounts appropriated pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (c) or amounts otherwise available under sections 306C and 306D of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1926c">7 U.S.C. 1926c</external-xref>, 1926d)—</text> <paragraph id="HD3DAF143D8EB47D48242622C6D8A6E87"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is an Indian Tribe or a Native Hawaiian organization; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H14BAD54AD10A41A7899CFDB43563AAD8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of a grant under section 306D of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1926d">7 U.S.C. 1926d</external-xref>), includes a consortium formed pursuant to section 325 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/83">Public Law 105–83</external-xref> (111 Stat. 1597).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H827BB70ED8D84ED89B09E048F44FB097"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No matching contribution</header><text>The funds made available under subsection (c) shall not require any matching contribution otherwise required by any other provision of law (including regulations).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H73D6C50864D943A1B43E6902151C7927"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>For purposes of any loan or grant to, or cooperative agreement or contract with, an eligible entity using amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (c)—</text> <paragraph id="H278E968CA84E45C0A78FCAC8D7BC28E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the requirements under section 306C(a)(2) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1926c">7 U.S.C. 1926c(a)(2)</external-xref>) shall not apply; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2886796546148F19091ACDC3E0F1E9C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an eligible entity or the members of an eligible entity shall not be required to demonstrate an inability to finance the proposed project—</text> <subparagraph id="H6BA5BC2C388D46E5B85C228AF89958D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>from the resources of the eligible entity or members; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9D8A0E34FEF047A0AFE0797C4CB73986"><enum>(B)</enum><text>through commercial credit.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H61DFD0019B724A69BB30A4B3B18F7189" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Interagency collaboration</header><text>The Secretary shall consult with the Director of the Indian Health Service regarding agency collaboration, project prioritization, and staffing needs to ensure the amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (c) are used in the most effective manner to promote access to water and sanitation.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HCAC071B98A2F4EC4BE34CD254FA8C72C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Indian Health Service</header> 
<subsection id="HBCF1EE351B064582A6AE76913EFF9808"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of Secretary</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Indian Health Service.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H813142D7A21C47A09F77D4140EB2A5A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sanitation facilities construction program</header> <paragraph id="H0003177485834DFBA6B154DC7AB18E3B"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>For purposes of section 7(a)(1) of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to transfer the maintenance and operation of hospital and health facilities for Indians to the Public Health Service, and for other purposes</quote>, approved August 5, 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2004a">42 U.S.C. 2004a(a)(1)</external-xref>), the term <quote>Indian homes, communities, and lands</quote> shall include non-commercial community structures that are essential to the life of an Indian Tribe or to Tribal government services on Tribal land providing indispensable educational, health, or other community services, such as schools, hospitals, clinics, nursing homes, homes of Tribal employees, Tribal offices, and post offices.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD23F66B23F704DCCA02A56B28AFBF42B">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $500,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030, to remain available until expended, to carry out section 7(a)(1) of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to transfer the maintenance and operation of hospital and health facilities for Indians to the Public Health Service, and for other purposes</quote>, approved August 5, 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2004a">42 U.S.C. 2004a(a)(1)</external-xref>).</text>
        </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H454935A009CF4798AA3E24D07F890BE6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical assistance funding</header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030, to remain available until expended, for Indian Tribes to enter into contracts for—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H131DF475A1E54E2B874D157552F0B6C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">technical assistance; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H61589D6784E342B588A9750DA8331442"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">activities authorized under section 302(b)(2) of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1632">25 U.S.C. 1632(b)(2)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5C435008AE514CAA8C95E4A04FF94A12"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Operation and maintenance funding</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H199C6360A8B44BA8928DE54E90AD5EAE"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Secretary may provide financial assistance for the operation and maintenance of drinking water and sanitation facilities serving Indian Tribes that are owned and operated by an Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A315315116C4BA4A2A423B3F1E83CDD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030, to remain available until expended, for the operation and maintenance of drinking water and sanitation facilities serving Indian Tribes under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0BDFDB1B318249028007F2FDDB8D0947"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority for funding</header><text>In awarding funding for the operation and maintenance of drinking water and sanitation facilities under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall prioritize drinking water and sanitation facilities that the Secretary determines to be the most in need of assistance.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC049FDB1C02144048563C702811FA657"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Future funding</header><text>For not less than 5 fiscal years after the date on which a drinking water or sanitation facilities project described in paragraph (1) is completed, to the extent to which funds are available, the Secretary shall include the completed project as eligible for sustained funding support and guidance to ensure that—</text> <subparagraph id="HEB5479A2FC0F472AA5504920973C8045"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the investments in the drinking water or sanitation facilities in the scope of the project are adequately maintained and operated for the health and welfare of Indian Tribes served;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H76A1548241374238B569BA77035F4ACD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the infrastructure investment is protected; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE6F81174D6BE4BD8B13BD4551C4B9307"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the intended health promotion benefit is realized.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H08853D1C674A48BDA157DCA23A24CD24"><enum>6.</enum><header>Funding for Native American Affairs Technical Assistance Program of the Bureau of Reclamation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of the Interior $18,000,000 for use, in accordance with section 201 of the Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/373d">43 U.S.C. 373d</external-xref>), for the Native American Affairs Technical Assistance Program of the Bureau of Reclamation for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030, to remain available until expended.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

