<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5D91EF02BD3148588286690F10BDC701" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3328 IH: To establish an Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3328</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250513">May 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei of Nevada</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish an Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2A08AD9032E2442592AB1A6ABDD71289" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H8DFF8510BBCA4151BA55343F37D070B8"><enum>1.</enum><header>Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2651a">22 U.S.C. 2651a et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H85086816EC0D494D8F9D016B357F315D"> <section id="H56D97DEDE9A848A0865CDD6EDF6FB40C"><enum>65.</enum><header>United States Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs</header> <subsection id="HF0CD41C0B64449128B258C9B8D43C9F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is authorized within the Department of State an Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs, appointed under subsection (b).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H79062C1B902D4033905F1E9827084600"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The Ambassador shall be appointed by the President, by, and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5B3C384700E444968ECBCAA3898B08B7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Ambassador is authorized to represent the United States in matters and cases relevant to Arctic affairs and shall be responsible to the Secretary of State for all matters, programs, and related activities pertaining to the Arctic region in the conduct of foreign policy by the Department, including, as appropriate, leading the coordination of programs carried out by United States Government agencies abroad, and such other related duties as the Secretary may from time to time designate.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H2915F0D5259D4E1984D1907E7570E924"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Areas of responsibility</header><text>The Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs is authorized to maintain continuous observation and coordination of all matters indicated by the Secretary of State, including those pertaining to energy, environment, trade, and infrastructure development and maintenance, and, in consultation with the heads of other relevant departments and agencies, those pertaining to law enforcement and political-military affairs in the conduct of foreign policy in the Arctic, including programs carried out by other United States Government agencies when such programs pertain to the following matters, to the extent directed by the Secretary of State:</text> <paragraph id="H93921BE135C24492B3D942C9471F097B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>National security.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3CB9F15A616241EF89791A5B289C8A97">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Strengthening cooperation among Arctic countries.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8AAE1A4E8AE34DD1BBF76B855C162C89"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The promotion of responsible natural resource management and economic development.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9622EE97C9E8491D9DB4353F3A962D09"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Protecting the Arctic environment and conserving its biological resources.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE87DA69F894341D992EDDDD188DC7B9E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Arctic indigenous peoples, including by involving them in decisions that affect them.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1CC0DA9C573C4C7CBFF7D074BCA1E0A6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Scientific monitoring and research.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD77B9F7FCEAD47289A7D0C050F3F4DAC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional duties</header><text>In addition to the duties and responsibilities specified in subsections (c) and (d), the Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs shall also carry out such other relevant duties as the Secretary may assign.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H642BD5D5D06D4906B3741427205B4B31"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H4B42FC81A12D404FA268553331725B01"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Arctic region</header><text>The term <term>Arctic region</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H266A6F8F8FEC46829EB3ED14EAD66357"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the geographic region north of the 66.56083 parallel latitude north of the equator;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE885F90F95847EE8126512AB7516D1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all the United States territory north and west of the boundary formed by the Porcupine, Yukon, and Kuskokwim Rivers;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB4390A3538E2490C9FC7F1B098E1619A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>all contiguous seas, including the Arctic Ocean and the Beaufort, Bering, and Chukchi Seas; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3C53B11F7D194F2E8596FF0552E4479D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Aleutian Chain.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H79E36FBE8FFC43CD9458573D0F7BDDA6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Arctic countries</header><text>The term <term>Arctic countries</term> means the permanent members of the Arctic Council, namely the United States, Canada, Denmark, Iceland, Norway, Sweden, Finland, and Russia.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

