<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFB77D26028194FDAB49BA8A8888B913A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2797 IH: House Expansion Commission Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2797</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a commission to study and develop proposals for expanding the House of Representatives, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF3BF0DFDCAF34178AE1C1981B6D08C42" style="OLC"><section id="H149257204EC44A25BD12789D6C7C622B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>House Expansion Commission Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H1B92DF21A2484CA7942215DCE9BC89F4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H13BBA6B372E44A668B366F54543DB55B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For nearly a century, the number of members of the House of Representatives has been set at the 1929 cap of 435 members.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF3FECCC048E44118B6DCC28B89D6593"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of constituents represented by each member of the House of Representatives has dramatically increased since the number of members of the House of Representatives was arbitrarily capped in 1929.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BF6F1CCEA2447A79E5F065505AFEB6D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The 1929 cap on the number of members of the House of Representatives was instituted when the United States population was 123 million. Since then, the United States population has tripled to about 346 million which means the average congressional district now represents nearly 800,000 constituents, according to data from the Bureau of the Census.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89CB71BCE82A47A48D7C574FEA4C8D5C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>With current population growth estimates, the average congressional district could have approximately 829,000 constituents by 2050.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CEC581338F84EBA9B43E5E2E572FABC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A growing movement in Congress, and in think tanks, seeks to increase the number of members of the House of Representatives to increase public access to members, improve diversity, and enhance Member ability to serve their constituents.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE865E5FE2214F888A39289406CE325C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Representative Earl Blumenauer (D-Ore.) introduced House bill 622, the Restoring Equal and Accountable Legislators in the House Act, in the One Hundred Eighteenth Congress, which would add 150 seats to the House of Representatives, increasing it to 585 members.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H3F32FEE43B63434796A0F30391E44DF9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is established a commission to be known as the <quote>U.S. House of Representatives Expansion Commission</quote> (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>). </text></section><section id="H48DA554A4A32448588184A8AEE87EE3C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duties of commission</header><subsection id="HDA4EE991EC024B5A9078F111EE1C90B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall study—</text><paragraph id="H8BD160F2AA974C2AB6039ABBB56206D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the current size of the membership of the House of Representatives considering—</text><subparagraph id="HD8F913247FE74933B1F62340CC449C4B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the correlation between the current size of the House and fair representation and efficacy; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC27EE6F3B823441AB919A10727B25AC4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether an expanded House of Representatives can better serve Congress’ core Article 1 function; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FD1A90FF08344D98385E9AF0EFCF1C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the option of a one-time expansion compared to the feasibility of recurring expansions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48564E256C7B468CA35E61137942FBF6"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> the so called <quote>Cube Root Law</quote>, <quote>Wyoming Rule</quote>, and other relevant methods to increase the size of the House of Representatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F08CCA2D07141D6A68CD5E7DC614263" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the cost implications and practical challenges to the House of Representatives associated with expanding the number of members of the House of Representatives including the logistics for—</text><subparagraph id="H6BF72984946C4D45B21FF970108EBE93" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>offices and meeting spaces;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H842C0CACB760418AA81C3C21F892EF46" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>congressional support entities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C87D704CD5C42FC8062E35A0D0174C3" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>hiring congressional staff;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H860F8B1AAEA144F68A9F5B530BEA4BCE" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>voting by members of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1504FA87E5134F6898254E2B06EE39C5" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>House administration offices; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1217E97823449D48A616106A972A586" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>funding;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7AC2327BF052472EA6A7B294E8D9FEDD"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how countries with similar legislative structures expanded their legislative bodies and the outcomes of such expansions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B2E3FF60C874FCA9BDC3EE76245B545"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the historical context of the last time the number of members of the House of Representatives was changed and key motivations behind the amendments made by the Act entitled <quote>An Act to provide for the fifteenth and subsequent decennial census and to provide for apportionment of Representatives in Congress</quote>, approved June 18, 1929 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/2a">2 U.S.C. 2a</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98C8396C01C749EF888D695629A63B5E" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>whether an expanded House of Representatives can better exercise the powers vested in Article I of the Constitution;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H110BE060ED1040799FA0964F5889C2DC" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how expanding the number of members of the House of Representatives may affect district size variance across States and impact underrepresented constituencies; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D5D46F1F87D42F4869B4D3F1AEE333C"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the potential effects of an expanded House of Representative on the ability of the House to enact laws.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H18B7DE1C663E45EE87C863A6A5DC2F1D" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the study under subsection (a), the Commission shall consult with the Architect of the Capitol, the Administrator of General Services, the Sergeant at Arms of the House of Representatives, the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, the Clerk of the House of Representatives, and such other persons as the Commission considers appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7AADE34FB7D245A789F4F80159B1BA15" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report and proposals</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the first meeting of the Commission, the Commission shall submit to the President and to the Congress a report of the study of the Commission, and shall include in the report proposals based on such study for—</text><paragraph id="H3816F3C1DA504EBC85514122287398EA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expanding the size of the membership of the House of Representatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB15F277D44E4FA38B28081E53D41857" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>potential ways to expand the House of Representatives to bolster the key role of the House of Representatives in representing the American people in Congress; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA20A9A3F2DD41C2BB3BEFE5404216BC" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>solutions to any identified challenges that may arise from such expansion.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5346B69C4F454233883E5864D5647771"><enum>5.</enum><header>Membership</header><subsection id="H52C2E0B8F8E84B39AEDF84D4DA926F43"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Number and appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall be composed of 13 members who are not Members of Congress at the time of appointment, and who shall be appointed not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, as follows:</text><paragraph id="H9954A06032024D1A815EB6504AB246A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>5 members appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78487E082C874C218876D830BB6D6376"><enum>(2)</enum><text>5 members appointed by the minority leader of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24A60A8A0A1D4135876575BCA2328FAC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>1 individual, appointed by the majority leader of the Senate, who previously served in the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B84404FD18F4484BD5F5FEF447B4F09"><enum>(4)</enum><text>1 individual, appointed by the minority leader of the Senate, who previously served in the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98963FC6D47E4B11BFB55034F56048FD" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>1 member appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the minority leader of the House of Representatives to serve as Chairperson of the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1D6953B0C9A34D53946DB9D4A16DA2BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Terms</header><paragraph id="H33401697227D422B99668634267C872D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member shall be appointed for the life of the Commission. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FDD3C5D9A0B445D88D347E5474EFD11"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A vacancy in the Commission shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCFC317C6C9746E7B642E1E03AFBD7C0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In making appointments under this section, the appointing authorities shall seek to appoint individuals who are particularly qualified to perform the functions of the Commission, by reason of either practical experience or academic expertise in politics, government, mathematics, or statistics.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H696787FF5DA54F70B5F388D08ADE1052" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Basic pay</header><paragraph id="H6B408E349E85476CB315BDD9E4008D70" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rates of pay</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), Members shall serve without pay. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2F9E44B36704F4A83197F24CE19DDB9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>Each member shall receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with applicable provisions under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B005F6BA2D94001969B32AA5ED1A131"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>7 members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number may hold hearings.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD241DEE20A5B407285D0324EF4828E1F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Commission shall meet at the call of the Chairperson or a majority of its members.</text></subsection></section><section id="H038BDCD917944E208796A017F3020881"><enum>6.</enum><header>Personnel of Commission</header><subsection id="HBAFC705C10604D7C964EE7C20032B90F" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The Commission shall have a Director who shall be appointed by a majority vote of the Commission. To the extent or in the amounts provided in advance in appropriation Acts, the Director shall be paid at a rate not to exceed the rate of basic pay for level IV of the Executive Schedule.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5AE8AA09416E4AA58DAE1A5057309F54" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Staff</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director, with the approval of the Commission, and the Commission may appoint such personnel as may be necessary to enable the Commission to carry out its duties, without regard to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service, and without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates, except that no rate of pay fixed under this subsection may exceed—</text><paragraph id="HDC222F4F36C7417D8F5AFF902DB345F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the equivalent of that payable to a person occupying a position at level IV of the Executive Schedule, in the case of an employee appointed by the Director; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BA2D07643A948E9B50E8348A3B77C3C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the equivalent of that payable to a person occupying a position at level V of the Executive Schedule, in the case of an employee appointed by the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA8159D08E95A406B8506C720C7876ED0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Experts and consultants</header><text>With the approval of the Commission, the Director may procure temporary and intermittent services under section 3109(b) of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1F5B19D6A79949479A5051E34ED81B55"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Detail of government employees</header><text>Upon the request of the Commission, the head of any Federal agency may detail, without reimbursement, any of the personnel of such agency to the Commission to assist in carrying out the duties of the Commission. Any such detail shall not interrupt or otherwise affect the civil service status or privileges of the personnel.</text></subsection></section><section id="H24B53E4DAAE344D2813E80CEC0D560FA"><enum>7.</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><subsection id="H1730A8642C7C4D64B1D723FB33D13F4F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Hearings and sessions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may, for the purpose of carrying out this Act, hold hearings, sit and act at times and places, take testimony, and receive evidence as the Commission considers appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H801D48F0DD014D4DB334636D4553D422" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Powers of members and groups of members</header><text>Any member or group of members may, if authorized by the Commission, take any action which the Commission is authorized to take by this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC6381E93F6C640B0BD7868E9B202806C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Obtaining official data</header><text>The Commission may secure directly from any Federal agency information necessary to enable it to carry out its duties, if the information may be disclosed under section 552 of title 5, United States Code. Upon request of the Chairperson of the Commission, the head of such agency shall furnish such information to the Commission. </text></subsection><subsection id="H6A52D0CC0FEA4C279EF61FAFA48C3C72"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administrative support services</header><text>Upon the request of the Commission, the Administrator of General Services shall provide to the Commission, on a reimbursable basis, the administrative support services necessary for the Commission to carry out its responsibilities under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF9329D8580754C0A8791B066E9B3D3FD" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Volunteer services</header><text>Notwithstanding 1342 of title 31, United States Code, the Commission may accept and use voluntary and uncompensated services as the Commission determines necessary.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDE0C9E1556054F4ABB873445A781FBB2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Postal service</header><text>The Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as departments and agencies of the United States. </text></subsection><subsection id="HFA27300A0D4348EB91C048FDF698D490" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Contract authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may enter into contracts for the acquisition of administrative supplies and equipment for use by the Commission, to the extent that funds are available for such purpose. </text></subsection></section><section id="H97929C68766848C7B9CFF5D6160014D2"><enum>8.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission shall terminate 90 days after submitting the report under section 4(c).</text></section><section id="H317713F47A144B4C97AD637B544256B9"><enum>9.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

