<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3EAF57DFC46E41D8A3F07FF48E816712" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3584 IH: Stratton Ridge Air Force Memorial Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3584</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250523">May 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to relocate a memorial honoring the 9 Air Force crew members who lost their lives in an airplane crash in the Cherokee and Nantahala National Forests during a training mission on August 31, 1982, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD1BD0C9FDA8A4867B0AF1B18AD45A614" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HEEF81755E901419DB7B07A3C8A1ABE73" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stratton Ridge Air Force Memorial Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H88F1D9610FBF4FD0B2BA6C6E53F94479" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Relocation of memorial honoring the 9 Air Force crew members who lost their lives in an airplane crash during a training mission on August 31, 1982</header> <subsection id="H51507EC0720946E2B21C3A6EE8924092"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With the consent of the owner of the private land adjacent to the Cherohala Skyway in the State of North Carolina on which there is located a memorial honoring the 9 members of the Air Force crew of the C–141B transport plane that crashed during a training mission over the Cherokee and Nantahala National Forests on August 31, 1982 (referred to in this section as the <quote>memorial</quote>), and subject to subsections (b) through (e), the Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) may authorize, by special use authorization, the installation, and any maintenance associated with the installation, of the memorial at an appropriate site at the Stratton Ridge rest area located at mile marker 2 on the Cherohala Skyway in Graham County, North Carolina, in the Nantahala National Forest.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8A4EB312B18C4CDB80F8AF8ACDC4B86B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Site approval</header><text>The site at which the memorial is installed under subsection (a) is subject to approval by the Secretary, in concurrence with—</text> <paragraph id="H8F6F74FE8A1A418F8D12584C55AD0247"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the North Carolina Department of Transportation; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H30C80031F8B34BD2B32C17AA721ACD4C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the site is located adjacent to a Federal-aid highway, the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4281F795FCF24FC1833EDA9CC877F8A1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>No Federal funds may be used to relocate, install, or maintain the memorial under subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE8F3BC5F249E4ECAA6DD06D270F25110"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Costs</header><text>The individual or entity requesting the installation of the memorial on National Forest System land under subsection (a) shall be responsible for the costs associated with the use of National Forest System land for the memorial, including the costs of—</text> <paragraph id="H69D32B1EE5E84C58819BA04C34501161"><enum>(1)</enum><text>processing the application for the relocation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H611D4491F04D48508F3D42FF3EC5734B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>issuing a special use authorization for the memorial, including the costs associated with any related environmental analysis; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H16010DC973664713B9427F5997786BC5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>relocating, installing, and maintaining the memorial.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3A9D9E5570FE4A71BF43AE8BEFF98644"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text>The special use authorization for the installation of the memorial under subsection (a) may include any terms and conditions that are determined to be appropriate by the Secretary, including a provision preventing any enlargement or expansion of the memorial.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill> 

