<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H350DB5C689234D5B99CEBD9BE829DEDD" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 656 IH: Condemning the tragic act of gun violence on July 28, 2025, in New York City that led to one of the deadliest mass shootings in the city’s history, and calling for stronger, comprehensive Federal action to prevent gun violence nationwide.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 656</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250815">August 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning the tragic act of gun violence on July 28, 2025, in New York City that led to one of the deadliest mass shootings in the city’s history, and calling for stronger, comprehensive Federal action to prevent gun violence nationwide.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on July 28, 2025, a gunman with a history of mental illness opened fire inside a New York City office building located in Midtown Manhattan, killing 4 individuals, including 1 New York Police Department (NYPD) officer, and injuring several others, before taking his own life;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the shooting marks the deadliest mass shooting in New York City in 25 years;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the victims included NYPD officer Didarul Islam, leaving behind his pregnant wife and 2 young children; Aland Etienne, an on-duty security officer and union member; Wesley LePatner, an executive at Blackstone and community leader; and Julia Hyman, a young associate at a real estate firm in the building;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the shooter used a military-style semiautomatic rifle that would be unlawful to possess under New York’s assault weapons ban but was assembled legally in Nevada, a State with weaker gun laws and regulations;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the shooter purchased and used large-capacity ammunition magazines that are unlawful to possess in New York but were legally available in Nevada;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the shooter traveled across State lines from Nevada to New York with the weapon, as well as a handgun and additional ammunition, for the purpose of executing this senseless mass shooting;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the patchwork of State gun laws in the United States undermines public safety and the will of the people in States with strong gun safety laws, such as New York, who remain at the mercy of the weakest gun laws in the country;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the overwhelming percentage (78 percent) of guns recovered and traced from crime scenes in New York over the last 10 years come from out of State;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Congress has the power and responsibility to enact commonsense Federal gun safety legislation to uniformly address America’s gun violence epidemic;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Federal laws requiring universal background checks, banning weapons of war, and prohibiting gun ownership for those who are an extreme risk (<quote>red flag laws</quote>) could have prevented this mass shooting; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas a majority of Americans support commonsense gun safety measures and recognize the urgent need to reduce gun violence without infringing on the Supreme Court’s interpretation of the Second Amendment: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H27C5AC5D41D44232B3E41D2083A510DA"> 
<section id="H1AB3C320D48A4B149B04C4FEB3D5EB16" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HB3478471268E41A79EB1764E73500C1E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns the senseless act of gun violence that occurred in New York City on July 28, 2025;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H34BD51A0E62145ACAAE045FDD30AB40C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the lives of the 4 victims and extends its deepest condolences to their families and loved ones;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFFA942AF664B482A9D47CB291B2FD8B2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the bravery of New York Police Department officer Didarul Islam, security officer Aland Etienne, and all first responders who risked their lives to protect others;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0B809DA886CB41E18AF61C4D831AC99D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>acknowledges that States with strong gun laws are endangered by States with weak gun laws, and that the trafficking of firearms across State lines puts the safety of all Americans at risk; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD43D7C71892E4B07B710ADFA263147AF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>acknowledges that Congress has a duty to pass comprehensive Federal gun safety legislation in order to prevent future tragedies and address the epidemic of gun violence in the country.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

