<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9988A0885E454EF4B204BAB972452455" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5247 IH: To provide for the International Security Affairs authorities of the Department of State.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5247</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the International Security Affairs authorities of the Department of State.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB64136192D7A4AA680E2729A69D9CF07" style="OLC"> 
<title id="H7FF941280E784BBBB26AA31F525F852F"><enum>IV</enum><header>International Security Affairs</header> 
<section id="H854461A361A64ECF97E9303819047933"><enum>401.</enum><header>Under Secretary for International Security Affairs</header> 
<subsection id="HFF048EF0B22C4521B22145971F7FD050"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There shall be in the Department an Under Secretary for International Security Affairs who shall be responsible to the Secretary for matters pertaining to international security policy and assistance, arms control, nonproliferation, disarmament, nuclear weapons policy, international counterterrorism, transnational organized crime, international narcotics control, emerging threats, political-military affairs, and such other related duties as the Secretary may from time to time designate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H48721FF2D3BB4CD1863B3799F7F0CFAB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>In addition to the responsibilities described under subsection (a), the Under Secretary of State for International Security Affairs shall maintain continuous observation and coordination of all matters pertaining to international security in the conduct of foreign policy, including, as appropriate, the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC3DAD2BFE5B14B6C8490876857DB4FCF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Developing policies for consideration by the Secretary and Deputy Secretary related to international security policy, including, as appropriate—</text> <subparagraph id="HB8B02C0151AC452FA424FABFB8B1008E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the areas of nonproliferation, arms control, strategic export controls, regional security and defense relations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA65F8771ADD44F9F997C74771722335D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>United States military-related activities with foreign policy implications; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H385462E312A54815A8C356C5201CFCFA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>arms transfers, security assistance, international counterterrorism, transnational organized crime, international narcotics controls, and other related matters.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC6E5375BED9D43719F357D9B2F8CBF10"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Leading engagements with other agencies of the United States Government and in bilateral and multilateral engagements related to such matters as described in this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1DABDC991C284B469268C0E0568C585D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Providing guidance to Department personnel in the United States and overseas who conduct or implement policies, programs, and activities related to matters described in this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC257FDB85FDA4EC6B8BEBAC5FED46EDB"><enum>402.</enum><header>Office to monitor and combat trafficking</header> 
<subsection id="HE4967327639543FFA00A6E4633137D20"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> 
<paragraph id="HF322D87F29AC48B28F8D03F57C6B1463"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish within the Department an Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking, which shall provide assistance to the Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking and shall report directly to the Under Secretary for International Security Affairs for matters relating to day-to-day administration and coordination of activities and programs. Any such Office shall be headed by a Director, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, with the rank of Ambassador-at-Large, and shall have two deputy directors. The Director shall report to the Secretary and shall have the primary responsibility for assisting the Secretary in carrying out the purposes of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7101">22 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>) and may have additional responsibilities as determined by the Secretary. The Director shall consult with nongovernmental organizations and multilateral organizations, and with trafficking victims or other affected persons. The Director shall have the authority to take evidence in public hearings or by other means.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H13782E641DA54A64AAC5A9A608317973"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Staff</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The heads of each of the Federal departments and agencies represented on the Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking are authorized to provide staff to the Office on a non-reimbursable basis.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEFCC10244232400283735E184863B015"><enum>(b)</enum><header>United States assistance</header><text>The Director shall additionally be responsible for—</text> <paragraph id="H2C60FE45C1C94EB3BBDAE640A8B2C4F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all policy, funding, and programming decisions regarding funds made available for trafficking in persons programs that are centrally controlled by the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEF23B9EB931B42D09F71600D90E1AD16">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>coordinating any trafficking in persons programs of the Department or of other Federal Government agencies;</text>
          </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6EAF091C3CBC443D9ABFA592D6EE21C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compiling, drafting, and coordinating the production and issuing of the annual report;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC42B72962AE41F3917D112BA39CBB99"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ensuring, in coordination with other relevant officials, that all Department staff have completed annual anti-trafficking training pursuant to section 107(c)(4) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7105">22 U.S.C. 7105(c)(4)</external-xref>) and section 708(a) of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/4028">22 U.S.C. 4028(a)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9FF7B7FC7CAE484BA4BA9A9CE33382A9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encouraging the inclusion in country and regional planning of a counter-trafficking in persons analytic component to guide foreign assistance program design and implementation and to inform diplomatic engagement pursuant to section 105(f) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7103">22 U.S.C. 7103(f)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6C875C0CC674075840FFF9BD66F169C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>organizing and coordinating the Trafficking in Persons Report Heroes Award.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
<section id="H8A467FD3FB844B8594E62BFAE866B2C4"><enum>403.</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations for International Security Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Of the funds authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of State under section 141, the Under Secretary for International Security Affairs shall receive the funds necessary to fulfill the Under Secretary’s responsibilities for fiscal years 2026 and 2027.</text></section> <section id="H5A53BF4919054D31A15F513C3F1805C0"><enum>404.</enum><header>Assistant Secretary for Political-Military Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be in the Department an Assistant Secretary for Political-Military Affairs who shall be responsible to the Under Secretary for International Security Affairs for matters pertaining to coordination with the Department of Defense or foreign militaries, and such other related duties as the Secretary may from time to time designate.</text></section> 
<section id="H1B265175CA4A41D48BFFD83FF8D03554"><enum>405.</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations for Political-Military Affairs</header> 
<subsection id="H4448BA7010AF44C6AA86745FDAEA2061"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Administration of accounts</header><text>The Assistant Secretary for Political-Military Affairs shall direct, oversee, and otherwise exercise responsibility of funds made available for—</text> <paragraph id="H051B72CCB4A445F2AC19961D4F7E9529"><enum>(1)</enum><text>international military education and training; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H92F486F19FE14F06A4950B26B4E89BF4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the national security engagement account.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H715FC860A4B448D29C1E527BCA17F7EA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds authorized to be appropriated to the Under Secretary for International Security Affairs under section 403, the Assistant Secretary for Political-Military Affairs shall receive the funds necessary to fulfill Bureau functions and the Assistant Secretary’s responsibilities for fiscal years 2026 and 2027.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H769A093748D3461BB83A4BBEC645FACF"><enum>406.</enum><header>Assistant Secretary for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs</header> 
<subsection id="HF5368C07D0D149389539976F4F81DDFB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is authorized to be in the Department an Assistant Secretary for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs who shall be responsible to the Under Secretary for International Security Affairs for matters pertaining to international narcotics, anti-crime, and law enforcement affairs, and such other related duties as the Secretary may from time to time designate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAB53631FE2AB4DCBAED3E75802E593D6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>In addition to the responsibilities described under subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs shall maintain continuous observation and coordination of all matters pertaining to narcotics, transnational crime, and law enforcement affairs in the conduct of foreign policy by the Department, including, as appropriate, the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2F41C5C7A1E442978DBF66E2DD6816F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Leading the coordination of programs carried out by United States Government agencies abroad.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87E98C4FFB4E4C9689AAA4A8C9ECB691"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Overall supervision of policy and resources of international narcotics, anti-crime, and law enforcement activities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H759596C7C3864632A86C57A9B604FDC9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Combating international narcotics production and trafficking, including by carrying out relevant delegated responsibilities under chapter 8 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2249B5CD761C4B9E8370464BC35E2BD4"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strengthening foreign justice systems, including judicial and prosecutorial capacity, appeals systems, law enforcement agencies, prison systems, and the sharing of recovered assets, for the purposes of investigating, prosecuting, and litigating criminal cases related to illicit narcotics production and trafficking and transnational organized crime.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7FAE0A7AD228414A9C4E9EF61BBCC856"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Training and equipping foreign police, border control, other government officials, and other civilian law enforcement authorities for anti-crime purposes, including ensuring that no foreign security unit or member of such unit shall receive such assistance from the United States Government absent appropriate vetting.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H49C195F212254B62827BF645DEE4D6B4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Combatting all forms of transnational organized crime, including human trafficking, illicit trafficking in arms and cultural property, migrant smuggling and facilitating illegal immigration for profit, corruption, money laundering, the illicit smuggling of bulk cash, other forms of illicit finance, the licit use of financial systems for malign purposes, and other new and emerging forms of crime.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H50066C6E19C348889F123862EFCCAADF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Identifying and responding to global corruption in accordance with United States national security interests and foreign policy objectives, including strengthening the capacity of foreign government institutions responsible for addressing financial crimes.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB06A5BF9777B4973A4E5734C067B34A2"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Coordinating with the Office of National Drug Control Policy to ensure lessons learned from other Federal departments and agencies are available to the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs of the Department.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H02A40C8FC28149359F121C6FEBFB984B"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Developing standard requirements for monitoring and evaluation of Bureau programs, including metrics for success that do not rely solely on the amounts of illegal drugs that are produced or seized.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1DF91D2AE49948B8BB38DAAFD8A9A2C7"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Carrying out timely and substantive consultation with chiefs of mission and, as appropriate, the heads of other United States Government agencies to ensure effective coordination of all international narcotics and law enforcement programs carried out overseas by the Department and such other agencies.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC8F646F09D3E40B7A6AB7D499AA799B9"><enum>(11)</enum><text>In coordination with the Under Secretary for International Security Affairs, annually certifying in writing to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives that United States enforcement personnel posted abroad whose activities are funded to any extent by the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs are complying with section 207 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3927">22 U.S.C. 3927</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9EB0CDA5FA0742D3A939D60A4AA88A07"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Performing such other duties as the Under Secretary for International Security Affairs may from time to time designate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H0583703BD53545FE8F54662FA568E8AF"><enum>407.</enum><header>Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs</header> 
<subsection id="HE78B94E6DDC04B259D7C24C6AF1FD3C6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs, which shall perform such functions related to international narcotics, anti-crime, law enforcement, and transnational crime as the Under Secretary for International Security Affairs may prescribe.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9A1ABCC124B243079B65A2D9ACA35E16"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assistant secretary</header><text>The Assistant Secretary for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs shall be the head of the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H7C0E707EF33B4D5FB6B301C32D52DB98"><enum>408.</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs</header> 
<subsection id="HD946CD4153C34DB49F03F3E57F573830"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Administration of accounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs shall direct, oversee, and otherwise exercise responsibility of funds made available for international narcotics control and law enforcement.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE1953491CC00462B9C0D4FDC8C443711"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds authorized to be appropriated to the Under Secretary for International Security Affairs under section 403, the Assistant Secretary for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs shall receive the funds necessary to fulfill Bureau functions and the Assistant Secretary’s responsibilities for fiscal years 2026 and 2027.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H9C097AB72CE643E28166891542283F1B"><enum>409.</enum><header>Bureau of Arms Control and Nonproliferation</header> 
<subsection id="HFEAD682CA9254379B0B1F4C068E9A72E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a Bureau of Arms Control and Nonproliferation, which shall perform such functions related to verification and compliance with international arms control, nonproliferation, disarmament agreements or commitments, and other related international security policy issues, as the Under Secretary for International Security Affairs may prescribe.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE9C2DD98ED754DEC8C592AF24BE7279B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assistant secretary</header><text>The Assistant Secretary for Arms Control and Nonproliferation shall be the head of the Bureau of Arms Control and Nonproliferation.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H94BE7ABF28774C88BBC72E82A0070D19"><enum>410.</enum><header>Assistant Secretary for Counterterrorism</header> 
<subsection id="H752CE46DD08D4ECA8A93532A23AA0141"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is authorized to be in the Department an Assistant Secretary for Counterterrorism who shall be responsible to the Under Secretary for International Security Affairs for matters pertaining to international counterterrorism activities and programs and such other related duties as the Secretary may from time to time designate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7ED076E4B8CA439491D70C8DE70117D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>In addition to the responsibilities described under subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary for Counterterrorism shall maintain continuous observation and coordination of all matters pertaining to international counterterrorism matters in the conduct of foreign policy, including, as appropriate, the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE115BBBD546B4D43A31CAB4DD70E11A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Overall supervision, including policy oversight of resources, of international counterterrorism activities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC28B613767D649B68307AC6C6DC8933E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Serving as the principal policy advisor to the Secretary regarding international counterterrorism matters.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C3D65CEC98848AEAFDD83B9107EF46E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Representing the Secretary on international counterterrorism issues in international and interagency meetings, as appropriate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E4B9C7FD21D4EC3AE67745B0633AB21"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Countering, in conjunction with other relevant bureaus of the Department and other Federal departments and agencies, all forms of international terrorism.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H677533D46CE348B3B66A920FAAE5A245"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Leading United States foreign policy for counterterrorism efforts, including cooperation, coordination, and assistance that advances the interest, safety, and economic prosperity of the American people.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D061D72932044538CF049F010CF5DF1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Performing such other duties as the Under Secretary for International Security Affairs may from time to time designate.</text></paragraph> </subsection></section> 
<section id="H887552000EEB4B2F96E9AEDEE5D2059E"><enum>411.</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations for Counterterrorism</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Of the funds authorized to be appropriated to the Under Secretary for International Security Affairs under section 403, the Assistant Secretary for Counterterrorism shall receive the funds necessary to fulfill Bureau functions and the Assistant Secretary’s responsibilities for fiscal years 2026 and 2027.</text></section> <section id="H569DFF9D77DC4B3981FBFFA1F4339524"><enum>412.</enum><header>Assistant Secretary for Emerging Threats</header> <subsection id="H61403D91E11D4063A5939A45C53FA425"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is authorized to be in the Department an Assistant Secretary for Emerging Threats who shall be responsible to the Under Secretary for International Security Affairs for matters pertaining to emerging security threats and such other related duties as the Secretary may from time to time designate.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H344B1A250C664927827BAE87AF9C1A1A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>In addition to the responsibilities described under subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary for Emerging Threats shall maintain continuous observation and coordination of all matters pertaining to emerging security threats in the conduct of foreign policy, including, as appropriate, the following:</text> <paragraph id="H417FA954225E4746B543D3DE694C575A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Serving as the principal emerging security threats official within the senior management of the Department and as the advisor to the Secretary for emerging security threats, including with respect to lethal autonomous systems, engineered bioweapons, and emerging uses of artificial intelligence, biotechnology, quantum information science, and emerging foundational technologies.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H09ECFD09B00B459980512CE28ABBA788"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Mitigating threats resulting from military applications of emerging technologies, including in the fields of artificial intelligence, biotechnology, and quantum information science, in support of United States foreign policy and national security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAE495933444941DF827C77780AA6BF76"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Leading engagement, in coordination with relevant executive branch agencies, on development of diplomatic policy for national security related activities and emerging threats in the polar regions, outer space, and undersea domains.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H35C7C6DECEA24A8BA3EA58198288EA99"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Leading engagement, in coordination with relevant executive branch agencies, on the development of diplomatic policy for quantum information science, including in the field of quantum cryptography, navigation and timing, spectrum, imaging, and detection; sensors and computing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H82E5B65C62E44B0D81AD2636983D33D2"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Performing such other duties as the Under Secretary for International Security Affairs may from time to time designate.</text></paragraph> </subsection></section> 
<section id="H35C0BA505ABC41409BDBF460D1257557"><enum>413.</enum><header>Bureau of Emerging Threats</header> 
<subsection id="H8194D5D2F4174822A44A0854784F991D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a Bureau of Emerging Threats, which shall perform such functions related to emerging security threats, including with respect to lethal autonomous systems, engineered bioweapons, military application of cyberspace operations, undersea and outer space domains, emerging and foundational technologies, associated security issues in polar regions, and emerging uses of artificial intelligence, biotechnology, quantum information science, as the Under Secretary for International Security Affairs may prescribe.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H63C12B09EF7D451B96E90746BFD477B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assistant secretary</header><text>The Assistant Secretary for Emerging Threats shall be the head of the Bureau of Emerging Threats.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H567F6596079144A1BC4F62A67C0763EC"><enum>414.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations for emerging threats</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Of the funds authorized to be appropriated to the Under Secretary for International Security Affairs under section 403, the Assistant Secretary for Emerging Threats shall receive the funds necessary to fulfill Bureau functions and the Assistant Secretary’s responsibilities for fiscal years 2026 and 2027.</text></section> <section id="HD4B9D39F7416475C9E74E4D9BEDCECC9"><enum>415.</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any reference in any statute, reorganization plan, Executive order, regulation, agreement, determination, or other official document or proceeding to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H18F5848E19DC4C16AC2F01F9CF9C03F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Under Secretary for Arms Control and International Security Affairs shall be deemed to refer to the Under Secretary for International Security Affairs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H24D9AC97152D4D20B3F68AC513BEE672"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Under Secretary for Security Assistance, Science, and Technology shall be deemed to refer to the Under Secretary for International Security Affairs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H16CB04F7F69348E6876C2627CB810CCB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Under Secretary for Security Assistance shall be deemed to refer to the Under Secretary for International Security;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H99F33F32B3554A37BC568517A8EF7FFF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Assistant Secretary for Arms Control, Deterrence, and Stability shall be deemed to refer to the Assistant Secretary for Arms Control and Nonproliferation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC3E7E1A9B6D64C3E840798A5091D9AF1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Assistant Secretary for Arms Control, Verification, and Stability shall be deemed to refer to the Assistant Secretary for Arms Control and Nonproliferation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H37136579C4A34A79AC7BF8275963B973"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Assistant Secretary for Verification, Compliance, and Implementation shall be deemed to refer to the Assistant Secretary for Arms Control and Nonproliferation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD7DDC135C07E41B5B2A79F7D65D02377"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Assistant Secretary for Verification and Compliance shall be deemed to refer to the Assistant Secretary for Arms Control and Nonproliferation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDCB534774B314421B393611E6A14CC82"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the Assistant Secretary for International Security and Nonproliferation shall be deemed to refer to the Assistant Secretary for Arms Control and Nonproliferation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HED339CA08C624EC3AF8E0AF837952708"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the Assistant Secretary for Nonproliferation shall be deemed to refer to the Assistant Secretary for Arms Control and Nonproliferation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD44D0910BE3141C6B3991467461F7F8F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the Assistant Secretary for Nonproliferation shall be deemed to refer to the Assistant Secretary for Arms Control and Nonproliferation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2BE06AAFE53D48D9BE14E010707C2E17">
                    <enum>(11)</enum>
 <text>the Assistant Secretary for Arms Control shall be deemed to refer to the Assistant Secretary for Arms Control and Nonproliferation;</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0670FFA4C7E3466A81DE13AE5895438C"><enum>(12)</enum><text>the Bureau for Arms Control, Deterrence, and Stability shall be deemed to refer to the Bureau for Arms Control and Nonproliferation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H793012D39AB64040B748228848BD9AE7"><enum>(13)</enum><text>the Bureau for Arms Control, Verification, and Stability shall be deemed to refer to the Bureau for Arms Control and Nonproliferation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H21FFAB6A432A46B8BA7D60E8316A9386"><enum>(14)</enum><text>the Bureau for Verification, Compliance, and Implementation shall be deemed to refer to the Bureau for Arms Control and Nonproliferation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33BF0664AE9E4C5296135CC0483528B8"><enum>(15)</enum><text>the Bureau for Verification and Compliance shall be deemed to refer to the Bureau for Arms Control and Nonproliferation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H15DE7756E2624BBAA0AB3B0E48148AF8"><enum>(16)</enum><text>the Bureau for International Security and Nonproliferation shall be deemed to refer to the Bureau for Arms Control and Nonproliferation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H42281A5ADA1246F7BB79944FC3D83267"><enum>(17)</enum><text>the Bureau for Nonproliferation shall be deemed to refer to the Bureau for Arms Control and Nonproliferation; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H71FE9E2B367044F7B13A68E53F927013"><enum>(18)</enum><text>the Bureau for Arms Control shall be deemed to refer to the Bureau for Arms Control and Nonproliferation.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H6CDC482681FD4A649CFC56B64EAC1D14"><enum>416.</enum><header>Classification to United States Code</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Office of Law Revision Counsel is directed to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H23BFC11AAD4E4992BAC97DFF1BA9F27C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>utilize sections 98–128 of title 22, United States Code, to classify the sections of this title; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H593A36D6D6C24AF0A5256F8383E66330"><enum>(2)</enum><text>maintain the legislative history, under editorial notes, of repealed law which previously occupied the corresponding sections of United States Code.</text></paragraph></section> </title> 
</legis-body></bill>

