<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FLO25253-DLD-8C-1W4"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S730 IS: African Burial Ground International Memorial Museum and Educational Center Study Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 730</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250225">February 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a study to assess the suitability and feasibility of establishing the African Burial Ground International Memorial Museum and Educational Center at the African Burial Ground National Monument, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>African Burial Ground International Memorial Museum and Educational Center Study Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id822969c7c46d4fa1bd8596fa5a4320c1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF66EB4834C6847138FD3D6119E81E94A"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Museum</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Museum</term> means the African Burial Ground International Memorial Museum and Educational Center.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf0d9fd05611b4f8d9f5764d879a4f318"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National Monument</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>National Monument</term> means the African Burial Ground National Monument in the city of New York, New York.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf60aaf14a0d34aa6a1044f1374910619"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id91c29e0def824f54a023eccdacbd1020"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of New York.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idce15c196d1764758899a953e4350f48a"><enum>3.</enum><header>African Burial Ground International Memorial Museum and Educational Center study</header><subsection id="id48a31dda9b4c4d98ba22d6eb3f781562"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><paragraph id="id5abe4cacaea74769b7376a4f8577dbae"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with State and local historic preservation officers, State and local historical societies, State and local tourism offices, and other appropriate organizations and government agencies, shall conduct a study to assess the suitability and feasibility of establishing a museum and educational center at the National Monument, to be known as the <quote>African Burial Ground International Memorial Museum and Educational Center</quote>—</text><subparagraph id="idff807bdd7666413a95d1f3346ecc27d2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to serve as a permanent living memorial and special tribute—</text><clause id="ida09d0da30cad45b18ff065daef025279"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to the enslaved who are buried at the African Burial Ground; and</text></clause><clause id="id667d3d05a2fd448c97ce4d237eab5848"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to other Africans who were enslaved in the United States and other parts of the world;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id825e1d5b4c5d4e3ab53cd6270d9866ec"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to reflect on the significance of the African Burial Ground;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc5b6c53f921342968c9c900c912e07a0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to examine the African cultural traditions brought to the United States by the enslaved;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id42361068ee04431c8baa275bf3bf4f3b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to explore in-depth the institution of slavery in the United States and other parts of the world;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3ba574576fb742149c2b69953e704a75"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to provide a space for—</text><clause id="id4af3d5f8dc594c7c857977cee5b85c17"><enum>(i)</enum><text>permanent and temporary exhibits; and</text></clause><clause id="id2d54902adb3242cf8ed03b95d6c41654"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the collection and study of artifacts and documents; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id071d8eae6e234e7eaabf08490cabf020"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to encourage collaboration between the Museum and the National Museum of African American History and Culture, other museums, historically Black colleges and universities, historical societies, educational institutions, and other appropriate entities and organizations, such as the African Burial Ground Memorial Foundation, including collaboration with respect to—</text><clause id="id1bef98f914ac4b76927f7be923ab5f6f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the development of cooperative programs and exhibitions, including through digital, electronic, and interactive technologies;</text></clause><clause id="id6b826078ec5146b48dd55c2916925e86"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the identification, management, and care of Museum collections; and</text></clause><clause id="id47e11eb688064d938e5da7f48b8c7be4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the training of Museum and National Park Service professionals and other persons concerned with heritage preservation; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id93287a61c11b408ab45d8f2d46781d0b"><enum>(G)</enum><text>in addition to any collaboration encouraged under subparagraph (F), to be associated with the National Museum of African American History and Culture, in a manner to be determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3f617fca016d47628253f645b3dd2c17"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The study conducted under paragraph (1) shall include analysis, documentation, and determinations regarding whether—</text><subparagraph id="idd52567aaee9a4a4d81a378a22da61c46"><enum>(A)</enum><text>there is an assemblage of collections to be acquired and housed in the Museum that—</text><clause id="id4bef4bbffd844d7bb6c0680db037b5ff"><enum>(i)</enum><text>represent distinctive aspects of African cultural traditions brought to the United States by the enslaved;</text></clause><clause id="id71bae27c45b44ee790117432f512ed73"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are worthy of recognition, conservation, and interpretation; </text></clause><clause id="idd5e2a2c1af7a40fa8a8bc5aa407e0868"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>are important to any identified themes of the Museum;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb0cd93a57d545bfabe35fa50facce04"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include DNA samples of well-preserved human remains that would enable researchers to trace home <quote>roots</quote> in Africa of those individuals buried at the African Burial Ground; and</text></clause><clause id="id8102ea972be440d187d9cb104a25ce8c"><enum>(v)</enum><text>are unlike any other anthropological collection in other symbolic sites;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6dadf69cabd347f7a6b4172f88018568"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Museum provides outstanding opportunities—</text><clause id="id8312e49ca685483e8e35acf60af088bd"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to understand how the international slave trade contributed to the African diaspora;</text></clause><clause id="id3b66b48c6bcf4476ae4be623ba6d30eb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to explore in-depth the institution of slavery, as practiced in other parts of the world and in urban, rural, northern, and southern parts of the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="idbf2ce5d0de43485e897251190f448b3d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to help the people of the United States understand the past and honor the history of all people in the United States;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideb18062a4b85413ea2e7adb84935b72c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>residents, business interests, State and local governments, and nonprofit organizations, such as the African Burial Ground Memorial Foundation— </text><clause id="ida40a76d24f4a4a4c9618bb24faa5a685"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are involved in the planning of the Museum;</text></clause><clause id="idcfce26fa856a4d3693f2cb4f72c62a3b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have developed a conceptual financial plan that outlines the roles of all participants in the Museum, including the Federal Government; and</text></clause><clause id="id1284ae6931dd4a9dbf6b6c33752e1221"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>have demonstrated support for the designation of the Museum;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id445b8adad5ab4e82aa2e03522625472a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior, the Administrator of the General Services Administration, or other potential management entities would be best suited to operate the Museum; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idef7b94f572f54cc1b9a17dc9c2f380bd"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the public supports the proposed location for the Museum at—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida929ac67a72f4d9982d7d907255228e1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">22 Reade Street, which is adjacent to the National Monument; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddedde238ca9e461f96eaec40b0af507c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any area within the National Monument other than the area described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id98c052c5f9024875be6784227028fd00"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date on which funds are first made available to carry out this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report that describes—</text><paragraph id="id9091985872b440488c1387172c249ad3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the results of the study under subsection (a), including a description of—</text><subparagraph id="idebef0bd25fe44916af838ad37f75ad88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the availability and cost of collections to be acquired and housed in the Museum;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8116d86ebe6e4b5abaa32e6131654102"><enum>(B)</enum><text>criteria for evaluating possible locations for the Museum in the State; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc1de27d1361b4728a0dc36fb85509537"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the costs of acquiring property for, constructing, operating, and maintaining the Museum; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb2268656bbb74e1d8f7c4fc7e42bf7da"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any conclusions and recommendations of the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

