<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC36613D3D2794C65959C1E1D670D12E0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 681 IH: To amend the Act of August 9, 1955 (commonly known as the “Long-Term Leasing Act”), to authorize leases of up to 99 years for land held in trust for the Mashpee Wampanoag Tribe and the Wampanoag Tribe of Gay Head (Aquinnah), and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 681</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250123">January 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Act of August 9, 1955 (commonly known as the <quote>Long-Term Leasing Act</quote>), to authorize leases of up to 99 years for land held in trust for the Mashpee Wampanoag Tribe and the Wampanoag Tribe of Gay Head (Aquinnah), and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1700BE6DBA2B45E7929C207ED51BEDBA" style="OLC"><section id="H61A9980E39A84FBFA4FC30A42E8CED0D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Mashpee Wampanoag Tribe and Wampanoag Tribe of Gay Head (Aquinnah) leasing authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (a) of the first section of the Act of August 9, 1955 (69 Stat. 539, chapter 615; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/415">25 U.S.C. 415(a)</external-xref>) (commonly known as the <quote>Long-Term Leasing Act</quote>), is amended, in the second sentence, by inserting <quote>, the Mashpee Wampanoag Tribe Reservation, and the Wampanoag Tribe of Gay Head (Aquinnah) Reservation</quote> after <quote>Confederated Tribes of the Chehalis Reservation</quote>.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

