<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H2931C178DCAF43398D80BEFE581F1ED0" key="H"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2072 IH: To require the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to extend the time period during which licensees are required to commence construction of certain hydropower projects.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2072</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20250311">March 11, 2025</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001322">Mr. Baumgartner</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To require the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to extend the time period during which licensees are required to commence construction of certain hydropower projects.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H4D5E439A5C52408097D0AE46558B1BF5"> 
<section id="HBB798863BF8942368EAFA350EF0316CC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Extension of time to commence construction of certain hydropower projects</header> 
<subsection id="H70B7D45199584E20A52B665D2BCB63B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of covered project</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered project</term> means a hydropower project with respect to which the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission issued a license before March 13, 2020.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H911FE666B84849BFB3743AF03631CC34"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of extension</header><text>Notwithstanding section 13 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/806">16 U.S.C. 806</external-xref>), on the request of a licensee of a covered project, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission may, after reasonable notice and for good cause shown, extend in accordance with subsection (c) the period during which the licensee is required to commence construction of the covered project for not more than an additional 6 years beyond the 8 years authorized by that section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6110FB6FC310496393D7CBD0C53CEA4E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Period of extension</header><text>An extension of time to commence construction of a covered project under subsection (b) shall—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H076E78FDDFF9456BBEA6E8E1D28EA96D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consist of not more than 3 consecutive 2-year periods;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA4121AF4C9734AFE9028F40BCEE3F69E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>begin on the date on which the final extension of the period for commencement of construction granted to the licensee under section 13 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/806">16 U.S.C. 806</external-xref>) expires; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H609A5D47EA374612985C243D3E6C6AFC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>end on the date that is not more than 6 years after the latest date to which the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission is authorized to extend the period for commencement of construction under that section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1BDFE07C38B54351B79E23CB1645A454"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reinstatement of Expired License</header><text>If the time period required under section 13 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/806">16 U.S.C. 806</external-xref>) to commence construction of a covered project expires after December 31, 2023, and before the date of enactment of this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H3A2E84708A0D4534B8DA573621A78C4E" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission may reinstate the license for the applicable project effective as of the date of expiration of the license; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8C8452D9F8F943369A974C609B1DAB90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the extension authorized under subsection (b) shall take effect on the date of that expiration.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill>

