<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0F0B1196DB5D42CCB4739D5A0D99010C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3486 IH: Stop Illegal Entry Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3486</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250519">May 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="K000405">Mr. Knott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to increase penalties for individuals who illegally enter and reenter the United States after being removed, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H368A9504030B4774AB30C10FF5D8CB86" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HADAD9D9DD16E48378C651EFC307D5A7A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Illegal Entry Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HB40FAF79F324479B9F9FE1100AFDB1D3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Commission of crimes by aliens unlawfully present in the United States</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 275 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1325">8 U.S.C. 1325</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H65F0A023F306431FA34E8678A6F244EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>2 years</quote> and inserting <quote>5 years</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBD0D3099630A400B83CF444B63FED8EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H6717F03A21994B6DB81D79F32C952D11" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H82F99E1E17444389AE7C02E9E4AF158B"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any alien—</text> 
<paragraph id="H984728EA52174C458CCA0A1B3A18E2F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>who—</text> <subparagraph id="HAA3670AA08B64E88B3E7FED3EC5F7AFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enters or attempts to enter the United States at any time or place other than as designated by immigration officers,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7E1C708890F3494AADDEA8B87ED45B69"><enum>(B)</enum><text>eludes examination or inspection by immigration officers, or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2C0B6A7EBFF74467BD9C78E7D50449B5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>attempts to enter or obtains entry to the United States by a willfully false or misleading representation or the willful concealment of a material fact, and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBE63FBCBB6314BD780AED3473023B38A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">thereafter is convicted of any crime punishable by more than 1 year of imprisonment, </text> </paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">may be fined under title 18, United States Code, and shall be imprisoned not less than 5 years and may be imprisoned for any term of years or for life.</continuation-text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="H7A740227EBE040FA81008EC8C304855E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Increased penalties for reentry of removed alien</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 276 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1326">8 U.S.C. 1326</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H95D2221A9881484B9079ADF92B4D17A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) and (d) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E3D269985C5492D97E13DB5F1507762"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsections (a) and (b) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H950FFF2198E04A5F87202E84E984A08E" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H12EE4359F2184550912DD7C8F08AF302"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsections (b) and (c), any alien who—</text> <paragraph id="H29F8913774C54A6CB29BA67DD50681C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has been denied admission, excluded, deported, removed, or has departed the United States while an order of exclusion, deportation, or removal is outstanding; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB0154591799E491A8F83DAADFAD16EF4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>thereafter enters, attempts to enter, or is at any time found in, the United States, unless—</text> <subparagraph id="H4DE579B834EA41D289FBA062DFD07248"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prior to the alien’s reembarkation at a place outside the United States or the alien’s application for admission from foreign contiguous territory, the Secretary of Homeland Security has expressly consented to such alien’s reapplying for admission; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H48827736C5BB41C498BBFB82AC2166D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to an alien previously denied admission and removed, such alien establishes that the alien was not required to obtain such advance consent under this or any prior Act,</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</continuation-text></subsection> <subsection id="H53C1350DACF54224BD89B1A82994F08E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criminal penalties for reentry of certain removed aliens</header> <paragraph id="H0C0C5A96CFDC443D97F6A55F07029B16"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the penalty under subsection (a), and except as provided in subsection (c), an alien described in subsection (a)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H421EF4043FC34508BD196019523A3A86"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who was convicted before such removal or departure of 3 or more misdemeanors involving drugs, crimes against the person, or both shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned not more than 15 years, or both;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDAA44D7F94814D71A271CE640B4F061E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who has been excluded from the United States pursuant to section 235(c) because the alien was inadmissible under section 212(a)(3)(B) or who has been removed from the United States pursuant to the provisions of title V, and who thereafter, without the permission of the Secretary of Homeland Security, enters the United States, or attempts to do so, shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, and imprisoned for a period of 10 years, which sentence shall not run concurrently with any other sentence;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H468EAE3D516548DF96D672205FD5B8E4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>who was removed from the United States pursuant to section 241(a)(4)(B) who thereafter, without the permission of the Secretary of Homeland Security, enters, attempts to enter, or is at any time found in, the United States, shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned for not more than 10 years, or both; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0FB1204E9AC14A7D8A6DB4DF3378CF35"><enum>(D)</enum><text>who has been denied admission, excluded, deported, or removed 3 or more times and thereafter enters, attempts to enter, or is at any time found in the United States, shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCE50B735FEC14FC7AD66A9010E9D6B0F" commented="no">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
                            <header>Removal defined</header>
 <text>In this subsection and in subsection (c), the term <term>removal</term> includes any agreement in which an alien stipulates to removal during (or not during) a criminal trial under either Federal or State law. </text>
                        </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H08E37FFCD00245A18A39489543F79942"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Mandatory minimum criminal penalty for reentry of certain removed aliens</header><text>Notwithstanding the penalties provided in subsections (a) and (b), an alien described in subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="H0EEC557B32D04C2A83BCE8102BEE7448"><enum>(1)</enum><text>who was convicted before such removal or departure of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA673F250566842FDA688BA3B75BDCE04"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any aggravated felony;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F6EC7FD8FCF4239BA61F8B2E6865F0B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any crime defined as a felony by the relevant jurisdiction (Federal, State, Tribal, or local) of conviction; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE355084B6A924B2A82765C2F0691D2BA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any crime punishable by more than 1 year of imprisonment; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD5C6AA0999DE44409A2D622429F8689A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>who was convicted under this section at least 2 times before such removal or departure,</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">may be fined under title 18, United States Code, and shall be imprisoned not less than 10 years and may be imprisoned for any term of years or for life.</continuation-text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H495D3459824C4FBFBAC229E7464A53AD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d), as redesignated by paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H97F0EE3980CC44BBB20DEA67037657FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 242(h)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 241(a)(4)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA68FF8BEF1EC4E93B9AEEAADA26AD815"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> and inserting <quote>Secretary of Homeland Security</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

