<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MUR25710-XPG-TC-4SF"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2743 IS: Save Our Safety-Net Hospitals Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2743</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250909">September 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to modify certain limitations on disproportionate share hospital payment adjustments under the Medicaid program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Save Our Safety-Net Hospitals Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H93CBC435789F44598929DE1B782E20C8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modifying certain limitations on disproportionate share hospital payment adjustments under the Medicaid program</header><subsection id="H4A2F2EA6B3384DBFAFF8BEBCD0669948"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1923(g) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-4">42 U.S.C. 1396r–4(g)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H05878AED4C334B5DB8EBFEB53814FB09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="HFB61C25269ED46F6B8D047419F450A8F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H8732FF9E92EB46BBA54FF7DAB2AAB9E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>(other than a hospital described in paragraph (2)(B))</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="HF1DA17AF665E49F5BDA8F8A367529F18"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (i), by inserting <quote>with respect to such hospital and year</quote> after <quote>described in subparagraph (B)</quote>; and </text></clause><clause id="HD7572D6D88DD481BAE8547576DFAF8A3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text><subclause id="H87FCFA631A5C4713A0A5172486A11CDE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subclause><subclause id="HC3CDDF91050346899EBE0639B543E20D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in subclause (II), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H496C2A6F382E47FCAB9497D692942AAA"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0710A2B3989431287DCACC72120ED13"><subclause id="H71A89E0822214694A0170F9DAF4996AF"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">payments made under title XVIII or by an applicable plan (as defined in section 1862(b)(8)(F)) for such services.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57B23BF884AF48C2BFB406469A971040"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><clause id="HC915206B8DBF4C03A5F9B88F5AEB0C7A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>in this clause are</quote> and inserting <quote>in this subparagraph are, with respect to a hospital and a year,</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HABF4258CC59D46B0B2C5BA9FCEDF7978"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H17F8BE3E2716455B9F17AA90273B4AB3"><clause id="H0C4E46A2B5B6419CB46691B250E95974"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Individuals who are eligible for medical assistance under the State plan or under a waiver of such plan and for whom the State plan or waiver is a payor for such services after application of benefits under title XVIII or under an applicable plan (as defined in section 1862(b)(8)(F)), but only if the hospital has in the aggregate incurred costs exceeding payments under such State plan, waiver, title XVIII, or applicable plan for such services furnished to such individuals during such year.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H229D735C27074FC78EF9BE43C44E3C7A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18399E813FF6402082F1384B7D24A5F5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (2); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2EFA0CC447D4DDF9A55CCF09AD0BA1A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>Notwithstanding paragraph (2) of this subsection (as in effect on October 1, 2021), paragraph (2)</quote> and inserting <quote>Paragraph (2)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1DFA9EF355B746318575AF98E27A6ECE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4B44CC6143941C6BD0C788947E19639"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall apply to payment adjustments made under section 1923 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-4">42 U.S.C. 1396r–4</external-xref>) for Medicaid State plan rate years beginning on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1FB0767A92014EA9AFDD4C11A5B3EC54"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State option to distribute unspent DSH allotments from prior years up to modified cap</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBAF274B0819F425D82BF167119BAB9D7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, for any Medicaid State plan rate year that begins on or after October 1, 2021, and before the date of enactment of this Act, a State did not spend the full amount of its Federal fiscal year allotment under section 1923 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-4">42 U.S.C. 1396r–4</external-xref>) applicable to that State plan rate year, the State may use the unspent portion of such allotment to increase the amount of any payment adjustment made to a hospital for such rate year, provided that— </text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDD0788588B5347878F6A0829AB64DF13"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such payment adjustment (as so increased) is consistent with subsection (g) of such section (as amended by this section); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4F33D87119A4D068820D120273D229C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the total amount of all payment adjustments for the State plan rate year (as so increased) does not exceed the disproportionate share hospital allotment for the State and applicable Federal fiscal year under subsection (f) of such section.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE020552C5CDA459784CC44944A965710"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No recoupment of payments already made to hospitals</header><text>A State shall not recoup any payment adjustment made by the State to a hospital for a Medicaid State plan rate year described in subparagraph (A) if such payment adjustment is consistent with section 1923(g) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-4">42 U.S.C. 1396r–4(g)</external-xref>) as in effect on October 1, 2021.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAB90D585E823497F928BC1417DB8E2E6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Authority to permit retroactive modification of State plan amendments to allow for increases</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03EE052BFC5F4DCB909C259E35A1C7E2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), solely for the purpose of allowing a State to increase the amount of a payment adjustment to a hospital for a Medicaid State plan rate year described in subparagraph (A) pursuant to this paragraph, a State may retroactively modify a provision of the Medicaid State plan, a waiver of such plan, or a State plan amendment that relates to such rate year and the Secretary may approve such modification.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A6D51ABAC334D798514A2E01DCC6208"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>A State may not submit a request for approval of a retroactive modification to a provision of the Medicaid State plan, a waiver of such plan, or a State plan amendment for a Medicaid State plan rate year after the date by which the State is required to submit the independent certified audit for that State plan rate year as required under section 1923(j)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-4">42 U.S.C. 1396r–4(j)(2)</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD45464B2359049168CEF45C559FD5463" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reporting</header><text>If a State increases a payment adjustment made to a hospital for a Medicaid State plan rate year pursuant to this paragraph, the State shall include information on such increased payment adjustment as part of the next annual report submitted by the State under section 1923(j)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-4">42 U.S.C. 1396r–4(j)(1)</external-xref>). </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

