<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H66F42E84E0F047AFA7C4B330BEEABA3A" public-private="public" resolution-type="constitutional-amendment" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HJ 6 IH: Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to provide for balanced budgets for the Government.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 6</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250103">January 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</sponsor> submitted the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to provide for balanced budgets for the Government.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="constitutional-amendment" id="H24F30178227D4F279FACFEAAC32F820B"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HAE78499258054E17B467DD4A7E0447DB"><text>That the following article is proposed as an amendment to the Constitution of the United States, which shall be valid to all intents and purposes as part of the Constitution when ratified by the legislatures of three-fourths of the several States:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" id="H97241FC9EA9C46328EC169F7A907E53A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><constitution-article id="H78C46D4249C9450E9570893AD3BCC6DE"><enum> —</enum><section id="H0B8C56C13C294D9E88C1181A870909EC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Total outlays for any fiscal year shall not exceed total receipts for that fiscal year, unless two-thirds of the whole number of each House of Congress shall provide by law for a specific excess of outlays over receipts by a rollcall vote.</text></section><section id="H15F775168F0340E9A6DB76673CFF3873" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to each fiscal year, the President shall transmit to the Congress a proposed budget for the United States Government for that fiscal year in which total outlays do not exceed total receipts.</text></section><section id="H7A9BA9F570604856A105F2733031FB1E" section-type="section-one"><enum>3.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress may waive the provisions of this article for any fiscal year in which a declaration of war is in effect by a rollcall vote.</text></section><section id="H540CC03CF0B9490A9E249D80C2DFBAF6" section-type="section-one"><enum>4.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress may waive the provisions of this article for any fiscal year in which a declaration of national emergency is in effect, as so declared by a joint resolution, adopted by a majority of the whole number of each House, which becomes law.</text></section><section id="H6AEA0A2146674BC79114B8ABD0478F2E" section-type="section-one"><enum>5.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress may waive the provisions of this article for any fiscal year in which a declaration of a natural disaster is in effect, as so declared by a joint resolution, adopted by a majority of the whole number of each House, which becomes law.</text></section><section id="H1F12EB40F6374F35A7EAEC439D1B70E8" section-type="section-one"><enum>6.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress shall enforce and implement this article by appropriate legislation, which may rely on estimates of outlays and receipts.</text></section><section id="H687221B26F1448D2B2BCE2BA71540E6C" section-type="section-one"><enum>7.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This article shall take effect beginning with the fifth fiscal year beginning after its ratification.</text></section></constitution-article><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

