<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC8D8B0ACA2534CC59F487A7B550DF037" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5337 IH: Motor Carrier Safety Selection Standard Act of 2024</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5337</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250911">September 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a national motor carrier safety selection standard for entities that contract with certain motor carriers to transport goods, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6A5A6120337E439EB7F76484FAB4F392" style="OLC"><section id="HD5133AFDA85B424C8D46855DE7C6D08E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Motor Carrier Safety Selection Standard Act of 2024</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9EF2D963D9094FBA9D6A662EE4E3891A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Motor carrier selection standard of care</header><subsection id="H8DC1F040F670416FBB39833671E96BFE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Selection standard</header><paragraph id="HFCEA28C7624941D4A19ACA1C3FC32CFA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For any claim of negligent selection of a motor carrier against a covered entity with respect to the covered entity contracting with a covered motor carrier for the shipment of goods or household goods, the covered entity shall be considered reasonable and prudent in the selection of that covered motor carrier if, not later than the date of shipment and not earlier than 45 days before that date, the covered entity verifies that the covered motor carrier—</text><subparagraph id="H6E2591F0FE784B1DA147EF2CCBFB423F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is registered under section 13902 of title 49, United States Code, as a motor carrier or a household goods motor carrier;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70E14855E9FE4A2C90AAAD09ACEA85D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has at least the minimum insurance coverage required by Federal and State law; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE0ED486A07F4503B1C6202B3B2212D0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has been confirmed by the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration, including through a public confirmation described in subsection (c)(1), to be in compliance with all required Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration safety standards to operate as a motor carrier.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H814DC9A16BFE4B0589B17531F7998525"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall cease to be effective on the effective date of a regulation promulgated under subsection (c)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC6BCD7F0BE7B4C3EBFFC032F9ED8E0AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public confirmation</header><text>The public confirmation described in paragraph (1)(C) shall include 1 of the following statements, depending on the status of the motor carrier:</text><paragraph id="HF8B94C19AB2B4C06BD0E8FBBA4841E21"><enum>(1)</enum><text><quote>This motor carrier is confirmed to meet all operating requirements of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) and is authorized to operate on the nation’s roadways.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H412572D878E24E5898C84970DDB95678"><enum>(2)</enum><text><quote>This motor carrier is not confirmed to operate on the nation’s roadways and fails to meet 1 or more requirements of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) to operate as a motor carrier.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF535F25A6A4342B492A47E30CD516679"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Safety fitness rule</header><paragraph id="H8CF1A99EDFF745C19D50E418B906C40D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall promulgate final regulations amending appendix B to part 385 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), to revise the methodology for issuance of motor carrier safety fitness determinations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D2B4B8CDAE446ECB5A1D47BEEB8AEA7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In promulgating the regulations under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consider the use of all available data to determine the fitness of a motor carrier.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8437FB336795457AAE39B9F8089ADAF0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Factors for an unfit determination</header><text>The regulations promulgated under paragraph (1) shall provide a procedure for the Secretary to determine whether a motor carrier is not fit to operate a commercial motor vehicle in or affecting interstate commerce in accordance with section 31144 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76A79C6F6F454F02BAF523AB47382B32"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The regulations promulgated under paragraph (1) shall include the requirements described in subsections (a)(1) and (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5494D3C4A32C4C7C88027F74D066FF86"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exemption for individual shippers</header><text>For any claim of negligent selection of a motor carrier against a person acting as an individual shipper with respect to that person contracting with a covered motor carrier for the shipment of goods or household goods, that person shall, on demonstration that the person contracted with a covered motor carrier, be considered reasonable and prudent in the selection of that covered motor carrier without having to satisfy any of the requirements described in subsection (a)(1) (or any similar requirement in the regulations promulgated under subsection (c)(1)).</text></subsection><subsection id="HA8592232F4C24CBF88BB5CC79CAA086E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing in this Act preempts or supersedes any State law (including regulations) relating to drayage.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAAE43F9FE34E41439881A607F3E6A250"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HA9082B6C2C834B72824947C3511BF68E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><subparagraph id="H3314D4514BD0412695DDD83305963678"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>covered entity</quote> means a person acting as—</text><clause id="H7AB75119BC114629B78FCB36FC1E559E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>except as provided in subparagraph (B), a shipper or consignee of goods;</text></clause><clause id="H09E64F3D3F75418EA63F3AC199BA87DE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a broker, a freight forwarder, or a household goods freight forwarder (as those terms are defined in section 13102 of title 49, United States Code);</text></clause><clause id="HCBD9039BA9F64E7A87A296E360F1E84C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an ocean transportation intermediary (as defined in section 40102 of title 46, United States Code), when arranging for inland transportation as part of an international through movement involving ocean transportation between the United States and a foreign port;</text></clause><clause id="H5CCA8646316B456E9C763FCAC5DC02A6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an indirect air carrier holding a Standard Security Program approved by the Transportation Security Administration, only to the extent that the person acting as an indirect air carrier is engaging in—</text><subclause id="HB60337B6B6314CB7A047C3796500CE8F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>activities as an air carrier (as defined in section 40102 of title 49, United States Code); or</text></subclause><subclause id="H5074B99AA2694A70A5883D9A203DC93D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>air commerce (as defined in that section);</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6E1D843056C9416D99D4BA8AE1DFAEBA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a customs broker licensed in accordance with section 111.2 of title 19, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), only to the extent that the person acting as a customs broker is engaging in—</text><subclause id="H301AFC019850412BA82AC37DD4495A8E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a movement under a customs bond; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H914B4F4332384BCC965527ABAD014FF9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a transaction involving customs business (as defined in section 111.1 of that title (or a successor regulation)); or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HE3A4E225590F498295A197875F895A73"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a motor carrier registered under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/139">chapter 139</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73F06E97C47342E197D90E7F53120602"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <quote>covered entity</quote> does not include a person acting as an individual shipper.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C22E8E9780E4048BE1D68CF18CCC5C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered motor carrier</header><text>The term <quote>covered motor carrier</quote> means a motor carrier or a household goods motor carrier that is subject to Federal motor carrier financial responsibility and safety regulations, except for motor carriers that operate commercial motor vehicles of passengers, as defined in section 31101(1)(B) of 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFD6121B8E0D4353865F981B05956543"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Household goods</header><text>The term <quote>household goods</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 13102 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE1D460EA91643AEA8EB510B76BCFFEA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Household goods motor carrier</header><text>The term <quote>household goods motor carrier</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 13102 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD8EFEFD871B496A989A18B5D5F5976C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Individual shipper</header><text>The term <quote>individual shipper</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 13102 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF2C0268E6684E198E12C1D851C99100"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Motor carrier</header><text>The term <quote>motor carrier</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 13102 of title 49, United States Code, except for motor carriers that operate commercial motor vehicles of passengers, as defined in section 31101(1)(B) of 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H770A5583A12440708D62D0AB488D6FED"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

