<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H95B5D24E45BB4A90B634B811874F5EAC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5098 IH: Strengthening Our Workforce Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5098</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250902">September 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000136">Mr. Vasquez</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for conditional lawful permanent residency for certain aliens.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0242502E6A874F588931B72BCFE79C5E" style="OLC"><section id="H834A6D9BDFEC4B55A757424F4201B7AF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Our Workforce Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1D23CD84A5EA49549AE9113CD0CD0EAB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Conditional lawful permanent residency</header><subsection id="H45FEEEE5F86249E086B8F257C686A2B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may adjust the status of an alien to that of a conditional lawful permanent resident in accordance with this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H315B88FFF16641AE99F7AD9E7E85FD53"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Status defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>conditional lawful permanent resident</term> means a status as a nonimmigrant with a period of stay of 2 years, with employment authorization to be provided concurrently. </text></subsection><subsection id="H0079500E007D4DC286C73F1AE1AA455B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An alien is eligible for adjustment of status if that alien—</text><paragraph id="HD3709AE0E5734877BAC1ACF6F356FE39"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submits an application, at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the Secretary may require;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H74C86FFC52FF494DA7CB9B0AE38F6F7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>pays such fee as the Secretary may establish;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA789A55CED64043AC7CCF2DC3B30AC5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is present in the United States as of January 1, 2024—</text><subparagraph id="HE5F7D903324C4598BFDC9008D0AD94B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>without lawful status under the immigration laws; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1A0E3ED3023426F9B7359F4704D2B01"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with deferred action granted to the alien pursuant to the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals program announced by President Obama on June 15, 2012; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A3CC6489B094232B5DA837B1D6ED332"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with status as a nonimmigrant that has employment authorization;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9A11FAD8B654BA2AD7AC70AE1A7A255"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been continuously present in the United States during the period beginning on January 1, 2024, through the date of the application for status; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D01870CDFD04DDC8DCA53BBE427EBB3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>has been employed for a cumulative period of one hundred days (consecutive or not) at any time, in a covered profession; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5517647A0F594AC39DF3A7487DDE2B53"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> is not inadmissible under paragraph (1), (6)(E), (6)(G), (8), or (10) of section 212(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)</external-xref>), except that with respect to any benefit under this Act, and in addition to the waivers under subsection (g), the Secretary may waive the grounds of inadmissibility under paragraph (1), (6)(E), (6)(G), or (10)(D) of section 212(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)</external-xref>) for humanitarian purposes, for family unity, or because the waiver is otherwise in the public interest;</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H91A01F8380DB44D9BF438AD638042374"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conditions of status</header><text>An alien granted conditional lawful permanent resident status under this section shall conform to the following requirements:</text><paragraph id="HA6268FCC8F1E47099B20D629CB0422CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The alien shall remain continuously physically present in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6276F81CED3E48D58A0C652087E94C55"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The alien shall maintain not less than one hundred cumulative days of annual employment for two consecutive years in a covered profession.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2874B8E4754A4B81AB9782C00743F4F6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The alien shall be subject to all grounds of deportability under section 237.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H55D050C7469D450F84C797C4C1ED065B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Adjustment of status</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the time that the conditional lawful permanent resident status of an alien terminates, the Secretary shall immediately adjust the status of that alien to that of a lawful permanent resident—</text><paragraph id="HEB8ECFADFD674A63897EC06FF6CF7302"><enum>(1)</enum><text>unless the alien makes a timely objection in writing; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H953B17B2B2EC42BBB5308E76B98BB466"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the alien pays such fee as the Secretary may establish and passes an additional background investigation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2A4C433B543B43CBBB8C920D7DBCB2B9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Not subject to numerical limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An alien whose status is adjusted to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residency under this section is not subject to the worldwide levels or numerical limitations of section 201(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H01D6A45D21C846A8840C80E933BC6AED"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Criminal and national security bars</header><paragraph id="H5ECAFF3142634E7CB8A07EC5977C615C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grounds of ineligibility</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), an alien is ineligible for adjustment of status under this title if any of the following apply:</text><subparagraph id="H185619D6EFA6461ABF5FF32200E0AE60"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The alien is inadmissible under paragraph (2) or (3) of section 212(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A57C1C607174EA7B6385B31EF6EF1C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Excluding any offense under State law for which an essential element is the alien’s immigration status, and any minor traffic offense, the alien has been convicted of—</text><clause id="HA7B843C3E3BF4A70B47CCADCD728A3A0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any felony offense;</text></clause><clause id="H2959059DC3D94E8D91B9F54241C18B54"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>three or more misdemeanor offenses (excluding simple possession of cannabis or cannabis-related paraphernalia, any offense involving cannabis or cannabis-related paraphernalia which is no longer prosecutable in the State in which the conviction was entered, and any offense involving civil disobedience without violence) not occurring on the same date, and not arising out of the same act, omission, or scheme of misconduct; or</text></clause><clause id="H8ADB307693C64A8B929443D5E817BC95"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a misdemeanor offense of domestic violence, unless the alien demonstrates that such crime is related to the alien having been—</text><subclause id="H6DB3FB85425941BDB9844CFF7DC799C0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a victim of domestic violence, sexual assault, stalking, child abuse or neglect, abuse or neglect in later life, or human trafficking;</text></subclause><subclause id="HBBD4CC0B19F1404B91A558C49A106792"><enum>(II)</enum><text>battered or subjected to extreme cruelty; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HA996D6C61F0D49E98A9B1881B686D16B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a victim of criminal activity described in section 101(a)(15)(U)(iii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(U)(iii)</external-xref>).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E15AF0E5C7B4AA1AECAE76506088575"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waivers for certain misdemeanors</header><text>For humanitarian purposes, family unity, or if otherwise in the public interest, the Secretary may—</text><subparagraph id="HA51FEC7743AA4B2EA89257E6C10CD2EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>waive the grounds of inadmissibility under subparagraphs (A), (C), and (D) of section 212(a)(2) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(2)</external-xref>), unless the conviction forming the basis for inadmissibility would otherwise render the alien ineligible under paragraph (1)(B) (subject to subparagraph (B)); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64B030CFB6134ACF9EB376E937A89D8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for purposes of clauses (ii) and (iii) of paragraph (1)(B), waive consideration of—</text><clause id="HF88879AFE7434DF2B6D1368B7FFB4920"><enum>(i)</enum><text>one misdemeanor offense if the alien has not been convicted of any offense in the 5-year period preceding the date on which the alien applies for adjustment of status under this title; or</text></clause><clause id="H404716BE23E94A82BB51ADDB51767758"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>up to two misdemeanor offenses if the alien has not been convicted of any offense in the 10-year period preceding the date on which the alien applies for adjustment of status under this title.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H54D1D234365742379481EC048E702F32"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="HBAE589CFD1A54182B1EBB5E0BA338BAF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>felony offense</term> means an offense under Federal or State law that is punishable by a maximum term of imprisonment of more than 1 year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2323FCCFC59B4B6EB650AFF60393ADE6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>misdemeanor offense</term> means an offense under Federal or State law that is punishable by a term of imprisonment of more than 5 days but not more than 1 year; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D1314B1AA82430C90E4AB73E7D74535"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the term <term>crime of domestic violence</term> means any offense that has as an element the use, attempted use, or threatened use of physical force against a person committed by a current or former spouse of the person, by an individual with whom the person shares a child in common, by an individual who is cohabiting with or has cohabited with the person as a spouse, by an individual similarly situated to a spouse of the person under the domestic or family violence laws of the jurisdiction where the offense occurs, or by any other individual against a person who is protected from that individual’s acts under the domestic or family violence laws of the United States or any State, Indian Tribal government, or unit of local government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6FBD4384CA0D4534BB2E9E83AF3E4CA1"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text><paragraph id="H79F36D91D2DE4F9F93B0A098882AB096"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Terms used have the meanings given such terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H691F01B6F437426B86CD3215D8D468C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30F4ABEECF9746C3B57F2978C712318E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered profession defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>covered profession</term> means the following: </text><subparagraph id="HC610CC9103574842BFC97F3F7B054CA0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Health care.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F9A6086FC484F0BA4B8DEA3781EA593"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Emergency response.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C984BF7983D49FDBE2D1F103B955C53"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Energy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7693EA2CC0A40FE9E502E318430365A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Education, including early education.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C14ED35A5BF42868C1E9C5047F4AADD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Sanitation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1161D9752B5D489E94D66460892D1E1B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Restaurant ownership, food preparation, vending, catering, food packaging, food services, or delivery.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61B1690A010E4D058A51CB6E05F92467"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Hotel or retail.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD12760A817F949218901580A55CE68EF"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Fish, poultry, and meat processing work.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38EE45C84396438EAF023B3484D40E78"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Agricultural work, including labor that is seasonal in nature.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CF74B7C04E54A63922DE4F83D89C344"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Commercial or residential landscaping.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB65713BAE1AB4BD8A9EAD59BA43571C5"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Commercial or residential construction or renovation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87BC687178A749909CC7F08782635512"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Housing, residential, and commercial construction related activities or public works construction.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56B0F6B5E507488A9E1315D124F09426"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Domestic work in private households, including child care, home care, or house cleaning.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A8B6D1FC83046C19DD22FC7995B7D00"><enum>(N)</enum><text>Natural disaster recovery, disaster reconstruction, and related construction.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF066C23CC3C74125A876B4C7F2CAF73E"><enum>(O)</enum><text>Home and community-based work, including—</text><clause id="H0E096FCA785D46419901F9A32F62246C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>home health care;</text></clause><clause id="H5B209EF01B0A422685B10035DB2FB3CD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>residential care; </text></clause><clause id="H557C25483D594E5297E307E08AEE13CC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>assistance with activities of daily living;</text></clause><clause id="H0438530F292D413786AD2584B82A12D1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any service provided by direct care workers (as defined in section 799B of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/295p">42 U.S.C. 295p</external-xref>)), personal care aides, job coaches, or supported employment providers; and</text></clause><clause id="HDE6B638B97544457AA1F8D50727DB830"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any other provision of care to individuals in their homes by direct service providers, personal care attendants, and home health aides.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C1742AC8D0A4548BC2F88BCB2A21E64"><enum>(P)</enum><text>Family care, including child care services, in-home child care services such as nanny services, and care services provided by family members to other family members.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H295CA52F883C4A34948343433DD45CFA"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>Manufacturing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64CF538C3BF34F60AA461B8440D344B5"><enum>(R)</enum><text>Warehousing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E2C2B830D6E4F4BB407710E8989051C"><enum>(S)</enum><text>Transportation or logistics.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF756B3CD030A438CA2CEA1045AA8495D"><enum>(T)</enum><text>Janitorial.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12C4CD563A8D48EABBC38FE41CA03B34"><enum>(U)</enum><text>Laundromat and dry-cleaning operators.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56D56B1A91B94205B1B0DF4447EBC2E3"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Any other work performed by <quote>essential critical infrastructure workers</quote>, as described in the memorandum of the Department of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Advisory Memorandum on Ensuring Essential Critical Infrastructure Workers Ability to Work During the COVID–19 Response</quote>, which was originally issued by the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency on March 19, 2020, and last updated on August 10, 2021.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H724E55C121054DF18D45FF49B1716FE8"><enum>(W)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other work, industry, or profession that a State or local government deemed essential during the COVID–19 Public Health Emergency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C827E3FA7464ABBBACEE76490CC7FA4"><enum>(X)</enum><text>Workers who are employed in any of the listed professions who do so remotely or hybrid.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

