<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1C590B0A2743465C8C064F3B18E13BA1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3214 IH: Housing Oversight and Mitigating Exploitation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3214</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250506">May 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000590">Ms. Lee of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000136">Mr. Vasquez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect consumers from price gouging of residential rental and sale prices, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H90C7E5777739425C8039D2762C0F1B43" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H6BB5D299FF4347589098AA002FFD824F"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Housing Oversight and Mitigating Exploitation Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HOME Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H924D833FFB2748C3B2577D5A390A3DD3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H837A39CFABB3494BBB456E842D29E148"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affordable housing crisis period</header><text>The term <term>affordable housing crisis period</term> means the period during which the prohibition under section 3(a)(1) applies in the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C56DE5E6E6B4E2D8245260A60A18297"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H900BA32D77284C45BFAD920AC9AF679A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Single-family housing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>single-family housing</term> means a residence consisting of 1 to 4 dwelling units, but does not include a dwelling unit in a condominium or cooperative housing project.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H08F6C455EF954DB0AF220882261FFF58"><enum>(4)</enum><header>United States</header><text>The term <term>United States</term> includes each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, and any territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H64A4C99F20A24780A46E3EBC68342D6B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Unconscionable pricing of residential rental and sale prices during affordable housing crises</header>
<subsection id="HC4ABA426D4144BEE92CA686E859D268F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Unconscionable pricing</header>
<paragraph id="HFC5425D6C30D4C8F8D2E3712F5746D66"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>If the Secretary publishes in the Federal Register a determination that the United States is experiencing an affordable housing crisis, it shall be unlawful, during the affordable housing crisis period, for any person to rent a dwelling unit or sell any single-family housing in the United States at a price that—</text> <subparagraph id="H8D2A210ADE2542F499A39EC5DBD80A4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is unconscionably excessive; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFB967090A7944D2B8E6E53E23D56D402"><enum>(B)</enum><text>indicates the lessor or seller is exploiting the circumstances related to an affordable housing crisis to increase prices unreasonably.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA44E671D35642AFB2F3B45F86187F58"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations for affordable housing crisis determination</header><text>For purposes of determining whether the United States is experiencing an affordable housing crisis, the Secretary shall consider—</text>
<subparagraph id="HEC831FD520164D848853EF1D043D9C2E" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the interest rates applicable to mortgage loans;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H709600B9868E4CC6AA602F7F1E765FDF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the effective Federal funds rate;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H16690DBBFFA447918BC7951E751261B6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the refinance rates applicable to mortgage loans, including for fixed-fixed loans, fixed-variable loans, and variable-fixed loans;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H991ADB6776CB412BAA8083D2E2E6C437"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the median rental home price in the United States;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H96FAF8468DCA41F6A74F744D8196A349"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the median home sale price in the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HECAD523275404EEDA4CB3AE434966609"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the median household income in the United States; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D37ADADE7BF4284B79999C842BEDDAF"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the declaration of a major disaster or emergency under the section 401 or 501, respectively, of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>, 5191).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC595F6AE16F841E29DDB82546E59C04D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The prohibition described in paragraph (1)—</text>
<subparagraph id="HF804DED31F0B4983B72B90A993FF9A01"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may not apply for a period of more than 30 consecutive days, but may be renewed for such consecutive periods, each not to exceed 30 days, as the Secretary determines appropriate; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3C6929709ADB46D5B71ED70B457B310C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may apply for a period of time not to exceed 1 week before a reasonably foreseeable affordable housing crisis period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H537D085D967341AA93DC535A4CC01C85"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Factors considered</header>
<subparagraph id="H0B8AC4DA72394C7B8EDA61128F36B73B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In determining whether a person has violated paragraph (1), there shall be taken into account, among other factors, the aggravating factors described in subparagraph (B) and the mitigating factor described in subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC3FEE55AC7E544D58503C0EFAB70092D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Aggravating factors</header><text>The aggravating factors described in this subparagraph are the following:</text>
<clause id="H9D83E17290C049F8A76E6CDDF5E29AFD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Whether the amount charged by such person grossly exceeds the average price at which the housing unit was offered for rental or sale by such person during—</text> <subclause id="H0038F7F1BA4A4ABB94F85E3136465D17"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the 30-day period before the date on which the determination that the area is experiencing an affordable housing crisis was made under paragraph (1); or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HF1768E31585441028F42460352DD47E4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>another appropriate benchmark period, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HA2E7B5EE96054E8E93967F175D19233B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Whether the amount charged by such person grossly exceeds the price at which the same or a similar housing unit was readily obtainable for rental or purchase in the same area from other sellers during the affordable housing crisis period.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDA5328F387714B2A993090474CA5BB4A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Mitigating factor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The mitigating factor described in this subparagraph is whether the quantity of any housing dwelling units such person made available for rental or sale in an area covered by the affordable housing crisis period during the 30-day period following the date on which the affordable housing crisis period was determined increased over the quantity such person made available for rental or sale during the 30-day period before the date on which the affordable housing crisis period was determined, taking into account any usual seasonal demand variation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB0B6A1144CF344A9A1FD5438DF53EF88"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Advance notice</header><text>The Secretary shall provide advance notice prior to the publication of the determination under paragraph (1) for persons to comply with the prohibition described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H96D04AEEB3254531824C7764BAADB843"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Affirmative defense</header><text>It shall be an affirmative defense in any civil action or administrative action to enforce subsection (a), with respect to the renting out or sale of housing by a person, that the increase in the rental or sale price of such housing reasonably reflects additional costs that were paid, incurred, or reasonably anticipated by such person, or reasonably reflects additional risks taken by such person, to rent or sell such housing unit under the circumstances.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H832DE4222CC64407B543B85ED239F04D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>This section may not be construed to cover a transaction on a futures market.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H34AEFDD739AC4E37AADF05CB16D210B3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enforcement</header>
<paragraph id="H02BC8B7E04294E3BAAFCD1E633274D80"><enum>(1)</enum><header>HUD</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall enforce violations of subsection (a) of this section—</text> <subparagraph id="H241CC33AF973472F85273D3C5BDA9E01"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as the Federal Trade Commission has under the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to violations of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H04975E8A5D1B42C0967381BA977C68CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section, except that any reference in such terms and provisions to the Commission shall be treated as referring to the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3913CE40DB86417482EF7BD6254C97B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enforcement at retail level by State Attorneys General</header> <subparagraph id="H3DDB25C3FDE64B9BAD1ECB55FC4B0EA4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the chief law enforcement officer of a State, or an official or agency designated by a State, has reason to believe that any person has violated or is violating subsection (a), the chief law enforcement officer, official, or agency of the State, in addition to any authority it may have to bring an action in State court under its laws, may bring a civil action in any appropriate United States district court or in any other court of competent jurisdiction to—</text>
<clause id="HF93B8A5CE59D404ABCCF03ADF05350F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enjoin further such violation by such person;</text></clause> <clause id="HE6FCA59BF3604C088928E3018B62CB3F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>enforce compliance with such subsection;</text></clause>
<clause id="H151B04DCC7C04B3CA91FF4FFD0F5FF66"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>obtain civil penalties; and</text></clause> <clause id="HEBBD86B663504413B5A9360346C0CDDC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>obtain damages, restitution, or other compensation on behalf of residents of the State.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE359AC7BFA384FB89A2DA6CD10B818F8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The State shall serve written notice to the Secretary of any civil action under subparagraph (A) before initiating such civil action. The notice shall include a copy of the complaint to be filed to initiate such civil action, except that if it is not feasible for the State to provide such prior notice, the State shall provide such notice immediately upon instituting such civil action.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEAE773F938524C098AEF987C205B9BD7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Authority to intervene</header><text>Upon receipt of the notice required by subparagraph (B), the Secretary may intervene in such civil action and upon intervening—</text>
<clause id="H459CE728FF3847F4B509C159763876BD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be heard on all matters arising in such civil action; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF08F8749400D4DE59DCFDB0B62940E21"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>file petitions for appeal of a decision in such civil action.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC3D4F26FA5914DB98E0A86D886FC5C03"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>For purposes of bringing any civil action under subparagraph (A), nothing in this paragraph shall prevent the chief law enforcement officer of a State from exercising the powers conferred on the chief law enforcement officer by the laws of such State to conduct investigations or to administer oaths or affirmations or to compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary and other evidence.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8DAD2DF9B1D147D08CD5668514CE1044"> <enum>(E)</enum> <header>Limitation on state action while Federal action is pending</header> <text>If the Secretary has instituted a civil action or an administrative action for violation of subsection (a), a chief law enforcement officer, official, or agency of a State may not bring an action under this paragraph during the pendency of that action against any defendant named in the complaint of the Secretary or another agency for any violation of this Act alleged in the complaint.</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3C5CA08BDA544FA2A92B3BDCA118EEC3"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>This paragraph may not be construed to prohibit an authorized State official from proceeding in State court to enforce a civil or criminal statute of such State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H29C1ED7A88784E0B93C297D01A516346"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Low-Income housing assistance</header> <paragraph id="HB568F67FB27646F6B81058B3A9F3570B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Deposit of funds</header><text>Amounts collected in any penalty under subsection (d)(1) shall be deposited in the Housing Trust Fund established under section 1338 of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4568">12 U.S.C. 4568</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB95E9696C07C49A7BB901F07CC02E288"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>To the extent provided for in advance in appropriations Acts, the amounts deposited in the Fund shall be used to increase and preserve the supply of rental housing affordable to extremely low- and very low-income families, including homeless families, in accordance with section 1338 of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4568">12 U.S.C. 4568</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB31EAD21B2E4408F9F6724A32660FEBA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effect on other laws</header> <paragraph id="HDB1B9B80221D4080A66C37220657B8B4"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Other authority of Federal housing administration</header> <text>Nothing in this section may be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary under any other provision of law.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H47BDD3DCE1FD4D6982482A8BD03D0FEC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State law</header><text>Nothing in this section preempts any State law.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HAA8E980BA24F4E9CA2EBE4AE2D6708A9"><enum>4.</enum><header>HUD investigation and report on housing prices</header> <subsection id="H1B81EF111952465584F407481D2F70F4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Investigation</header> <paragraph id="HE73E0AE8138F4141893F0131D5DD0BD4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct an investigation to determine if the prices for rental housing units or sale of single-family housing are being manipulated by reducing housing capacity or by any other form of market manipulation or artificially increased by price gouging practices.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0A657224377348929E4E94F9B8030C20"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>In conducting the investigation under paragraph (1), the Secretary may consider the impact of mergers and acquisitions in the real estate industry, including mergers and acquisitions involving developers, managers, owners, and investors.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7E21408A8B364D6BA2DF5CFDDDC9FF04"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph id="HF923D2FAC74D4FD0B7F476E3CD6B44A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a report on the investigation conducted under subsection (a).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF0B7C6595CFC409DBE66A3A1988254EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HB496893CD8B94D6592CB7C817E370A0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a long-term strategy for the Department of Housing and Urban Development and the Congress to address manipulation of rental housing markets and markets for sale of single-family housing, and in preparing the strategy the Secretary shall utilize data on race, gender, and socioeconomic status; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0DDB3CFA1495439AA783CDC6892959C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description and analysis of how non-occupant investors in single-family housing impact underserved communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1F52CD377760470FB0F34716D99737F0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exemption from Paperwork Reduction Act</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">Chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, shall not apply to the collection of information under subsection (a).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H5B80C4ED08DC41448BE285A881C707FE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $1,000,000 for fiscal year 2025.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HF01C64C1758F4F1C8D92D87417F8E3E8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Housing cost monitoring and enforcement within HUD</header> <subsection id="H3DC90214CBAF41B0935FDB6912173EC1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of the housing monitoring and enforcement unit</header> <paragraph id="H0E9D6236AA964A73B7BA904FD0FBFA44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish within the Department of Housing and Urban Development the Housing Monitoring and Enforcement Unit (in this section referred to as the <quote>Unit</quote>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H483B973508444167AAF54FCD1E7F6F62"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties of the unit</header>
<subparagraph id="H9943C1B67683418998524F62E7591E7B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Primary responsibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The primary responsibility of the Unit shall be to assist the Secretary in protecting the public interest by continuously and comprehensively collecting, monitoring, and analyzing rental housing market data, data for markets for sale of single-family housing, and data on investor-owned, non-owner occupied housing units, in order to—</text> <clause id="H64BCE02B8BA54B09940F902653DB779D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>support transparent and competitive market practices;</text></clause>
<clause id="H07C155947FE44F5DA72D0E787375B3D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify any market manipulation, including by collecting and analyzing data on race, gender, and socioeconomic status, any reporting of false information, any use of market power to disadvantage consumers, or any other unfair method of competition; and</text></clause> <clause id="HAC7AE38C65C54A99AD1109EA11EB61EE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>facilitate enforcement of penalties against persons in violation of relevant statutory prohibitions.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4BB2A3F834F744778D89322B09944F91"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Specific duties</header><text>In order to carry out the responsibility under subparagraph (A), the Unit shall assist the Secretary in carrying out the following duties:</text> <clause id="H770A386AB4EE4369A8305FE6706CBA32"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Receiving, compiling, and analyzing relevant buying and selling activity in order to identify and investigate anomalous market trends and suspicious behavior.</text></clause>
<clause id="H44B1AA2478534996A3E81134B83B7C5A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Determining whether excessive concentration or exclusive control of housing-related infrastructure may allow or result in anti-competitive behaviors.</text></clause> <clause id="H77A115FA775549629EF333813BA4CA59"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Obtaining a data-sharing agreement with State and local jurisdictions, housing agencies, and relevant public and private data sources to receive and archive information on housing purchases by institutional investors within a given area.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H4EB76E816BA543CEA7003E34525BF59F"><enum>6.</enum><header>Investigations of excessive housing purchases</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall monitor purchases of single-family housing in each housing market area in the United States, as determined by the Secretary, to determine whether any single purchaser of such housing, including any purchaser that is an institutional investor, is purchasing an excessive amount of such housing made available for sale in any such market area. If the Secretary determines that any single purchaser has purchased more than 5 percent of the single-family housing made available for sale in any market area over a 3-year period, or if, in aggregate, large institutional investors have purchased more than 25 percent of the single-family housing made available for sale in any market area over a 1-year period, the Secretary shall conduct an investigation to determine the purposes of and circumstances involved in such purchases, including price gouging, market manipulation, and unfair investment practices that drive homeowners out of the market.</text></section> <section id="H6D4050DC40DB462CBE5164FDFBF0A482"><enum>7.</enum><header>Identification of unfair screening practices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary, the Federal Trade Commission, and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection shall jointly—</text>
<paragraph id="H76F07A369C0040C2852793AB7AB0E569"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out a program to collect information to identify practices that unfairly prevent applicants and tenants of rental housing from accessing or staying in housing, including the establishment and use of tenant or applicant background checks, the use of algorithms in tenant screenings, the provision of adverse action notices by landlords and property management companies, and the use of information regarding tenant income sources; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A5A8D2146764CC9B47C39CF32168240"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit a report to the Congress annually describing the information collected under the program carried out pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H7CABE2C979884074AEAB9F58C0532433"><enum>8.</enum><header>Limitation on Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac investments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart A of part 2 of subtitle A of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4541">12 U.S.C. 4541 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26D72EEEED834D33B484B8E821CFE29C"> <section id="H7C5A763912DC477095393FE532F2E087"><enum>1329.</enum><header>Limitation on enterprise investments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director shall, by regulations issued after notice and opportunity for interested parties to comment at a public hearing, establish standards and criteria for the purchase by the enterprises of mortgages on multifamily rental housing as the Director considers necessary to ensure basic renter protections and prevent egregious rent increases for tenants in such housing.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="H3D226525906547E3803233559C6F67AD"><enum>9.</enum><header>Review of anti-competitive behaviors</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Attorney General and the Federal Trade Commission shall jointly conduct a review to identify any anti-competitive behaviors in the single-family housing and residential rental markets, including anti-competitive information sharing, and not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act shall submit a report to the Congress setting forth the findings of such review.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

