<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25E89-RPR-01-PNT">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2626 IS: Strengthening United States Leadership at the IDB Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2626</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250731">July 31, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on
                    Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To strengthen the leadership role of the United States at the Inter-American
            Development Bank, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening United States Leadership at the IDB Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id2c7d7e4187954c3b96f1581f42889642">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="idc2f27bac69bc4e99997f1bb701798e92"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Appropriate congressional committees</header> <text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text>
                <subparagraph id="id455a4b62bfd047b4955b7b1047a90d19">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id0810622765044bdd95d3cedb3b0a2578"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id1181139772264198bc27853ee1a072dc">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>IDB</header>
 <text>The term <term>IDB</term> means all of the current and former institutions in the IDB Group, including the Inter-American Development Bank, the Inter-American Investment Corporation (commonly known as <quote>IDB Invest</quote>), IDB Lab, and any related or predecessor entities.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id76ebdf6293a4413ca50ec4354d652943">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>PRC</header>
 <text>The term <term>PRC</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="ida73fe4b4cdc3430a95082e79d1f95839"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>means the People’s Republic of China;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="id31a50c9e938c45ef91db1a6c236cc8b1">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>except as provided by subparagraph (C), includes all Special Administrative Regions of the People's Republic of China, including Hong Kong and Macau; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7430fa94bf9d472fbdb65e0e61590e13">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">excludes Taiwan.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id19701fa63115482bbc6903d954d156ad"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>PRC entity</header> <text>The term <term>PRC entity</term> means any corporation, company, limited liability company, limited partnership, business trust, business association, or other similar entity owned by, controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of the Government of the People's Republic of China.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="idb4fcf57a33534918840f7d3d73da8cf4">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>United States policy related to the People’s Republic of China at Inter-American
                Development Bank</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall instruct the United States Executive Director at the Inter-American Development Bank to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States to reduce the influence of the PRC and PRC entities in IDB operations, activities, and projects, including by—</text>
            <paragraph id="id37ac68f1e5f9403db72557ad0f4cbb84">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>reviewing any IDB projects, or loans, grants, or other financing, that include entry into a contract, provision of funding, or provision of other financing, involving the PRC or PRC entities, for potential risks to the national and economic security interests of the United States; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id8bbd63fe7bee4f03806cc059cb318a57">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>voting against—</text> <subparagraph id="id26c05943f1ae449a81d23e3ddb499954"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>any project, or loan, grant, or other financing, that—</text>
                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3aa5df8ea5284d02b71937f9830c9d29">
                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">would include the participation of PRC trust funds created within the IDB; or</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="id66b1ff6c71af4df48d6831bec11be612">
                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>after a review is conducted under paragraph (1), the United States Executive Director or the Secretary of the Treasury determines poses a risk to the national and economic security interests of the United States; and</text>
                    </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="id2cce0a1b45544c62aa3cab4fad33add9">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the issuance, sale, or transfer of additional shares of stock in the IDB to the PRC in a manner that increases the voting share of the PRC at the IDB relative to the voting share of the United States.</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="id546ed2c912574adab194e69f67d0f973">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>Encouraging Inter-American Development Bank procurement from United States and
                partner country entities</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Director at the Inter-American Development Bank to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States to advocate for—</text>
            <paragraph id="id35c9d52625fe4cfd93639ad26cdfcbf5">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>increased internal and external capacity-building by the IDB to encourage procurement by entities from the United States and member countries of the IDB that are allies or partners of the United States, rather than entities from the People’s Republic of China; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idc010a80521e84cdcb541cc648792c384">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>implementing IDB procurement policies that prioritize value for money, transparency, and integrity over lowest upfront cost.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="ide4a36f8736ea4f73be373fde24e193f2">
            <enum>5.</enum>
            <header>United States Development Finance Corporation collaboration with Inter-American
                Development Bank</header>
            <subsection id="id885c3f65211649d8b036a8e3fe46fece">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Director at the Inter-American Development Bank to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States to encourage collaboration between the IDB and the United States International Development Finance Corporation (in this section referred to as the <quote>Corporation</quote>) on projects, financing, loans, or grants in IDB borrowing member countries.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idff2433243d1641bc9bb1b761636453e6">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Report required</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes the following:</text>
                <paragraph id="id0f0415c6beff42ab98029d7bb59ab60e">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>An overview of collaboration between the Corporation and the IDB since the signing in 2019 of a memorandum of understanding between the IDB and the Corporation's predecessor agency with respect to investments in projects in Latin America and the Caribbean.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id77d556c6056d4c8bbcf7caefed2de5ac">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>An analysis of potential areas to expand collaboration between the Corporation and the IDB in IDB borrowing member countries.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

