<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7B369D3B5206440AAD8E232752CA7C85" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5785 IH: Voluntary Grazing Permit Retirement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5785</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251017">October 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To expand the authorization of voluntary Federal grazing permit retirement, provide increased flexibility for Federal grazing permittees, promote the equitable resolution or avoidance of conflicts on Federal lands managed by the Department of Agriculture or the Department of the Interior, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9EB8E32E586444C391F973D8130B5AC0" style="OLC"><section id="H058CCA074A2F47C0BE3B27943837F023" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H35663CF969D04CEB945D6E7A8C4CDD78"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Voluntary Grazing Permit Retirement Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8DDA2AA3701742D0941E378110A8C964"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H058CCA074A2F47C0BE3B27943837F023" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF9EDF432E9324FE8B4F706F5BF599B76" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HBD2CC4C32EF34EC3A3718FE5D1FB0456" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB7CE41920DDD4F46BB5C22098FCCA235" level="section">Sec. 4. Voluntary grazing permit retirement program.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2B32D5CE3BFA4855958A63031BB05B8B" level="section">Sec. 5. Effect of waiver of grazing permit.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="HF9EDF432E9324FE8B4F706F5BF599B76"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HE7EF3E11CC1644288AE7E8D3A566D483"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Voluntary grazing permit retirement is a successful land management tool that has been authorized by Congress for specific purposes and in numerous areas throughout the 16 Western States, including Death Valley National Park, Capitol Reef National Park, Arches National Park, Cascade-Siskiyou National Monument, Oregon Caves National Monument and Preserve, and Wilderness Areas in the Owyhee Canyonlands and Boulder-White Clouds.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4020DE23F614958B5DF67211FDE5E31"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Expanding the authority for voluntary grazing permit retirement to include all Federal lands managed by the Department of Agriculture and the Department of the Interior in the 16 Western States will aid in the resolution of land and resource management conflicts and provide Federal grazing permittees and lessees with increased flexibility and opportunities when making decisions about the future of their livestock operations.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HBD2CC4C32EF34EC3A3718FE5D1FB0456"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HF87D88C6F59B4C98BBBBBBC5F427ABD6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administratively retired grazing allotment</header><text>The term <term>administratively retired grazing allotment</term> means a grazing allotment, or portion of a grazing allotment, on Federal lands managed by the Secretary that is or becomes vacant or closed due to the voluntary waiver of the grazing permit or lease by the holder of the grazing permit or lease issued by the Secretary with the intention of permanently ending livestock grazing on that grazing allotment, or portion of a grazing allotment, as a result of an agreement with a third party.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CA11781F61C44F593D984DFE2F7F6C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commercial livestock grazing; livestock grazing</header><text>The terms <term>commercial livestock grazing</term> and <term>livestock grazing</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H77910113B0714269A48793CB02A67C75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>mean the grazing of domestic livestock on Federal lands as authorized by a grazing permit or lease; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1252256FA8A64C4B915E9FAEDD11BCA2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>do not include the grazing of beasts of burden on Federal lands while used for recreational or administrative purposes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H65FC5EBBEFC447B2B0066F90A1F520F7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grazing allotment</header><text>The term <term>grazing allotment</term> means the designated portion of Federal land upon which domestic livestock are authorized to graze by a grazing permit or lease.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5636DD4EDAA4A22B7986AE2315F1B47"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Grazing permit; lease</header><text>The terms <term>grazing permit or lease</term> and <term>grazing permit and lease</term> mean any document authorizing the use of Federal lands for the purpose of commercial livestock grazing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F09352E62374D7A835846ACD4628965"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Permittee; lessee</header><text>The terms <term>permittee or lessee</term> and <term>permittee and lessee</term> mean a livestock operator that holds a valid existing grazing permit or lease.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A0785F229974908AFFD1030472D958C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Range developments</header><text>The term <term>range developments</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H7B84D10606DE4E7885C66F565606AEC0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means structures, fences, and other permanent fixtures placed on Federal lands for the furtherance of the purpose of livestock grazing; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE18A2A960E074EF0A818C75DDB2E70A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include rolling stock, livestock, and diversions of water from Federal lands onto non-Federal lands.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBB0290BFAFF4441B6CB78CA46C93E96"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretaries</header><text>The term <term>Secretaries</term> refers to the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51F890793BEE415095CEDCDF9545AF25"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of the Interior, as appropriate to the administration of a grazing permit or lease.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FB1CC9693114BDFB3AF61564763D712"><enum>(9)</enum><header>16 western states</header><text>The term <term>16 Western States</term> means Arizona, California, Colorado, Idaho, Kansas, Montana, Nebraska, Nevada, New Mexico, North Dakota, Oklahoma, Oregon, South Dakota, Utah, Washington, and Wyoming.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HB7CE41920DDD4F46BB5C22098FCCA235"><enum>4.</enum><header>Voluntary grazing permit retirement program</header><subsection id="H185D9FB46C3041C49AD1684BC7165F13"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Voluntary waiver of grazing permit or lease</header><paragraph id="HCB3F1D3A06CA459B8DB4640263CDF26F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Acceptance by Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the limitation set forth in subsection (c)(1), the Secretary shall accept, on a first-come, first-served basis, any grazing permit or lease related to Federal land in the 16 Western States that is voluntarily waived by a grazing permittee or lessee with the intention of permanently ending livestock grazing on that grazing allotment or on a portion of that grazing allotment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BDA64701E5543DEB38B0A38826DD822"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Secretary shall immediately terminate any grazing permit or lease accepted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC2EC7EC7F5F44699605D3A112FDF4E9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No new grazing permit or lease</header><text>With respect to each grazing permit or lease voluntarily waived under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H871D22A342BA43F2BD56285A9310C332"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not issue any new grazing permit or lease within the grazing allotment covered by the grazing permit or lease; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C93E5FE997141C2817ACFFA41211EB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure a permanent end to livestock grazing on the grazing allotment covered by the grazing permit or lease.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H96C66920C167442AA6615D420CF9FE3E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver of grazing permit or lease on common allotments</header><paragraph id="H1CCA690C4EAE499D99C4A6AF7E86204C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a grazing allotment or portion of a grazing allotment covered by a grazing permit or lease that is waived under subsection (a) is also covered in part or in whole by another grazing permit or lease that is not waived, the Secretary shall reduce the level of commercial livestock grazing on the grazing allotment to reflect the waiver.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC6E3664FBDE4AF493BFF3FD5E0801B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorized level</header><text>To ensure that there is a permanent reduction in the level of livestock grazing on the land covered by the grazing permit or lease waived under subsection (a), the Secretary shall not allow grazing to exceed the level established under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE2CD9566AAA2496EA69BBB3720AAE6CC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation</header><paragraph id="H0585AF49F68447AB8607BC842F74C817"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretaries shall accept per fiscal year under this section—</text><subparagraph id="H58B17D71628D4FCBBE8CE660459628C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not more than 100 grazing permits, in the aggregate, for all of the 16 Western States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3AAD563F6264D5ABB451497CF0E6658"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not more than 25 grazing permits for land located in whole or in part in any individual State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H25B8B423EFC7413081ECA149D8F43CD9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This limitation shall not apply to administratively retired grazing allotments as of the effective date of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4C753086D3814870B66825B836C1CDF9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administratively retired grazing allotments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to grazing allotments administratively retired before the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H02F032663F324742BFBAAC71BA2C00DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not issue any new grazing permit or lease within the grazing allotment covered by the grazing permit or lease; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D86A84C16BC499FBA246739936EF370"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure a permanent end to livestock grazing on the grazing allotment covered by the grazing permit or lease.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2B32D5CE3BFA4855958A63031BB05B8B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effect of waiver of grazing permit</header><subsection id="H257896C9815E410A89E70D4EAE9A5764"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Effect on range developments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A permittee or lessee who waives a grazing permit or lease to the Secretary under section 4 shall be deemed to have waived any claim to all range developments on land covered by the grazing permit or lease waived, notwithstanding any other provision of law.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAB7FD8B4AD5945FBB2E4D06BBD1394AA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Securing retired allotments against unauthorized use</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that grazing allotments retired from grazing under this Act are rendered reasonably secure from trespass grazing by domestic livestock.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9B84D88231AA40EA89B878167551A5C4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Relation to other authority</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect the authority of the Secretary to modify or terminate any grazing permit or lease in accordance with other law.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6CBBDC86A60149D3A560E61E3E692DE2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Relation to valid existing rights</header><text>Nothing in this Act affects the allocation, ownership, interest, or control, in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act, of any water, water right, or any other valid existing right held by the United States, an Indian Tribe, or a State, county, or municipality, or a private individual, partnership, or corporation.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

