<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H05EE9F2AEC7543358F27E0395A4201EE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1634 IH: ThinkDIFFERENTLY About Disability Employment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1634</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250226">February 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for a memorandum of understanding between the Small Business Administration and the National Council on Disability to increase employment opportunities for individuals with disabilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3F34C3EE770848B7A149B6F10108AC51" style="OLC"><section id="HFC3C5C3C241C4398A155235D3C76EDAB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>ThinkDIFFERENTLY About Disability Employment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA3771DE8579F41038062B01CAB76B404"><enum>2.</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding to increase employment opportunities for individuals with disabilities</header><subsection id="H111387B9F69E4E9ABD97AE5DDE27E212" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Small Business Administration, in consultation with the Chair of the National Council on Disability, shall—</text><paragraph id="H834E57090D934D9FB1F04CCA2BEDB46D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide assistance to individuals with disabilities who desire to become entrepreneurs or to be self-employed;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AB1D1098E934A10B22C8BC165A76FAB" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">help individuals with disabilities find employment at small business concerns (as defined under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>));</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3066C6DCCA9B4A03A415233E719240E3" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist small business concerns with hiring individuals with disabilities and with accessibility issues applicable to individuals with disabilities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H81104B0278CB4F93800E4D1DC6D9DB85" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding or agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, in consultation with the Chair, shall carry out and coordinate the activities described in subsection (a) by entering into one or more memoranda of understanding or other appropriate agreements.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5EAFF3FDBB7F4AF5AE3AEC4D5A0AA588"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Outreach and education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the activities described in subsection (a), the Administrator, in consultation with the Chair, shall conduct outreach and education about such activities.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCF73A9D84B344F7DA71787B7AE9E09C3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator, in consultation with the Chair, shall submit to Congress a report on activities carried out pursuant to any memorandum or agreement described in subsection (b) that includes the following:</text><paragraph id="HB8B4B1EEA16A4248BF781D301FD6C687" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how the Administrator, in consultation with the Chair, carried out such activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AE3C8656D7940D2A6060D1ED5DFC77F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of opportunities to expand the technical capabilities of the Small Business Administration in carrying out such activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H470F9E4355574392BED723DFD3B4FE50"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of achievements under any such memorandum or agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8346C37528494E2390B46E2748CCB123"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the plans of the Administrator, in consultation with the Chair, to continue activities to expand employment opportunities for individuals with disabilities.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7179280FB5784191AE234A53149FF18E" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Compliance with CUTGO</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional amounts are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act or the amendments made by this Act. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

