<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFDB7185DAAC748B19848D6B64C773B94" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4309 IH: National Concussion and Traumatic Brain Injury Clearinghouse Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4309</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250710">July 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the establishment and maintenance of a National Concussion and Traumatic Brain Injury Clearinghouse, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA3A2307C14C342C6AD4A59EF0A0FFE17" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7A70A6A06D374339A09616742FE1A2E2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Concussion and Traumatic Brain Injury Clearinghouse Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HBBFB6E6721CB43489520DF10253D962B"><enum>2.</enum><header>National concussion and traumatic brain injury clearinghouse</header> <subsection id="H65E6C222B25B46DDBB36457C2AA4138A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal official designated under subsection (b) (referred to in this section as the <quote>designated Federal official</quote>) shall establish and maintain a clearinghouse of concussion and traumatic brain injury best practices, medical knowledge, appropriate certification, and research, to be known as the National Concussion and Traumatic Brain Injury Clearinghouse.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H779D6848C86B4163B8014471CAE135E8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation of Federal official</header> 
<paragraph id="H7AB00491FE734263B48BEF5BA10C1F7A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and the Secretary of Labor shall jointly designate one of such officials to establish and maintain the clearinghouse under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4BA59F43F7FC49A49E18DA7322E269B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deemed designation in absence of agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a Federal official is not designated under paragraph (1) on or before the last day of the 60-day period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall be deemed to be the designated Federal official for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H06118ABA12DD40C9BEBD9DAFE0EF40D7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Design</header><text>The designated Federal official shall design the clearinghouse under this section to provide vetted, high-quality information on concussion and traumatic brain injury, and associated comorbidities—</text> <paragraph id="H645D0F87C2D54653AAE781D9A8F5BEFC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to medical professionals so they may access reliable best-practice information to provide appropriate care for their patients; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBF8F94B758224B928E720407AF7F41A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to patients and other stakeholders so they may—</text> <subparagraph id="H4E59D54FC6044643A9E20D48FC2BE333"><enum>(A)</enum><text>easily find appropriate medical professionals; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2FC4DE80853D4C37ACD20B5F9869B490"><enum>(B)</enum><text>access high-quality information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA59CE6DB53784D7ABDC7CB8EF5D63D31"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Arrangements with other entities</header><text>In carrying out this section, the designated Federal official may disseminate information through arrangements with nonprofit organizations, consumer groups, Federal, State, or local agencies, or the media.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2587EA1416874FB4A2CA1201869E6EFC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The designated Federal official shall establish the clearinghouse under this section not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

