<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4B5A3495D5CA4CEA97F26FE5E40A8AF2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2718 IH: Family Notification of Death, Injury, or Illness in Custody Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2718</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish Federal policies and procedures to notify the next-of-kin or other emergency contact upon the death, or serious illness or serious injury, of an individual in Federal custody, to provide model policies for States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes to implement and enforce similar policies and procedures, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6F50B5FF5A934F69BE4FB59CA81A5A38" style="OLC"><section id="H6D6A5E2C8B884DF9B57858CCB6AAADD9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Family Notification of Death, Injury, or Illness in Custody Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H593711E4E025414B94A4AA191220621A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HFCB402DAC5FE411981AF928F304D26C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the event an individual dies or becomes seriously ill or injured while being detained, arrested, or while in law enforcement custody, their family members deserve to be notified in a timely and compassionate manner. Such notification is necessary to uphold the basic human dignity of incarcerated people, a concept rooted in the Eighteenth Amendment and Due Process Clause of the Fourteenth Amendment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC9842AB157F4DFBBE7E0F11FD8E6B91"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The lack of a national standard governing notification of death, illness, and injury that occur in prisons, jails and police custody can lead to inhumane treatment of incarcerated people and their loved ones. Poor communication regarding the death of a loved one may exacerbate the grief and other physical and psychological reactions of surviving relatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCA528C795324C2A97BEA3F3B6E5AF6D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>On Easter Sunday of 2016, Wakiesha Wilson was found dead in her cell in the Los Angeles Police Department’s Metropolitan Detention Center. Her mother called the police to determine Ms. Wilson’s whereabouts but was not initially given any information. It was not until March 30, 3 days later, when Ms. Wilson’s mother was told to call the coroner that she learned her daughter had died.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEE125F3B3B14810BF45E06B0352772A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In Georgia, Jennifer Bradley testified before the General Assembly in September 2021 that she is still waiting for answers about the stabbing death of her 23-year-old son at Macon State Prison in March 2020. She told the committee that it was an incarcerated person, not a prison official, who first notified her of her son’s death. As of the hearing, she had not yet received his belongings.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H285FEADE96AE434F96311A88372DEDD2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Jordan Fisher found out about the death of her father, Thomas Willis, at Valdosta State Prison in Georgia when a letter she had sent her father was returned back to her stamped: <quote>Return to sender: inmate dead</quote>. She was unable to obtain further information about her father’s death from prison officials. What information she uncovered came from letters from her father’s cellmate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71F52A20318842C1B64E6A25CFEC33AC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Sara Roth did not receive notice from the Clayton County Jail in Georgia that her mother, Regina Salman, had fallen and suffered serious injuries, including a collapsed lung that required hospitalization. When her mother’s longtime boyfriend went to visit the jail, he was told Ms. Salman was no longer there but was not provided additional information. More than a month later, the hospital called Ms. Roth and informed her that her mother was on a ventilator and dying of a severe brain tumor. Her mother was taken off the ventilator 3 days later without ever regaining consciousness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18E021907F484C7F9BD397E53DE24F25"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The failure to release autopsy results can prevent families and loved ones from seeking justice for wrongful deaths. After Harvey Hill was arrested for trespassing and booked into jail in Canton, Mississippi, guards beat him severely and kicked him repeatedly in the head. Mr. Hill died in an isolation cell. The State medical examiner’s report recorded his death as a homicide, but it was not released until 25 months after his death and 13 months after the statute of limitations expired for assault.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F29C3A89B5F4DC7A34BAE7E232F89A8"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In recent years, deaths in custody have reached the highest levels on record. In 2018, two years prior to the rapid spread of COVID–19 behind bars, at least 1,120 people died while detained in local jails and 4,513 people died in the custody of State and Federal prisons. This represented an all-time high in the number of deaths in both local jails and State prisons since the Bureau of Justice Statistics (BJS) started collecting mortality data.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EAEE496C5E44DEFB8C2B85840BAC0B6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The spread of COVID–19 behind bars significantly increased the death toll of people in custody. At least 2,700 people are estimated to have died of COVID–19 in prisons, jails and detention centers, and the COVID–19 death rate in State and Federal prisons between April 2020 and April 2021 was more than double that of the general population. This is likely a significant undercount, given uneven and inconsistent reporting. In some instances, people are released from local jails to die in hospitals, whether of COVID–19 or other causes, and their deaths are not recorded as a death in custody.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HCED9B0C124094DB2B89B1743987C63DE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H7DD4E0F42757453B8F7F68E9382D5E12"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Custodial record</header><text>The term <term>custodial record</term> means the central file of an individual in custody.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2316CC0A86224DCA91680AE987A24048"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Detention agency</header><text>The term <term>detention agency</term> means any government agency, including a law enforcement agency or correctional agency, that has the authority to detain people for violations or alleged violations of criminal or civil law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3F3C548FA2848599B5679F8954DC984"><enum>(3)</enum><header>In custody of a detention agency</header><text>The term <term>in the custody of a detention agency</term> includes, but is not limited to, a person who is detained, under arrest, or is in the process of being arrested, is en route to be incarcerated, or is incarcerated at a jail, prison, boot camp prison, contract correctional facility, community correctional facility, or other correctional facility (including any juvenile detention facility).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA202DBF62A2E4288A96D1483E32B7D1E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Taking custody</header><text>The term <term>taking custody</term> means the point at which the detention agency takes custody or control of an individual, including during or prior to booking or intake screening as a new commitment, in transfer from another institution, as a court return, as a return from a writ, or as a holdover.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HABFF7112EB7E4FF8A79D2B3A9AABB218"><enum>4.</enum><header>Emergency contact notification policies and procedures</header><subsection id="HF8BF01D3B09B4C3BBFCC0EB343E1C0C8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Emergency contact notification policies and procedures</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall, consistent with the requirements in this section—</text><paragraph id="H5491CA187B1C451E946D5E431B2998A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>implement policies and procedures for the detention agencies of the Department of Justice to notify the next-of-kin or other emergency contact in the event of the death, or serious illness or serious injury, of an individual in the custody of a detention agency of the Department of Justice; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24A206329415402BAFDD62938802C1C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop and distribute model policies and procedures for detention agencies of States, territories of the United States, Tribes, and units of local government to notify the next-of-kin or other emergency contact in the event of the death, or serious illness or serious injury, of an individual in the custody of that detention agency, and provide assistance to such detention agencies so that the agencies may implement such procedures or substantially similar processes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD2342E0237F24F25832FB9A8A5550D80"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of emergency contact notification policies and procedures</header><paragraph id="H7E8834C461C740A8A15FA970E20F196A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Emergency contact information</header><text>The policies and procedures described in subsection (a) shall address the collection and use of emergency contact information for individuals in custody, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="HC0E7DDDC9AFD487996F1409886885FF3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Emergency contact information requested upon taking custody</header><text>In the case of an individual taken into the custody of a detention agency, the agency shall, at the time of taking custody, ask the individual—</text><clause id="H1D6EE946C1D24C2592A0F61AC7B9DC9D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for the name, last known address, telephone number, and email of any person or persons who shall be notified in the event of the individual in custody’s death or serious illness or serious injury, and who are authorized to receive the individual’s body;</text></clause><clause id="HB00385E27D50424A89CC7FC4E094D77B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the order in which the individual in custody prefers the emergency contacts described in clause (i) to be notified;</text></clause><clause id="H7169FFEA479D4DEDA13D91A1F367E474"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>whether the individual in custody would like a faith leader to participate in such notification process and, if so, of what denomination; and</text></clause><clause id="HD5842C379FF04D9CBE012DC291AD7875"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>whether the individual has in place a medical proxy decision maker or medical power of attorney, advanced directive, or do not resuscitate order.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBABACD0A249C4693827B9DE749A94C4D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Emergency contact list modification</header><text>The detention agency shall permit an individual in custody to modify their emergency contact information at any time and provide a periodic opportunity, but not less than annually, for individuals in custody to update their emergency contact information and to fill out a medical power of attorney, health care proxy, advanced directive, a do not resuscitate order, or any other similar document that complies with the State law in the location of detention.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA43D68673BB4D51935F772BF72CBD20"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Disclosure of purpose and permissible uses of emergency contact information</header><text>The detention agency shall provide the individual in custody information about the purpose and permissible uses of the emergency contact information provided pursuant to this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DC038D08B1C4835A947E0A3583F7074"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Standardized emergency contact form</header><text>The policies and procedures described in subsection (a) shall include a template form for recording the individual in custody’s next-of-kin or other emergency contact and other information under subsection (b)(1)(A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CA56FDA208C4F539F1655D1EC10E7A9"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Custodial record</header><text>The detention agency shall record the individual’s next-of-kin or other emergency contact information on the form described in subparagraph (D) and include that form in the individual’s custodial record.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB3E70D81CC245A0908F0128C735B160"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification requirements for death, serious illness, and serious injury while in custody</header><text>The policies and procedures described in subsection (a) shall describe the notification requirements in the event an individual dies, is seriously injured or becomes seriously ill while in the custody of a detention agency, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="H4F44DEC26C37419A92BC55A1BCD21C2E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notification timeframe</header><clause id="H35005527AF1C4E98A14F511DD36CEA6B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Notification of death</header><text>In the event an individual dies while in the custody of the detention agency, the detention agency shall notify the individual’s emergency contact not later than 12 hours after the declaration of death and between the hours of 6:00 a.m. and to midnight local time.</text></clause><clause id="H140921BAC7A84D1D8E4F4F364626CD5E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Notification of serious illness or serious injury</header><text>Notice to the next-of-kin or other emergency contact shall be made as soon as practicable after the serious injury or serious illness occurs, but in any event not later than 48 hours from such determination and between the hours of 6:00 a.m. and to midnight local time. The notification should occur prior to any required medical procedure, where practical and if such timeframe will not delay treatment, but in any event, not later than any medical discharge or clearance.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10F6DDD600EF4E59B5D3E16A9ED418CA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Death notification information required</header><clause id="HDB54D85F77F64D99A1F85CE15E4D4142"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Such notification shall include all pertinent circumstances surrounding the death, including—</text><subclause id="H7BFC63AE28124809805ABF9AD6259D6A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the official time of death;</text></subclause><subclause id="HA18466AC2DFF4AF7BB69C6BE56FACC6C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the cause of death (if determined); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H211EEB3D3B7E4C0FBBAF50757E585EC6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>whether the individual’s death is under investigation and the reason for opening an investigation.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H41413091FA994FB795B9871D2769D467"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>No cause of death determined</header><text>If the cause of death has not been determined at the time of the notification, the detention agency shall follow up with the individual’s emergency contact once such a determination has been made to provide that information within 24 hours of such determination.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25F38666EF8F499D9871ABF46D404BCD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Serious illness or serious injury notification information required</header><text>Such notification shall include pertinent details of the serious injury or serious illness, including—</text><clause id="H791150E4375342B3B3AB628020A564A6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the cause and nature of the serious injury or serious illness event;</text></clause><clause id="H63D279C1B4DE4A19BE6655DDA4F9DAE1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether the individual is incapacitated, unconscious, or unable to speak;</text></clause><clause id="H0356D0E88D514A7EA4303986583BE8A4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>whether any medical procedures or lifesaving measures were, or will be, performed in response to the incident; and</text></clause><clause id="HA62EB307F488406F876FC79A4D068508"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>contact information of the facility and provider that is providing medical treatment.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6806219AE684D22A5955B2AFB1EAE5D"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Definition of serious illness or serious injury</header><text>The policies and procedures described in subsection (a) shall define when a medical event, episode, condition, accident, or other incident constitutes a serious illness or serious injury. In defining such term, the Attorney General shall require notification at least in cases in which—</text><clause id="H40913FDF02FB4391AEE4ACBFA3028101"><enum>(i)</enum><text>without immediate treatment for the condition, death is imminent;</text></clause><clause id="H1220C0B7F6A342898061EBF077852DC8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>admission to a hospital is required;</text></clause><clause id="HA16903C7EA264F88A64C81BA7E8F9C96"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an individual is unconscious or incapacitated such that they are incapable of providing consent for medical treatment; and</text></clause><clause id="H1E4C3694E1154B2FB7CCCE50F6D481B8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an individual has been diagnosed with a terminal illness.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H744470502C944364837131094AC67342"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Additional requirements related to notification</header><text>The policies and procedures described in subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><clause id="H258BF4471AB544F680214E835223B50A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Compassionate and professional notification</header><text>Standards for providing notification in a compassionate and professional manner to minimize confusion and trauma suffered by the next-of-kin or other emergency contact, including—</text><subclause id="H8A03D1A08FB842AB877590B326C428F4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a description of what information cannot be included in a voicemail, such as notification of death or serious illness;</text></subclause><subclause id="HC8AE1FB347184A8AB02012370E35218A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an offer for an in-person or virtual face-to-face meeting in the event a notification of a death in custody is provided to the emergency contact during a live conversation over the phone; and </text></subclause><subclause id="HDDEBDADAB1DD4E1E8E0E19FA4163BF4E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a requirement that notifications are provided in a private setting and, when practicable, in person and by a mental health professional, designated case worker, or chaplain trained in notification best practices.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC304375005604974976B0F856027C62A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notification opt out</header><text>Standards to ensure that notifications should not occur where the individual is advised of their right to notification and instructs the agency not to do so, or where they request the opportunity to provide such notification personally, in which case the detention agency shall provide an opportunity for the individual to deliver such notification within the time period identified above.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB64F89AE016140E0923FB167437A0F24"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Belongings and remains</header><text>Standards for handling the belongings and remains of an individual who died in custody, including—</text><subparagraph id="H502EEC54FB9841BB9FF1E626D123588E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>returning the individual’s belongings and remains, if desired, to the next-of-kin or other emergency contact and providing at least 7 days for the emergency contact to make a decision as to the disposition of the belongings and remains;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4724564AB08941F5A931722F8439B4BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>following up with the individual’s next-of-kin or other emergency contact in the event of a death in custody with the outcome of any critical incident review or other internal investigations not available at the time of the initial notification; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F9A286FAF7249BD9E10F57F6290C91B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>documenting and maintaining within the individual’s custodial record any incident of unclaimed or a rejected claim for the body or property of the deceased, including a detailed description of where any unclaimed body and property have been disposed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H844BC64D2F75432AB846DC1AF8A8BF04"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Documentation of attempts</header><text>Requirements that each notification attempt shall be documented and maintained within the custodial record, including—</text><subparagraph id="HA43D4D738B194218889A9B9B21D2276E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the staff name and corresponding agency or department contact information for each individual responsible for carrying out the notification;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD018436A0D9843459D590C8721F92C26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date and time of each successful and unsuccessful contact; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E6B2860B84E4802968956651EC642A2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the name and contact information to which each attempt was made, and any reason for failed or unsuccessful contact.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H081C1964A82142E48B1F67A8201B4384"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Additional procedures in the event of serious illness or injury</header><text>Standards to ensure that detention agencies—</text><subparagraph id="HA119C0F8B81E433FAB94E6CB4415DD53"><enum>(A)</enum><text>implement medical proxy decision maker or medical power of attorney, advanced directive, or <quote>do not resuscitate</quote> orders;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H414B65DD2AED4D3E82F6DED1488D8B9F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide meaningful opportunity for communication between the emergency contact and medical staff caring for an individual in custody;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A18297C213E4CFB845491314E7505B6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure emergency contacts are given the meaningful opportunity to visit with a seriously ill or seriously injured individual in custody, with the opportunity for in-person visitation when practicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF852375F7C904E008BA9F0E31BE151DD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide information about an individual’s emergency contact to an outside hospital facility, and allow the hospital to follow its established bylaws concerning communication with next-of-kin or other emergency contacts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC90CB9109FA54DEF8A40443BA1CA9D94"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Autopsy notifications</header><text>Requirements that, in the event an autopsy is performed following a death in custody—</text><subparagraph id="H89D896A2E2CE4A919D8F078457B8797D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the next-of-kin or other emergency contact shall be informed not later than 12 hours after any determination that an autopsy shall be performed and given the option to receive the results of the autopsy described in subparagraph (B). Such notification shall include the reason that the autopsy is being performed and the procedures by which the next-of-kin or other emergency contact can obtain the autopsy report; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1495F8FF138D4FD59A60558C78015295"><enum>(B)</enum><text>pursuant to subparagraph (A), a copy of the autopsy report and results shall be made available to the next-of-kin or emergency contact upon completion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC0531DC1530D4D5AB5C948838263107D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Written notification plan</header><text>The policies and procedures described in subsection (a) shall instruct detention agencies to develop a written notification plan, or revise an existing written notification plan, that provides for notification of a death, serious illness, or serious injury of an individual in custody that conforms with the policies described in subsection (b). Such written notification plans shall be published on the detention agency’s website and made accessible to individuals in the agency’s custody through inclusion in any intake information, manuals, or other materials distributed or made available to individuals upon being taken into custody.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5885142FDE8449DDAD6A82CC699E6A6A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><paragraph id="H21739E7A3D794E77B1F85ACA81EEAC5B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>DOJ support of state and local implementation of model policies</header><text>To support implementation of the model policies and procedures described in subsection (a)(2), the Attorney General shall provide ongoing online training and directed outreach to law enforcement, prosecution and defense agencies through national and State membership associations and by other means.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD242E5E480F846FF9E9E4B02855FB06C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication of emergency contact policies and procedures</header><text>The Attorney General, acting through the Assistant Attorney General of the Office of Justice Programs, shall publish the policies and procedures described in subsection (b) on its website and shall include a copy of the procedures described subsection (b)(1) in any intake information, manuals, or other materials distributed or made available to individuals upon being taken into custody of a detention agency of the Department of Justice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F37D207D41A4669B8FD37B10A1684EB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Intergovernmental service contracts</header><text>Any Department of Justice detention agency, including the U.S. Marshals Service, that contracts with State, municipality, Tribal, private, or other entities to house individuals in custody shall require adoption of the procedures or substantially similar processes as described in subsection (b)(2) as a condition of such contract or contract renewal as soon as practicable but not later than 7 days of taking the individual into custody.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF41D8EE2F40D421FA8967760F0F2FB58"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Department of justice office of inspector general to monitor compliance with notification and communication requirements</header><text>The Attorney General shall appoint an Ombudsman within the Department of Justice with the authority to receive and investigate complaints regarding the failure to provide the notifications required in the Act, and inadequate notifications, and the failure to provide opportunities for communication and visitation in accordance with this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0D4FE884617E4559B91F3F51BEAE0A73"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text>Information collected under this Act by a detention agency, or any agent working on behalf of such detention agency, may not be disclosed or used for any purpose except as provided in this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD11027618D18408CA848A94B5C19F1A7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Voluntary collection</header><paragraph id="H8B55C49A90EB4B59923E2F87D1000BE4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to require the individual in custody to provide the emergency contact information described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H160DA6F2E8C54448925B6F0DB6C2ADD3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No coercion</header><text>The detention agency may not—</text><subparagraph id="HC54455A257594FC0864CF340BE0B3DA3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>attempt to coerce or persuade the individual in custody to provide the information described in subsection (a); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A7F717119A44E9EAE84160E0316C60B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>impose a penalty, fine, or fee on the individual for the individual’s failure or refusal to provide the information requested or for providing information that is later determined to be inaccurate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H379BCBFFDF50453C8D6BBD02ECE47FDA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Inadmissibility</header><text>No information disclosed or used in violation of this Act may be admitted into any State, Federal, or other court as evidence or for any other purpose, except in the case of information that has been discovered through any independent means.</text></subsection></section><section id="HF4F091CECC0647FE997DCBA2F227847E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to create any legal or financial obligation on the part of any individual designated as a next-of-kin or other emergency contact under this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

