<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FLO25820-D7X-GH-VN4"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2887 IS: Route 66 National Historic Trail Designation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2887</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250918" legis-day="20250916">September 18 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the National Trails System Act to designate the Route 66 National Historic Trail, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H6E57838FEFE54129B06417F4042D7249"><section section-type="section-one" id="H5C97FF5DC5A54CDD8391E5B8F82CD8E0"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Route 66 National Historic Trail Designation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H2FBB9E1EB691404DA3971B022F026AFA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation of the Route 66 National Historic Trail</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5(a) of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1244">16 U.S.C. 1244(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc02a6d32e4a946e6ac4db299ac1a27f5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating the second paragraph (31) (relating to the Butterfield Overland National Historic Trail) as paragraph (32); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9401f7804ebb4dc5b4ce1c4d622f09fb"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id535F4FFEFC23496C9368AF5011FB2411"><paragraph id="H6CE023C513D345E387A9BEE1C9C7E81F"><enum>(33)</enum><header>Route 66 National Historic Trail</header><subparagraph id="H5C698B6C062D463EB2A0BB3543B3F0D6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Route 66 National Historic Trail, a trail that includes all the alignments of U.S. Highway 66 in existence between 1926 and 1985, extending along a route of approximately 2,400 miles from Chicago, Illinois, to Santa Monica, California, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Route 66 National Historic Trail, Proposed Route</quote>, numbered P26/141,279, and dated December 2017.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F47A930D3404DCF97BE616DE48DABC2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability of map</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The map described in subparagraph (A) shall be on file and available for public inspection at the Department of the Interior.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25B5B9192EDD41D7A242D2D3A74AE5C5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Administration</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76614c3a49e14ec68b030257ee24a8ba"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall administer the Route 66 National Historic Trail in a manner that respects and maintains the idiosyncratic nature of the Route 66 National Historic Trail.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd501aeae4eb44a339d62598c226eb2dd"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Tribal consultation</header><text>Consistent with Executive Order 13175 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5301">25 U.S.C. 5301</external-xref> note; relating to consultation and coordination with Indian Tribal governments) and all other applicable Federal law, the Secretary of the Interior shall conduct active, meaningful, and timely consultation with all affected Indian Tribes prior to undertaking an activity with respect to the Route 66 National Historic Trail that would have substantial direct impacts on 1 or more Indian Tribes.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id869485a4ece5461e87c6af829f9f91fa"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Land acquisition</header><text>The United States shall not acquire for the Route 66 National Historic Trail any land or interest in land that—</text><clause id="id5fb7f3c920434cf4afe0e16077c9819d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is located outside the exterior boundary of any federally managed area without the consent of the owner of the land or interest in land; or</text></clause><clause id="id0ded652287fc4f94a3b384d1f2703dcb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>extends more than an average of <fraction>1/4</fraction> of a mile on either side of the Route 66 National Historic Trail.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E28BF71D3A649A4BA1848D011DCCE5E"><enum>(E)</enum><header>No buffer zone created</header><clause id="idB363C3192D364532A029213D6F75EDB0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this paragraph, the acquisition of land or an interest in land authorized by this paragraph, or any management plan for the Route 66 National Historic Trail creates or shall be construed to create a buffer zone outside the Route 66 National Historic Trail.</text></clause><clause id="id6B7064A5E1484B8282CC5C9920B75CAE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Outside activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The fact that an activity or use on land outside the Route 66 National Historic Trail can be seen, heard, or detected from the Route 66 National Historic Trail, including from any land or interest in land acquired for the Route 66 National Historic Trail subject to the limitations described in subparagraph (D), shall not preclude, limit, control, regulate, or determine the conduct or management of the activity or use.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FD11ED81AF54A2F82608AE55DB53CD8"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Effect on energy development, production, transportation, or transmission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this paragraph, the acquisition of land or an interest in land authorized by this paragraph, or any management plan for the Route 66 National Historic Trail shall prohibit, hinder, or disrupt the development, production, transportation, or transmission of energy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A54E6FD60D94088A8EEDDBA0B3AD6F1"><enum>(G)</enum><header>No Eminent Domain or Condemnation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this paragraph, the Secretary of the Interior may not use eminent domain or condemnation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA3A4C996F7E542FDA099E4B7F325761C"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Not a designation of <quote>lands in the National Park System</quote></header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the designation of the Route 66 National Historic Trail by this paragraph shall not have the effect of designating the Route 66 National Historic Trail or any land on which the Route 66 National Historic Trail is located as <quote>lands in the National Park System</quote> for purposes of section 28(b)(1) of the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/185">30 U.S.C. 185(b)(1)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6D612EA2E2B8466EA020DCC7C719CEA8"><enum>(I)</enum><header>No new authorities or permits</header><clause commented="no" id="idd2ea61111bd84607a22dcd8f7d1106ea"><enum>(i)</enum><header>No effect on authority To Grant easements or rights-of-way</header><subclause commented="no" id="id33AD4D3198374BAEA57A5D2A2D3BCF41"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the designation of the Route 66 National Historic Trail by this paragraph shall not alter or affect the existing authority of any Federal, State, or local agency or official to grant easements or rights-of-way over, under, across, or along any portion of the area designated as the Route 66 National Historic Trail.</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="idE830D9FBA4CB4EF78470617F0A15BFB3"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Authority of heads of Federal agencies to grants easements or rights-of-way</header><text>Notwithstanding the designation of the Route 66 National Historic Trail by this paragraph, the head of any Federal agency having jurisdiction over any Federal land on which the Route 66 National Historic Trail designated by this paragraph is located (other than land that is considered to be <quote>lands in the National Park System</quote> for purposes of section 28(b)(1) of the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/185">30 U.S.C. 185(b)(1)</external-xref>) as a result of a designation under any other law), shall have the authority to grant easements or rights-of-way over, under, across, or along any applicable portion of the Route 66 National Historic Trail in accordance with the laws applicable to the Federal land.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="ide405dcae77f549ba8995924d7f6b7931"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>No new permits required</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the designation of the Route 66 National Historic Trail by this paragraph shall not subject the Route 66 National Historic Trail or any land on which the Route 66 National Historic Trail is located to any other Federal laws (including regulations) requiring a Federal permit or authorization that would otherwise be made applicable as a result of the designation of the Route 66 National Historic Trail as a component of the National Trails System.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

