<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4C4866E44E0A46428514CEAF3A5659A5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5078 IH: Protecting Information by Local Leaders for Agency Resilience Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5078</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250902">September 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000300">Mr. Evans of Colorado</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to reauthorize the State and local cybersecurity grant program of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H201F8FA941AD4CA8A6DC7363DC066997" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H49131A58A8B74F0590C12FC06E76C26E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Information by Local Leaders for Agency Resilience Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PILLAR Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HB9E21FD6AEC64A738DA8F240BD7D2BAC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reauthorization of CISA State and local cybersecurity grant program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2220A of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/665g">6 U.S.C. 665g</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H9ECC58FF43FC4C1C927007BACCA07BF4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H387C04CE45DD47AF96509F55DDE384AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (4), (5), (6), and (7) as paragraphs (3), (4), (6), (8), (9), (10), and (11), respectively;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8C114E0284A941B79664D8683ACA3B5B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (3), as so redesignated, the following new paragraphs:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC8FCAF82D5C74A80B6C428B466CCE27C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H6BC220D79EE24446BDDADAAF73C33F62" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>artificial intelligence</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 5002(3) of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (enacted as division E of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401(3)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00F9583D41DE4124A19630BD3BAD7226"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence system</header><text>The term <quote>artificial intelligence system</quote> means any data system, software, hardware, application tool, or utility that operates in whole or in part using artificial intelligence.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0D17F45CBBC84D33BF8A36151A3C7AB6" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4), as so redesignated, the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H47CEEDA517D945898A81C5CA3F51DBAF" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H2856824E2C4A4792A3F665091DB77F4F" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Foreign entity of concern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>foreign entity of concern</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 10634 of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/19237">42 U.S.C. 19237</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/167">Public Law 117–167</external-xref>; popularly referred to as the <quote>CHIPS and Science Act</quote>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB225A9315FD94900A0C064AA36EA95CE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (6), as so redesignated, the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEEE2AC59765747FA8ABE1C76BA6B719B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H46BADF09B49C4570A844DDA02634F70D"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Multi-factor authentication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>multi factor authentication</quote> means an authentication system that requires more than one distinct type of authentication factor for successful authentication of a user, including by using a multi-factor authenticator or by combining single-factor authenticators that provide different types of factors.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDB1C2081BD124FF7AB956FBBF17724C5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), by striking <quote>information systems owned</quote> and inserting <quote>information systems or operational technology systems, including either or both of such systems using artificial intelligence, maintained, owned, or</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF0464068ED3841BDB09EE97A4E9E5DE0"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>in subsection (d)(4), by striking <quote>to the information systems owned</quote> and inserting <quote>to the information systems or operational technology systems, including either or both of such systems using artificial intelligence, maintained, owned, or</quote>;</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCE8CF2A17538434598961D53C03CD4A7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text> <subparagraph id="H23EBA0D2BA1E437DBB05729DF6F4AE6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> 
<clause id="H3EC890654B8B46B49298C66060BCD90B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(i), by striking <quote>information systems owned</quote> and inserting <quote>information systems or operational technology systems, including either or both of such systems using artificial intelligence, maintained, owned, or</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H2B77E5825D9A4BD3A0D8C70FA5758177"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> 
<subclause id="H3CEFA4A03AF146729F6A2DB953654A0C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by amending clauses (i) through (v) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H09DB979D97C643638BC6658534AF2DA4" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <clause id="H0B6C0CF444FE4D2D896C24651B065968" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">manage, monitor, and track applications, user accounts, and information systems and operational technology systems, including either or both of such systems using artificial intelligence, that are maintained, owned, or operated by, or on behalf of, the eligible entity, or, if the eligible entity is a State, local governments within the jurisdiction of the eligible entity, and the information technology deployed on such information systems or operational technology systems (as the case may be), including legacy information systems, operational technology systems, and information technology that are no longer supported by the manufacturer of the systems or technology at issue;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8EB57E1C3E9644BE8E8EDA41D4DB56D5" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">monitor, audit, and track network traffic and activity transiting or traveling to or from applications, user accounts, and information systems and operational technology systems, including either or both of such systems using artificial intelligence, maintained, owned, or operated by, or on behalf of, the eligible entity or, if the eligible entity is a State, local governments within the jurisdiction of the eligible entity;</text></clause> <clause id="H3A2F3987BC9E4373ADD708212CABD149" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enhance the preparation, response, and resiliency of applications, user accounts, and information systems and operational technology systems, including either or both of such systems using artificial intelligence, maintained, owned, or operated by, or on behalf of, the eligible entity or, if the eligible entity is a State, local governments within the jurisdiction of the eligible entity, against cybersecurity risks and cybersecurity threats;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0FBED85771E54852A7FB53F95C4C9915" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implement a process of continuous cybersecurity vulnerability assessments and threat mitigation practices prioritized by degree of risk to address cybersecurity risks and cybersecurity threats on applications, user accounts, and information systems and operational technology systems, including either or both of such systems using artificial intelligence, maintained, owned, or operated by, or on behalf of, the eligible entity or, if the eligible entity is a State, local governments within the jurisdiction of the eligible entity;</text></clause> <clause id="H62F738E5A56F4BD89361B6AF560268F6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>ensure that the eligible entity and, if the eligible entity is a State, local governments within the jurisdiction of the eligible entity, adopt and use best practices and methodologies to enhance cybersecurity, particularly identity and access management solutions such as multi-factor authentication, which may include—</text> 
<subclause id="H952E3A50785B41D0988622CDF529DBE5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the practices set forth in a cybersecurity framework developed by the National Institute of Standards and Technology or the Agency;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H6DD126C7601F41058B34C71F32200BFF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>cyber chain supply chain risk management best practices identified by the National Institute of Standards and Technology or the Agency;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HC4031715AF1E40C3A60446E4859DCB62"><enum>(III)</enum><text>knowledge bases of adversary tools and tactics;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H5170FDEFB4D746FA90462EAC21D15DB2"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>technologies such as artificial intelligence; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE14FA0E2E8C948A58C86BA8D22E7D3D7"><enum>(V)</enum><text>improving cyber incident response capabilities through adoption of automated cybersecurity practices;</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subclause> <subclause id="HD5630CA4D3C649F6ADBD6D365D104EF8" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in clause (x), by inserting <quote>or operational technology systems, including either or both of such systems using artificial intelligence,</quote> after <quote>information systems</quote>;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HEF7FC8DE14C14B5B89415EF96E55A481" commented="no">
                            <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text>in clause (xi)(I), by inserting <quote>, including through Department of Homeland Security State, Local, and Regional Fusion Center Initiative under section 210(A)</quote> before the semicolon;</text>
                        </subclause> 
<subclause id="HC10B830D2DF54FFD853BC2C98B788756" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>in clause (xii), by inserting <quote>, including for bolstering the resilience of outdated or vulnerable information systems or operational technology systems, including either or both of such systems using artificial intelligence</quote> before the semicolon;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD0BB0190577A4F799EF15F516A2F03D5"><enum>(V)</enum><text>by amending clause (xiii) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7B527128F372467DB2F83707B3BDF1F8" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<clause id="HC567E82AC1D141F997AFAB674BB6F5AE" commented="no"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implement an information technology or operational technology, including either or both of such systems using artificial intelligence, modernization cybersecurity review process that ensures alignment between information technology, operational technology, and artificial intelligence cybersecurity objectives;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause> <subclause id="H23BB31B10CD546AABF812F00D3EF4344"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>in clause (xiv)(II)—</text> 
<item id="HEF33F0E58B914D7E8FE3A4C9BA307233"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in item (aa), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></item> <item id="H0F12849264844BE4B905D7FB6E46B796"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in item (bb), by inserting <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon; and</text></item> 
<item id="HD9E2D34C79B347588A1EAA23019BCA62"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new item:</text> <quoted-block id="H9219A4AF11C844F5BB930AB6FF38E15D" style="OLC"> <item id="H0347D70423D64C9A9B71F731E926317E"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>academic and nonprofit entities, including cybersecurity clinics and other nonprofit technical assistance programs;</text></item><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="HB2ABCC78B6AF40A4A125D189AF848029"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>by amending clause (xv) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H66D1D85179F34D7D816EFAAE84E222E6" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <clause id="HA7FD8C42147F4996B88795C291F3CD0E"><enum>(xv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure adequate access to, and participation in, the services and programs described in this subparagraph by rural areas and other local governments with small populations within the jurisdiction of the eligible entity, including by direct outreach to such rural areas and local governments with small populations; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H8DE826987C4A4462A15E386F8D6BEF94"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F)—</text> <subclause id="HD4F514BFEC8B456E92F53837FB50B807"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HBB509CBEADFA48E5A6F4DE56A2A031D8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by amending clause (ii) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9CDF18CE68184957A82D1B19CCA61C4D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <clause id="H4A39E5BC32F9451EB4C8F02BFCD9A7C2" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reducing cybersecurity risks to, and identifying, responding to, and recovering from cybersecurity threats to, information systems or operational technology systems, including either or both of such systems using artificial intelligence, maintained, owned or operated by, or on behalf of, the eligible entity or, if the eligible entity is a State, local governments within the jurisdiction of the eligible entity; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subclause> 
<subclause id="HDA6E31BF6839498CA2C28B2639BECC14"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFEDF121CF3B1425CB28DCDA6B6FB3001" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <clause id="H7CD852C038ED42D497614E3C343F727E" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assuming the cost or partial cost of cybersecurity investments made as a result of the plan.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H18704022CE8F43ADAFA07C0B5DB977D9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3)(A), by striking <quote>the Multi-State Information Sharing and Analysis Center</quote> and inserting <quote>Information Sharing and Analysis Organizations</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88E6A8A4C9CE40B6A2513D8A1C5350A4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (g)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0AE5E566F161416E9E409D36AC747913"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)(A)(ii), by inserting <quote>including, as appropriate, representatives of rural, suburban, and high-population jurisdictions (including such jurisdictions with low or otherwise limited operating budgets)</quote> before the semicolon; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8CEEDF1B46EC4D5BB4BB484696D1B3DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (5) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6B3C673E18204B9A974FFB0946E1E6C0" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H0B47418A85864C279EA4E0A0161D95B2" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rule of construction regarding control of certain information systems or operational technology systems of eligible entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection may be construed to permit a cybersecurity planning committee of an eligible entity that meets the requirements of this subsection to make decisions relating to information systems or operational technology systems, including either or both of such systems using artificial intelligence, maintained, owned, or operated by, or on behalf of, the eligible entity.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HC70C9055BCFC483A9800D7FA68A35A85"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (i)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB60FF78A2C704FAA8CABB6AE46AA3766"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(B), by striking <quote>2-year period</quote> and inserting <quote>3-year period</quote>;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF810A0EC63B942078F4DFD9D4D134E13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> 
<clause id="H83B3719FDC784ACAB78B328CBA6697D1" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>2023</quote> and inserting <quote>2027</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H0687BBCF9A714407A22480CDEE2FE897"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>2023</quote> and inserting <quote>2027</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF92859C39F6D4E7F8D43689A05C42C3C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text> <clause id="H1F3D063EA0E141F88DA4A0814955F4CE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>shall</quote> and inserting <quote>may</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2EB01D9465864F84B8C7A379A2621C54" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>information systems owned</quote> inserting <quote>information systems or operational technology systems, including either or both of such systems using artificial intelligence, maintained, owned,</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H646822348AF44F7CA4D983BFA3A816D9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in subsection (j)(1)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE8C324B4E2024A27A693A923A619C670"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0D3B0A1828EE48ED991D4D392122EDA2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E)—</text> 
<clause id="HD2439D668B2B4700A68FBB54FF157A3F" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>information systems owned</quote> and inserting <quote>information systems or operational technology systems, including either or both of such systems using artificial intelligence, maintained, owned,</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H0A411FE4CCC54A469CC6BE611C54D76C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking the period and inserting a semicolon; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H65B2604A777244E1B73D38D86A97B101"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB10993818BC74BE9BE158EC357AD0B7C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H299C060C0F724730822A0E0D4EC5B248" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to purchase software or hardware, or products or services of such software or hardware, as the case may be, that do not align with guidance relevant to such software or hardware, or products or services, as the case may be, provided by the Agency, including Secure by Design or successor guidance; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6775E89A2F534D6D9D50C869F3461C41" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to purchase software or hardware, or products or services of such software or hardware, as the case may be, that are designed, developed, operated, maintained, manufactured, or sold by a foreign entity of concern and do not align with guidance provided by the Agency.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H76AD37834F054943A058C656610D93C1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>in subsection (l), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>2022</quote> and inserting <quote>2026</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA30C0060491B474C9A45EE4B7BCEC95B"><enum>(9)</enum><text>in subsection (m), by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB608F3EB227F44609ABCB3F58C21D7AE" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H45793C54DF514C05BEC11C4D75CB3D5C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal share of activities carried out using funds made available pursuant to the award of a grant under this section may not exceed—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9FFB82C687AD4950848C4A2A18959C60" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a grant to an eligible entity, 60 percent for each fiscal year through fiscal year 2035; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCE4ECC20B6DE45B2BC085E0EA516249A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a grant to a multi-entity group, 70 percent for each fiscal year through fiscal year 2035.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph" commented="no">Notwithstanding subparagraphs (A) and (B), the Federal share of the cost for an eligible entity or multi-entity group shall be 65 percent for an entity and 75 percent for a multi-group entity for each fiscal year beginning with fiscal year 2028 through fiscal year 2035 if such entity or multi-entity group entity, as the case may be, implements or enables, by not later than October 1, 2027, multi-factor authentication and identity and access management tools that support multi-factor authentication with respect to critical infrastructure, including the information systems and operational technology systems, including either or both of such systems using artificial intelligence, of such critical infrastructure, that is within the jurisdiction of such entity or multi-entity group is responsible.</continuation-text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H65F98D8A04454C05B3FD5E4B9BD7257F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>in subsection (n)—</text> <subparagraph id="H3B9A5B7210644A5E96F39D4BE816CCE0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> 
<clause id="HC6667038513842FA8A31A33A8B2E55D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text> <subclause id="HF2B8FBA3A5D748238F5F5D7F90237D60" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>a grant</quote> and inserting <quote>a grant on or after January 1, 2026, or changes the allocation of funding as permissible within the allowances of</quote>; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HC8059DA84E59469DAC0EF3CC3976328F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by amending clauses (ii) and (iii) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3F8A44B5EE964046B83735F8A8FDEB35" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <clause id="HB382D167E53B4C9CBCC66318795DB272"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with the consent of the local governments, items, in-kind services, capabilities, or activities, or a combination of funding and other services, having a value of not less than 80 percent of the amount of the grant; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H958CD10EC2E34C12A464568EAE4F9DF2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with the consent of the local governments, grant funds combined with other items, in-kind services, capabilities, or activities, or a combination of funding and other services, having the total value of not less than 80 percent of the amount of the grant.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause> </clause> <clause id="HA26108C3A21B426E87F320B04FFEB3D7" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by amending clauses (ii) and (iii) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7A41654FDEA94F2BB24892C1F77B9AEA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<clause id="HB2610530CBA64574A811805D8CF14FF8" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">items, in kind services, capabilities, or activities, or a combination of funding and other services, having a value of not less than 25 percent of the amount of the grant awarded to the eligible entity; or </text></clause> <clause id="HDD534EA7AF09431094477483872DF30D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>grant funds combined with other items, in kind services, capabilities, or activities, or a combination of funding and other services, having the total value of not less than 25 percent of the grant awarded to the eligible entity.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9A8DCB9456B9491FA62148A34002A274"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (5) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HEE1A193D40A84213ACBF353530375EDF" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HEF1D0505306A45E295C89F9ABEA1E473"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Direct funding</header><text>If an eligible entity does not make a distribution to a local government required under paragraph (2) within 60 days of the anticipated grant disbursement date, such local government may petition the Secretary to request the Secretary to provide funds directly to such local government.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB18D175A154947A78AFE11510747AE66" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><text>in subsection (o), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>and representatives from rural areas and other local governments with small populations</quote> after <quote>governments</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2BC32020CECA46B4B314908F182557D2"><enum>(12)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (p) through (s) as subsections (q) through (t), respectively;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB533411044234F08A099A95E464AD132"><enum>(13)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (o) the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block id="H796035268A3E4344AD3F07B3265207C3" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H3331817212DA4C938710EE3A017B34B4" commented="no"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Outreach to local governments</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall implement an outreach plan to inform local governments, including those in rural areas or with small populations, about no-cost cybersecurity service offerings available from the Agency.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H287FEC510BBC42E7827A555DD4191B1B"><enum>(14)</enum><text>in subsection (r), as so redesignated—</text> <subparagraph id="H9C15D0E827514BC8B5FB2C113EF066C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A)—</text> 
<clause id="HD9D8E731B5C74B0793EA46C3655D0FF6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></clause> <clause id="H38874081DD634277BD4470DB6F7078FF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text> 
<subclause id="H8C124F7C6C80488BBC671890FA18FFE2" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>information systems owned</quote> inserting <quote>information systems or operational technology systems, including either or both of such systems using artificial intelligence, maintained, owned,</quote>; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H886001DC48254FD8A80F58978EE6BB39"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HB080EE660BCF4057AFF9A1915AE64545"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8AE255A4246244A98F6CFA765792E822" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <clause id="H2F4D368F64354250A171DD4914E8F372" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assuming the costs associated with continuing the programs specified in the Cybersecurity Plan by including such programs in State and local government budgets upon full expenditure of grant funds by the eligible entity.</text> </clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H98D2C4ADEC874EF891EE3862732ACE7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(E)(ii), by striking <quote>information systems owned</quote> and inserting <quote>information systems or operational technology systems, including either or both of such systems using artificial intelligence, maintained, owned</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H04A4277E22E54CF0851B914B7A46D7EB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (6) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF64DAD1A96334C699BE8496398F00C99" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H5E59C84B68384D85989F187BB0DE98B6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>GAO review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than four years after the date of the enactment of this paragraph and every four years thereafter until the termination of the State and Local Cybersecurity Grant Program, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a review of the Program, including relating to the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H13BBB4AA71F942ABAA642253B56D7DE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The grant selection process of the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD71137F506E34EF495C1EE532E842639"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A sample of grants awarded under this section.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H610C0EF1FF0C4474BFD68BA007819478"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A review of artificial intelligence adoption across the sample of grants reviewed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H57C816B183974D60ABC339A4B3C7A75D"><enum>(15)</enum><text>in subsection (s), as so redesignated, by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC610FC5EF8A64452AA7194D4D97B3C47" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H667D700125AF4281AB68838D645D6956"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The activities under this section are subject to the availability of appropriations.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H96B2832E9FB34D7E87364B0EF2B5017B"><enum>(16)</enum><text>in subsection (t), as so redesignated, in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>2025</quote> and inserting <quote>2035</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

