<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBC225DE41F0348E7916B411DE649C454" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 698 IH: Recognizing the victims, survivors, and thousands of other Americans impacted by the September 11, 2001, attacks, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 698</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hernández</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the victims, survivors, and thousands of other Americans impacted by the September 11, 2001, attacks, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on September 11, 2001, the United States became a Nation transformed;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, at 8:46 in the morning, American Airlines Flight 11 was hijacked by al-Qaida terrorists and crashed into the North Tower of the World Trade Center;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, at 9:03 in the morning, United Airlines Flight 175 was hijacked by al-Qaida terrorists and crashed into the South Tower of the World Trade Center;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, at 9:37 in the morning, American Airlines Flight 77 was hijacked by al-Qaida terrorists and crashed into the Pentagon;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, at 10:03 in the morning, United Airlines Flight 93 was hijacked by al-Qaida terrorists, heroically diverted from aiming at the United States Capitol or the White House by the passengers with knowledge that America was under attack, and crashed into a field in Shanksville, Pennsylvania;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Twin Towers, where up to 50,000 people worked each day, collapsed and more than 2,600 people died;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 125 people died in the Pentagon;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 256 people died on the 4 hijacked planes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 400 of those who died were firefighters, police officers, paramedics, and military personnel who ran toward danger and assisted those in need;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than two decades after September 11, 2001, nearly 7,000 people have died from illnesses or cancers linked to their exposure at Ground Zero, and tens of thousands of individuals across the country still suffer from physical and mental health impacts;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in the immediate aftermath of the terrorist attacks on September 11, 2001, the United States vowed to never again allow a similar attack on United States soil;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on November 22, 2002, Congress passed the Homeland Security Act of 2002, establishing the Department of Homeland Security, standing firm on the commitment to prevent future attacks against the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on March 1, 2003, the Department of Homeland Security first opened its doors with the mission of reducing the vulnerability of the United States to terrorism, minimizing the damage, and assisting in the recovery, from manmade and natural disasters that occur within the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the September 11, 2001, attacks were the last complex foreign terrorist attacks on United States soil, which is a testament to the hard work of our homeland security, intelligence, law enforcement, and military personnel;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Department of Homeland Security personnel with institutional knowledge and expertise on counterterrorism, transportation security, cybersecurity, border security, emergency preparedness, and privacy, civil liberties, and civil rights have been terminated; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Final Report of the National Commission on Terrorist Attacks Upon the United States concluded that one of the United States Government’s failures in the lead up to the attacks was one of intelligence–the United States failed to <quote>connect the dots</quote>, between information that could have helped thwart the terrorist attacks;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas today, the intelligence community and its elements—including the Department of Homeland Security’s Office of Intelligence and Analysis, which was created to fill the critical gaps identified in the aftermath of the September 11, 2001, attacks—are more important than ever;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in response to the September 11, 2001, attacks, Congress provided billions of dollars in preparedness grant funding to support first responders in communities that were targeted on September 11, 2001, and those that continue to be targets of terrorist attacks;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas today, delayed funding and politically driven conditions on such funding, undermines the effectiveness of terrorism-prevention funding for targeted cities, like New York City and Washington, DC, and put lives at risk;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas cities that have been consistently assessed to be top targets for terrorists since the September 11, 2001, attacks have witnessed $134 million in cuts to terrorism-prevention funding; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas all of these recent actions could again leave the Nation vulnerable to threats: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H9CCAE2C216AE4BD2AC04284E2411154B"><section id="H1EBF79BF3FBC41F7A9E63ED93E463C5E" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H4CDD970C655A40FBB137481D1F63C6C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the victims, survivors, and thousands of other Americans impacted by the September 11, 2001, attacks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H232D4DE403DC42C6A8FB85F108AEC39C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the valiant efforts of public servants who have worked over the years, day in and day out, to maintain the security of the Nation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC38C1E6309AE43DFB96736190650D43B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>opposes weakening of the United States counterterrorism and preparedness posture; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8334E1A1D0AA41C5B71F3A137E7288BB"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">urges the United States Government to honor the lives lost on September 11, 2001, by remembering the lessons learned that tragic day and upholding the Department of Homeland Security’s mission to safeguard the American people, our homeland, and our values. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

