<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H426611FA2B5342ACBBFE16987AEBDCDF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3340 IH: Modernizing Access to Our Public Oceans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3340</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250513">May 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000478">Mr. Fry</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the standardization, publication, and accessibility of data relating to public outdoor recreational use of Federal waterways, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H270D4258CE4E44D5AF648F6CA6F68D57" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H861F57EBA38B401280EBDF2CC23895AE"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Modernizing Access to Our Public Oceans Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEA8D8D93FBE4493199324CDC807BF3E6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3689CD7791AD4E19A376611B237BA6FB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exclusive economic zone</header><text>The term <term>exclusive economic zone</term> has the meaning given that term in section 107 of title 46, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE4989BEEC1AA4F07843FE19B7DC09C9C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fishing restriction</header><text>The term <term>fishing restriction</term> means a restriction on fishing in a federally managed fishery established under section 303(b)(2) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1853">16 U.S.C. 1853(b)(2)</external-xref>), including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3F0108683BCD414D9D0530070F0BC00A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a full or partial fishing closure, in terms of both area and duration, or a seasonal closure;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8DEAA5769DD8462FA4C4778912C87CC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a no-catch zone in the fishery;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H51C268F222634217808A0E6B7088BA34"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a restriction on the method of catch for the fishery; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD5E6FD0C191C4CACAC1BCC5F51486A4C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>another restriction on fishing, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC526ED33A4244F4E891953980334A607"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Indian Tribe; Tribal organization</header><text>The terms <term>Indian Tribe</term> and <term>Tribal organization</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89BEA7CAB4C0427A92E60F3B3EFE6B62"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Native Hawaiian organization</header> <text>The term <term>Native Hawaiian organization</term> has the meaning given the term in section 6207 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7517">20 U.S.C. 7517</external-xref>), except that the term includes the Department of Hawaiian Home Lands and the Office of Hawaiian Affairs of the State of Hawaii.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2A22EDA4A464230AFD075BA24655228"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Nonprofit organization</header><text>The term <term>nonprofit organization</term> means an organization that is described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1C99245821664531B9586C9B835FCEBA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Recreational vessel</header><text>The term <term>recreational vessel</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2101 of title 46, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6774C250D0414BC4A85CE8DF8E8C1DD8"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H20DA0960AEF340AFA5E4E48198D98514"><enum>3.</enum><header>Data standardization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 31 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with relevant stakeholders, including State and local governments, Indian Tribes, and Native Hawaiian organizations, shall develop and adopt standards with respect to the coordination and dissemination of geospatial data relating to fishing restrictions, use of the exclusive economic zone by recreational vessels, and access to Federal waters by such vessels, including such data made available under section 4.</text></section> 
<section id="HCF14CE52E8F7434C8390317E0058D2CD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Data publication and accessibility</header> 
<subsection id="H06D526AAA02B44C5B84B4347C9B759D4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Data on fishing and recreational vessels in exclusive economic zone</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Office of Science and Technology of the National Marine Fisheries Service, and to the maximum extent practicable, shall make available on a publicly accessible website geographic information system data that—</text> <paragraph id="H67889E554AE44B878C6FFDF5F68E938B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>includes, with respect to the exclusive economic zone—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB69B8EE2680E4C709EEBEEC5ECA192E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information with respect to the conditions under which fishing restrictions are imposed and the areas within the exclusive economic zone that are open or closed to recreational boating, diving, and related recreational activities (as determined by the Secretary), including for safety reasons such as because of the presence of harmful algal blooms;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3F75DBCBACA1486384DB260EC062D0D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the areas of the exclusive economic zone with restrictions on the use of motorized propulsion, horsepower, or fuel by or of recreational vessels; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H59590FCADBDA45F89D2DA25EA2097A5E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the types of recreational vessels that are restricted on each area of the exclusive economic zone;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE845F6C7902C463A8C7B4E89AC72C81D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describes the geographic boundaries of areas where fishing restrictions occur; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD59E316AE0734389972BE87881264147"><enum>(3)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7D4000E11CDC46469EAD50A33ED13B24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifies Federal marine protected areas, including National Marine Sanctuaries, national marine monuments, and other federally protected waters; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAAFF221812204D48AC3A93F56920A3BB" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes information on what fishing, recreational boating, and other related recreational activities are authorized in each such area.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA326047AAF454D6894C42249D18AC689"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Data on navigation within exclusive economic zone</header> 
<paragraph id="H200CB90D08CC4664A6C9F0421B49CE2A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall continue to make available digitized geographic information system data that includes, with respect to access to the exclusive economic zone—</text> <subparagraph id="H5E42E0DE7B2E4161AF027F9745AC8739"><enum>(A)</enum><text>navigation information;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA0DFC7A4A717463D812E6D5A6097B80E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>bathymetric information;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBDD1A5AB80C84805B3589A51F623CB07"><enum>(C)</enum><text>depth charts; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF0ED505474DD4D5184E1D0E47A694EA5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other information, consistent with law and policy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H96DED5077DC14C94A085B7DD1A52863D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Website</header><text>The Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, make the data described in paragraph (1) available on the website on which the Secretary makes the data described in subsection (a) available.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEE6A13C2E0AE4CEBB165DA1201602F04"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data accessibility</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the website on which the Secretary makes the data described in subsections (a) and (b) available—</text> <paragraph id="HE65D20D2CD5047A5BDF4B6FC1FE82347"><enum>(1)</enum><text>organizes that data so that the data is findable, accessible, interoperable, and reusable; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6AF11AAEC59C4FD6B2133D633B6F60E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes a mechanism by which users can be easily updated when new data becomes available.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0B47C5B7DFEA467AB0325C74DFC077ED"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public comment</header><text>The Secretary shall develop—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6082289FB9041E0AAB564C7165A51FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a process to allow members of the public to submit questions or comments regarding the data described in subsections (a) and (b) and the accessibility of that data under subsection (c); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0A73A697EE642D28907100D199FACA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">methods to improve the accessibility of data.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE1C84D7901EB4B8FB139FC77A71FBAAD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Secretary shall update—</text> <paragraph id="H3139F124ECE3439DA801FB6D2D23C71F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the data described in subsections (a)(1) and (b) not less frequently than 2 times each year; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H53C889F4478B498C8106A2E2C44B005C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the data described in paragraphs (2) and (3) of subsection (a) in real time.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H106965C1B3AC43F6AE7752770EC4DB8B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Nondisclosure of certain information</header><text>The Secretary may not, consistent with applicable law and policy, disclose, in any geographic information system data made publicly available under this section—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F36735EBBB1432BAC2E7F427693BC48"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information regarding the nature, location, character, or ownership of historic, paleontological, cultural, or archaeological resources; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFEB75545FC04449A893BCBB2CF1A25C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commercial fishing information, including proprietary information.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H20D6CD766CBB405290681404DFF906EA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Treatment of Tribal waters and fishing areas</header><text>The authorities granted by this section shall not apply with respect to any usual or accustomed fishing areas or Tribal waters.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H023D27BD5963417BA26273A877D66B57"> <enum>5.</enum> <header>Cooperation and coordination</header> <subsection id="H5BA5306C26F24D4A8E7F899EE8F242CD"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Community partners and third-Party providers</header> <text>For purposes of carrying out this Act, the Secretary may—</text>
        <paragraph id="H49B27A96AAF440C48328C7C97033A8CD">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>coordinate and partner with non-Federal entities, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HBDACBB18954E4F379CE455DD484F7B3E"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>States;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H7C036F36579C405689B4982227751C23">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>Indian Tribes, Native Hawaiian organizations, and Tribal organizations;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H463164CD7800410199D0972DD2C670E6"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>interstate commissions (as defined in section 303 of the Interjurisdictional Fisheries Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/4102">16 U.S.C. 4102</external-xref>));</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H7D04DAA540DF422591C00C9343080486">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>Regional Ocean Partnerships (as defined in section 10202 of the James M. Inhofe National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1468">16 U.S.C. 1468</external-xref>));</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HD727A3BC5B374CB5AEC0D3B2D3E598A9">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>experts in data science, analytics, and operations research;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H71DB61B04EAC40FCBC47606E6CC9D153"> <enum>(F)</enum> <text>the private sector, including technology or geospatial data industries;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H8285029F3F4B4C8785C8821D691EAD4B">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>nonprofit organizations; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF14C9842A6F94EB6992F3D72635531A3"> <enum>(H)</enum> <text>institutions of higher education (as defined in section 201 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>)); and</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1B314C62D9FC4DDE84959EF9C1A1DB53">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>enter into agreements with experts within entities described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (H) of paragraph (1) to carry out any of the provisions of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H32E9E36B2D2B42C9A92E93D894D0FAE7">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Interagency coordination</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, work with the relevant offices of the Department of the Interior, the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Defense, the Department of Energy, the Environmental Protection Agency, the Coast Guard, the Army Corps of Engineers, and the Interagency Working Group on Ocean and Coastal Mapping codified by section 12203 of the Ocean and Coastal Mapping Integration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3502">33 U.S.C. 3502</external-xref>), to ensure compatibility and interoperability among applicable Federal databases with respect to the collection and dissemination of geospatial data relating to public outdoor recreational use of the exclusive economic zone.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H3991E9DAAB5841E48D201C459334257E">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Applicability of Federal, State, and Tribal law and regulations</header>
 <text>The Secretary, in developing and distributing geospatial data under this Act, shall make clear that the data are subject to applicable laws and regulations of the Federal Government, States, and Indian Tribes.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H85AEF90989AD4B97961A997E8BF58FD2"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed—</text> <paragraph id="H57FCBFAB087142C88BE0597078789232"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to modify or alter the definition of the term <term>navigable waters</term> under any provision of Federal law;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBFFD602252C3476499C42788D9059A93"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to affect the jurisdiction or authority of Federal or State agencies to regulate navigable waters;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0C5B73454B6E4BA1923FDA986F95AADC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to increase or diminish the responsibility or authority of Federal or State agencies or Indian Tribes to manage fisheries under existing law;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H31A0C5E1C123428FB9AF37DF62B78472">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>to satisfy any requirement for government-to-government consultation with Indian Tribes or Native Hawaiian organizations; or</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3C451F9A9058451AB52BF3F61A845686" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to affect or modify any treaty or other right of any Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

