<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFE488CE979BD44B3ABE7F0C2C595AFF3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3819 IH: Prioritizing Revised Operations To Eliminate Cyanobacteria Toxins in Florida Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3819</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250606">June 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To modify the project for Central and Southern Florida to include public health considerations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H350FAEB04A764C30AADFB502B13D77CB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC09CC1E739624FCFBEA4B875232F3EFF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prioritizing Revised Operations To Eliminate Cyanobacteria Toxins in Florida Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PROTECT Florida Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7B3495692374437E94226E35BF75488B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Management of the central and southern Florida system</header> <subsection id="H3980496E03EA453CB3D6E090744A50CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works shall direct the Army Corps of Engineers to modify water infrastructure management in Central and Southern Florida to ensure public health shall overlay all authorized project purposes. Such authorized project purposes shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H36F5778649A2450AB0E2F220DAF16ED0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>flood control;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6F7CE6C58B24701AAF0F3F5CA025FED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>navigation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H613D62BF4B3744738C68B897F8801F2C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>water supply for agricultural irrigation, municipalities, industry, and Everglades National Park;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF19A9593D6C54925B0B7E9AA634B4A5F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>regional groundwater control, and salinity control;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC0279812C4D4B9A955D6D770A865983"><enum>(5)</enum><text>enhancement of fish and wildlife; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H84F0F30D2364419AB5908AE330B0C6DF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>recreation.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H05ACAF8BA5E0415892A9D905A2823686"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public health</header><text>For the purposes of this Act, the term <term>public health</term> is defined as follows:</text> <paragraph id="H288F770FF0DC448A9779C2B313349A92"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Managing Lake Okeechobee and the Central and Southern Florida system—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5E9544A11F1B4D818908D1CD166A7B0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to minimize the potential of toxic cyanobacteria and other harmful algal blooms; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H652B35A9CE244E8B98197D5B8BAC9DB0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prevent discharges containing cyanobacteria or related toxins into the St. Lucie and Caloosahatchee watersheds, downstream users, and other areas where such cyanobacteria or related toxins will cause or exacerbate public health risks.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFFDCCAF55CF748738209B4948051C46A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Ensuring the integrity and stability of the Herbert Hoover Dike.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53C101B912CA4EF18534303B2E043DFA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Maintaining all provisions of applicable State, Federal, and Tribal water quality laws, policies, and regulations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H211DB5072D04401B902C8202DCA1A74A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Ensuring necessary water volume and quality reaches the greater Everglades, Tribal lands, Everglades National Park, Florida Bay and Caloosahatchee Watershed to restore the natural habitat.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC3CEC9429C2E4480B1BDE120E1657797"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Modification of operations</header><text>The Secretary of the Army shall modify operations of all current project elements to ensure that public health of all citizens, including downstream users, shall overlay the operating regimes of these various elements.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H67C3033D6F99433A9F7BF83A8DDC421B">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Master operational manual</header>
 <text>The Secretary of the Army shall update or develop a Master Operational Manual, in cooperation with the State of Florida, to ensure that all of the various existing operational project elements of the Central and Southern Florida project shall be managed as a system to protect public health and Everglades Restoration. As new elements are completed and added to the project, the Master Operational Manual shall be updated to include the new features.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H458222BA644441608C1ABA2714BDDA39"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Secretary of the Army, in conjunction with the National Academies of Sciences, shall undertake a study of the legacy of pollution and nutrient loading as well as the impacts of soil amendments from current and past operational regimes. The study shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H224FC776EF1A4658AECC9F4D6579687F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the components of the nutrient load and soil amendments, and how this nutrient loading is and will continue to impact Everglades restoration efforts; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBC81C875D607422DB398FFF4F88F32ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>proposed solutions to ameliorate the impacts of this pollution to downstream watersheds.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H27F6847EB9294A2D843FC8F551EF4004"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter or amend—</text> 
<paragraph id="H07100A090A1D4C01A0B70641ED6BFFE8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Water Rights Compact between the State of Florida and the Seminole Tribe of Florida;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB183AC5A9BCE432FB69FEA2E6C6D9636"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the water quality standards of the Miccosukee Tribe of Indians of Florida;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE7FE4379D68A4C98926AE66A7E24CDCF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>State water quality standards, applicable National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System discharge permits, and Everglades Forever Act watershed permits; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDCE73E34B78B4A9AAB3F812AA1DE6F65"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the schedule for completion of the Central Everglades Planning Project or Comprehensive Everglades Restoration Plan projects authorized on or before enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAA3D7E73EA244BE881BD90640524CAFC"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of restoration funds</header><text>No restoration funds shall be used by the Secretary to undertake Deep Well Injection (DWI) of flood or any other excess waters.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H00E670BFDECA46E1B34ECA95E0A2F6AB"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out the provisions of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

