<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB35CEAF1B5724271A60FEBA00F4D579A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4642 IH: Fiscal Contingency Preparedness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4642</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000592">Mr. Golden of Maine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000600">Ms. Perez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Treasury, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, to examine the ability of the Federal Government to respond to potential fiscal shocks, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE801B617F3AD4789ABE3F2609553FBD0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9562D63A31FB4E0C90B9DCA7A4A09DA5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fiscal Contingency Preparedness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HBDAD5FA1E28849499D583E855DC94086"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual report</header> 
<subsection id="H5E91F91CA9C64378BEBBCE9BF5A871A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 331(e) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF878E26DF3CC4B1FB910838709A49617"> <paragraph id="HE0CC04849CB94667859B26C811B81E85" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAA95B085A11D49AD920E2F6E663A2BF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>As a component of the report required under paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Treasury, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall examine the fiscal risks and fiscal impacts of the response of the Federal Government to potential national and international fiscal shocks.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph indent="up1" id="H52204784F2CF4C9183198A1F02816B79"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In making the examination required under subparagraph (A), the Secretary of the Treasury, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall—</text> <clause id="H82073DFF7B6F43C49DA89196C34437F4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>include an assessment of the fiscal risks and fiscal impacts of the Federal Government responding to events, such as—</text> 
<subclause id="HCDDFEA14CE9A4B99AEED04E6650A8D02"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an economic recession or depression;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H7FE2FD00474147FB871B15F9BD58C15A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a domestic energy crisis;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF182A4E42FF6491695210908C87EFDA1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a catastrophic natural disaster;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HBCC7E6D621C44DC8B995C0BDBFB2CA59"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a health crisis, such as a global pandemic;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8E791AB8B1B64775B836A7B7E83E7A08"><enum>(V)</enum><text>a significant armed conflict or event;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H820850F8F2A345F08FF27B8E8F9F253B"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>a significant cyber attack; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA6E8FB04B797465196B7C6C418733994"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>a financial crisis;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H4FB05FC7DA1141CD8BCC5E61E4B79CF4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>determine the estimated short-term and long-term fiscal effects on the Federal Government in the case of an event described in clause (i); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H53578C0661DF4CD38852668C88313B4D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>describe significant economic impacts and indicators selected by the Secretary of the Treasury, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, to convey the short-term and long-term fiscal effects on the Federal Government in the case of an event described in clause (i) in the method that best accomplishes the goal of the examination.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph indent="up1" id="HDD97AA2B43A0464B99F3E5A1BBE663EA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>In making the examination required under subparagraph (A) and determining the scope and magnitude of an event described in subparagraph (B)(i), the Secretary of the Treasury, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, may consider historical instances of those events and the response of the Federal Government to those historical instances.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph indent="up1" id="HE09A29C814FD49F581327AF28117F710"><enum>(D)</enum><text>In including the examination required under subparagraph (A) in the report required under paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Treasury, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, may structure and report the examination in the method that best accomplishes the goal of the examination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H75E2BDDCD13C4D60BF99F50844E74653"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the later of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1F7CE1FC5A6C42DE9F94CFC67BECF1A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the first date following the date of enactment of this Act on which the Secretary of the Treasury, in coordination with the Office of Management and Budget, submits a report under section 331(e)(1) of title 31, United States Code; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H61E9E3E0B3394C38A48717A123C2E027"><enum>(2)</enum><text>180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H845B75B6FE7544B1A057BA92A2B34B98"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary of the Treasury publishes the first examination required under section 331(e)(3)(A) of title 31, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), after the date of enactment of this Act, and periodically thereafter as determined necessary by the Comptroller General of the United States, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text> <paragraph id="HFA077D89E1474E34A2714721BB8A5A0F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review the methodology and results of the fiscal analysis performed during the examination;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H50A905D4FA664AB8AB34F6CF0F6EF83D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publish a report of the findings of the review under paragraph (1) on the website of the Government Accountability Office; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF08A21A69E694026865676E22303D8B4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>submit to the Committee on the Budget of the Senate and the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives the report published under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

