<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H43D90A92D6014FA5B2025A07936A250F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5323 IH: To enhance subnational diplomacy efforts within the Department of State, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5323</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250911">September 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enhance subnational diplomacy efforts within the Department of State, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5C77787A408C4537BAED4643E2EDBA95" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC92ED6330E134A6B96CBE84F05AB49F2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Office of Subnational Diplomacy</header>
<subsection id="H352B4011F82F4057988A1AFA2AE22940"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There shall be established in the Department of State an Office of Subnational Diplomacy (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Office</quote>). The Office shall enable the work of the Department with sub-national units of governments (such as State, county, city, and municipal governments) within the United States to improve the ability of such units of government to attract foreign investment, counter foreign malign influence within the United States, and contribute to the foreign policy priorities of the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5E441AD92EF747D2A14A9177E25EF75B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Head of office</header><text>The head of the Office shall be the Special Representative for Subnational Diplomacy, who shall report to the Under Secretary of Economic Affairs.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HAEAAC8A77E5741E79A7A98341E85E67C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Special Representative for Subnational Diplomacy shall additionally be responsible for—</text> <paragraph id="H6C0FC7E1FC4A4A9DA2D00459253057E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>advising the Under Secretary of Economic Affairs on sub-national engagements within the United States;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H412CF7D76CE34F35BA102B6033C5A1FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>serving as the principal official on such matters within the Department;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF60B49B6ECC4D61984788CC5AA4346F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>coordinating the Department’s support for local and municipal governmental engagements with foreign governments;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H332ED9786D224B76A30781306FCBDFCC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>advising subnational government officials on the potential risks of engagements with countries of concern and sharing best practices to build resilience against foreign political interference and malign influence;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H250EF8FF2635465299868F652FDC41BD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>assisting subnational governments in—</text>
<subparagraph id="H4726E16C28E64843A883C0E4679C33E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>attracting or bidding to host major international events;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF1F87D7B0F5B4A2AA9C290F8FFDE1082"><enum>(B)</enum><text>tracking foreign direct investment at the county and municipal levels to highlight trends and opportunities;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0EBC00BBF593450593D9FD933A86F1E8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>attracting foreign direct investment and other forms of economic cooperation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6B3B7F4766484FD29ED026E1C2221FD1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>building the capacity and knowledge of subnational government staff who have responsibility for engaging with foreign countries;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE3ED48DA61624C43A6D799CDC1F3314B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>advancing sports diplomacy with foreign countries and entities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H52AC80C6A6DB40C991360CD1222DA189"><enum>(F)</enum><text>implementing programs to cooperate with foreign governments and entities on policy priorities or managing shared resources; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H256B2A9A782641FF9182F194E47AC78D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>understanding the local implications of foreign policy developments or policy changes;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H379E57F1537047788A74F857C547A8AC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>supporting the economic interests of the United States through subnational engagements, in consultation and coordination with other relevant agencies;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H92DAD4ADD41A437BB8CC6075501B0A15"><enum>(7)</enum><text>advising and informing local officials during the negotiation of agreements or memoranda of understanding with foreign governments related to subnational engagements and priorities; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H27D378D498984A759DD547A74E65BD2A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>coordinating subnational engagements with associations of subnational elected leaders, such as the United States Conference of Mayors, National Governors Association, National League of Cities, and similar associations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

