<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H366C04E0E6D441DC8E0A1AC283B1B3E5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3161 IH: Preventing Environmental Hazards Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3161</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250501">May 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To make protection against damage and loss resulting from the erosion and undermining of shorelines available under the National Flood Insurance Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1EDF4388A5964369A2B7149404431396" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFCCAD0C309964EDF9159CD115E70645B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Environmental Hazards Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H01582489AFC14C089908CACBA0A739F5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Flood insurance coverage for structures on land subject to imminent collapse or subsidence</header> <subsection id="H01EFCE9A9C854DD0ACF0E9E98B5C1E08"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1306 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4013">42 U.S.C. 4013</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA43B4E8C04534020A1C5C9EDA4C5A41C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HDEA7122B36184A17AD58B9D2265D959C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Erosion coverage</header> 
<paragraph id="H09809476327140ACADE455588281E403"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any structure covered by a contract for flood insurance under this title and located on land that is along the shore of a lake or other body of water is condemned or deemed unsafe for habitation by a State or local authority due to imminent collapse or subsidence as a result of shoreline erosion or determined by a State or local authority to be situated partially or wholly over water, a shoreline bluff, or escarpment, or below Mean Higher High Water on tidal waterbodies (regardless of whether as a result of long-term, chronic erosion or as a result of waves or currents of water exceeding anticipated cyclical levels), the Administrator shall (following final determination by the Administrator that the claim is in compliance with regulations developed pursuant to paragraph (7)(A)) pay amounts under such flood insurance contract for proper demolition or relocation as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="HD040121DF896499EB536551C04FE7E01"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Demolition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For proper demolition—</text> 
<clause id="HEA1D8A08FE744DDC8065C4667610BB27"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">following final determination by the Administrator, 40 percent of the value of the structure; and</text></clause> <clause id="HBD7BC1E4087045EE8326D9103B90414E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">following demolition of the structure (including any septic containment system) within 6 months of payment under clause (i) and prior to collapse, the remaining 60 percent of the value of the structure or the actual cost of demolition, whichever amount is less.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD1188FC9D45B4DB38915D4204DDFD6E0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Relocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For proper relocation (including removal of any septic containment system) if the owner chooses to relocate the structure, following final determination by the Administrator, prior to collapse, up to 40 percent of the value of the structure; except that the total payment under this subparagraph shall not exceed the actual cost of relocation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2B22FE9306E84A0291E4AA6C099FF795"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Collapse or subsidence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any structure subject to a final determination under paragraph (1) collapses or subsides, or a period of six or more months elapses, before the owner demolishes or relocates the structure and the Administrator determines that the owner has failed to take reasonable and prudent action to demolish or relocate the structure, the Administrator shall not pay more than the amount provided in paragraph (1)(A)(i) with respect to the structure.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H088C1CA9E52C453993F21996621DB2D0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Value of structure</header><text>For purposes of paying flood insurance pursuant to this subsection, the value of a structure shall be whichever of the following is lowest:</text> <subparagraph id="H3CD62C212CEA41DCA04C8905FBE9732F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The fair market value of a comparable structure that is not subject to imminent collapse or subsidence.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H85141BC9234647108B77C56672B4155B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The price paid for the structure and any improvement to the structure, as adjusted for inflation in accordance with an index determined by the Administrator to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H573422F46BB34603A7EAE88A35E6D97E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The value of the structure under the flood insurance contract issued pursuant to this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H063BB322E0374C15A924E199AAADC809"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Coverage terms</header> 
<subparagraph id="H86D9D91E8239426DAE78936252F39AD1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Maximum claim</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any provision of this subsection, the amount paid under a flood insurance contract in connection with any claim under this subsection may not exceed the lesser of—</text> <clause id="H0112087A0A404960BE06EE43FB79D072"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of coverage under the flood insurance contract for the structure; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1CCC17E2F31F4EE28C733456310FFBE5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$250,000.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H69898EAADC9E4CE6BEEC1A2553B26429"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion of loss of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Flood insurance coverage under this subsection shall not cover any loss of or damage to any contents of a structure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE898A57F057D4FB1B643382F67E3D411"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Applicability</header> 
<subparagraph id="H0B6FA2CBA1D442BBA0C2C07962599733"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of this subsection shall apply to contracts for flood insurance under this title that are in effect on, or entered into after, the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H84A929B33AB44A2A842EB3B9035B68B0"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Coverage on certification date</header> <text>The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to any structure not subject to a contract for flood insurance under this title on the date of a certification under paragraph (1).</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H363FF15318D846ECAD17FB5AC280BC6C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Period of coverage</header><text>The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to any structure unless the structure is covered by a contract for flood insurance under this title—</text> <clause id="HAC6E544A86FC4ADABC588F7A28E609B7" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for a period of 12 months on or before the date of the enactment of this Act; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC60682EF42A944A7946FC2C1CDDC31AD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for a continuous period of 4 years prior to certification under paragraph (1).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7DF3A7954BF24AF695D7D9FF5B55E13C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Termination of coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For any structure that is subject to a final determination under paragraph (1), no subsequent flood insurance coverage under this title or assistance under the Disaster Relief Act of 1974 (except emergency assistance essential to save lives and protect property, public health and safety) shall be available for the same structure, or a different structure on any remaining portions of the parcel of land originally afforded assistance under this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3C9DA3E691A44473BC73B3610C5A88FC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Regulations</header> 
<subparagraph id="HB5611CB90DD54BF8908672E4A7B8A524"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall promulgate regulations and guidelines to implement this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB662DD345F294555B4F55851C96B97B7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to issuance of regulations regarding the State and local certifications pursuant to paragraph (1), all provisions of this subsection shall apply to any structure that—</text> 
<clause id="H5E981A699AE94AD09FA612562003790E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>otherwise meets the requirements of this subsection; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8DCD6E9CD6554975970ECA3BE7BD9E47"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is imminently threatened by shoreline erosion, regardless of whether as a result of long-term, chronic erosion or as a result of waves or currents of water exceeding anticipated cyclical levels.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H15D4472CFBFA4684A0B8F9491E4B7C4C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by this section shall become effective on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

