<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB42F12853CA74F95AFCA176962F38227" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4175 IH: No Gratuities for Governing Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4175</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250626">June 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to clarify the offense pertaining to illegal gratuities concerning programs receiving Federal funds.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6F30EB99679347938F8193DAF70DC792" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1D9EB2A0BF814C158DE9E2A43CA365FE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Gratuities for Governing Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC7F89A36A43A4F9DAD6F5C517FB8020F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Illegal gratuities concerning programs receiving Federal funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 666 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H70B84C4AA9964F8580A8E8FF9FEBBEC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b) through (d) as subsection (c) through (e), respectively;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3E3D4EBB410640D49B4AFF74A357E3F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5B3B364ECF28448C8073420BED1E2681"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>if the circumstance described in subsection (b) of this section exists</quote> and inserting <quote>if the circumstance described in subsection (c) of this section exists</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCC7EE9B750D544CABEEC62FC7749DF8A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>imprisoned not more than 10 years,</quote> and inserting <quote>imprisoned not more than 15 years,</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA6749F52745C471E92C24CE7BB1470B3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H4C1B9AE18BC844649E9021E952ADC0DF" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HE6BE971C351245B29FA4463D6D47115A"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever, if the circumstance described in subsection (c) of this section exists—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1EAA417F1E1843D0BEB993EA93449B10"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">directly or indirectly, knowingly and purposefully gives, offers, or promises anything of value of $1,000 or more to any agent of an organization, or of a State, local, or Indian Tribal government, or any agency thereof, for or because of any official act performed by such agent in connection with any business, transaction, or series of transactions of such organization, government, or agency involving anything of value of $5,000 or more; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAE4C85FD830A45E58F24EA4B75DFAFF2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">being an agent of an organization, or of a State, local, or Indian Tribal government, or any agency thereof, directly or indirectly, knowingly and purposefully demands, seeks, receives, accepts, or agrees to receive or accept anything of value of $1,000 or more personally for or because of any official act performed by such agent in connection with any business, transaction, or series of transactions of such organization, government, or agency involving anything of value of $5,000 or more;</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 2 years, or both.</continuation-text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0498316D85444586AC68042ABBAC1C4F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (c), as redesignated, by striking <quote>circumstance referred to in subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>circumstances referred to in subsections (a) and (b)</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

