<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H94CF6ADA9E9B41FAB219CA67452215F6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3583 IH: To amend title 4, United States Code, to ensure that a funeral honors detail recites the 13 Folds of Honor when presenting a flag of the United States in connection with the death of a member of the Armed Forces or veteran.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3583</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250523">May 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000600">Mr. Diaz-Balart</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 4, United States Code, to ensure that a funeral honors detail recites the 13 Folds of Honor when presenting a flag of the United States in connection with the death of a member of the Armed Forces or veteran.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6A21C66AB5B14FA2945D65998DE6957F" style="OLC"><section id="HAEF2C8D8B6E543B3BF789C8837D7E3EB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Recitation of 13 Folds of Honor</header><subsection id="HF21C735B37B542258EDC2040A83AED7F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that this Act be dedicated to the 13 members of the Armed Forces who were killed at Hamid Karzai International Airport in Kabul, Afghanistan, in August 2021.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD1CD9D78710C4C7DA35BFAA5DD139F34"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/4/1">Chapter 1</external-xref> of title 4, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section (and conforming the table of sections for such chapter accordingly):</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H0A747CB4D464472CA0B5182C8FB05C06" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H9745687BC93B4F8AA993BAF7A0AE300D"><enum>11.</enum><header>Recitation of 13 Folds of Honor</header><subsection id="HE4D2F6C9985846D6886761DC798C2C39"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided by subsection (b), a funeral honors detail that presents a folded flag of the United States in connection with the death of a member of the Armed Forces or veteran under section 1491 of title 10, section 2301 of title 38, or other applicable provision of law, shall recite the following (to be known as the <quote>13 Folds of Honor</quote>) as part of such presentment:</text><list list-type="none" level="subsection"><list-item>The 1st fold of the flag is a symbol of life.</list-item><list-item>The 2nd fold is a symbol of the belief in eternal life.</list-item><list-item>The 3rd fold is made in honor and remembrance of the veterans departing the ranks who gave a portion of their lives for the defense of the country to attain peace throughout the world.</list-item><list-item>The 4th fold represents the weaker nature, for as American citizens trusting in God, it is to Him we turn in times of peace as well as in the time of war for His divine guidance.</list-item><list-item>The 5th fold is a tribute to the country, for in the words of Stephen Decatur, <quote>Our Country, in dealing with other countries, may she always be right; but it is still our country, right or wrong.</quote>.</list-item><list-item>The 6th fold is for where people’s hearts lie. It is with their heart that they pledge allegiance to the flag of the United States of America, and the Republic for which it stands, one Nation under God, indivisible, with Liberty and Justice for all.</list-item><list-item>The 7th fold is a tribute to its Armed Forces, for it is through the Armed Forces that they protect their country and their flag against all her enemies, whether they be found within or without the boundaries of their republic.</list-item><list-item>The 8th fold is a tribute to the one who entered the valley of the shadow of death, that we might see the light of day.</list-item><list-item>The 9th fold is a tribute to womanhood and Mothers. For it has been through their faith, their love, loyalty, and devotion that the character of the men and women who have made this country great has been molded.</list-item><list-item>The 10th fold is a tribute to the father, for he, too, has given his sons and daughters for the defense of their country since they were first born.</list-item><list-item>The 11th fold represents the lower portion of the seal of King David and King Solomon and glorifies in the Hebrews eyes, the God of Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob.</list-item><list-item>The 12th fold represents an emblem of eternity and glorifies, in the Christians eyes, God the Father, the Son and Holy Spirit.</list-item><list-item>The 13th fold, or when the flag is completely folded, the stars are uppermost reminding them of their Nation’s motto, <quote>In God We Trust.</quote>.</list-item></list></subsection><subsection id="HBEB7542E73A6462CA57A1BA19836E783"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The next of kin or other agent of a deceased member of the Armed Forces or veteran may elect to not have the 13 Folds of Honor recited under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

