<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE0E9652A2BF2432FB05C8A2058E58BBE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 784 IH: African Diaspora Council Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 784</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250128">January 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Advisory Council on African Diaspora Engagement in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAD0B68F320F54E0DB7A2ACBE6A5CB475" style="OLC"><section id="HBB503840724945C2B11B2835E1DC3CB1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>African Diaspora Council Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6CFF9D1FBF784A76B5C8F2200620BAFB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Advisory council on African diaspora engagement in the united states</header><subsection id="HAA8113E759EE49A19FB84D1054334680"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There shall be established by the Secretary of State an advisory council within the Department of State to be known as the <quote>Advisory Council on African Diaspora Engagement in the United States</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Advisory Council</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD589D22E901B471FA1DA84D81CB03952"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="HDF0D450CE04141FCB64B5E198E8983FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Council shall consist of not more than 12 members, appointed by the Secretary of State, who are representatives of and reflect the diversity of the African diaspora from African American and African immigrant communities, including individuals who have distinguished themselves in government, sports, creative industries, business, academia, social work, and faith-based activities. Appointments to the Advisory Council shall be made without regard to political affiliation. The Secretary of State shall consult with the Chairman and Ranking Member of the Committee on Foreign Relations in the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs in the House of Representatives during the process of selecting representatives to the Advisory Council.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81574E30FAF04A7383D7454C8A06B00C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>Each member of the Advisory Council shall serve a 2-year term, without compensation or reimbursement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5DC2C0889B5457EB71CB4AD53439A0B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The Secretary of State shall designate a member of the Advisory Council to serve as Chair of the Advisory Council.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H573892F8FA10431BBB531AD3ECE3C834"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Executive director</header><text>The Secretary of State shall designate a senior officer or employee of the Department of State to serve as Executive Director of the Advisory Council.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8EA7E89146FF4C7D8DA675D70DEE49E8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions</header><paragraph id="H6B6E4912F5A5400CA6DC37AC2F1C9B40"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Advisory Council shall advise the President, through the Secretary of State, on strengthening connections between the United States Government and the African diaspora in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0683410A426421B82EC3AF9B1BE16E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information, analysis, and recommendations</header><text>In advising the President under paragraph (1), the Advisory Council shall provide information, analysis, and recommendations that address the following:</text><subparagraph id="HB100E34B704F40FE885B783990E095DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Strategies to advance equity and opportunity for African diaspora communities, including through efforts coordinated by the Domestic Policy Council under Executive Order 13985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note; relating to advancing racial equity and support for underserved communities through the Federal Government).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AF8CBE667CE43AC9F943D6E6F59E164"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Ways to support the United Nations Permanent Forum on People of African Descent.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFB047D133644C899F827BD56E9148B2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Programs and initiatives—</text><clause id="H16E985CC26D847C192721F869706F3A6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to strengthen cultural, social, political, and economic ties between African communities, the African diaspora, and the United States, such as the Young African Leaders Initiative; and</text></clause><clause id="H6932BB815F954C1EB3A094A3887D3911"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to address challenges and opportunities to advance inclusion, belonging, and public awareness of the diversity, accomplishments, culture, and history of the African diaspora.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D1288CD3CA544629C455A0041FB0CF0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Programs and initiatives, such as the International Visitor Leadership Program, to expand educational exchange programs between Africa and the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H432A851CB48642DC8ED235AC8097C367"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Programs and initiatives to increase public- and private-sector collaboration and community involvement in improving the socioeconomic well-being of African diaspora communities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90E1D27D4D5D48B3B86BEB2E01F1D493"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Programs and initiatives, such as Prosper Africa, to increase participation of members of the African diaspora in the United States with regard to trade, investment, economic growth, and development programs relating to Africa.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44530A68250B445B8C2C6B38157E2659"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Such other topics the Secretary of State considers relevant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2CB1A8A60ED34A3BA732D2F87C9C58BC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Funding; administrative support</header><text>The Secretary of State shall provide funding and administrative support for the Advisory Council, to the extent permitted by law and using amounts otherwise appropriated to the Department of State.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3C3E31C48F07424CB249D9FD5DBCC781"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Advisory Council shall meet on a quarterly basis or more frequently as necessary.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7B91180C300B4D96815E20C946E6BCE3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Congressional engagement</header><text>The Advisory Council shall brief the Committee on Foreign Relations in the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs in the House of Representatives after each plenary session.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

