<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H28D88B024AB24CF6B0E20DF7CB86FC74" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 478 IH: Promoting New Bank Formation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 478</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250116">January 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the appropriate Federal banking agencies to establish a 3-year phase-in period for de novo financial institutions to comply with Federal capital standards, to provide relief for de novo rural community banks, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCB44B6BE594749E5BA82F9B82FC3E36E" style="OLC"><section id="H4B8EBBAC8AC54222B6DDCDCA255E45D9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting New Bank Formation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0E5BE2F9D2FE446E84E58AE343982A0F" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Phase-in of capital standards</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Federal banking agencies shall issue rules that provide for a 3-year phase-in period for a depository institution or depository institution holding company to meet any Federal capital requirements that would otherwise be applicable to the depository institution or depository institution holding company, beginning on—</text><paragraph id="H7D4330B51046457696BD263B1961718F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date on which the depository institution became an insured depository institution; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB1C476E6CBC4FDFAD092DF758B7618D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a depository institution holding company, the date on which the depository institution subsidiary of the depository institution holding company became an insured depository institution.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H3D0293F421F6418C98B96F7B4C685C19"><enum>3.</enum><header>Changes to business plans</header><subsection id="HA63D4B13BF20493DABB2ED1EB8FFFAFF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 3-year period beginning on the date on which a depository institution became an insured depository institution, the insured depository institution or its depository institution holding company may request to deviate from a business plan that has been approved by the appropriate Federal banking agency by submitting a request to such agency pursuant to this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCE1822061C9E4416AE5239255D3E83D4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review of changes</header><text>An appropriate Federal banking agency shall, not later than the end of the 30-day period beginning on the receipt of a request under subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="HA7C466E8615B4394B19875898B26FF38"><enum>(1)</enum><text>approve, conditionally approve, or deny such request; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H772F6C996D3249A582F31D462428B47D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>notify the applicant of such decision and, if the agency denies the request—</text><subparagraph id="H162B83385C55406C916B748BDA18D127"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide the applicant with the reason for such denial; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3247AF7181F4CF2BCABCE8B2C6888A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>suggest changes to the request that, if adopted, would allow the agency to approve such request.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H745C6BBAD4A84C82B72CA70680451715"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Result of failure To act</header><text>If an appropriate Federal banking agency fails to approve or deny a request within the 30-day period required under subsection (b), such request shall be deemed to be approved.</text></subsection></section><section id="H56308B4161624D85BA29B47DD8A4C532"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rural community depository institution leverage ratio</header><subsection id="HDA2C9617AD6A4800B11323C3D8BD2DE8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 3-year period beginning on the date on which a rural depository institution became an insured depository institution, the Community Bank Leverage Ratio for the rural community bank shall be 8 percent.</text></subsection><subsection id="H10D073D1E95442EA946F4B3AE0356091"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Phase-In authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal banking agencies shall issue rules to phase-in the Community Bank Leverage Ratio described under subsection (a) with respect to a rural depository institution by setting lower Community Bank Leverage Ratio percentages during the first 2 years of the 3-year period described under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HE07500F3BF0C4F5DA5451AFC9550CA6D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HB652BB6E19604F0B8F57B6044285D4AC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community Bank Leverage Ratio</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Community Bank Leverage Ratio</term> has the meaning given that term under section 201(a) of the Economic Growth, Regulatory Relief, and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5371">12 U.S.C. 5371</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8254EE1292434A42B1192C4BF6ED978E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rural depository institution</header><text>The term <term>rural depository institution</term> means a depository institution—</text><subparagraph id="H3A76299241954356A8B6A80DAB3A9A0F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with total consolidated assets of less than $10,000,000,000; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44D3FB5A79044C27AA9A39C21CF3EA92"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">located in a rural area, as defined under section 1026.35(b)(iv)(A) of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H444C06BC85034D8B9E69BBF4FBCBFB1B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Agricultural loan authority for Federal savings associations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5(c) of the Home Owners’ Loan Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1464">12 U.S.C. 1464(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H46B00F364B164279AE859DBDF11D0AFB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H80E1FD8FC150431CB253C32A6901990D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H61212F2CF9D5404995E5C5F68EF85E94"><enum>(V)</enum><header>Agricultural loans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Secured or unsecured loans for agricultural purposes.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HB839F73B0DE24FEEB6AB855AC9F21FE5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A), by striking <quote>business, or agricultural</quote> and inserting <quote>or business</quote>. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H5CA1423D1CFC4ED689DDD43041DB2180"><enum>6.</enum><header>Study on de novo insured depository institutions</header><subsection id="H8F157983DB194EC38063298ECB684995"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal banking agencies shall, jointly, carry out a study on—</text><paragraph id="HE1B42EE6F8404E01A55441751B2BD465"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the principal causes for the low number of de novo insured depository institutions in the 10-year period ending on the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0596431039B494D9A67862F3DCA873E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ways to promote more de novo insured depository institutions in areas currently underserved by insured depository institutions.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDE4207E3200547839DB3041431AB46E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 1-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the Federal banking agencies shall, jointly, issue a report to Congress containing all findings and determinations made in carrying out the study required under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="HA00F73F28A31450ABBACB31923458DC9"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the terms <term>appropriate Federal banking agency</term>, <term>depository institution</term>, <term>depository institution holding company</term>, <quote>Federal banking agency</quote>, and <quote>insured depository institution</quote> have the meaning given those terms, respectively, under section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

