<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1479AAB5D0574A0C8769B626F18C2D21" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4189 IH: To direct the Secretary of the Navy to recognize certain aspects of the National Navy UDT–SEAL Museum in Fort Pierce, Florida, as a national memorial, national memorial garden, and national K9 memorial, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4189</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250626">June 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Navy to recognize certain aspects of
      the National Navy UDT–SEAL Museum in Fort Pierce, Florida, as a national memorial, national
      memorial garden, and national K9 memorial, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H483A5831A0524C8899A8A633BD5D798B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H83DE929E7AE6486DAC916BA573FC47AB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Recognition of certain aspects of the National Navy UDT–SEAL Museum in Fort Pierce, Florida, as a national memorial, national memorial garden, and national K9 memorial</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Navy shall recognize the National Navy SEAL Museum Memorial, the Memorial Garden and Living Beach, and the Naval Special Warfare K9 Memorial of the National Navy UDT–SEAL Museum, located at 3300 North Highway A1A, North Hutchinson Island, in Fort Pierce, Florida, as a national memorial, national memorial garden, and national K9 memorial, respectively, of the Navy SEALs.</text> </section> </legis-body></bill>

