<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA18428EBB4DB402E87FA24528B9551C4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 330 IH: Organ Donation Referral Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 330</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250109">January 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation, to conduct a study on existing efforts of hospitals with respect to electronic automated referrals for purposes of organ donation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3B772848DE024DE5877631CCC20A4B3E" style="OLC"><section id="H8C2F6FFFBD224D9EBEC28E4B1192C782" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Organ Donation Referral Improvement Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H3A0EA370981B4AD89D96AE4B392AC42C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Studying electronic automated referral for organ donations</header><subsection id="H49C4C21E7CAE43BB96CE184881C063FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), shall conduct and complete a study on existing efforts of hospitals with respect to electronic automated referrals for purposes of organ donation.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAF321F256504422CB9DFBF2F795AE418"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study components</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The study conducted under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="HA675831572AB4CA7BBECA1228AFC098F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify savings in staff time, variation in timeliness to determine eligibility for organ donation, as well as potential improvement over human interaction for the identification of potential organ donors, if any, attained through the use of electronic automated referrals; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB895A760B37492DB1F268121AA7B5DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify benefits, if any, in identifying potential organ donors through the use of electronic medical records and standardized clinical criteria; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H26C80C7FBF6D4D55873D5B94861956ED"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review the impact of such electronic automated referrals, without the need for manual reporting, on donation volumes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76436B2CBAED40E28F03F372E6886B83"><enum>(4)</enum><text>assess published peer-reviewed clinical literature on such electronic automated referrals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1978B454FC5345EFAC53CBC7478514F8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>review best practices for using such electronic automated referrals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8618612DF3164D1FB4809B983AA76074"><enum>(6)</enum><text>review information technology practices to ensure the secure transmission of information for purposes of such referrals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H214DA03BFB7B4569834D1AB34D61D8E7"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop recommendations to promote the use of such electronic automated referrals; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90347E2F3A2D4D118C6B9D030D41ED51"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify what actions are needed to establish the use of such electronic automated referrals nationwide.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4D2DA0D49E6741FD9ADEA2778A3C3698"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report on the results of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H6BD3DB0E49954E38BA07376074FC75E1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Electronic automated referral defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>electronic automated referral</term> means an electronic system that identifies potential deceased organ donors via clinical criteria in a patient’s electronic health record and automatically refers such patients to the hospital’s collaborating organ procurement organization.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

