<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE55D9F9E214A44318003A8F4AADC4514" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2475 IH: Youth Homelessness Guaranteed Income Pilot Program Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2475</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a pilot program to provide financial and non-financial housing assistance to certain homeless individuals, to provide for a study of the effects of the pilot program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7CA00811D1D042A596A7364F15C390A5" style="OLC"><section id="H4C8D741E01E9457CA46666176C6A4EB4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Youth Homelessness Guaranteed Income Pilot Program Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDBF2EA30B6814A56AB10D89AFCCF4515"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H62484CC197FA4361B2BCFC60F7AB5F86"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each year, an estimated 4,200,000 youth and young adults experience homelessness in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3172C4AA8444A688242B9A3F7F869B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Youth and young adults face many barriers to safe and stable housing, such as systemic and structural racism, age discrimination, and a scarce supply of affordable housing suitable for occupancy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4B87E210B6C42B5A8A304F3B838DEC8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Black, Indigenous, and other youth and young adults of color have been systematically excluded from employment opportunities and access to stable income.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC172FE966824776ABDC6A2DEAD5A7AD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Prior to the COVID–19 pandemic, 1 in 5 young people of color were living in poverty, as opposed to 1 in 9 young White people, and the impact of the pandemic has resulted in an exponential widening of the inequity faced by Black, Indigenous, and other youth and young adults of color when seeking safe housing and careers of their choice with stable income.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8063D485BE3D4C388AC024B8107DE136"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Full-time minimum-wage earners cannot afford the average cost of a 2-bedroom apartment anywhere in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD1BE9F7E7694F3FB6917A00B303F819"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The changing nature of the economy—including the growth of the <quote>gig economy</quote> in which workers earn income providing on-demand work, services, or goods; unemployment risks posed by automation; and the fluctuating nature of waged labor—will result in increased income volatility and prevent upward economic mobility, especially among young adults.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H3EDC0754719F4679B1ADCC33E1DA5636" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HE449C218D2434917B52F2BA4FF04E586"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H4CA4E8D1FAF9455E83ABB2F7A90AB37A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H240074EC384D40E4BAB6BC1F60D52B6E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H049C6DD0D79343118CAF3BCFAE7E1811"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6E43ED9AE4C4790A4056FD901FFCBCF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H388F99CAE13C4EA0B9E0962A5E060259"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certified community development financial institution</header><text>The term <quote>certified community development financial institution</quote> means a community development financial institution, as defined in section 103 of the Community Development Banking and Financial Institutions Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4702">12 U.S.C. 4702</external-xref>), certified by the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund under section 1805.201 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B2C7BA117654087B59DC88897D1914C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Council</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Council</quote> means the National Youth Economic Advisory Council.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70700E3408DA44EB8AAC006F477F60FC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Database</header><text>The term <quote>database</quote> means the database created under section 4(b)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8F5F2E340F3454B8A77663139184658"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Fair market rent</header><text>The term <quote>fair market rent</quote> means the applicable fair market rental established pursuant to section 8(c) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(c)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H836D2C50CC4245D498FCCB7FDADF828B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Historically marginalized communities</header><text>The term <quote>historically marginalized communities</quote> includes low-income communities and minority religious, racial, and ethnic groups.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDAE2C84F88A84875823EDE0691D9CB5C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Homeless</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>homeless</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 103 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11302">42 U.S.C. 11302</external-xref>) and includes homeless children and youths as defined in section 725 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11434a">42 U.S.C. 11434a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA45865358DD441548805EA12EF95261E"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Low-income geographic area</header><text>The term <quote>low-income geographic area</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 351 of the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/689">15 U.S.C. 689</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE313A687D9774B2CA23EC29381CC2554"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Payment-receiving group</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>payment-receiving group</quote> means the group designated to receive cash payments pursuant to section 4(c)(3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE905A397341841C3948DA512445AED4F"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>pilot program</quote> means the Youth Homelessness Guaranteed Income Pilot Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC11DF278CEB40D6A0D5305E143495A2"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Program payment</header><text>The term <quote>program payment</quote> means a payment made under section 4(c)(3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1C31C02BF824501A8F6B4E2F8B6B0F1"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Racial and ethnic minority group</header><text>The term <quote>racial and ethnic minority group</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 1707(g) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300u-6">42 U.S.C. 300u–6(g)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71AAB29312324411950771E3B8FC3860"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HECB2FBED044447CD91976E526DAD2A83"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Socially disadvantaged group</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>socially disadvantaged group</quote> means a group whose members have been subjected to racial, ethnic, or gender prejudice because of their identity as members of a group without regard to their individual qualities.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HCEF2A6055E6A42508EB34651F75F6C4C"><enum>4.</enum><header>The Youth Homelessness Guaranteed Income Pilot Program</header><subsection id="H669C254C4B224E7C93FF30B0AEDA7B44" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program, entitled the <quote>Youth Homelessness Guaranteed Income Pilot Program</quote>, to provide housing assistance to certain eligible individuals in accordance with this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0FA3FC4501E3450781731CB0487A2AE5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preparation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act:</text><paragraph id="HBF0770DCA0D34F36BDB8E3BD6BD1A186"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Database of homeless individuals</header><subparagraph id="H09AE202C015848209D6544DF776EBFBE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Creation of database</header><text>The Secretary shall create a database of individuals who are homeless while living in the United States containing the information described in section 6(b)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD51CFBE18C814999BE25B477D7FAF9A0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible participants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Based on the recommendations issued by the Council under section 6(b)(1), the Secretary—</text><clause id="HCB729C74025744BCA95A5DF6EAC5160F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall make reasonable efforts using reliable sources to identify homeless individuals for inclusion in the database; and</text></clause><clause id="H2C58445010F946078AFC7A673CD0F5FC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may communicate recommendations to the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Education, or the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development with respect to the prescription of regulations described in subparagraph (C).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C52A90FAA1B4527B54E57FB28768287"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Authority to prescribe regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Education, and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may each prescribe regulations requiring a recipient of funds or other assistance under the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11301">42 U.S.C. 11301–11435</external-xref>)—</text><clause id="HCBFF9976A2AA47438BEE1296D90889A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to make reasonable efforts to identify homeless individuals who receive benefits or assistance provided through the funds; and</text></clause><clause id="HDD836ACA7C4F401EA919429B9F19F9F4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to submit sufficient information to the Secretary for the homeless individuals to be listed in the database.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1500EE08547E48C3A3129CCF6482B388"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Requirements for database information</header><text>The Secretary—</text><clause id="H924FEDBCAA6945F3816CDE2C1B7CE1D4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall verify the accuracy of the information in the database;</text></clause><clause id="HEE2FC2F5521540BB91F1C1E6CB6F8BFF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall include in the database, with respect to each individual listed in the database, only the information necessary to—</text><subclause id="H1831FD6514534A188B8F7C8AA47866DA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>determine the eligibility of the individual to participate in the pilot program; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H5497B6AED0874E45A422301A3B25882B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>administer the pilot program with the individual as a participant; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HEB9594B622D149EEB98EC10DB26C9C40"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>may not include in the database any information about the citizenship status, immigration status, or Social Security number of any individual listed in the database.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H522D8FC90AB44CBCB0372CFC03579351"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Report to Congress on the database</header><text>The Secretary shall submit a written report to the appropriate congressional committees describing the process used to create the database.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB533957C2C646CFBD217C0763030D5B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection of pilot program participants</header><subparagraph id="HA057608108EC4FB7A8646A6F57524C96"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in coordination with the External Partner and the Council, shall develop criteria for the selection of pilot program participants that are—</text><clause id="HD81A8670A93447DDA938B36AD250CEAD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consistent with the objectives of the study described in section 5;</text></clause><clause id="H254D44B08C8D4AD997C9A6EC568EB5E4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>inclusive of low-income geographic areas; and</text></clause><clause id="H8E63E9A4F77D405DA60BAF8C728CD93D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>representative of the demographics of the population of homeless individuals in the United States who have not attained 30 years of age.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70837DFAFCC44DC485861BC1B4533FB7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The Secretary shall select, consistent with the criteria developed under subparagraph (A), not more than 105,000 individuals listed in the database to participate in the pilot program, each of whom shall be—</text><clause id="H018ADED5B37E443299B0030294EB4D5E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an emancipated minor; or</text></clause><clause id="H64BDEDCA99714DC2A58DE84295046C2A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an individual who has attained 18 years of age but not 30 years of age.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38B2F668EEAE4F2EB5824A9CC6F5BF16"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Impermissible factors</header><text>The Secretary may not use citizenship or immigration status as factors in the selection of pilot program participants.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1D9F14DCAE9460A89D46D24A5FF57A9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conditions for participation in the pilot program</header><text>An individual may not participate in the pilot program until the individual, in a form and manner determined by the Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="HA48D159FF1CE4CECA8D3B16E416FEED5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consents to the disclosure of Federal and State income tax return information of the individual to the Secretary and the External Partner; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8DF590B961B4F63A59AE2DE5F4BAC24"><enum>(B)</enum><text>discloses other personal information determined by the Secretary to be necessary for the administration of the pilot program and the study described in section 5, including the ZIP Code of the primary place of residence maintained by the individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE6F986EE210443E2948FDF2588B1652A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Provision of assistance</header><paragraph id="H6A7C392204E047848D3C3399AB55130B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Secretary shall provide the assistance described in this subsection to the pilot program participants for 36 consecutive months.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85BFF8560E2247F78A05F1A6595906C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistance available to all participants</header><text>Based on the recommendations issued by the Council under section 6(b)(2), and in consultation with the External Partner, the Secretary shall, directly or by contract or cooperative agreement, provide to each participant, appropriate to the circumstances of the participant, the following:</text><subparagraph id="HA7129E8B1DE34C4BB5896F9AFE830E18" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Housing navigation services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC48C95DF02234CD0A5117C81DECA7375"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Financial coaching courses.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56C935427F754281A61665ADF75006D4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Workforce development services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DFE33B0B724436AB9459344CBC521C7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Educational attainment services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA74161363B3545DF9219E233F21524A0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Education on the landlord-tenant laws of the jurisdiction of residence of the participant and the rights that the participant would have as a tenant.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H074A15C682064A119EE62C443FF38E51"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Additional services recommended by the Council and the External Partner, at the discretion of the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4502C7287E8545808A9D8343B935552D"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance in identifying, applying for, and using any service or assistance available to the participant that is funded under the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11301">42 U.S.C. 11301–11435</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5962FC3D26FE4F8396EDEE41BFC49A54"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cash payments to the payment-receiving group</header><subparagraph id="H781BF3FE287146A18C1BE746A500831E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Division into 2 groups</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><clause id="H022C5919C25A4AFFAA7769A5035E261D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>divide the participants randomly into 2 groups, approximately equal in size and equally representative with respect to the criteria for the selection of participants; and</text></clause><clause id="H3DEF03E845FD402BB46F9510C5DD6A33"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>designate 1 group to receive cash payments pursuant to this paragraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBCD13F7214B435594B46AB9761710D0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Frequency; amount</header><clause id="H65431BC1C9BB468DA8A935DCC962A106"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall make a payment to each member of the payment-receiving group every month for the duration described in paragraph (1), with each monthly payment in the amount equal to or the greater of $1,400 or the adjusted fair market rent cost for the member involved.</text></clause><clause id="H33F2700392B9475396308F4E946D2FE9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Adjusted fair market rent cost</header><text>The Secretary shall determine the adjusted fair market rent cost for such a member based on the fair market rent cost for a 2-bedroom home in the ZIP Code designated by the member and any modifications recommended by the Council under section 6(b)(4).</text></clause><clause id="HB7810DC70A8E41A4BFCE4BEDA3A0BBE3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Lump sum payment permitted for the 1st year</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding clause (i), not more than half of the members of the payment-receiving group may elect to receive not more than the first 12 monthly payments under clause (i) in a single lump sum payment.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC10DAF2130849D8A3DB3EDC7A4093C1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Forms of payment</header><text>The Secretary shall make each program payment by whichever of the following methods is elected by the participant involved:</text><clause id="H940C56FCC57746189DA31069E3293B33"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Cash.</text></clause><clause id="H40D3698843474289BDB956359BC1CBBA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Electronic funds transfer.</text></clause><clause id="HFDA696029AEE4A10A8302346122E667B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Prepaid debit card.</text></clause><clause id="H21CB277499C6420FB5530A61519FBA0E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Any other method offered by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80FF2BCDDC1A477B8A6552CE9636A3A0"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Day of payment</header><text>Each member of the payment-receiving group may elect to receive the monthly payment on the first or last weekday of the month that is not a legal public holiday.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB1B91DC7B98D4683A4B0F8323AC77451" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Privacy protections</header><paragraph id="HFDFBFB72039C42288855A57EF16D8E36"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disclosures prohibited</header><text>A person shall not disclose any information related to the pilot program, except to the extent permitted by regulations prescribed under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF881CC010EBA400190F4C65412419D9E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations for sharing information</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Council and External Partner, may prescribe regulations to provide for the sharing of information in the database, without personal identifiers, with nonprofit organizations and academic institutions for noncommercial research purposes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A39661991A3485AA70D6D70504D70C6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Destruction of database</header><text>The Secretary shall destroy the database within 30 days after the Council terminates.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5A8CF5F9A154C1B9A849F3C3BEB1C3D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Violations</header><subparagraph id="H03C8C9832F444566AA21891B4A952843"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any person who, by virtue of an official position or affiliation with the Secretary, the Council, or the External Partner—</text><clause id="H84EA39D0CF9D42E081AA2C1F768B1BC0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has possession of, or access to, any record containing individually identifiable information the disclosure of which is prohibited by or under this Act; and</text></clause><clause id="HA79725FD0D7541D89968877457844195"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>knowingly discloses such a record to any person or agency not entitled to receive the record,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and fined not more than $25,000.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H524F4FA6E7E94C73A29D8CA1BDAD6A70"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any person who knowingly requests or obtains any record related to the pilot program from the Secretary, the Council, or the External Partner under false pretenses shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and fined not more than $25,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0F1D6DA4306642E6A8B54116CB31A826"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Relationship to other programs, benefits, and laws</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law:</text><paragraph id="H7CB6841204A1417B95826801FA0F589A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Participation in the pilot program, including the receipt of program payments, may not be considered for the purposes of determining—</text><subparagraph id="HA9AEBE35D1D84E24BB5E9B0EA5FB2234"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the eligibility of a participant for, or the amount or timing of, any benefit or assistance under any Federal program or under any State or local program financed, in whole or in part, with Federal funds; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFBD7444809C4E54A1C1F90C9D21A4B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether a participant is a public charge under section 212(a)(4) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(4)</external-xref>) or section 237(a)(5) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1227">8 U.S.C. 1227(a)(5)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC6A91788B5F40A98BDFDA9414128C6F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, gross income shall not include any program payment to a participant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDB2A07AC3BE43D19A0A1DA533A60F58"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 401 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1611">8 U.S.C. 1611</external-xref>) shall not apply to this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4EB7F5F103F24B6F9CD01F0055F234C5"><enum>5.</enum><header>Study</header><subsection id="H03CE26F24EF74D9DAE25878276E09425"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct, in coordination with the External Partner selected pursuant to this section, a study on the effects of the pilot program.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4F98C256B8BC4619ACEBFF5D3A2EAE62"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text>The primary objectives of the study shall be—</text><paragraph id="H98C230FFC7E2453DABF32FDE82EC9FE9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to analyze the effect of the program payments on—</text><subparagraph id="H336DF5462A99427DA5602CE9E7C3C457"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the housing outcomes of the pilot program participants;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C86893DE48541F5BEBBE364DF76FF1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the microeconomic outcomes of the participants;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC50A1AB68DF640C382F88635FD9D7BEE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the physical and mental health and well-being of the participants; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4B57866A4A04216AB659645E17C2050"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the social cost attributable to income volatility and homelessness, including through public expenditures for government-provided services in health, education, employment, and childcare; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4947F35CE374481DB14A8FC423FA0723"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to evaluate the feasibility of—</text><subparagraph id="HF8596345D3D34F9E8036BB5459107477"><enum>(A)</enum><text>expanding the pilot program to include more participants in the payment-receiving group; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA04B02E00E5E44FF8BE29939B5474239"><enum>(B)</enum><text>using direct cash transfers to reduce homelessness in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B4329287773496596180BDE8655B54D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection of the External Partner</header><paragraph id="H4AE51917F8BC4D39BB223E350CB01234"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Within 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and before complying with section 4(b)(2), the Secretary shall choose an organization with demonstrated experience and expertise in mixed-methods experimental design and the implementation of cash-transfer programs and randomized controlled trials to be the External Partner.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7130CC8F5FF4BAF83E52A6D4E8E6A7E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conditions on selection</header><text>The Secretary may require the External Partner to employ the services of certain qualified individuals in carrying out the responsibilities of the External Partner under this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8F2D4510A79414D972E8E4270AEEDF8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compensation for services rendered</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may pay not more than the hourly equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay for grade GS–12, step 5, of the General Schedule for each hour (including travel time) during which a person affiliated with the External Partner is engaged in the performance of duties of the External Partner under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE27DC42DAD8140FB9EA3B3A911B7D2AC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties of the External Partner</header><paragraph id="H4354DA4A56D04C7E81914B2244BB7DD9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Selection of study criteria</header><text>The External Partner shall make recommendations to the Secretary on—</text><subparagraph id="H9AF0B01664BB45E5BF04BE9F9FB37D1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how to accomplish the primary objectives described in subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40357B33D3724147A243723A47E6B4A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>additional objectives for the study.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CFA76BD45704A1294F54E11C4FECCF1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Data collection</header><text>Under the oversight of the Secretary, the External Partner shall collect the data required for the study and may use any information about a pilot program participant given by the Secretary to the External Partner for the study.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDC20A50CFF91489FAF5FDA3A223311F9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the External Partner, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees—</text><paragraph id="H5614BA934944407D8A6AD2CEBA0B3B7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an interim report, within 24 months after the commencement of pilot program services; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF675BA323EAE4B89BE68ECDBA130512C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a final report, within 12 months after the conclusion of the pilot program services.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE63F8B529C9342448751887011924084"><enum>6.</enum><header>National Youth Economic Advisory Council</header><subsection id="HBB2EE592DC4F4F0DA8B369D031C9D2E8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish the National Youth Economic Advisory Council.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCFFD7F090E5249178CFEA6861375C399" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><paragraph id="H1071B41BE73D4650BB9628B922FA0ABC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Recommendations for the database and the selection of the External Partner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council shall issue recommendations to the Secretary with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="H693597724739412496BBDFEC91E23F4B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the identification and utilization of reliable sources of information for identifying homeless individuals and listing the individuals in the database with sufficient information for the Secretary to select any individual listed in the database to participate in the pilot program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC2931903B8243AC8C9DF16EBD4438CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any regulation that may be prescribed by the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Agriculture, or the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development with respect to the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11301">42 U.S.C. 11301–11435</external-xref>) to facilitate the identification of homeless individuals for inclusion in the database; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD884D59C8A784240BC61E149D2E1750F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the selection of the External Partner.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6186E1255D8445B9051D74124340304"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recommendations for the selection criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council shall issue recommendations to the Secretary with respect to the selection criteria for pilot program participants that are consistent with the objectives of the study and with the demographics of the homeless population in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9188AB3C1B2847FCB5D320092D1D5660"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recommendations for forms of assistance</header><text>The Council shall issue recommendations to the Secretary on the forms of assistance to be provided to a pilot program participant pursuant to section 4(c)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H043DF8099DEB49CEB3E1EE1B16F9944F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Recommendations for the adjusted fair market cost</header><text>The Council shall issue recommendations to the Secretary on modifications to the fair market cost in the determination of the adjusted fair market cost under section 4(c)(3)(B)(ii).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H216A0C2738174866B64D909B73A98FA4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Recommendations for administration of the program</header><text>The Council may issue recommendations to the Secretary for improving the performance and administration of the pilot program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8227B2D3C9C424DB05573ABF46C87DA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Recommendations for the study</header><text>The Council may issue recommendations to the Secretary or the External Partner on other objectives of the study.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA9C48A8CA3084374833F3C68AE631F5D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="H60AB4873C5A747AA8D80C77E8B2340C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointment</header><subparagraph id="HFCB868FF5C5F4B82A09EE8306AD45FFE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Regular members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall appoint the following regular members of the Council:</text><clause id="H91F882D03AD74F7987D2CB956FE21A5D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A member representing the Secretary, who shall chair the Council.</text></clause><clause id="H628FC49456374218929F493D3A30DDA4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A representative from a national nonprofit homeless youth organization.</text></clause><clause id="HCEC726E2D37F4A318460D48D3E13FDFB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A representative from a national nonprofit civil rights organization representing historically marginalized communities or socially disadvantaged groups.</text></clause><clause id="HFF2592D742A7429DAA09D369A3F9589A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A representative from a national organization representing LGBTQ+ populations.</text></clause><clause id="HD3A270F650E64ABD9E00966D94CEC884"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A representative from an economic research organization or academic institution with expertise in cash-transfer programs.</text></clause><clause id="H752B6F40D68C40D0ABBD91C0E1DB18A7"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>A representative from a community advocacy organization with expertise in cash-transfer programs.</text></clause><clause id="H4B01C835852B46F79B13FCD309840732"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>A representative from a certified community development financial institution whose central demographic is of a racial and ethnic minority group.</text></clause><clause id="H2AEAED5091AB40C48C8DFF1AA7F6B620"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>A member representing the Department of Housing and Urban Development, nominated by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></clause><clause id="H90314360BCF349A08356CF48A8DDFC82"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>A member representing the Department of Education, nominated by the Secretary of Education.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H146E356C0A424AF6A87BAF6F3613565B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorized members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall appoint to the Council 3 individuals included in the database who were not selected as pilot program participants, after the Secretary begins providing the services under section 4(c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AD14EC552F9408E903C098D8EA1C374"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continuation of membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an incumbent member is appointed to the Council as a representative of an organization and the incumbent member ceases to be affiliated with the organization, the incumbent member may continue as a member until the Secretary appoints a new member in the stead of the incumbent member.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE747211D12B34F249995A7CBCA2B21AD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may remove a member for inefficiency, neglect of duty, or malfeasance in office.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB1D3AA9D2CBE4713AB5810859C980F1D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Pay</header><paragraph id="H146FDC725D2644C8B4DFFCB22A707F72"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rates of pay</header><text>Members of the Council shall each be entitled to receive the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay for grade GS–14, step 10, of the General Schedule for each day (including travel time) during which such members are engaged in the performance of duties of the Council.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61FB60380C614D1088F4057602912AEC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition of compensation of Federal employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the members of the Council who are full-time officers or employees of the United States or Members of Congress for purposes of title 5, United States Code, may not receive additional pay, allowances, or benefits by reason of service on the Council.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE47B68D868A7476C8847889FA72FC04F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>Each member shall receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with applicable provisions of subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC105741BED3246FFA4862AAA82A0E541"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Staff</header><text>On request of the Council and on a reimbursable basis, for the purpose of assisting the Council in carrying out the duties of the Council, the Secretary, the Secretary of Education, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services may each detail to the Council any personnel of their respective departments.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5AA7596FD37D434997E95FD5E8EB652E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Frequency of meetings</header><paragraph id="H69BFCEC0CBF644009260EB383B4C2E58"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Council shall meet at least every 3 months.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H919E2759EA21402EAC83F23E46DCC737"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Discretion of the Secretary</header><text>The Secretary may require the Council to sit for additional meetings at the discretion of the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EB055BC41A14A87813CCF51C7C6B4F3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Discretion of the Chair</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chair may require the Council to sit for additional meetings at the discretion of the Chair or on written request of <fraction>1/3</fraction> of the members.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F7C0D8649DC40BBBD030E2D59E639C2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notice to members</header><text>The Chair shall give each member of the Council notice of a meeting no fewer than 15 days before the meeting.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H90BF99B383E3415EA1B333CA62A7CC6B" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Charter; quorum</header><paragraph id="H55215EE35F574DC19FDF4283CC49E9E7" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Council charter</header><text>The Council shall comply with section 1008(c) of title 5, United States Code, as if—</text><subparagraph id="HB2DC1DDC2FE146978F1BC7170FF323BA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Council were an advisory committee but not a Presidential advisory committee;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A0CAAB96DEC49958812B3736B9802C1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary were the head of the agency to whom the advisory committee reports; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95DBFAD962944388A897192F2F9520EF" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the appropriate congressional committees were the standing committees of the Senate and House of Representatives having legislative jurisdiction over the agency to which the advisory committee reports.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDB2A7B89C61433EBA3DDB6907E81389" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional contents in Council charter</header><text>The charter filed pursuant to paragraph (1) shall contain provisions to determine—</text><subparagraph id="H61366C17F0444B6B83E0FA0CABC452B2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">quorum;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E8111B6FD8F4C879DCF92EA0D7E6A73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the information required to be disclosed, in any notice of a Council meeting, about the matters to be discussed in the meeting;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB877DA940C0D491BBC6925C1FE15E2BE" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>when a member has a conflict of interest in a matter being considered by the Council; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H220759D82EA140858262942A87407248" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the circumstances under which a conflict of interest in a matter may or shall disqualify a member from participating in considering, or voting on, the matter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H28936F5DB00D4AB38A651A3DB7B812C0" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>Until the filing of the charter, a majority of the members of the Council appointed shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number may hold hearings.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF7D8492A699149259969797F8CF1CE77"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Powers</header><paragraph id="H8D68D64976784BB89BC0305E120AEC3E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hearings and sessions</header><text>The Council may, for the purpose of carrying out this section, hold hearings, sit and act at times and places, take testimony, administer oaths or affirmations to witnesses appearing before the Council, and receive evidence as the Council considers appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8754427178DD4D42907738931CB3A9D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Obtaining official data</header><text>The Council may secure directly from any department or agency of the United States information necessary to enable the Council to carry out the duties of the Council under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43EB5629FCEB4DD9B776867FD0AA8FEF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administrative support services</header><text>On request of the Council, the Administrator of General Services shall provide to the Council, on a reimbursable basis, the administrative support services necessary for the Commission to carry out the duties of the Council under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDB125629E14E49B196E2E5566FDECC6C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="HEE36D5BC0724472AB1EA12C000C10DF8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interim reports</header><text>The Council may submit to the Secretary such interim reports as the Council considers appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0200B3433A3448B9548B230ACB58226"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>The Council shall submit a final report to the Secretary containing an assessment of the Council with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="H8353ECFF931143148C6362D532EDE694"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the pilot program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D6A6A361ACC43059884369F06CB4065"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the report submitted by the Secretary pursuant to section 5(e)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1CAB825B73A24674B9F07B8D0E35108D"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Council shall terminate within 30 days after the Secretary submits the report pursuant to section 5(e)(2).</text></subsection><subsection id="H97C703576CD743F2AB698C2BFF25B905"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Exemption from Federal Advisory Committee Act</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (g)(1) of this section, <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to the Council, but the Secretary may prescribe regulations directing the Council to comply with sections 1009 through 1111 of such title if the Secretary determines that the compliance is necessary for the Council to discharge the duties of the Council.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

