<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HEA07A3AE31F846069F438E24E85C5200" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 21 EH: Electing Members to certain standing committees of the House of Representatives.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="no">119th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="no">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. RES. 21</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20250109">January 9, 2025</action-date>
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Electing Members to certain standing committees of the House of Representatives.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="H08372FF9CF7B4ECD918611EDBC33E7E3"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H5D5ECCCE670340C3AB1FCD3BB5091FB0"><text>That the following named Members be, and are hereby, elected to the following standing committees of the House of Representatives:</text> <committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Appropriations:</header><text>Mr. Rogers of Kentucky, Mr. Aderholt, Mr. Simpson, Mr. Carter of Texas, Mr. Calvert, Mr. Diaz-Balart, Mr. Womack, Mr. Fleischmann, Mr. Joyce of Ohio, Mr. Harris of Maryland, Mr. Amodei of Nevada, Mr. Valadao, Mr. Newhouse, Mr. Moolenaar, Mr. Rutherford, Mr. Cline, Mr. Reschenthaler, Mrs. Hinson, Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas, Ms. Letlow, Mr. Cloud, Mr. Guest, Mr. Zinke, Mr. Clyde, Mrs. Bice, Mr. Scott Franklin of Florida, Mr. Ellzey, Mr. Ciscomani, Mr. Edwards, Mr. Alford, Mr. LaLota, Ms. Maloy, Mr. Strong, Mr. Moore of West Virginia.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Energy and Commerce:</header><text>Mr. Latta, Mr. Griffith, Mr. Bilirakis, Mr. Hudson, Mr. Carter of Georgia, Mr. Palmer, Mr. Dunn of Florida, Mr. Crenshaw, Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania, Mr. Weber of Texas, Mr. Allen, Mr. Balderson, Mr. Fulcher, Mr. Pfluger, Mrs. Harshbarger, Mrs. Miller-Meeks, Mrs. Cammack, Mr. Obernolte, Mr. James, Mr. Bentz, Mrs. Houchin, Mr. Fry, Ms. Lee of Florida, Mr. Langworthy, Mr. Kean, Mr. Rulli, Mr. Evans of Colorado, Mr. Goldman of Texas, Mrs. Fedorchak.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph> <committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Financial Services:</header><text>Mr. Lucas, Mr. Sessions, Mr. Huizenga, Mrs. Wagner, Mr. Barr, Mr. Williams of Texas, Mr. Emmer, Mr. Loudermilk, Mr. Davidson, Mr. Rose, Mr. Steil, Mr. Timmons, Mr. Stutzman, Mr. Norman, Mr. Meuser, Mrs. Kim, Mr. Donalds, Mr. Garbarino, Mr. Fitzgerald, Mr. Flood, Mr. Lawler, Ms. De La Cruz, Mr. Ogles, Mr. Nunn of Iowa, Mrs. McClain, Ms. Salazar, Mr. Downing, Mr. Haridopolos, Mr. Moore of North Carolina.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Ways and Means:</header><text>Mr. Buchanan, Mr. Smith of Nebraska, Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania, Mr. Schweikert, Mr. LaHood, Mr. Arrington, Mr. Estes, Mr. Smucker, Mr. Hern of Oklahoma, Mrs. Miller of West Virginia, Mr. Murphy, Mr. Kustoff, Mr. Fitzpatrick, Mr. Steube, Ms. Tenney, Mrs. Fischbach, Mr. Moore of Utah, Ms. Van Duyne, Mr. Feenstra, Ms. Malliotakis, Mr. Carey, Mr. Yakym, Mr. Miller of Ohio, Mr. Bean of Florida, Mr. Moran.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph> </section> </resolution-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </resolution> 

