<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Reported-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-MDM25360-5LR-N1-N05"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 29 RS: Expressing the sense of the Senate that the President of the United States possesses legal authority under existing law to take immediate and necessary action to secure the southwest border of the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 5</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 29</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250121">January 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</sponsor>, from the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name>, reported the following original resolution; which was placed on the calendar</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the Senate that the President of the United States possesses legal authority under existing law to take immediate and necessary action to secure the southwest border of the United States.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, since the start of the Biden-Harris Administration, nearly 11,000,000 individuals have been encountered attempting to enter the United States unlawfully;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas U.S. Customs and Border Protection has—</text><paragraph id="idb77129950fe54897b65ac9087d3f26dd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>apprehended nearly 400 suspected terrorists attempting to enter the United States illegally between ports of entry; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id03fa7b6f5cd54cd5887e33d9722defef"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encountered an additional 1,587 suspected terrorists at United States ports of entry; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id95300904459e4039b491cb84b52611d3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identified more than 1,700,000 special interest aliens;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since October 1, 2021, more than 120,000 illegal aliens with criminal warrants or convictions were encountered along United States borders, including—</text><paragraph id="id9dbd598a86ee46cb81cdba8445aec4ce"><enum>(1)</enum><text>more than 4,800 illegal aliens who were convicted of assault, battery, or domestic violence;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb17e2af90e7a4fcd89e27e5e5c5f1d76"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">more than 3,300 illegal aliens who were convicted of theft-related offenses;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id107db6f1c63b4fcca2ef6dc934595509"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">nearly 1,400 illegal aliens who were convicted of sexual offenses; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfb64d513d75344b3ad34aa61258d2457"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">nearly 200 illegal aliens who were convicted of homicide or manslaughter;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, under section 235(b)(2)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1225">8 U.S.C. 1225(b)(2)(C)</external-xref>), the Department of Homeland Security is authorized to immediately return certain applicants for admission or asylum to a contiguous foreign territory in accordance with the memorandum from the Secretary of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Policy Guidance for Implementation of the Migrant Protection Protocols</quote>, dated January 25, 2019, or any substantially similar policy changes issued or taken on or after January 20, 2025, whether set forth in a memorandum, executive order, regulation, directive, or by other action;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, under section 212(f) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(f)</external-xref>), the President has been given broad authority to suspend the entry of all aliens, or to impose any restrictions upon the entry of aliens the President deems appropriate, allowing the President to bar the entry of nationals whose admission could be detrimental to the interests of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, under section 208(b)(2)(C) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1158">8 U.S.C. 1158(b)(2)(C)</external-xref>), the Department of Homeland Security is authorized to promulgate additional limitations and conditions under which an alien shall be ineligible for asylum, including making asylum seekers ineligible if they enter or attempt to enter the United States across the southern border without first applying for protection from persecution or torture in at least 1 country, other than the alien’s country of citizenship, nationality, or last lawful habitual residence, through which the alien transited en route to the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the <quote>Remain in Mexico</quote> policy (also known as the Migrant Protection Protocols) was an effective measure that enhanced border security, helped deter illegal entries, and made the United States safer: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idf95d29d6e3934f2db3fea19142e449a4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>affirms that the President has the authority under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>), including sections 208(a)(2)(A), 212(f), and 235(b)(2)(C) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1158">8 U.S.C. 1158(a)(2)(A)</external-xref>, 1182(f), and 1225(b)(2)(C)) to take action to secure the southern border and protect the sovereignty and security of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idff3713606acc4d969954eebb7f8b6f71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>urges the President and the Secretary of Homeland Security to utilize all available statutory authority to expeditiously reinstate or implement policies and programs that will promote orderly and lawful entry at the border, deter illegal immigration, and protect national security, including by—</text><subparagraph id="id10754ff274ec4a4b8abc316775b1f4c9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>immediately removing illegal aliens;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id41b6d667a5ec4b44aeffb5a0d4b67d07"><enum>(B)</enum><text>immediately returning illegal aliens to Mexico;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9c345bbc037945d9b96a6eafe20f8ad2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reinstating the Migrant Protection Protocols (commonly known as <quote>Remain in Mexico</quote>) or any substantially similar policy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5d5fce359c5445bba4067a96bb59f9ee"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ending the catch-and-release policy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id14721554afc341188afa4a02755f5f4f"><enum>(E)</enum><text>ending abuses of humanitarian parole authority;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id596effcc68e745339163f49729dd0e54"><enum>(F)</enum><text>detaining inadmissible aliens;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id89657fb4ad1049e1b63e5eb952c681eb"><enum>(G)</enum><text>making illegal aliens ineligible for asylum;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id57670f77bdb34e1caf3bee4771a618c5"><enum>(H)</enum><text>using expedited removal authority; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id38fe2b7e18904fa5bd69882920948441"><enum>(I)</enum><text>eliminating taxpayer-funded benefits for illegal aliens.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body><endorsement><action-date date="20250121">January 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported the following original resolution; which was placed on the calendar</action-desc></endorsement></resolution> 

