<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H99B9520A5CCB4664956265603C25ABE3" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 556 IH: Impeaching Charles R. Breyer, Senior Judge of the United States District Court for the Northern District of California, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 556</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250627">June 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Impeaching Charles R. Breyer, Senior Judge of the United States District Court for the Northern District of California, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H36C06421DE7A42868BC472DE98D15AE1"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H25E7F89A97B74D55ABD4A989541DD271"><enum/><text>That Charles R. Breyer, Senior Judge of the United States District Court for the Northern District of California, is impeached for high crimes and misdemeanors, and that the following article of impeachment be exhibited to the United States Senate. </text><subsection id="H5EF2C868558545148F2FD46AB565C1FE"><enum/><text> Article of impeachment exhibited by the House of Representatives of the United States of America in the name of itself and of the people of the United States of America, against Charles R. Breyer, Senior Judge of the United States District Court for the Northern District of California, in maintenance and support of its impeachment against him for high crimes and misdemeanors.</text></subsection></section><section id="H0F7B814DD79E4184867E119B37B4BA6E" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum/><header>Article I: Abuse of Power</header><subsection id="H3EED0042830B4CD6A278D70CBA21FFEA"><enum/><text>Senior District Judge Charles R. Breyer, in violation of his oath of office, did knowingly and willfully use his judicial position to advance political gain while interfering with the President's constitutional prerogatives and enforcement of the rule of law. </text></subsection><subsection id="HCFC6DB7802324956B3D0F64D37FD497F"><enum/><text>The Constitution provides that the House of Representatives <quote>shall have the sole Power of Impeachment</quote> and that <quote>civil Officers of the United States,</quote> including Federal judges, are subject to impeachment and removal. </text></subsection><subsection id="H74693FE7AB9E45B394B37BDAE188B462"><enum/><text>Through his conduct, in which he violated his oath to the Constitution and duty of impartiality to the people of the United States, Senior District Judge Charles R. Breyer has abused the powers of his judicial authority, having engaged in actions that prioritize political gain over the duty of impartiality owed to the public and litigants as follows: </text><paragraph id="HF03DBCF45A0B48B9A37F14F470CD1D99"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Senior District Judge Charles R. Breyer attempted to use his power to prevent President Trump from using the National Guard to enforce the law in Los Angeles, California. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25D703DFB80D4E69B874E4775A32F178"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Senior District Judge Charles R. Breyer required President Trump to ignore the Constitution of the United States to return the National Guard to the Governor of California. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H482AB6F197164B01AAE8779A97AF369C"><enum/><text>This conduct jeopardizes the safety of the Nation, represents an abuse of judicial power, and is detrimental to the orderly functioning of the judiciary. Using the powers of his office, Senior District Judge Charles R. Breyer has attempted to seize power from the executive branch and interfere with the will of the American people. </text></subsection><subsection id="HFC7613E1565D4DD7B3E8E56396E98401"><enum/><text>In so doing, Senior District Judge Charles R. Breyer used the powers of his position to engage in actions that overstep his judicial authority. By making a political decision outside the scope of his judicial duties, he compromised the impartiality of our judicial system and created a constitutional crisis. </text></subsection><subsection id="H6E797DF46664429E9F8B5C61FE2E6645"><enum/><text>Wherefore, Senior District Judge Charles R. Breyer is guilty of high crimes and misdemeanors and should be removed from office. </text></subsection></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

