<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBAC6B3B5C1EB4677A2BCAC509A76FBBB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4109 IH: Recycling and Composting Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4109</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250624">June 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to carry out certain activities to improve recycling and composting programs in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H40E7D68620B249D197F7A2668D2852F9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H42C1A86BA60D4B6DBA5C35F11CA51E83" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Recycling and Composting Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB3CEB6CDA4E5487192A3E17683D4664A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header> <subsection id="H8604382E9DD148A0987222DC84C6FEE1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBE9C71AC0DB54669ACE5C1AB02A47221"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB22EF9A8A62E4BC5820B29E7929F4815"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compost</header><text>The term <term>compost</term> means a product that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA571B2249382429BB9583405D2C43CC1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is manufactured through the controlled aerobic, biological decomposition of biodegradable materials;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H74D22473B5EE42D880D80FD1ACA21888"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has been subjected to medium and high temperature organisms, which—</text> 
<clause id="HDC8BDA4C80BD492D806C675788AFDAB5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>significantly reduce the viability of pathogens and weed seeds; and</text></clause> <clause id="H567FB5F3BF95483397DD6900DF3BDE61"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>stabilize carbon in the product such that the product is beneficial to plant growth; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBCA6E1A39AA2424BB6047474C4081742"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is typically used as a soil amendment, but may also contribute plant nutrients.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD42FDDE9336C4280A2E720DA6C6265DF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compostable material</header><text>The term <term>compostable material</term> means material that is a feedstock for creating compost, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H464E6AB170FD4E0E98ED60D257BD23A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>wood;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4308E616824B49C883A34BA7710B4FFA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>agricultural crops;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H287C98449E6A4D86991E109A20F894ED"><enum>(C)</enum><text>paper, such as cardboard and other paper products;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD1A4197AAF42490F8C8E231BFAD192D1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>certified compostable products associated with organic waste;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4ECA4AE57D944FAE82C2A6127FCBE1AC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>other organic plant material;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F5C360A32CC4F99B4E8820720A61DD6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>organic waste, including food waste and yard waste; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7F0E2F1D3ABF41F0868D29AFE1B8DBC3"><enum>(G)</enum><text>such other material that is composed of biomass that can be continually replenished or renewed, as determined by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6CBF7C240C9A48EB8A3CA9484B5D6F79"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1910E291348C4C7A9B9D4D930849E6E6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Recyclable material</header><text>The term <term>recyclable material</term> means a material that is obsolete, previously used, off-specification, surplus, or incidentally produced for processing into a specification-grade commodity for which a reuse market currently exists or is being developed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3ADAD0AA83834CD5A8EE7EE1ECFCD54B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Recycling</header><text>The term <term>recycling</term> means the series of activities—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H136D3326F815452B9C3FA5E40653BC10"><enum>(A)</enum><text>during which recyclable materials are processed into specification-grade commodities and consumed as raw-material feedstock, in lieu of virgin materials, in the manufacturing of new products;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAC596F2942F94130AC848ACC937BE231"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that may, with regard to recyclable materials and prior to the activities described in subparagraph (A), include sorting, collection, processing, and brokering; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H102837A7419643F5B3659D91F63714ED"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that result, subsequent to processing described in subparagraph (A), in consumption by a materials manufacturer, including for the manufacturing of new products.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCD4D3545FE594236B969EF420976B4FA"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given the term in section 1004 of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6903">42 U.S.C. 6903</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF9B978B726E546B4BE27DC2F628FC187"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of processing</header><text>In paragraphs (5) and (6) of subsection (a), the term <term>processing</term> means any mechanical, manual, or other method that—</text> <paragraph id="H126AF2130CE74070BA0662667A828EA1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>transforms a recyclable material into a specification-grade commodity; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H98AD9A514C544EE88B49CD31B47EE15E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may occur in multiple steps, with different phases, including sorting, occurring at different locations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H1D3C340C1C154ECB9C070004A325CDD4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reports on composting and recycling infrastructure capabilities</header> <subsection id="H4ED63C5CD6274324836FDEEF4979A9E6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle D of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6941">42 U.S.C. 6941 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H586E2A5A0845418C9429832B76E9B133"> 
<section id="H5C631F159A684104B8BC4C8B96BCC7D5"><enum>4011.</enum><header>Reports on composting and recycling infrastructure capabilities</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD56EA5BE3A3046F0A3DA73CBF856659B"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF214C2FD78B4D219847AF97ADD1CD1E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Recycling and Composting Accountability Act terms</header><text>The terms <term>compost</term>, <term>compostable material</term>, <term>recyclable material</term>, and <term>recycling</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 2 of the <short-title>Recycling and Composting Accountability Act</short-title>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64A091D36A324FEC9DE34D70FFF5AD81" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Composting facility</header><text>The term <term>composting facility</term> means a location, structure, or device that transforms compostable materials into compost.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA5A1B9307CB24B71A1908CA1819FCA14"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAB1614FCB6FB495AAA263C048330C669"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Materials recovery facility</header> 
<subparagraph id="H86502B998214482BA9A566F764BAA642"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>materials recovery facility</term> means a dedicated facility where primarily residential recyclable materials, which are diverted from disposal by the generator and collected separately from municipal solid waste, are mechanically or manually sorted into commodities for further processing into specification-grade commodities for sale to end users.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA3BC9848391744A58BA407EACB7CDB62"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>materials recovery facility</term> does not include a solid waste management facility that may process municipal solid waste to remove recyclable materials.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B04AEE0B4644163A66F65A1D2E9AA10"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Definition of processing</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>processing</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2(b) of the <short-title>Recycling and Composting Accountability Act</short-title>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5EA0166298DB492DB0E2180F0A94C2B5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H495683FD2AB64C8B85FEE0D567B6CF77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall request information and data from, collaborate with, or contract with, as necessary and appropriate, States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes, for the provision, preparation, and publication of a report, or to expand work under the National Recycling Strategy to include information and data, on compostable materials and efforts to reduce contamination rates for recycling, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H79A4EF1C626E4F059ED742455C7EFAC9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an evaluation of existing Federal, State, and local laws that may present barriers to implementation of composting strategies;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H727D48A6280A49CB859D015C6A322C52"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description and evaluation of composting infrastructure and programs within States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8AB85EBA758E450BBFDFE43CCDAE9519"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an estimate of the costs and approximate land needed to expand composting programs; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0152CF22883D44268567E5E99DE59A5F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a review of the practices of manufacturers and companies that are moving to using compostable packaging and food service ware for the purpose of making the composting process the end-of-life use of those products.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H53F95916E6C74448948CAB75A3EAB53C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall submit to Congress the report prepared under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H64525C7A5BAE4DE79267A1948F7BE002"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inventory of materials recovery facilities</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this section, and every 4 years thereafter, the Administrator, in consultation with relevant Federal agencies and States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes, shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H773F7A50A1C44345BD82D5A7BAC8FE36"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prepare an inventory or estimate of materials recovery facilities in the United States, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HF62640599265433E9A59A39CF1466F98"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of materials recovery facilities in each State; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD10FCC6BA18E45C98E5DA9480B5A84EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a general description of the materials that each of those materials recovery facilities can process, including—</text> <clause id="H08FC1D6F09C74C47B204F0F70949F47E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of plastic, a description of—</text> 
<subclause id="H993E9D4308C340C9B66DD3B30D018CBD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the types of accepted resin, if applicable; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H4E6F7772188D4406A7E34667A8E1D7B7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the packaging or product format, such as a jug, a carton, or film;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H022419617B85471A8FABC140481955AC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>food packaging and service ware, such as a bottle, cutlery, or a cup;</text></clause> <clause id="HE2AD2ACE950B4F6AABBC1B29827C9D0D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>paper;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA5EC7345562C4C9CA3A20DBE5B2B037F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>aluminum, such as an aluminum beverage can, food can, aerosol can, or foil;</text></clause> <clause id="H639F232DC1934985B99F634F7DC7AD41"><enum>(v)</enum><text>steel, such as a steel food or aerosol can;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H153AB8DC08144985ADF208B54BA894A8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>other scrap metal;</text></clause> <clause id="H5BDDB5501CF54A1EA6AA40A1C5602F9B"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>glass; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEB1082163A154A25BFDBB22E311114EF"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>any other material not described in any of clauses (i) through (vii) that a materials recovery facility processes; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7250D9E3352940D792522D34019CCE10"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to Congress the inventory or estimate prepared under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA2CE83171E1645048C63D597AAD0D982"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Information on recycling and composting systems</header><text>The Administrator shall, as necessary and appropriate, collaborate or contract with States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes to estimate, with respect to the United States—</text> <paragraph id="H1FA458FEAA6B47C48EE3B95D95F765D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number and types of recycling and composting programs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9DCB2B681DE5467B98813DB566A4D9E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the types and forms of materials accepted by recycling or composting programs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDF341FDD5EB4BB790C1FB10D92E6894"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of individuals—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9586FBD22A5149AD827802C8CDB1B072"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with access to recycling and composting services to at least the extent of access to disposal services; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD143765E71B44A6DB2632219B360B2E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who use, on a percentage basis, the recycling and composting services described in subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H79AA4029325A4A4C9B9C65593C9292EB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the number of individuals with barriers to accessing recycling and composting services similar to their access to disposal services and the types of those barriers experienced;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E38E2B8C29141A9A83CEB8500497BD6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the inbound contamination and capture rates of recycling and composting programs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEB2399F17FC44B4E8F5F08A758F1F0E8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>if applicable, other available recycling or composting programs; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HABB396B93E1F4DC2A05E0C5FC7CDBBBF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the average costs and benefits to States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes of recycling and composting programs.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD54DB84B2F454D62A71838518B9FF157"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Recycling reporting rates</header> 
<paragraph id="H33AB6FB57002454FAEAA5005D8F130B5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Collection of data; development of rates</header><text>The Administrator may use amounts made available under section 6 of the <short-title>Recycling and Composting Accountability Act</short-title>—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC8994E97B9748B3B0E1E93FC708AD6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to biannually collect, in collaboration with States, to the extent practicable, information supplied on a voluntary basis to develop the estimated rates described in subparagraphs (B) and (C);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C5E695A188A45C0A7C8B462AADCF468"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop a standardized estimated rate of recyclable materials in States that provide information under subparagraph (A) that have been successfully diverted from the waste stream and brought to a materials recovery facility or composting facility; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C7EF842D8A440D193FE7FF34B186D00"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop an estimated national recycling rate based on the information described in subparagraphs (A) and (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H41347955825D48C495E155F4D0D0028C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use</header><text>Using amounts made available under section 6 of the <short-title>Recycling and Composting Accountability Act</short-title>, the Administrator may use the information collected and rates developed under paragraph (1) to provide requesting States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes data and technical assistance—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0ECF9289C7324CC1B62DEF2C067AA3B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to reduce the overall waste produced by the States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6277D3DE53C0459192E6594F8C8DC053"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to assist the States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes in understanding the nuances of the information collected relating to diversion activities; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59F24593833C43CC80744F5160F5D8F8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to increase recycling and composting rates of the States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H26431720C3DB469AAE011E2E59DE335F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report on end markets</header><text>The Administrator, in collaboration or contract with, as necessary and appropriate, relevant Federal agencies, States, units of local government, or Indian Tribes, shall—</text> <paragraph id="H753F0B1C75964A6FAB98408A8A8CCA38"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide an update to the report submitted under section 306 of the Save Our Seas 2.0 Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/224">Public Law 116–224</external-xref>; 134 Stat. 1096) to include an addendum on the end-market sale of all recyclable materials from materials recovery facilities that process recyclable materials, including, to the extent practicable—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H110063B8EFDD40DE9828FC044235B6B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total, in dollars per ton, domestic sales of bales of recyclable materials; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8DEF47C550B14D4AB8BAA099BD4EF8BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total, in dollars per ton, international sales of bales of recyclable materials;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA187F762EF4E4B4EB687916D02E2E7AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prepare a report on the end-market sale of compost from, to the extent practicable, compostable materials, including the total, in dollars per ton, of domestic sales of compostable materials; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB227823D12F94FE6B70EF5DD52604D36"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this section, submit to Congress the update to the report prepared under paragraph (1) and the report prepared under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCA301368D3154C32AD3549FEFAF0A3AF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Privileged or confidential information</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C596BD9671241B7A0A9D4EA852FE78B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information collected under subsection (e)(1) or paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (f) shall not include any privileged or confidential information described in section 552(b)(4) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC41169FF74E24EA59CB958CD5C3EF319"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nondisclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information collected to carry out this section shall not be made public if the information meets the requirements of section 552(b) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0417BC3D605040C0A168113BF9AFC709" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1001 of the Solid Waste Disposal Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 4010 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF328ED76C6C14F42870598086408CCCA"> <toc> <toc-entry level="section" bold="off">Sec. 4011. Report on composting and recycling infrastructure capabilities.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H5C547049C31A4AFBA0B2FCDDF144C47B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Federal agency activities related to recycling</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter until 2033, the Comptroller General of the United States shall make publicly available a report—</text> 
<paragraph id="H620CD3FE5B89420E88734AF9D782B32C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">detailing or, to the extent practicable, providing an estimate of—</text> <subparagraph id="H340B22E217764EC889E81E8E99EB757C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total annual recycling and composting rates reported by all Federal agencies; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H92856635902B4003849C133F756AB75C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total annual percentage of products containing recyclable material, compostable material, or recovered materials purchased by all Federal agencies, including—</text> <clause id="H9657BCC85B7543E19ABDC6BD2BD53932"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total quantity of procured products containing recyclable material or recovered materials listed in the comprehensive procurement guidelines published under section 6002(e) of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6962">42 U.S.C. 6962(e)</external-xref>); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD73E8002B24D40CB9C9A0D4C148552D2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the total quantity of compostable material purchased by all Federal agencies;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC80EBA1BD43C49459ED7A00D23F25D9C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identifying the activities of each Federal agency that promote recycling or composting; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2AEA3426B5A640E294CE16D1BB0FEDA8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifying activities that Federal agencies could carry out to further promote recycling or composting.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H80BF4A3E17C545828E9F69D847A3E2DB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Study on the diversion of recyclable materials from a circular market</header> <subsection id="H15BACB8D3C1E44159994807094CABF01"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall develop a metric for determining the proportion of recyclable materials in commercial and municipal waste streams that are being diverted from a circular market.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HED331D45D52E4E7080BD289277A79CB5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study; report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the development of a metric under subsection (a), the Administrator shall conduct a study of, and submit to Congress a report on, the proportion of recyclable materials in commercial and municipal waste streams that, during each of the 10 calendar years preceding the year of submission of the report, were diverted from a circular market.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD1E9B196783E4B5A9A25E402320F76AC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data</header><text>The report under subsection (b) shall provide data on specific recyclable materials, including aluminum, plastics, paper and paperboard, textiles, and glass, that were prevented from remaining in a circular market through disposal or elimination, and to what use those specific recyclable materials were lost.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBEB3F4C61D264B86894A3E152F9A2FB6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The report under subsection (b) shall include an evaluation of whether the establishment or improvement of recycling programs would—</text> <paragraph id="H8807B16F50924BD386E09A02169BC9D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improve recycling rates;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H50F64E0807D6463DA915B645156C6B2E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reduce the quantity of recyclable materials being unutilized in a circular market; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E5FBBF7017D4FF2B7903659C6338F9D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>affect prices paid by consumers for products using materials recycled in the circular market.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HE0939AAFFD154C4D93D3D9F0AAEACD84"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act $4,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029.</text></section> <section id="HAF61452F64894DA29DAE36B3EDEC556E" commented="no"><enum>7.</enum><header>Administration</header> <subsection id="H8DA6AFAACA474109A6B51959B18AE08D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Unfunded mandates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator or the Secretary of Commerce may not exercise any authority under this Act or any amendment made by this Act if exercising that authority would require a State, a unit of local government, or an Indian Tribe to carry out a mandate for which funding is not available.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEF658306C9294415A986BE850744F5FB" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nondisclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any information collected to carry out this Act shall not be made public if the information meets the requirements of section 552(b) of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

