<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25401-K6K-G9-HSL"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 209 ATS: Commending Southeastern Louisiana University on the occasion of its Centennial and its years of service to the State of Louisiana and the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 209</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250508">May 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S389">Mr. Kennedy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commending Southeastern Louisiana University on the occasion of its Centennial and its years of service to the State of Louisiana and the United States.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on July 7, 1925, the voters of Tangipahoa Parish approved a bond issue that led to the creation of Hammond Junior College;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas President Linus A. Sims opened the college to 40 students, taught by 5 faculty members, establishing the foundation for an institution committed to academic excellence and community service;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1927, the voters of Tangipahoa Parish supported the purchase of the 15-acre Hunter Leake estate for the purpose of expanding the college’s campus and allowing for future growth;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1928, Hammond Junior College became Southeastern Louisiana College and was adopted into the Louisiana State educational system under the State Board of Education, solidifying its place as a vital institution for higher education in Louisiana;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1934, a State bond issue provided for the construction of McGehee Hall, which became a historic centerpiece of the university and was placed on the National Register of Historic Places on January 18, 1985;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1970, Southeastern Louisiana College became Southeastern Louisiana University, reflecting its growth in academic offerings, student population, and regional impact;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as of the date of adoption of this resolution, Southeastern Louisiana University serves more than 15,000 students annually, offering a multitude of undergraduate, graduate, and professional programs through its 5 colleges and schools, fostering innovation, research, and career readiness;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Southeastern Louisiana University has academically distinguished itself in education, business, nursing and health sciences, the arts, sciences, and other fields while remaining dedicated to public service;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Southeastern Louisiana University has a strong tradition of intercollegiate athletics as a member of the Southland Conference, supporting student-athletes in their academic and athletic pursuits; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Southeastern Louisiana University has produced notable alumni who have made significant contributions in business, public service, education, health care, and the arts, strengthening the economy and cultural heritage of Louisiana: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id25b03f13f85046e0a16668d84f94d517"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commends Southeastern Louisiana University on the occasion of its Centennial and its years of service to the State of Louisiana and the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf1a337c41b8f4d79a184726ac97251ce"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes Southeastern Louisiana University for its dedication to higher education, research, and community service; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd067679d8ada4f759c35b942dc087897"><enum>(3)</enum><text>respectfully requests that the Secretary of the Senate transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text><subparagraph id="idf0651c2ebaff49dd961f9616ee454ec9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the President of Southeastern Louisiana University, the Honorable Dr. William S. Wainwright;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd0d7798c380846c5979843fa7a3715da"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Provost and Vice President for Academic Affairs of Southeastern Louisiana University, the Honorable Dr. Tena L. Golding; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide87af94b9c2d43aab8c17ebedaa7c1a4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Vice President for University Advancement of Southeastern Louisiana University, the Honorable Ms. Wendy Lauderdale.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

