<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-NEW25265-TRM-73-PG3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 131 ATS: Designating the third week of March 2025 as “National CACFP Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 131</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating the third week of March 2025 as <quote>National CACFP Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the third week of March is annually recognized as <quote>National CACFP Week</quote> to raise awareness of the Child and Adult Care Food Program (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>CACFP</quote>) of the Department of Agriculture;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Department of Agriculture has reaffirmed—</text><paragraph id="idde66bd8954e64595a3fe47f3a92bf33b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the vital role positive nutrition habits play in the healthy growth of children in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id886948d0b2314666ad60d987cf9f5d6a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the importance of nutrition education for the most vulnerable and youngest children, as well as adults, through centers and homes throughout the United States;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2024, the CACFP provided daily meals and snacks to more than 4,500,000 children in child care centers, family day care homes, emergency shelters, and after-school programs, and more than 115,000 adults in adult day care, providing almost 1,700,000,000 meals and snacks in total;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the CACFP not only provides nutritious meals and education but also increases the overall quality of child care in general, especially for children in low-income areas;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the innovative approach to oversight of the CACFP, which pairs child care, adult day care, and after-school sites with a non-profit sponsoring organization or a State agency, highlights a unique public-private partnership that supports working families and small businesses;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, although child care can be expensive in many locations throughout the United States, the CACFP increases the effectiveness and viability of child and adult care small businesses for many providers, especially in rural areas; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas an increasing number of studies demonstrate that access to the CACFP can measurably and positively impact the cognitive, social, emotional, and physical health and development of children, leading to more favorable outcomes, such as—</text><paragraph id="idCE70014BFA7140B1921490C42D792E5E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a decreased likelihood of being hospitalized;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5D3D3C064D734659B1A56E5D80102562"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an increased likelihood of healthy weight gain; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6CA78373C74E44FB8EE738FBCC63FD6C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an increased likelihood of a more varied diet: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id90DD120B6D4A452D9F624AFA58B8F31F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates the week beginning on March 16, 2025, as <quote>National CACFP Week</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id61B27B45A48C41318354020989197B93"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the role of the Child and Adult Care Food Program in improving the health of the most vulnerable children and adults in child care centers, family day care homes, emergency shelters, adult day care facilities, and after-school care in the United States by providing nutritious meals and snacks.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

