<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H14BBE522206F4A708289382624B42647" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 273 IH: Expressing support for the diplomatic relations required to encourage the Government of Mexico to fulfill its water deliveries on an annual basis to the United States under the treaty between the United States and Mexico regarding the utilization of the Colorado and Tijuana Rivers and of the Rio Grande.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 273</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250331">March 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000594">Ms. De La Cruz</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the diplomatic relations required to encourage the Government of Mexico to fulfill its water deliveries on an annual basis to the United States under the treaty between the United States and Mexico regarding the utilization of the Colorado and Tijuana Rivers and of the Rio Grande.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the treaty between the United States and Mexico regarding the utilization of the Colorado and Tijuana Rivers and of the Rio Grande, signed at Washington, February 1944 (59 Stat. 1219), commits the Government of Mexico to send an average of not less than 350,000 acre-feet of water annually over a 5-year cycle to the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Mexico repeatedly waits until the end of this 5-year cycle to fulfill such water commitment; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas each year, farmers in south Texas are experiencing water shortages: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H03E4716AE0454F4AAE0ED2D3D7899944"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HE6FEF98606B34E69A95E2DEE9148AA77"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="H8E72A5B887B14454AD5E30F3657ABA02"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the diplomatic relations required to encourage the Government of Mexico to fulfill its water deliveries on an annual basis to the United States under the treaty between the United States and Mexico regarding the utilization of the Colorado and Tijuana Rivers and of the Rio Grande, signed at Washington, February 1944 (59 Stat. 1219);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA13166BF6AC74FF492358A32AE54B975"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages Mexico to fulfill such commitments on an annual basis; </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H44243BB793BB487297AE37F074A4741D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acknowledges that farmers in south Texas are experiencing water shortages; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7BD13A97DCFF4D7FBD6BC5EFDA76B14C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages new commitments to ensure that the United States receives annual deliveries of at least 350,000 acre-feet of water under such treaty.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

