<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2EDEAA70D2FB459A8E2822DAEC3C4FA7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4911 IH: People Over Long Lines Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4911</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250805">August 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to ensure that voters in elections for Federal office do not wait in long lines in order to vote, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1FE375C28E744D0EBF03E5CB343CF719" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HF5F7ABE26E0A46B7B4567962D3C0C8FF"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>People Over Long Lines Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>POLL Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H17113180BC5440B0964EC381790374B1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="HC605897BD6854EC38F4804FF56F8A44A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The right to vote for all Americans is fundamental and rules for voting and election administration should protect the right to vote and promote voter participation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H50494CDB80B94701B0A9C82DD8AA0DBC">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>It is the responsibility of the State and Federal Governments to ensure that every eligible citizen is able to register to vote and to cast a ballot.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCAD81624252741499CBD8724688FF349"><enum>(3)</enum><text>There continues to be an alarming movement to erect barriers to make it more difficult for Americans to participate in our Nation’s democratic process. The Nation has witnessed unprecedented efforts to turn back the clock and erect barriers to voting for communities of color, which have faced historic and continuing discrimination, as well as disabled, young, elderly, and low-income Americans.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF357AB61ED5E40D7AECE5BBC8AEB00C0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>One way voting in communities of color has been suppressed is through long waits at polling locations. Studies have shown a number of contributing factors, including the drastic reduction of early voting days, poor allocation of resources to certain communities, cuts to election funding, and a reduction of polling locations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H13F710C98A524659BC3998EC1BE6CAE4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A 2019 study led by economist Keith Chen of the University of California, Los Angeles, matched anonymous location data from 10,000,000 smart phones to 93,000 polling places to create the most extensive map to date of voter wait times across the United States. The results showed one very clear disparity: voters in predominantly Black neighborhoods waited 29 percent longer, on average, than those in White neighborhoods. They were also about 74 percent more likely to wait for more than half an hour.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A66C0C9BADE4220B09BA1F1BA33E44D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Waiting in long lines discourages people from voting, undermines confidence in the electoral system, and imposes economic costs on voters.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAF54C00979EA4B56BC6B615E690CDAC8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Long lines are estimated to have deterred between 500,000 and 700,000 people from casting their ballot in 2012.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE7AEE96508E4811BFC425B2993681F3"><enum>(8)</enum><text>These problems led to the creation of the bipartisan Presidential Commission on Election Administration, which issued a 2014 report that set forth a standard: <quote>No citizen should have to wait more than 30 minutes to vote.</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H76ACAF84D31F451F87B51434E31FE7F5"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Despite the work of the Presidential Commission on Election Administration, long lines continue, particularly in communities of color where racial discrimination in voting is a clear and persistent problem.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB3C6C85E7847434DB879079268307AA8"><enum>(10)</enum><text>In the Arizona 2016 Presidential primary, in one Maricopa County polling place for mostly Latino voters, some waited for 4 hours or more in the 80-degree heat to cast their ballots. For the 2016 general election, 3 people collapsed while waiting to vote in an hours-long line in Georgia, and a line to vote in Ohio was a half-mile long.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5E6D96A1FD324856BE1522EBF087CC29"><enum>(11)</enum><text>According to a nationwide study, in 2016, roughly 3 percent of people standing in line at voting locations left before they could vote as a result of long lines.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H40A913F29D9B4F19B4EC9B35F4870BDE"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The disenfranchisement that long lines create for voters is not limited to that one election. Research suggests that for each hour would-be voters wait, their probability of voting in the next election drops by 1 percentage point.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2381FC18CAEB485B81CC35CE1BA6271D"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Congress has the authority under article I, section 4 of the Constitution of the United States to enact laws governing the time, place, and manner of Federal elections.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3BF8CA7E2464841A2D3B994FB3612C5"> <enum>(14)</enum> <text>Congress also has authority under section 2 of the 15th Amendment to enforce the right of citizens of the United States to vote, which shall not be denied or abridged by the United States, by legislation.</text>
      </paragraph></section> 
<section id="HA46E9209B0B640CAA459E2EAFA916D53"><enum>3.</enum><header>Preventing unreasonable voter waiting times</header> 
<subsection id="HF628453380084DBBA9DA509E818918D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State plans required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title III of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20901">52 U.S.C. 20901 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by section 2(a) of the COCOA Act of 2024, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HBBB53304D6C54C8197510BB719A44D3A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating sections 305 and 306 as sections 306 and 307; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB23BD2D70B7E4993BA0037A58B8F6DBB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 304 the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4FC68012A84647A2B386854DD3D85259"> <section id="H0D2F989AA1CE434FAFB6EF1DD446B019"><enum>305.</enum><header>Unreasonable voter waiting times</header> <subsection id="H217C0997E9824667B9F32DA0ED3DC2C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State plans</header> <paragraph id="H335982C7725141F2B3444F0BEFDED3EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days before each election for Federal office, each State shall make public (including through the website of the State on which election information is normally published) and submit to the Commission a written plan which meets the public notice and comment requirements of paragraph (2) and describes the measures it is implementing to ensure, to the greatest extent possible, an equitable waiting time for all voters in the State, including for voters with disabilities, and a waiting time of less than 30 minutes at any polling place in the election.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB17DD05294F04850B5CE188F0611B476"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public notice comment requirement</header><text>The public notice and comment requirements of this paragraph are met if—</text> <subparagraph id="H7B0C21E9B1B046A38D7F243661FCB75D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 30 days prior to the submission of the plan to the Commission, the State made a preliminary version of the plan available for public inspection and comment;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H81F9B72F54594B14B9B9B8291369F6FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the State publishes notice that the preliminary version of the plan is so available; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H34B5621335174B9DB47C66C88A632D95"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the State took the public comments made regarding the preliminary version of the plan into account in preparing the plan which was submitted to the Commission under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="HE476632BD49B4A9781CA6E1AD5E96599"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on unreasonable voter waiting times</header><text>Each State shall ensure that no person voting in an election for Federal office shall wait for more than 30 minutes at any polling place for purposes of casting a vote in such election. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H82966956C9CA4821BA011B16D5E6F627"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Remedial plans for states with excessive voter wait times</header> <paragraph id="HB0EB5DB2C7DD4A2DA3DB327204934276"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Review of voter wait times</header><text>After each election for Federal office, the Commission shall review voter waiting times for each jurisdiction for which voting in such election took place and make publicly available a report on its findings. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9E580B30969F49D0ABC02A2A2D1BDA53"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State remedial plans</header> 
<subparagraph id="H8B700052A8EA4843A74CFEEEEA611769"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Remedial plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 209, each jurisdiction for which the Commission, after the review conducted under paragraph (1), determines that a substantial number of voters, including voters with disabilities, waited more than 60 minutes to cast a vote, or in which there were substantial violations of the standards established under section 299, shall comply with a State remedial plan established by the Attorney General to provide for the effective allocation of resources to administer elections for Federal office held in the State and to reduce the waiting time of voters. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H49AC3BFF658F4036B2755A9972EB3E3A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each remedial plan established by the Attorney General shall provide for coordination between the Commission, the Attorney General, and the State involved to monitor the compliance of the State with the remedial plan during the period leading up to the election and on the date of the election and to respond to serious delays in the ability of voters, including voters with disabilities, to cast their ballots at polling places.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H273F4594723E4844933C695010B4B258"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>A jurisdiction shall not be required to comply with a State remedial plan required under subparagraph (A) if the Commission determines that the voter waiting times were less than 60 minutes for 2 consecutive regularly scheduled general elections for Federal office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB3FC318C9FED4908A93009588BDF2A1C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Jurisdiction defined</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>jurisdiction</term> has the meaning given the term <term>registrar's jurisdiction</term> in section 8(j) of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1973gg-6">42 U.S.C. 1973gg–6(j)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFCDA1E7C3FC34E4DA8AE72E279A28BDC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Standards</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Attorney General shall establish standards for conducting the review under paragraph (1) and for establishing remedial plans under paragraph (2)(A).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE0FC1108B9249058F335D20DA367981"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Role of Office of Civil Rights and Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall carry out this section acting through the Assistant Attorney General for the Civil Rights Division of the Department of Justice and in consultation with the Commission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC37E552BB06148AFB91DFCAC627B091E" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Appropriations</header><text>In addition to other amounts authorized to be appropriated to the Commission, there are authorized to be appropriated for each of the fiscal years 2025 through 2034, $5,000,000 for each such year for the Commission to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA681C85DEF314483A0AC04956497EC2B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Emergency ballots</header> <paragraph id="H034EDB58F75A49B58452EBE9A85011B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the event of a failure of voting equipment or other circumstance at a polling place that causes an unreasonable delay, any individual who is waiting at the polling place to cast a ballot in an election for Federal office at the time of the failure shall be advised immediately of the individual's right to use an emergency paper ballot, and upon request shall be provided with such an emergency paper ballot for the election and the supplies necessary to mark the ballot.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6DBE280A59C34B4699942B4750343FCC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ballot requirements</header><text>Any emergency paper ballot provided under paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HDE8530D3A20E4A419B5630E38A12DD9B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include the names of each candidate for each Federal office for which voting occurs at such polling place; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3AEA8326B7A34DA6BFB39CEB48C07E6A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be available in each language for which other ballots provided at the polling place are available.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H529D0B64C82C4A369F152D2F5AE9EC84"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disposition of ballot</header><text>Any emergency paper ballot which is cast by an individual under this subsection shall be counted in the same manner as a regular ballot, unless the individual casting the ballot would have otherwise been required to cast a provisional ballot in the absence of the delay, in which case that ballot shall be treated in the same manner as a provisional ballot.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="HCC005666A13D43DB84D92A547B2F81F8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text>Title IV of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21111">52 U.S.C. 21111 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF3DFD966C85B43798666D3F81BFD9DD8"> <section commented="no" id="HB4D1A3F0811E4BDA92BBC28F760A9CDE"><enum>403.</enum><header>Private right of action for unreasonable voter waiting time</header> <subsection commented="no" id="HCDE8767E227942CAB113924DEA310C46"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a violation of section 305(b), section 402 shall not apply and any person who is aggrieved by such violation may commence a civil action in any appropriate district court of the United States for relief.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H08305DB8AC8145A99632219E23CDAF18"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relief</header><text>In any civil action commenced under subsection (a):</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H16C8183485794161A2C916634A22AB83"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the court finds a violation of section 305(b), the court shall assess a civil penalty equal to the sum of—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H3F99245394B8479CAE76D07E84CF9B0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$50; plus</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H57F6DCD8348D48F4B273D07A9255DE5A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an additional $50 for each additional hour the person waited at the polling place to cast a vote; plus</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H55D8CEE8B8D143EA9F4D358967D0C45F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reasonable attorney fees, including litigation expenses, and costs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HEF0E367D0C064F23A360C85868D93E3F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>If the court determines that the violation was due to an intentional action to suppress votes or was made with reckless disregard of the requirements of section 305—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H6927C9D35A25483195B03F4AABAB0810"><enum>(A)</enum><text>paragraph (1)(A) shall be applied by substituting <quote>$650</quote> for <quote>$50</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE5357705978C4D91B478D8A347568C93"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>paragraph (1)(B) shall be applied by substituting <quote>$150</quote> for <quote>$50</quote>.</text>
                                </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="HD913303715E54CC7B3FC743F980B14E4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 202 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20922">52 U.S.C. 20922</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H6BBBBEEA34B34B73BFB0A183201EA74B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (5) and (6) as paragraphs (6) and (7), respectively; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEAD8A86500244262B54C1C868C36AAF0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB859156199F43A49D7E007E31E59905"> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1783863E4DD14EC098C53457C40A19CC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>carrying out the duties described in section 305(c);</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H519313A3B81A492E852E23E203504F47"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><text>The table of contents of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H69E4547779664992B49B33837AB21264"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating the items relating to sections 305 and 306 as relating to sections 306 and 307, and by inserting after the item relating to section 304 the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBEE7052D62D043289454CAE20611C260"> 
<toc> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H0D2F989AA1CE434FAFB6EF1DD446B019">Sec. 305. Unreasonable voter waiting times.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">and</continuation-text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H2E4061A88B2B4C3180622B96F60D34D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after the item relating to section 402 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0389152FA0D249849660F0019FF9C728"> <toc> <toc-entry level="section" idref="HB4D1A3F0811E4BDA92BBC28F760A9CDE">Sec. 403. Private right of action for unreasonable voter waiting time.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HDA8DB1DB67C74E628732016F7FE359D5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to elections held on or after the expiration of the 180-day period which begins on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" id="HB60D34133C45462C9C4A56E5C59D4923"><enum>4.</enum><header>Minimum required voting systems, poll workers, and election resources</header> 
<subsection commented="no" id="HC5A8C87D640440C397B5E1FF2F415B91"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Minimum Requirements</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H2037E820BDB748AEAE85C8780077DFC1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title III of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21081">52 U.S.C. 21081 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subtitle:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73E6C82278A94FB5ACF3870268A5D5F7"> <subtitle commented="no" id="H8AA45730C8C8410D96302DB2A67816C6"><enum>C</enum><header>Additional requirements</header> <section commented="no" id="HE26718435DCC4773A1CEC74CFEA2C9E4"><enum>321.</enum><header>Minimum required voting systems and poll workers</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H5BFBE824C2434931AF302379ECB04812"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Each State shall provide for the minimum required number of voting systems, poll workers, and other election resources (including all other physical resources) for each voting site on the day of any Federal election and on any days during which such State allows early voting for a Federal election in accordance with the standards determined under section 299.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H2BD1EC09502B4AF9AC181977B3D4E842"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section and section 299—</text> <paragraph id="HE77220ACD90A454888D6F6777F26D484"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>voting site</term> means a polling location; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB477FE5AC9E34CCF824D511BD85DBBDB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>voting system</term> means the total combination of mechanical, electromechanical, or electronic equipment (including the software, firmware, and documentation required to program, control, and support the equipment) that is used at a voting site—</text> <subparagraph id="H560A875A8CA541328C6128E0DF75F1CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to check the official list of eligible voters for purposes of confirming that an individual is eligible to cast a vote at the site;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H62B5ADAFCDB44456AA7061F2FA2E1D20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to cast and count votes; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1530A21741704F12B7BDB90507A86B49"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to maintain and produce any audit trail information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H778411B4038746EEB8BED3CE7A35F540"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State shall be required to comply with the requirements of this section on and after January 1, 2027.</text></subsection></section></subtitle><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H387A2F45D8BD42AA8AE862ED5259A8C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 401 of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21111">52 U.S.C. 21111</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>and 303</quote> and inserting <quote>303, and subtitle C</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H6FD9FEDEC058427AA3CBC3510C979701"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by adding at the end of the items relating to title III the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA274097C1DC943D1874A6EEFF38CECBA"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="subtitle">Subtitle C—Additional Requirements</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 321. Minimum required voting systems and poll workers.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HF7F6D16F6DA3434AA349F6749BF4258C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Standards</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="HBE8ABAC09DCE4169B2778102BB843303"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title II of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20921">52 U.S.C. 20921 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subtitle:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCEF6CE8B77DF4F65A7750A65ADE54C98"> 
<subtitle commented="no" id="H6BEB57DA268546E8A32213DEF173C52F"><enum>E</enum><header>Guidance and standards</header> 
<section commented="no" id="HD14685606268439A95AFC38314A1D7C0"><enum>299.</enum><header>Standards for establishing the minimum required voting systems and poll workers</header> 
<subsection commented="no" id="HD8456CADDE0146D0B55B4BC7253265F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of the POLL Act, the Attorney General, acting through the Assistant Attorney General for the Civil Rights Division of the Department of Justice and in consultation with the Commission, shall issue standards regarding the minimum number of voting systems, poll workers, and other election resources (including all other physical resources) required under section 321 on the day of any Federal election and on any days during which early voting is allowed for a Federal election.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H8898A8F9AEE64832AFF40FE5B51885B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distribution</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H0076AAA128444D87BD6BF6876E3CED40"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The standards described in subsection (a) shall provide for a uniform and nondiscriminatory distribution of such systems, workers, and other resources, and shall take into account, among other factors, the following with respect to any voting site (as defined in section 321(b)):</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HEA868288774049A1A402E33F80BBDDF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The voting-age population.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H9FEEF2CB94884F7A91426D4B001B6201"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Voter turnout in past elections.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HEAC37EC8802D4C91B13C7A449BDABDFC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The number of voters registered.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4A5DC3B471BF433DA480160AD04FC9AD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The number of voters who have registered since the most recent Federal election.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H728012781DE94625BEC9F98ACB2ED1C7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Census data for the population served by such voting site.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H8B894180174C4001B2C4C2DAB2188A23"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The educational levels and socio-economic factors of the population served by such voting site.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HECE58F2DA2A34FC483B368BEB0273AF5"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The needs and numbers of disabled voters and voters with limited English proficiency.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD995291E3AEA4CBEACC496D2673029E5"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The type of voting systems used.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H03809681AD85440E8585229E79A396D0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No factor dispositive</header><text>The standards shall provide that any distribution of such systems shall take into account the totality of all relevant factors, including the effects of State laws on the availability of such systems and resources for use by local election officials, and no single factor shall be dispositive under the standards.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HC4B1C833C6744F7FA430C0FF49585E29"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>To the extent possible, the standards shall provide for a distribution of voting systems, poll workers, and other election resources, with the goals of—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H8EEE23303A5E4C659B24B1BD74FA8D56"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensuring an equal waiting time for all voters in the State; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H0B538060DEE846CDAB142FEBDA157A66"><enum>(B)</enum><text>preventing a waiting time of over 30 minutes at any polling place.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H6B889B66F0634645BA201BB4245F9549"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Special rule regarding electronic poll books</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraphs (1), (2), and (3), in the case of any voting site that uses an electronic poll book, the standards described in subsection (a) shall require at least 1 paper poll book (containing all of the information necessary to confirm that an individual is eligible to cast a vote at the site) for each such electronic poll book used at such voting site.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H89FAE53BFF8E47EC898AA5BDE6C35C67"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deviation</header><text>The standards described in subsection (a) shall permit States, upon giving reasonable public notice, to deviate from any allocation requirements in the case of unforeseen circumstances such as a natural disaster or terrorist attack.</text></subsection></section></subtitle><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H922149B6C17148BFBAA668FD24B50E8C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 202 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20922">52 U.S.C. 20922</external-xref>), as amended by section 3(c), is amended—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HF38CAE494439432FB201D6A9B312C1DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (4), (5), and (6) as paragraphs (5), (6), and (7), respectively; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HEF208287667648C8B3190FF68D128B36"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H77AE841512564786909DC80ACFE6B083"> <paragraph commented="no" id="H7FC90BF3CA6F4FC2B532DABC675FC73F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carrying out the duties described in subtitle E;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H393D87AC8D71439D955B7D7B0AF7DC2E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by adding at the end of the items relating to title II the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H18A3858267F1401886D0C0817E1CE5D0"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="subtitle">Subtitle E—Guidance and Standards</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 299. Standards for establishing the minimum required voting systems and poll workers.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8F801567E824CA8B4367FEC7D7DD197"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prohibition on campaign activities by chief State election administration officials</header> <subsection id="H8BBAD58FF9744683A2018306F658FC72"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Title III of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30101">52 U.S.C. 30101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 319 the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="traditional" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA06399812C7E47D6953841625408F55B"> 
<section id="H562363929D64430FA660A97FB15D1C86"><enum>319A.</enum><header>Campaign activities by chief State election administration officials</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H590E6CB7322A45F59B052D7D66F1996C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a chief State election administration official to take an active part in political management or in a political campaign with respect to any election for Federal office over which such official has supervisory authority.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HCDBC17B2FADC43F8901D3ECA4406FE14"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Chief State election administration official</header><text>The term <term>chief State election administration official</term> means the highest State official with responsibility for the administration of Federal elections under State law.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H826819683D074801A886EB0BF6264D4A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Active part in political management or in a political campaign</header><text>The term <term>active part in political management or in a political campaign</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="HD3752B7802FA4989B10AB82898EE2894"><enum>(1)</enum><text>serving as a member of an authorized committee of a candidate for Federal office;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H19607A63F8524843ABC829E536B89925"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the use of official authority or influence for the purpose of interfering with or affecting the result of an election for Federal office;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HCAD61FE4DB104C8AAA1794F32CCE75BA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the solicitation, acceptance, or receipt of a contribution from any person on behalf of a candidate for Federal office; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HD3422A2CA5DE43168906F848C72BC59F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any other act which would be prohibited under paragraph (2) or (3) of section 7323(b) of title 5, United States Code, if taken by an individual to whom such paragraph applies (other than any prohibition on running for public office).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE7A5FA6BA7C04831AC3C54D6CBCE653B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exception in case of recusal from administration of elections involving election official or immediate family member</header> <paragraph id="HA228611C80114550B220470BCB52AA8D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This section does not apply to a chief State election administration official with respect to an election for Federal office in which such official or an immediate family member of the official is a candidate, but only if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6E51C532CCDF49819032EC2713474F31"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such official recuses himself or herself from all of the official’s responsibilities for the administration of such election; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0EA378360BE24839A8A31478A7BEECB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the official who assumes responsibility for supervising the administration of the election does not report directly to such official.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAC18E973042F424E94A6A2A0E81AFB64"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Immediate family member defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In paragraph (1), the term <term>immediate family member</term> means, with respect to a candidate, a father, mother, son, daughter, brother, sister, husband, wife, father-in-law, or mother-in-law.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H68810D86FD644641BB5DAAE5724DBC43"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to elections for Federal office held after January 1, 2027.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC980EBB83E944C269C98BA3DA6730309"><enum>6.</enum><header>Payments to States to prevent unreasonable wait times and promote well-run elections</header> 
<subsection id="HAA1FA5E1F0834185819059880255C66D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subtitle D of title II of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21001">52 U.S.C. 21001 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57E14010C7524360B9317AD4719FA6FD"> <part id="H14F07352968641E49D69AD87A6845CFE"><enum>VII</enum><header>Payments for preventing unreasonable voter wait times</header> <section id="H3B8E5432389E449784C3709899E0EAF0"><enum>297.</enum><header>Payments to States</header> <subsection id="H094E32825CE3422E97DC2BA0FFF87EC4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall make a payment to each eligible State. Such payments shall be made not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this part.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H61962207F0B34E1E951A70E92BF3831E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible State</header><text>For purposes of this section, a State is an eligible State if such State has filed with the Commission a State plan covering the fiscal year in which the State describes how it intends to use the funds provided under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H68B676558E64488B94CA45E5AA8E0056"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible State shall use the payment received under this part to meet the requirements of sections 305 and 321.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0484E8049BAC4598A14CFFDC4148F16E"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amount of payment</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE1B612C500464AE09032404A1262E877"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount of payment made to a State under this section shall be the minimum payment amount described in paragraph (2) plus the voting age population proportion amount described in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F692F25279F4B00A1897B64AF8EF847"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum payment amount</header><text>The minimum payment amount described in this paragraph is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3F3C4F195A9F4E40A7E903503A2277B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of any of the several States or the District of Columbia, one-half of 1 percent of the aggregate amount made available for payments under this section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0CBEECE0124E4773BB02F8EC0742033C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, or the United States Virgin Islands, one-tenth of 1 percent of such aggregate amount.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0312B6F84ED4A5B803DF1F6077A7BCC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Voting age population proportion amount</header><text>The voting age population proportion amount described in this paragraph is the product of—</text> <subparagraph id="H9A98E7E85DDE4DEBB21FBE2AE3900AA3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the aggregate amount made available for payments under this section minus the total of all of the minimum payment amounts determined under paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFFE1CECE96834ECD9409CE6632772015"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the voting age population proportion for the State (as defined in paragraph (4)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF70B84F0BDC6418284E9239C0D2821D1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Voting age population proportion defined</header><text>The term <term>voting age population proportion</term> means, with respect to a State, the amount equal to the quotient of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCB88DB4C4CB24E999FB971D6860E4C09"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the voting age population of the State (as reported in the most recent decennial census); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB0E17B2C13584579A62CA667EEA81AFE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total voting age population of all States (as reported in the most recent decennial census).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5CB5ABBE2D60412C924CB0895A7F3B25"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Authorization of appropriations</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEDF4EA144B8B466BB1A00233D28DE997"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated for payments under this section $500,000,000 for each fiscal year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E7E6381187B4566A66AFB272848ED04"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Any amounts appropriated pursuant to the authority of paragraph (1) shall remain available without fiscal year limitation until expended.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5326EEC1D6E8414E987BF59EA9B8463B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 296 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H24101601A0C443E2B9D54583C66ADC0F"> <toc> <toc-entry level="part" idref="H14F07352968641E49D69AD87A6845CFE">Part VII—Payments for preventing unreasonable voter wait times</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section" idref="H3B8E5432389E449784C3709899E0EAF0">Sec. 297. Payments to States.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

