<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD49216C31FBF4C85888F552E569B94F9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4859 IH: Disclosure of Engagements with Attorney Law Firms Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4859</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250801">August 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Comptroller General to report on settlements with covered law firms.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H996237DEC78F4FBDA3E66543ABD4442F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H19B7BECB10B54AE4B527B266DDB98677" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Disclosure of Engagements with Attorney Law Firms Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>DEAL Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H3E772F4DBA1E43FB8CCE84FD896B245A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on settlements with covered law firms</header> 
<subsection id="H69F0E50B1C3D433D84B425CF0A6E3CF8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall report on any settlement made with a covered law firms to determine if there has been a violation of section 3302(b) of title 31, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Miscellaneous Receipts Act</quote>).</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HFFD3499F9D1F40E88A83E365E01FCF2B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Settlement made with a covered law firm defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>settlement made with a covered law firm</quote> means any written or oral agreement, arrangement, memorandum of understanding, or other commitment between any law firm and any officer, employee, or agent of the Executive Branch, including the President, that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE03D74E5063C448D93729FA36033C95D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provides the delivery of legal services, including pro bono representation, by the law firm or its agents;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H26A94C27B3014E72A91506924C5A0339"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implies that legal services provided by the law firm are directed toward causes, initiatives, or beneficiaries identified, approved, or jointly selected by the Executive Branch;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD7BE6621870E44F4A35A4AF350E13A75"><enum>(3)</enum><text>was entered into in connection with, or contemporaneously with, the withdrawal, rescission, or non-enforcement of any executive order, administration action, or regulatory threat directed at the law firm;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB24BD0A16E8D4E8FAD3B6040877DA0FE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>has an estimated value of legal services exceeding $1,000,000 over the term of the agreement; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H17E3ABB7DFE44B19942CFEADD0E606CF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>was entered into between the date of February 1, 2025, and April 30, 2025.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

