<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HEE1486961B7140168F672458CF9D3E92" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 113 RH: Directing the Secretary of Homeland Security to transmit to the House of Representatives certain documents relating to Department of Homeland Security policies and activities related to the security of Department information and data and the recruitment and retention of its workforce.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
<calendar display="yes">House Calendar No. 7</calendar>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 113</legis-num>
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–11]</associated-doc>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250205">February 5, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported adversely, referred to the House Calendar, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">Directing the Secretary of Homeland Security to transmit to the House of Representatives certain documents relating to Department of Homeland Security policies and activities related to the security of Department information and data and the recruitment and retention of its workforce.</official-title>
</form>
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="HF88A89ED5D224C6A92AACF73BCC2F359">
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H2A31D2E9D11A420DB6B87DD63E44CA52"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That, not later than 14 days after the date of the adoption of this resolution, the Secretary of Homeland Security is directed to transmit to the House of Representatives copies of any documentation, including any document, record, memo, correspondence, or other communication of the Department of Homeland Security or any portion of any such documentation, of the Department relating to the security of Department information and the recruitment and retention of its workforce, to the extent such documentation or any portion thereof is in the possession of the Secretary, that refers or relates to the following:</text> <paragraph id="H16FA5AD03FBC4C248FAF9D1CB56D98A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any documentation related to requests by the Department of Government Efficiency (as established pursuant to Executive Order 14158) for access to Department of Homeland Security information systems or data.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFF88A2DFC243401191E29E4EC5930833"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any documentation related to any access to Department of Homeland Security information systems granted to the Department of Government Efficiency by the Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCFDB961F387F4C148F225419E748BD72"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any documentation related to any data supplied to the Department of Government Efficiency by the Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9AE4FD82B7EC4B829AB8CAC9C1F1C83E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any documentation related to how the Department of Homeland Security evaluates requests by the Department of Government Efficiency for access to Department of Homeland Security information systems of data.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA16425669D3A45D38220880A92E6F619"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any documentation related to Department of Homeland Security policies related to providing individuals who are not employees or contractors of the Department access to Department information systems.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFB6CA269E7434A6489DFA559DB7C414A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any documentation related to Department of Homeland Security policies related to providing individuals who are not employees or contractors of the Department access to Department data.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H689788BA9F16400C9951F625F1CAD859"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any documentation related to Department of Homeland Security efforts to investigate or ascertain whether, why, and the extent to which, employee data has been accessed by the Office of Personnel Management for non-routine purposes, as well as any security implications of such access.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA9BEE485CA7D42F495D216F01A7695E7"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Any documentation related to implementation of a Memorandum signed by President Trump on January 20, 2025, ordering a <quote>freeze on the hiring of Federal civilian employees</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0B91D082F404455C835BF5228270675B"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Any documentation related to the number of individuals with offers of employment from the Department of Homeland Security pending on January 20, 2025, and a description of the job offers accepted.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC663E8A8CB3544D1A87997819B5EE737"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Any documentation related to the number of individuals who had accepted offers of employment from the Department of Homeland Security as of January 20, 2025, who have not been onboarded as of the date of adoption of this Resolution, and a description of the jobs that remain vacant.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BF4188959D2437DB76075C7CFD82F0A"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Any documentation related to the number of employees who accepted the Office of Personnel Management’s deferred resignation offer as of the date of adoption of this Resolution, and such employees’ job titles.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H84A48A85B6AE4F2E828DE3124E071829"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Any documentation related to the designation of national security employees for purposes of the January 20, 2025, Memorandum signed by President Trump ordering a <quote>freeze on the hiring of Federal civilian employees</quote>, and the January 28, 2025, deferred resignation offer from the Office of Personnel Management.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body> <endorsement display="yes"> <action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date> <action-desc>Reported adversely, referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement> </resolution> 

