<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KIN25489-728-89-FRX"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2855 IS: Immersive Technology for the American Workforce Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2855</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250918" legis-day="20250916">September 18 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Secretary of Labor to carry out a competitive grant program to support community colleges and area career and technical education centers in developing immersive technology education and training services programs for workforce development, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H6D35B2299E1D48EC8473B1958F67C91E"><section section-type="section-one" id="H0239E1D7F57F44D3B29F3AA422C25FA8"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Immersive Technology for the American Workforce Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H8FCE04711A1C473C89BDB2DB5E6E6E7F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants for immersive technology education and training services programs (such as career pathways)</header><subsection commented="no" id="H016A16A3058E4A068CA49936CCBCCE0B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, from the amounts appropriated to carry out this section, the Secretary of Labor shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to carry out immersive technology education and training services programs through activities described in subsection (b). </text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE1F6E0750E0A4B19BF52601D8FB770BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall use such grant for the creation or alignment, and implementation, of a career pathway that provides, through immersive technology, a sequence of education and training services that provides the necessary skills for employment leading to economic self-sufficiency, and that includes integrated education and training services that use immersive technology, including a program that—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id64e02115df4647c89c68a27404e87dcf"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is designed to increase the provision of training services for students (including individuals who are members of the Armed Forces or are veterans) in order to facilitate the entry of such students into in-demand industry sectors or occupations;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idba8e5290f69e4480b8cacbaf4a1ce1e8"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is accessible to individuals with barriers to employment, which shall be in accordance with the requirements under title II of the Americans With Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12131">42 U.S.C. 12131 et seq.</external-xref>) and in accordance with paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 188(a) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3248">29 U.S.C. 3248(a)</external-xref>); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idec1e906ffcbb45a3842ef953f0baf8ad"><enum>(3)</enum><text>enables the training of instructors in the use of immersive technology for immersive technology education and training services programs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H2E548371BADA4B00B41757780617455A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duration of grants</header><text>A grant awarded to an eligible entity under this section shall be awarded for a period of not more than 5 years. An eligible entity awarded a grant under this section may not receive a subsequent grant for the same purpose.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H70A49F9B0B064DAA82F5492AC9B06F33"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible entity seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including, in the case of a program that leads to a recognized postsecondary credential, a description of the quality of the program leading to the credential.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE5F2FE37268448DB80F460F7CF3B6AAE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to any eligible entity that—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H1573C322E7464D36975EA878AB6E2B65"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is working with, or in carrying out a program to be funded with such a grant plans to work with, an employer that has demonstrated an interest in, or commitment to, the hiring of individuals who have obtained the necessary skills for employment as a result of the program; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07d165fbf36f404095f6f05fd1ff4c52"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes a covered community college or an area career and technical education school; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd2ce63c26f3d4c3f9b4b29986bbde74f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>submits an application under subsection (d) that demonstrates 1 of the following (with additional priority given to an eligible entity that demonstrates more than 1 of the following):</text><subparagraph id="H570A36CCF9084D84ADDE07867D4E9D07"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Alignment with—</text><clause id="H53B6182C4FBB409E98E8618630F4A321"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the State plan under section 102 or 103 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3112">29 U.S.C. 3112</external-xref>, 3113) of the State in which the eligible entity will be carrying out a program to be funded with such a grant;</text></clause><clause id="HC7FA83B44473410783CF4189F36A0435"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the local plan under section 108 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3123">29 U.S.C. 3123</external-xref>) of the local area in which the eligible entity will be carrying out such a program; or</text></clause><clause id="H24F72B9919B141C7A7F9C30F1DC3CDFA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the State plan under section 122 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2342">20 U.S.C. 2342</external-xref>) of the State in which the eligible entity will be carrying out such a program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9B180E96FD044725A8A2B265B6242196"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Using quantitative data and evidence, the extent to which the program to be funded by such a grant will meet the needs of employers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H91604B2DB8FD4E4CB4A49FA3C6240CA8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>How such a program will target a specific in-demand industry sector or occupation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H742036E0C4734BF98E041E1F6688F3E7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>How such a program will retrain workers from an industry sector that is experiencing decreasing employment at the national or State level.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8E691E0B154940008001E1D4DA83787D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>How such a program will target and service individuals with barriers to employment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8D3274D53D0B4E6D8C6F3C4CFF048EA8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>How such a program will serve a rural community.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H50FD284842094C6A8DBE71F4E71817DD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph commented="no" id="HC2F3A84CEEB346B4A053EBC97AFDBADC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report to the Secretary</header><text>Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary a report, not later than the date that is 2 years after the beginning of the initial grant period for such grant, and annually thereafter (so the report is last submitted during the year following the final grant period for the grant) that includes a description of each program funded under the grant, including the levels of performance achieved for each indicator of performance under section 116(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3141">29 U.S.C. 3141(b)(2)(A)(i)</external-xref>), disaggregated, with respect to the participants of such program, as described in section 116(d)(2)(B).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6B64B171CEB04E81968275AA6265A15D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the first grant is awarded under this section and biennially thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes a summary of the information submitted under paragraph (1) for the most recent 2-year period.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HB54B3126B8B646558655F068DB20CCD1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall reserve not less than 1 percent and not more than 5 percent of any amounts made available for each fiscal year to conduct a rigorous, independent evaluation of, and provide technical assistance for, the programs carried out under this section.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H769F9479908A44E0A2E1A47A0D4D5895"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination each eligible entity that receives funds under a grant awarded under this section, not later than 30 days after the third year of the grant period, as described in subsection (c), shall—</text><paragraph id="H042ED8D33828443CBC0846D8D045550D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish a description of best practices for using immersive technology for immersive technology education and training services programs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CDE6F672FF64FB2A7F0334203E66818"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publish such description of best practices on a publicly available website of the Department of Labor.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H6C5105D9ECC448D7A5C64B3E6E68A536"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section: </text><paragraph commented="no" id="HD3790243426D44A09AC731C19527AE13"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered community college</header><text>The term <term>covered community college</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7C9260C3416D4747AF7446596A9AEF6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a public institution of higher education (as defined in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>)), at which—</text><clause commented="no" id="H540C9930D20B4EE481344A9FDEA6F79B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the highest degree awarded is an associate degree; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H479D6F137478420EA517B94F0979750D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an associate degree is the most frequently awarded degree;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDF0D2E19D8734ADBB59CFDFD4FF69DC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a branch campus of a 4-year public institution of higher education (as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>)), if, at such branch campus—</text><clause commented="no" id="HB9BE7BA1D8D04EA69008E2ACFD068F16"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the highest degree awarded is an associate degree; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HFBB2E62A2A8E4403A87FA28699B14D25"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an associate degree is the most frequently awarded degree;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9BA042FFC32D4AD3AC83DCCA7E030E4E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a 2-year Tribal College or University (as defined in section 316(b)(3) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c(b)(3)</external-xref>)); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF469D490D851487AB680955AC65514AE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a degree-granting Tribal College or University (as defined in section 316(b)(3) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c(b)(3)</external-xref>)) at which—</text><clause commented="no" id="HBDF10B6F3BD240ECAF8851A9EEF35200"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the highest degree awarded is an associate degree; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H025CCC9FA3544E91A93B3430B064F0E4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an associate degree is the most frequently awarded degree.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7BFA566BD84E4615A1F8AC564C5563B4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means an industry or sector partnership, which shall include representatives of 1 or more of the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id60ebb0ee34974b51a940815e98d5ee6d"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution of higher education.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF66F47DC099949EEB90633F87EBF853B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A covered community college. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E4C9E9A66A04824A8B8E3F8CC8F62AF"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An area career and technical education school. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF5DC0745FF0245FBADCF1921715A1E6A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A postsecondary vocational institution (as defined in section 102(c) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002(c)</external-xref>)). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H68FF1B8538D44FE9A587CE922A43C6C7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A consortium of such colleges, schools, or institutions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H65DF6BB405DF4426B995B70C5FDF9D36"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Immersive technology</header><subparagraph id="H69BB35A9723148E2A7BBEEE6F1D867AB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>immersive technology</term> means the technology of tools (including extended reality, virtual reality, augmented reality, and mixed reality) that integrate the physical environment with digital content to support user engagement.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5945DD2695D34601B3ED0DE119DEA31F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Augmented Reality</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>augmented reality</term> means an immersive technology tool that layers computer-generated imagery onto a user’s view of the physical world, thus providing a composite view. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BF04DE175644FA0835FE1170300E52F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Mixed reality</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>mixed reality</term> means an immersive technology tool that blends augmented reality and virtual reality, allowing users to experience simulated content within their physical worlds and to manipulate and interact with virtual elements in real time. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC69104B45ED54BF484065866FF97C315"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Virtual reality</header><text>The term <term>virtual reality</term> means an immersive technology tool that occludes a user’s physical surroundings with a simulated environment. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc88391ae78744094bdab54c9259c4209"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Immersive technology education and training services program</header><text>The term <term>immersive technology education and training services program</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8be591eae4384295ad2a6bf2c73eb9d1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a program of education and training services provided, in part or in whole, through immersive technology; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec61a2e226124c88a31520bf11c361a9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a career pathway described in subsection (b) that is so provided.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H473586EFAF7F4295834A09320C4BC35C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rural</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id30d2959ebe944c4db7942429582560c2"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The term <term>rural community</term> means a jurisdiction or population not located within an urban area.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4b8fe378fd934aa4be6a7e1f70fca8f2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Urban area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph, the term <term>urban area</term>, means a gathered jurisdiction that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id58c6a8008ab34e17b277311fc83b7d97"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contains 50,000 or more people; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6a6e083498094a51a989621b6be83bb4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is comprised of clusters consisting of at least 2,500 gathered jurisdictions but contains fewer than 50,000 people. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ccc759002b743b6968e988bdbcb0f86"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Training services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (7), the term <term>training services</term> means training services as described in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>), provided through classroom instruction.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5961B19580149F2BF248941E8821DCE"><enum>(7)</enum><header>WIOA terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in this section, any term used in this section that is defined in section 3 of that Act shall have the meaning given that term in that section 3.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddaa481897866472fb2cd669aea0fa40c"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $50,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2026 through 2035.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

