<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA25811-JJN-WT-Y46"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 403 ATS: Expressing support for the designation of October 14, 2025, as the “National Day of Remembrance for Charlie Kirk”. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 403</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250918" legis-day="20250916">September 18 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S434">Mr. Moreno</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S389">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S439">Mrs. Moody</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of October 14, 2025, as the “National Day of Remembrance for Charlie Kirk”. </official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Charlie Kirk was a champion of free speech, civil dialogue, and faith;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Mr. Kirk consistently promoted the values of individual liberty, open debate, the importance of civic engagement, and the defense of constitutional principles;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Charlie Kirk was recognized as one of the leading voices among young leaders in the United States, creating opportunities for civic education, fostering youth leadership, and promoting principles of liberty and democracy across the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Charlie Kirk was the founder and executive director of Turning Point USA, a nonprofit organization of thousands of chapters across the United States dedicated to educating students about the principles of freedom, free markets, and limited government;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Charlie Kirk authored multiple national best-selling books, that engage readers in critical conversations about civics, culture, and the future of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, through Mr. Kirk's writing, public speaking, and media presence, Charlie Kirk reached millions of United States citizens, inspiring the next generation to become active participants in civic life; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Mr. Kirk's life’s work has contributed to strengthening public discourse, defending constitutional principles, and fostering active citizenship; and</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Mr. Kirk's life work, especially his efforts to bring these American ideals to life on college campuses in the United States, cost him his life by means of an assassin's bullet on September 10, 2025: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idc0c272ac2fa94956b956a2d608e4dda2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of October 14, 2025, as the <quote>National Day of Remembrance for Charlie Kirk</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide70a8e8345b14dbb8335bfb1e1a9bb8f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes Charlie Kirk for his contributions to civic education and public service; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0c7582f2d9cb47d6889c96aa774c1f7b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages educational institutions, civic organizations, and citizens across the United States to observe this day with appropriate programs, activities, prayers, and ceremonies that promote civic engagement and the principles of faith, liberty, and democracy that Charlie Kirk championed.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

