<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H91060DC815EF4A66B09E277EB836B806" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 246 IH: Impeaching Theodore Chuang, a judge of the United States District Court for the District of Maryland, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 246</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250324">March 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000626">Mr. Davidson</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Impeaching Theodore Chuang, a judge of the United States District Court for the District of Maryland, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HCE48100D5C7C464FA060D7EF279CC95B"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HC157494D03AC49D09D943DE5B7700286"><enum/><text>That Theodore Chuang, a judge of the United States District Court for the District of Maryland, is impeached for high crimes and misdemeanors, and that the following article of impeachment be exhibited in the Senate:</text><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HADD56589C03A44A28E8466908A5D4400"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Article of impeachment exhibited by the House of Representatives of the United States of America in the name of itself and of the people of the United States of America, against Theodore Chuang, a judge of the United States District Court for the District of Maryland, in maintenance and support of its impeachment against him for high crimes and misdemeanors.</text></subsection></section><section id="H405D615B63444A7CB63BD2D2220F54CA" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum/><header>Article I</header><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD1BE5D06D76A41FDA57885154340408B"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Theodore Chuang, a judge of the United States District Court for the District of Maryland, engaged in a pattern of conduct that is incompatible with the trust and confidence placed in him as a Federal judge as follows: </text></subsection><subsection id="H71195CCC0FA147DEA06E6EC83C2C8991"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Judge Chuang, in his memorandum opinion on March 18, 2025, related to the case J. Does v. Elon Musk, et al., issued a preliminary injunction ordering, among other things, the government <quote>to reinstate access to email, payments, security notifications, and other electronic systems, including restoring deleted emails, for current USAID employees and PSCs</quote>. In issuing a temporary restraining order requiring provision of systems access to these employees and PSCs, Judge Chuang has without merit marginalized the President’s Article II authority, which vests the power to conduct foreign policy in the President of the United States. This patent violation of the separation of powers—which prevents the President from responding to threats to our national security posed by USAID employees who have, among other things, disbursed funds to organizations linked to Foreign Terrorist Organizations—is entirely inconsistent with serving the United States as a district court judge.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB208D6E6C5FF4379923D09335B9FA278"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Judge Chuang, in mandating the immediate provision of access to government systems without regard for the President’s duty under Article II to defend the national security of the United States, has done so in a manner that is arbitrary and capricious. Judge Chuang mandated such access without regard for the troubled history of foreign assistance through the United States Agency for International Development (USAID). A March 2021 GAO report indicates that from FY2015 until FY2019, USAID did not consistently ensure that subawards provided for projects in the Gaza Strip and Judea and Samaria complied with regulations aimed at preventing financial support for terrorism. More recently, in November 2024, USAID was found to have financed hundreds of thousands of meals for al-Qaida affiliated fighters in Syria. While arguing that the Trump Administration’s reorganization of USAID caused <quote>irreparable harm</quote> to the plaintiffs, Judge Chuang failed to consider that his decisions could easily inflict <quote>irreparable harm</quote> on Americans and American interests.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB5F7CFF8C0D14920A9A61D8A92E2C82C"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> Accordingly, Judge Theodore Chuang has engaged in conduct so lacking in due concern for the separation of powers and the national security of the United States that he is guilty of high crimes and misdemeanors, is unfit to hold the office of Federal judge, and should be removed from office.</text></subsection></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

