<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25I86-D90-0D-4K6"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2821 IS: American Tech Workforce Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2821</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250916">September 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to reform the H–1B nonimmigrant visa program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HB3C8C059F98B4887A179199D6B9123C6"><section section-type="section-one" id="H4956601E99814AFE9F515B59E11DF92D"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Tech Workforce Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9B59C97A5EAB45AAA89A3D09B10C8ABC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HF7DA771D726446CEBDC5DD5B8DEB66B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The H–1B nonimmigrant visa is a program that is being used to supplant United States workers with inexpensive foreign labor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3400BD7CCEBC4C9AA20EE6FEB6016C6F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Sixty percent of H–1B nonimmigrant visas are assigned wage levels that are substantially below the local median wages for their relevant occupations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABAA543001E8481E91912E8BB079146B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The ability to hire non-United States workers at wages substantially below median wage levels, adjusted for locality and occupation, clearly disincentivizes the hiring of United States workers. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F7F4538C9DA45DDB02F1C582727ED3D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In 2024, the 8 companies receiving the most initial approvals for H–1B nonimmigrant visas were Big Tech companies, including Amazon, Meta, Google, Microsoft, and Apple, which continues a 10-year trend.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCF1034CC06F4FE594749925A249ACE7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Optional Practical Training Program, which was established without explicit congressional authorization—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2fe72c35ff3a460f9aac0335bbf304cb"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was expanded by the Obama Administration for student visa holders who have completed their studies and earned a degree in a science, technology, engineering, or math field to provide greater benefits to Big Tech companies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id83bcc655438a4c55a96fcabc37a83752"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allows such student visa holders to work in the United States for up to 3 years, while waiving their employer’s payroll tax withholding obligations with respect to such workers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide7c2174bfcc2460f9c8846861e3b4a10"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">functions as a tax break and significant incentive for employers not to employ United States workers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H7C61E02773754F268DB6C0177808190D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Termination of Optional Practical Training Program; employment authorization to terminate after completion of course of studies</header><subsection id="H01A11404E22749B9A26168F9762C81E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 274A(h) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC480F5640DF3481B81EF272E1231B536"><paragraph id="H5BA47FE5BD6C428E9A8E7E09F6A113DA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prohibition of employment authorization for certain aliens who are no longer engaged in full-time study in the united states</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5921dcf920684328a9a4274b9692e591"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Termination of optional practical training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Optional Practical Training Program authorized under section 214.2(f)(10)(ii) of title 8, Code of Federal Regulations, is terminated.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idad787a77908247e1aaaa66ae4e6e9750"><enum>(B)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an alien who is present in the United States as a nonimmigrant described in section 101(a)(15)(F)(i) may not be provided employment authorization in the United States through the Optional Practical Training Program, or any successor program. Any employment authorization for a nonimmigrant described in section 101(a)(15)(F)(i) shall terminate upon the completion of the nonimmigrant’s course of studies and may not be extended beyond such date of completion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H1930C10D56974D3AA20D0EDFBD7DEECB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transition rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Every application for Optional Practical Training by a nonimmigrant described in section 101(a)(15)(F)(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(F)(i)</external-xref>) that is pending on the date of the enactment of this Act shall be denied and any fees paid in conjunction with any such application shall be refunded. </text></subsection></section><section id="H75BAB1F1DE5B4211824403F1E156E6AB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Other provisions regarding H–1B nonimmigrant applications</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 212(n) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(n)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE676D1A3793248A5BAD88F2A29565249"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H724A7FE3CA6B4782AFAB755117EE3F8E"><subparagraph id="HEDCE56F2572743C2A94304D1A9B99D5D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The employer is offering, and will offer during the period of authorized employment, an annual wage to the H–1B nonimmigrant that is not less than the greater of—</text><clause id="H0683AA69C1FB40E299E5F21598647600"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the annual wage that was paid to the United States citizen or lawful permanent resident employee who performed identical or similar work to the work to be performed by the H–1B nonimmigrant during the 2-year period immediately preceding the date on which the employer filed such application; or</text></clause><clause id="H010E6417101C49E4BFC8F6347E52B5D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id2023f8227fe8417e818395792f950621"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$150,000, if offered during the 1-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of the <short-title>American Tech Workforce Act of 2025</short-title>; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a126757a249490996dfb70541608038" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for any 1-year period beginning on July 1 after the period described in subclause (I), the sum of—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb9b9b228e6634f65a3e292f0a5fce403"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount specified in subclause (I); and </text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7bea5d0e7084480d898adde498e9695a"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such amount multiplied by the cumulative percentage change in the Consumer Price Index since such date of enactment.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HD119AC507EAF455AB6307A583F805953"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H98AC3B91E58C42EFAA946DB6BCB2E195"><paragraph id="HE114CFF8C27246A696176A71B6B5642A" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A visa issued to an H–1B nonimmigrant pursuant to a petition filed by an employer pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be valid for a period not to exceed 1 year if any part of the work assigned to such H–1B nonimmigrant will be performed at a third-party worksite.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AE9773E65B641E9957237950E46ED17" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An H–1B nonimmigrant visa may not be issued if any part of the work assigned to the H–1B nonimmigrant for the beneficiary of the applicant will be performed at a third-party worksite unless such assignment—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id94808206632b41f5bd9d12b439cb744f"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is specific and nonspeculative; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4cdb56ebc6d240d9a0acf65c18053643"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">continues for the entire work period requested in the petition. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE9B382B0F614B998C87C983FEBD5FE3" indent="up1"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In issuing an H–1B nonimmigrant visa or granting such status to an alien during a fiscal year, petitions from employers shall be approved by prioritizing petitions that offer higher compensation rates above petitions that offer lower compensation rates, regardless of the order in which such petitions were filed.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="id8ce2434b88a64319868050ba1cab05e5"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or in the amendments made by this Act, may be construed to authorize any Federal agency to grant work authorization to any alien through any program that has not been authorized by an Act of Congress.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

