<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H78479C49BF57456F8B79036617A4B20F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2811 IH: SNAP Staffing Flexibility Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2811</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to allow for blended workforces to carry out the supplemental nutrition assistance program under certain conditions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD6D53B3B1B584FCE8B012B95A02C9F96" style="OLC"><section id="H1E014147B4654F3593CD0BBBFC994311" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><subsection id="H83356084A4F9492097436485CE2E72A2"><enum>(a)</enum><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>SNAP Staffing Flexibility Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA331562FA3A04016B4443DFD7AD24C25"><enum>2.</enum><header>SNAP staffing flexibility</header><subsection id="HC75DDD8341E44F6A83A8CFC8B8C861B0"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Section 11 of the Food and Nutrition Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2020">7 U.S.C. 2020</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H61824E0CBB8348AA8672B2A4FEB1FF12" style="OLC"><subsection id="H2E13E945308E4C09B3F3CD9F3F627D40"><enum>(y)</enum><header>SNAP staffing flexibility</header><paragraph id="HC12C05CEECFC437FB05500AF8443CD2A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 11(e)(6)(B) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008, a State agency (as defined in section 3 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008) may, by contract with the State agency at a reasonable cost in accordance with the State agency’s standard contracting rules, hire a contractor to undertake supplemental nutrition assistance program certification or carry out any other function of the State agency under such program so long as—</text><subparagraph id="H55AA124A70EA4B6683AFE3EE18209CEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the contract does not provide incentives for the agency or contractor to delay eligibility determinations or to deny eligibility for individuals otherwise eligible for supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H185465ED6A1D4FF5AA688846ADC309CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the contractor has no direct or indirect financial interest in an approved retail store.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H54B9CDC974BC4D7A8D101329A2D62BE8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use</header><text>A State agency may use the authority provided in paragraph (1) when the State experiences increases in supplemental nutrition assistance program applications or an inability to timely process such applications from causes that include but are not limited to—</text><subparagraph id="H6DD019F81AB04D6B9EF6F5693A2AC1C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>pandemics and other health emergencies,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAD8F1B9FCCB4F3CB7CB1121EAB3A2DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>seasonal workforce cycles,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90A5F5726DF748D99AC187F2F73E7099"><enum>(C)</enum><text>temporary staffing shortages, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB04436231CB44334A44C79BA9882ED1C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>weather or other natural disasters.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H62BA880F85CD4C4EA3DE57F6C8F81442"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A State agency that hires a contractor under paragraph (1) shall ensure such action—</text><subparagraph id="HF8C0A4B5350E435BBB7609FFE14F7C8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is consistent with all principles under section 900.603 of title 5 of the Code of Federal Regulations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE882E1765884DA0987FDF510879FC6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is part of a blended workforce and does not supplant existing merit-based personnel in the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB90F43A60354867AF7C28C6FA19AC9C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>A State agency shall notify the Secretary of its intent to use the authority provided in this section and shall provide any information or data supporting State agency increases in supplemental nutrition assistance program applications or any inability to timely process such applications.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H322750F0545B40E9B80EB3CFF448C949"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>Not later than 10 days after the date of the receipt of a notification submitted by a State agency under paragraph (4), the Secretary shall make publicly available on the website of the Department of Agriculture the notification submitted by such State agency and any accompanying information or data supporting such notification so submitted.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64244151D91E4090A633170224D0A171"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate, an annual report that contains—</text><subparagraph id="HC806E34A7EA44362BCE2496ABD0E180D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of measures taken to address increases in supplemental nutrition assistance program applications and any inability to timely process such applications;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B4196CDC15C42FB99C3F0B2A813AA4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information or data supporting State agency notifications provided pursuant to paragraph (4); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7052433BD8924079B22882D748444F79"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations for changes to the Secretary’s authority under this Act to assist the Secretary, States, and local governments of States in preparing for any future increases in supplemental nutrition assistance program applications or inability to timely process such applications.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0660DEA762BF4746BEA59FE2C98CCEAE"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Temporary staffing shortages</header><text>In cases of temporary staffing shortages, the authority provided to State agencies under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="HFE0D9D302B5E4B52A35B2BBF08583829"><enum>(A)</enum><text>expire when the backlog of supplemental nutrition assistance program applications has been eliminated; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75216178702E4E26B6EF4070740286C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not override any collective bargaining agreement or memorandum of understanding in effect between the State and employees of the State or of a local government of such State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

