<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9D03F3037D154803BB6553539A7E4A4D" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 404 IH: Recognizing and celebrating “National Salvation Army Week” on May 12 through May 18, 2025.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 404</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250513">May 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing and celebrating <quote>National Salvation Army Week</quote> on May 12 through May 18, 2025.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, since its founding in 1865, the Salvation Army has been dedicated to serving individuals and families in need, without discrimination;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for more than 150 years, the Salvation Army has provided essential social services, including disaster relief, food assistance, shelter, rehabilitation programs, and youth development initiatives in local communities across the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas President Dwight D. Eisenhower first declared <quote>National Salvation Army Week</quote> in 1954, recognizing the organization’s unwavering commitment to serving communities nationwide;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Salvation Army serves more than 27,000,000 Americans annually, offering compassion, hope, and support to the most vulnerable populations, including individuals experiencing homelessness, veterans, seniors, human trafficking survivors, and those recovering from addiction;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Salvation Army’s Red Kettle Campaign, first launched in 1891, has become one of the most recognizable and impactful annual charitable traditions, raising funds to support millions in need each year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Salvation Army continues to be a trusted partner at the local, State, and Federal levels, providing critical services that address poverty, hunger, and emergency assistance in times of crisis;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, across the Nation, the Salvation Army operates shelters, food pantries, job training programs, and emergency disaster relief efforts that strengthen communities and improve lives; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas volunteers, donors, and officers of the Salvation Army exemplify the spirit of service, working tirelessly to provide relief and opportunity for those in need: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H4ABB165108844AFC89C19065A77919A0"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H25962361E7AE4087935DADB281AB3B89"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H24F85EA1E72C4A588AE49F26C8906D9A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes and celebrates <quote>National Salvation Army Week</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5E7D87F410041FA9B58513C5E5CD975"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends the Salvation Army for its historic and ongoing efforts to uplift and serve individuals and families across the country; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA472DC49873F4286BD20042480436BBF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages all Americans to join in acts of service and generosity, supporting the Salvation Army’s goal to combat human need with love and compassion, wherever it persists.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

