<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP25786-CH8-LW-CT5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2359 IS: Strengthening Accountability for Employers Hiring Individuals and Reforming Enforcement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2359</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250721">July 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S434">Mr. Moreno</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require certification of employment eligibility compliance in annual reporting of certain securities issuers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Accountability for Employers Hiring Individuals and Reforming Enforcement Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAFE HIRE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id10cc42ac44e641b6b9b2a6e4dd8cc28c"><enum>2.</enum><header>Executive certification of employment eligibility compliance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 13 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78m">15 U.S.C. 78m</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id132c1169c8c84a3394318f0c4f6fc6cd"><subsection id="id4a06056fba1047d084b92fd53d3bc324"><enum>(t)</enum><header>Certification Requirements</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf543af1f0fb64f37b039485181b1bbcf"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="id28f44018f0bd4a78958c62aff2af3fe1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered employer</header><text>The term <term>covered employer</term> means any issuer of a security registered under section 12 or person required to file a report under section 15(d).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id23a6958b1d004107b0495ddc421914ff"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Internal controls</header><text>The term <term>internal controls</term> means policies, procedures, and systems reasonably designed to—</text><clause id="id55f1a11c384247a282c89d9c933ecde3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ensure compliance with employment eligibility verification requirements under Federal law, including section 274A of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="iddf258e7d757c43cb9b8853c134ea2b3d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identify and prevent the use of fraudulent or unauthorized documentation in the hiring process; and</text></clause><clause id="id60db853752e0449586ee04710f3dff73"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>promptly detect, report, and remediate any known violations of such requirements.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idca53d11a2311464583f36844958cd52f"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Principal executive officer</header><text>The term <term>principal executive officer</term> has the meaning given in section 229.402(a)(3) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id597bbc9cd1584e00b792fc4dd32acd2e" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Principal human resources officer</header><text>The term <term>principal human resources officer</term> means the most senior officer of a covered employer with responsibility for human capital management, including employment eligibility policies and compliance. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida5ec07e7356543da9f5f6cbeb35e1063"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The principal executive officer and the principal human resources officer (or officers performing similar functions) of each covered employer shall submit with each annual report filed under subsection (a) or section 15(d) the following:</text><subparagraph id="idd5ca431022314e73b3bd1d5d45f37a05"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A certification that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id52f910b9599d4edf9ec01d94e520818b"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the certifying officers have reviewed the report;</text></clause><clause id="id5f73d7d693064b368e1177268ac0994a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>based on the knowledge of the certifying officers, the report does not contain any untrue statement of a material fact or omit to state a material fact necessary to make the statements made, in light of the circumstances, not misleading;</text></clause><clause id="id233df70399f04d17a778e22b13005611"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>based on the knowledge of the certifying officers, the report fairly presents, in all material respects, the employment practices of the issuer, including the number and legal work status of persons employed;</text></clause><clause id="idaa1be4941aea42508d2d3ed37d2cfc17"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the certifying officers—</text><subclause id="id031da811693943f5a9dd89b5564a52eb"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are responsible for establishing and maintaining internal controls with respect to employment eligibility verification (including Form I–9 compliance and E-Verify);</text></subclause><subclause id="ide2ae964aa7114211bc4e4300447b28a8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>have designed such internal controls to ensure that material information relating to compliance with section 274A of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a</external-xref>) is made known to such officers by others within the company;</text></subclause><subclause id="id828825f801a443eeb0cd4cb41f0535e9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>have evaluated the effectiveness of the internal controls described in subclause (II) not less than 90 days prior to the submission of the report; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idfdd12e0c63fc4ad0a1dd1e10921ccd59"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>have presented in the report their conclusions about the effectiveness of such internal controls based on their evaluation; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id55149bf6550048d29cfbed6d15bd01fb"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the certifying officers have disclosed to the Department of Homeland Security and the Department of Justice—</text><subclause id="id443163da8613439fa345faa3a2f0c6ab"><enum>(I)</enum><text>all significant deficiencies in the internal controls of the covered employer which could adversely affect the ability of the covered employer to ensure compliance with Federal employment eligibility requirements; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id440f1c9f30d84384bbee4e26028ac312"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any known material violation of section 274A of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a</external-xref>), including the employment of unauthorized aliens, as defined in subsection (h) of that section.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf29ad8bb6569433cbd5438a343851ff8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A list of all disclosed significant deficiencies and known material violations described in subparagraph (A)(v).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc70b5839dd204a78958ea55eb7b36ea1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Criminal penalties for false certification</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3aca103238fa4f49b89b1a4ee85d6e88"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for a principal executive officer or principal human resources officer (or other officer performing similar functions) of a covered employer to—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0b54c5348b3a4c8c808f996021e4b83c"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certify any statement described in paragraph (2)(A) knowing that the report does not comply with the requirements therein; or</text></clause><clause id="idd06c8824e5f34abfaa78ea845d6e3c6d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>willfully fail to make the certification under paragraph (2)(A) or submit the list of disclosed significant deficiencies and known material violations pursuant to paragraph (2)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd24d00dc335743fbb7a069f29b075f98"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Penalties</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide73c48c20ead4a198f2e2e25a4873023"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any individual who violates subparagraph (A) shall be fined not more than $1,000,000, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</text></clause><clause id="iddeffbaa776334084b439953d9c57c754"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Enhanced penalty</header><text>Any individual who violates subparagraph (A) with respect to the employment of unauthorized aliens in violation of section 274A(a)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a(a)(1)</external-xref>) shall be fined not more than $5,000,000, imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id059c320a85024c2aa769535ef93a76a2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Implementation and rulemaking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Chair of the Securities and Exchange Commission, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Attorney General, shall—</text><paragraph id="id8d348722ae9141038168205b025e19e8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prescribe rules requiring the inclusion of the certification described in section 13(t) of the Securities and Exchange Act of 1934, as added by section 2, within the annual reports filed on Form 10–K or any successor form;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idebb1266d11564fdc8ea33b74d7bc843d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish requirements for public availability of such certifications; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id181bdf791e83437b9b32962ecba5737c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promulgate any regulations necessary to carry out the purposes of this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

