<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25483-06T-L5-6WY"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 230 ATS: Supporting the goals and ideals of National Hospital Week, to be observed from May 11 through May 17, 2025. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 230</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250514">May 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of National Hospital Week, to be observed from May 11 through May 17, 2025. </official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, beginning in 1921, National Hospital Day was established by former President Warren G. Harding to be celebrated annually on May 12, the birthday of Florence Nightingale, the founder of modern nursing, as a way to honor her role in revolutionizing hospital care;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas National Hospital Day was established following the 1918 Influenza Pandemic as a way to foster community trust in hospitals;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, beginning in 1953, National Hospital Week was established and continues to coincide with the birthday of Florence Nightingale;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas National Hospital Week is a time of year to reflect on the important contributions that hospitals make to provide safe, high-quality health care;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2025, approximately 6,093 hospitals in the United States provide essential and life-saving health care every day in a variety of hospitals settings, including—</text><paragraph id="id5e1f4f7afb80463bb51cf8e9ee999601"><enum>(1)</enum><text>1,377 critical access hospitals, which serve as essential health care hubs that bring medical services closer to individuals who would otherwise have to travel long distances for health care, that provide health care to <fraction>1/5</fraction> of the United States population residing in rural areas;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddebf0338adfa41aca186113f8b09b522"><enum>(2)</enum><text>nearly 1,700 teaching hospitals, of which roughly 300 are major teaching hospitals such as university hospitals or academic medical centers, that provide essential training to future medical providers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide411d69212aa46e8a67c96148a7282bb"><enum>(3)</enum><text>654 non-Federal psychiatric hospitals that are essential partners in addressing mental health and substance abuse disorders across the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf4d3f629469d407d99bf75c9c9693144"><enum>(4)</enum><text>170 Department of Veterans Affairs medical centers that are uniquely responsible for providing health care to more than 9,100,000 veterans;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2023, hospitals in the United States provided health care to more than 34,000,000 admitted patients and in 2024 delivered more than 3,600,000 babies;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as of April 2025, hospitals employed more than 5,716,000 individuals, including physicians, registered nurses, and allied health professionals;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas non-clinical hospital staff, including sanitation workers, food service workers, and many others, work to keep hospitals open 24 hours a day, 7 days a week, in order to ensure hospitals are always available to individuals that need health care;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas hospitals, through direct care and community outreach, can provide the expertise and resources needed to address the unique health care needs that exist in rural and urban areas of the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas hospitals work collaboratively to uphold the health care system of the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id0887d6e495f048c28db3f7319f7c1c51"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of National Hospital Week, to be observed from May 11 through May 17, 2025;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf13b7a1a0ef44df38adc5a7fd1fe534c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the significant role that hospitals play in the delivery of health care in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida5d0bda27afa449aab0ecc102ea0a9de"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to observe National Hospital Week with appropriate recognition, ceremonies, activities, and programs to demonstrate the importance of hospitals to the everyday lives of patients and communities.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

