<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-LAN25087-F18-3H-XPM">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 454 IS: Expressing support for the designation of the week of October 24, 2025, to October 31, 2025, as “Bat Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>III</distribution-code>
        <congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. RES. 454</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action display="yes">
            <action-date date="20251016">October 16, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</sponsor> submitted the following
                resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
        <official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the week of October
            24, 2025, to October 31, 2025, as <quote>Bat Week</quote>.</official-title>
    </form>
    <preamble>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas bats are vital to the sustainability of natural ecosystems, national economies, and human health by controlling damaging insect pests, pollinating plants that produce fruits and vegetables, dispersing seeds to ensure healthy functioning forests and fields, and saving farmers in the United States more than $3,700,000,000 in pest control every year;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas bats have captured the human imagination through backyard sightings, folklore, art, myths, and legends, making outreach and education about the importance of bats instrumental;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas bats are present throughout the world, except in extremely cold regions, and are the second-largest order of mammals with over 1,400 species;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas white-nose syndrome, a fungal disease that has killed millions of bats in North America, has now spread to 40 States and 12 species of hibernating bats;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the disease has caused significant declines in populations of the tricolored bat, the little brown bat, and the northern long-eared bat, which is listed as endangered by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the Department of the Interior, through the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, the United States Geological Survey, the National Park Service, and the Bureau of Land Management, is leading the international response to the disease in partnership with the United States Forest Service and more than 150 Federal and State agencies, Tribes, nongovernmental organizations, and universities;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the United States Geological Survey and the United States Fish and Wildlife Service co-lead the multinational, multiagency North American Bat Monitoring Program, which, since 2015, has consolidated nearly 94,000,000 records from partners in 49 States, 9 Canadian Provinces, and 20 Tribal organizations, demonstrating the power of collaborative conservation science to monitor changes in North American bat populations;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the United States Geological Survey conducts scientific research on bats that helps resource managers and policymakers make informed decisions regarding the conservation of bats across North America; and</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, in the past decade, the international partnership of States, Tribes, Federal agencies, nongovernmental organizations, and other institutions has made extraordinary progress to understand white-nose syndrome, slow the spread of the disease, and develop treatments that hold promise for ending this epidemic: Now, therefore, be it</text>
        </whereas>
    </preamble>
    <resolution-body>
        <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1">
 <text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="id05c515a98ef6428daa7dc471ce59e617"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>expresses support for the designation of the week of October 24, 2025, to October 31, 2025, as <quote>Bat Week</quote>;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idbb9396f208fa47b2b0b3dd9ba76a488e">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>encourages the observance of Bat Week with appropriate events and activities;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id5177ee807dbf423c805260ced04cc16a">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>acknowledges the important role bats play as pollinators and pest control for agriculture; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id3b6f6f5ea9ab42d1acb6aa30d3e8d587">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>intends to—</text> <subparagraph id="idd88008f470c141c2aa82033ae1fefb8d"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>continue working to conserve bat species and their habitat; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="idb61082102fab41c1a5d65d99e6e94abd">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>work to defeat the disease known as white-nose syndrome.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </section> </resolution-body> </resolution>

