<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3BC150D734A9439FB40E2AC099626746" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2741 IH: Providing Empathetic and Effective Recovery Support Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2741</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To address the behavioral health workforce shortages through support for peer support specialists, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB49C8EE481294ED08389E4C74E62822A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H87160C147132474AAC344D42F80D5CA2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Providing Empathetic and Effective Recovery Support Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PEER Support Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0BD6EBA5ADE478384B98CA95D859519"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition of peer support specialist</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8107DDA0C7B14EC58710F38E10D5CCE8"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>peer support specialist</term> means an individual—</text>
<paragraph id="HDB0EB257C9224A4B921A19D2D3B63DCF"><enum>(1)</enum>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA68FCEE6CD0A4756A788E51E03441B1F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who has lived experience of recovery from a mental health condition or substance use disorder and who specializes in supporting individuals with mental health conditions or substance use disorders; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H69A5F5991C854266981D6F50257E8087" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who has lived experience as a parent or caregiver of an individual with a mental health condition or substance use disorder and who specializes in supporting families navigating mental health or substance use service systems; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB5B8D2A39DD484B92B4B69B9C618AED"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who is certified as qualified to furnish peer support services, as described in subsection (b), under a process that is determined by the State in which such individual furnishes such services or determined appropriate by the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4121E939640E4021855E5DB55880817C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Peer support services</header><text>The services described in this subsection shall be consistent with the National Practice Guidelines for Peer Supporters issued by the National Association of Peer Supporters (or a successor publication) and inclusive of the Core Competencies for Peer Workers in Behavioral Health Services of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration.</text></subsection></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H86DB2FB727744E91A0EFF3E8FAC917D9"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recognizing the peer support specialist profession</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2026, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall revise the Standard Occupational Classification system to include an occupational category for peer support specialists.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="HE7B92C468EE448D5AE6D5C95DF56D09A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishing the Office of Recovery</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part A of title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290aa">42 U.S.C. 290aa et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 501C (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290aa-0b">42 U.S.C. 290aa–0b</external-xref>) the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEDE40E918B98472683AFD864A6537C9B">
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H1541D482F67449FB8E41F03F45F7C2B0"><enum>501D.</enum><header>Office of Recovery</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H856EABD1FADC406183930D6805FC3C24"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>There is established, in the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, an Office of Recovery (referred to in this section as the <quote>Office</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H114D98B682CF45F6B29854D9E7505366"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The Office shall be headed by a Director who has demonstrated experience in, and lived experience with, mental health or substance use disorder recovery.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H6BBAB9F88D994AE18C0B2448A1BCD14F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>Through the Office of Recovery, the responsibilities of the Director shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H92CCE6F4214A4699AF1BA009253BAFF7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>providing leadership in the identification of new and emerging issues related to recovery support services;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2E0C63B93666422D9A7FCFC39F8D7D9F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supporting technical assistance, data analysis, and evaluation functions in order to assist States, localities, territories, Indian Tribes, and Tribal organizations in developing recovery support services and identifying best practices with the objective of expanding the capacity of, and access to, recovery support services;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H96015DB85B024EC2B38A993F66ED92F6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>providing support for the training, education, integration, and professionalization of the peer support specialist workforce;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA23CCFE3A35F4C508B30EB23BB5D7F36"><enum>(4)</enum><text>disseminating best practice recommendations with respect to peer support specialist training, certification, supervision, and practice to States and other entities that employ peer support specialists;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H47B77C2B02A445F89F5D796E6A78543C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supporting peer support specialists with ongoing professional development and retention activities; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H32ED770AF9354C83B1C1916BD2BF1DEE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>developing recommendations on creating career pathways for peer support specialists.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE223E61B9781438F8B70CDA17CDAA725"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Functions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date of enactment of this section, the functions of the Office shall include the responsibilities described in subsection (c) and the functions of the Office of Recovery of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration on the day before such date of enactment, including all of its personnel, assets, authorities, obligations, and liabilities, except as otherwise specified in this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H811922E5661C4D37A1F84D639DC0E526"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition of peer support specialist</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>peer support specialist</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2 of the <short-title>Providing Empathetic and Effective Recovery Support Act</short-title></text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H15C5A755545D428E9F4B62FBA4C34FC0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Research and recommendations on criminal background check process for peer support specialists</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5ABCFBD51714439A3886F76D9DB74A4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), in coordination with the Attorney General, shall develop a report on research and recommendations with respect to criminal background check processes for individuals becoming peer support specialists. </text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E9E488142914190933EBC20728DFEA2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H637B14A1375D490881ACD2080A0888F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of evidence-informed literature on the effectiveness of peer support specialists in improving the mental health and the substance use disorder recovery of other individuals;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H07289C99328042CB9CBF0A9039EF6362"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a survey of each State's laws (including regulations) that contain criminal background check requirements for serving as a peer support specialist, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HBA6BD69C480849EA8E3752530501C7BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an analysis of criminal offenses that are included in State laws (including regulations) that prevent individuals from earning a peer support specialist certification or from practicing as a peer support specialist;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BC68B630C0442309E0C5E80010F9C08"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an analysis of requirements (if any) under the State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) or under a waiver of such plan relating to background checks for providers participating under such plan or waiver and the extent to which any such requirements differ from similar requirements imposed under State law (including regulations); </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7EE79C11BA9B46C9A5873C1538C255A3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of requirements (if any) of any State receiving a grant under part B of title XIX of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x">42 U.S.C. 300x et seq.</external-xref>) relating to background checks for providers participating in a program under, or otherwise providing services supported by, such grant;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2FA1A40AD8DE4B5F89128BAC66CC599B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a review of State laws (including regulations) that provide exemptions from prohibitions regarding certification or practice of peer support specialists; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B81A2324FD249FAA63A30BE504E7A3F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an indication of each State that has gone through the process of amending or otherwise changing criminal background check laws (including regulations) for the certification and practice of peer support specialists; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3D10ED3C97DE489B91668BCEEA87F38D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations to States on criminal background check processes that would reduce barriers to becoming certified as peer support specialists. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H50CCCDB0579A4960AE1CBAF7BA860BCA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H867D00029A324D4D85B6A118862AD420"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">post the report required under subsection (a) on the publicly accessible internet website of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA71AB37864E4B839305F80B00840591"><enum>(2)</enum><text>distribute such report to—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HABD3C2627B27471782D5E57B3D99DD1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State agencies responsible for certification of peer support specialists;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF358D5DFDA1F4331A45CE18BF3A32A21"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services; </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H677CDE5D828D4600B03CEB167C040D1D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State agencies responsible for carrying out a State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act or under a waiver of such plan; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8B7A7559C39346438D4F017AEBD8156A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>State agencies responsible for carrying out a grant under part B of title XIX of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x">42 U.S.C. 300x et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

