<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3DB9249D6ED445D78F53E0430D58EC79" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 217 IH: Recognizing Girl Scouts of the United States of America on its 113th birthday and celebrating its founder Juliette Gordon Low and the legacy of providing girls with a secure and inclusive space where they can explore their world, build meaningful relationships, and have access to experiences that prepare them for a life of leadership.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 217</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250311">March 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing Girl Scouts of the United States of America on its 113th birthday and celebrating its founder Juliette Gordon Low and the legacy of providing girls with a secure and inclusive space where they can explore their world, build meaningful relationships, and have access to experiences that prepare them for a life of leadership.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas March 12, 2025, marks the 113th anniversary of Girl Scouts of the United States of America, whose mission is to <quote>build girls of courage, confidence, and character, who make the world a better place</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Girl Scouts offers girls 21st century programming in science, technology, engineering, and math (STEM), the outdoors, entrepreneurship, and beyond, helping girls develop invaluable life skills through the Girl Scout Leadership Experience;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, today, more than 50,000,000 women—trailblazers, visionaries, and leaders—are Girl Scout alums who embody the Girl Scout mission every day;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Girl Scout movement began on March 12, 1912, when Juliette <quote>Daisy</quote> Gordon Low, a native of Savannah, Georgia, organized a group of 18 girls and provided them with the opportunity to develop physically, intellectually, socially, and spiritually;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas public service and civic engagement were a cornerstone of Juliette Gordon Low’s life and remain an important part of today’s Girl Scout experience, with programming designed to encourage girls to seek opportunities to learn about Federal, State, and local government, research and engage with their elected officials, and inspire girls to become civically minded individuals equipped with the tools to make a positive change in the world;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Girl Scouts’ commitment to getting girls outdoors, including exciting summer camp experiences, comes from Juliette Gordon Low’s lifelong appreciation for nature and the environment;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Juliette Gordon Low utilized her extensive network of friends across the country and around the world to establish the foundation for the Girl Scout movement, creating opportunities for girls to form lifelong friendships with fellow Girl Scouts;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Juliette Gordon Low believed in the power of global connections and the ability of Girl Guides and Girl Scouts to positively impact their communities and the world, serving as the movement’s worldwide ambassador and first Girl Scout Global Citizen;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on March 25, 2025, the Juliette Gordon Low Commemorative Quarter will be released into circulation by the United States Mint, celebrating the enduring legacy of the Girl Scout founder and the Girl Scout movement; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Juliette Gordon Low’s journey from trailblazing leader to a face on our Nation’s currency is a testament to the power of girls and women everywhere: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HDCD3C3ABCBEB400E9D9602B30A942C57"> 
<section id="HCF7A68469C6E46D3A40E00BACE25A01D" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H4ED4E62309604B938632C3345EBD05A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes Girl Scouts of the United States of America for 113 years of building girls of courage, confidence, and character, who make the world a better place;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEEB12A77C58040129AE6F760EED79082"><enum>(2)</enum><text>congratulates all Girl Scouts who earned the Gold Award in 2024;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE97ABDF753E24A518C907A9F7129F03C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commemorates the trailblazing founder of Girl Scouts of the United States of America, Juliette Gordon Low, for making her mark on American currency; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA337F299720B480EAAC044A2EAD693CE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages Girl Scouts of the United States of America to continue to champion the ambitions, nurture the creativity, and support the talents of future women leaders.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

