<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG25524-JR5-RV-X81"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1263 IS: Operational Security Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1263</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250402">April 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish the Office of Security Training and Counterintelligence in the Executive Office of the President, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Operational Security Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id1f6171e46deb4681ac2294f8462919f3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Office of Security Training and Counterintelligence of Executive Office of the President</header><subsection id="id5183e93d188b48a3abd43a9a99843abc"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Office of Security Training and Counterintelligence</header><text>There is in the Executive Office of the President an Office of Security Training and Counterintelligence (in this section referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id00ae361b6349416e8061eb6579c7b6cb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Director</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb60cec2c6631408b89ff3d666b80f45b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be at the head of the Office a Director of the Office of Security Training and Counterintelligence (in this section referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>) who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id13ab1a11163d4ed68f746641ae941454"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall make an initial appointment of the Director not later than the date that is 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9e9b24ac2f5144239f850ac5549ba0db"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualifications of the Director</header><text>The Director shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd8a6d8e68b64ffe834d7c585acaff56"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be a recognized security expert, including expertise in cybersecurity, physical security, or counterintelligence; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id769c70ad4620498fb11f5b0204ff5f85"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be eligible to access classified information at the level of <quote>Top Secret</quote> and be eligible to access sensitive compartmented information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id69405a96650d41c4afd5d2f4ac2a85ad"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Detailees</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76bc865f6de34a24b925afcd2c54ff1b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (3), the Office shall be staffed by career security and counterintelligence professionals detailed from Federal agencies.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idda2ce02c456e4664ad4bd4eef572259d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>From Office of Director of National Intelligence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (3), the Director of National Intelligence may detail to the Office any of the personnel of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence to assist in carrying out the functions of the Office under subsection (e).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b5fe3e860de4e10b81cd73803b53523"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clearance</header><text>Any personnel detailed to the Office under this subsection shall possess a security clearance in accordance with applicable laws and regulations concerning the handling of classified information.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4cf1a5c2425a41ef8ddacc56f5762d8e"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The primary functions of the Office are to provide, within the Executive Office of the President, advice on the following:</text><paragraph id="idd9c856a9e8d245ce9abeb4b66d1fb7c7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Security training</header><text>Training, education, and research activities to equip and prepare personnel of the Executive Office of the President through the development and management of on-line and in-person courses, curricula, conferences, and other products.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb47b0d693a00485aa4d4f0c250b7c1ac"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Counterintelligence and insider threat</header><text>Activities to identify, assess, deter, and mitigate foreign and insider threats to the Executive Office of the President, both directly and through collaborative engagement with other intelligence and law enforcement organizations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide0e0957e41f44eb7bfc3a5eb748e93ee"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Protection of classified information</header><text>Protection and preservation of classified information and other sensitive information, including with regard to the use by personnel of the Executive Office of the President of unclassified commercially available messaging applications, as well as preservation of such information through collaborative engagement with the National Archives and Records Administration.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5450686fa2c4476e888c804def761fe1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Advisory Board</header><paragraph id="idbbb364bd9aff4f14ae06a68998f4c7ac"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8f918f1a85fe4af19883810b0fc34bc8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby established an advisory board to advise the President, the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs, the Director of the Office, and such other personnel of the Executive Office of the President as the Board considers appropriate on best practices in security training, counterintelligence and insider threats, and protection of classified information.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id50fa358e429347338017c827d6c5c3ab"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The advisory board established by subparagraph (A) shall be known as the <quote>Security Training and Counterintelligence Advisory Board</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Board</quote>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id412fb791c7e64fef867a294903a5e6be"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idefb6ed26c0ef4458b96438f93718e956"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Composition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraph (B), the Board shall be composed of 4 members, appointed as follows:</text><clause id="idcff53ec0d2eb45b3ac076f70fc4bc1cc" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>One member appointed by the Democratic leader of the Senate.</text></clause><clause id="id4cfd442f08374cd2929f3d624bf9af5a" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>One member appointed by the Republican leader of the Senate.</text></clause><clause id="idc6a9e987c17447e7a47267732a63c175" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>One member appointed by the Democratic leader of the House of Representatives.</text></clause><clause id="id684dc6518ccc4ff5a7cd762bec8e3daf" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>One member appointed by the Republican leader of the House of Representatives.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4702ef27d87349c784750d111be4184e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The members appointed under subparagraph (A) shall meet the following criteria:</text><clause id="idfd94c2f1a8964aea91cc1375d8e0011b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Each member shall be a recognized expert in security, including expertise in cybersecurity, physical security, or counterintelligence.</text></clause><clause id="id88e92276b39547d0aee880b3738279d1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Each member shall be eligible to access classified information at the level of <quote>Top Secret</quote> and be eligible to access sensitive compartmented information.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7671f780da1741c2877f9b5d9ed22ace"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Terms</header><clause id="ideb459d70e4f94c1d8f27bc468c305d82"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each member appointed to the Board, including the Chairperson selected under paragraph (3), shall be appointed or elected, as applicable, for a 2-year term and members of the Board may be reappointed for additional terms of service as members of the Board. Members may continue to serve until they are either reappointed or replaced.</text></clause><clause id="id6e3b74f4988446b9912767be9ba15eba" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>The Board shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees (as defined in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>)), in writing, an annual report which shall set forth the recommendations of the Board for improving security training, counterintelligence and insider threat awareness, and the protection of classified information and other sensitive information used by personnel of the Executive Office of the President.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide4af163b42634a32a37991453b134929"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><subparagraph id="id158f21db1937475985469aa946cccd3a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the first meeting of the Board, the members of the Board shall elect a Chairperson of the Board.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide28d9d3a366642ec967e89648fd928ea"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>In addition to meeting the criteria under paragraph (2)(B), the Chairperson may not be an employee, or former employee, of the Executive Office of the President.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

