<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7128EDAFBE604B15A6E12CD2B3D055B0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>110 HR 1144 IH: Frederick Douglass Trafficking Victims Prevention and Protection Reauthorization Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1144</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250207">February 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reauthorize the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H17476DB3EA1D4C8BA3CA61311A4C5241" style="OLC"><section id="H12841CDAD8954E97877B70A4B15D9E4F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Frederick Douglass Trafficking Victims Prevention and Protection Reauthorization Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HECD16C3FDB2B4E2D89A857EE92C368B4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H12841CDAD8954E97877B70A4B15D9E4F" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HECD16C3FDB2B4E2D89A857EE92C368B4" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H07093CC388D44607A283926A3B05BD62" level="title">Title I—Combating Trafficking in Persons in the United States</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6EBF7978C71147EAA628D4FFCF74D1AB" level="section">Sec. 101. Modifications to grants to assist in the recognition of trafficking.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H82D18F30A2D04EC580C98511B513B33C" level="section">Sec. 102. Human Trafficking Survivors Employment and Education Program.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HCDEB24E320E84C3D808AFE101774884A" level="title">Title II—Fighting Human Trafficking Abroad</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H035D7C8DB5F343FDB321AF9C1FAEFB87" level="section">Sec. 201. Modifications to program to end modern slavery grants.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H54656987C78B4E29A1D58CC9A838D9EA" level="section">Sec. 202. Amendments to tier standards.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H00B72B54CA6C43339B4DF9A032FA54BE" level="section">Sec. 203. Counter-trafficking in persons efforts in development cooperation and assistance policy.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H1DE4EC235FF54FECB0AA7CCD87913B77" level="section">Sec. 204. Clarification of nonhumanitarian, nontrade-related foreign assistance.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H309C3C08373942D8AAA41777AEC07BB4" level="section">Sec. 205. Trafficking for the purposes of organ harvesting.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H802A900650D34D90964BF44383E37653" level="section">Sec. 206. Elimination of duplicative reporting.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H90AA5704B3334EF99FEB722947C067FD" level="section">Sec. 207. Effective dates.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H8552D26E508C4BD3BB48CAB190DB52B9" level="section">Sec. 208. Printed version of the annual tip report.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H199B338DF5904A1D858C2794C5897694" level="title">Title III—Authorization of Appropriations</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9BFC59CDC43647B39DCD69C41B03A266" level="section">Sec. 301. Extension of authorizations under the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H46E214434ACB48D7B3224B9101506DFF" level="section">Sec. 302. Extension of authorizations under the International Megan’s Law.</toc-entry></toc></section><title id="H07093CC388D44607A283926A3B05BD62"><enum>I</enum><header>Combating Trafficking in Persons in the United States</header><section id="H6EBF7978C71147EAA628D4FFCF74D1AB"><enum>101.</enum><header>Modifications to grants to assist in the recognition of trafficking</header><subsection id="HF9888D37AB2F4AA2A8AABCC6D025BF8A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments to authorities to prevent trafficking</header><text>Section 106(b)(2) of the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7104">22 U.S.C. 7104(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H876976F049B14D44BACC9FD207DD523A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Grants to assist in the recognition of trafficking</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Frederick Douglass Human Trafficking Prevention Education Grants</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7173D99E0B12411DBE8C9552438B0DD5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><subparagraph id="HCC5902999F9944CB8F4DD3B3C8D814A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting <quote>under a program named <quote>Frederick Douglass Human Trafficking Prevention Education Grants</quote></quote> after <quote>may award grants</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63181419D60749B597496CD4F8319C96"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by inserting <quote>, linguistically accessible, and culturally responsive</quote> after <quote>age-appropriate</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0935F98010994881907BEA20F0F25839"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the heading of subparagraph (C), by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">for frederick douglass human trafficking prevention education grants</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">program requirements</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4015FFE2ADE44BED884149F5073BF8A4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (D) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H81F70CE6530144D8A3C0D5F96351E0E3" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HE7DBA97E42DF4C2AAEE90D48EC695B6A"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding Frederick Douglass Human Trafficking Prevention Education Grants under this paragraph, the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="H5AD5EE300D9A4CD3969C4B863A75472C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>give priority to local educational agencies serving a high-intensity child sex trafficking area or an area with significant child labor trafficking;</text></clause><clause id="H6C71C967CE6E4D10B3AFDEC66CAEF858"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>give additional priority to local educational agencies that partner with non-profit organizations specializing in human trafficking prevention education, which partner with law enforcement and technology or social media companies, to assist in training efforts to protect children from labor trafficking and sexual exploitation and abuse including grooming, materials depicting the sexual abuse of children, and human trafficking transmitted through technology; and</text></clause><clause id="H1745313F69A040DAB47475467C18A78C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>consult, as appropriate, with the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Labor, and the Attorney General, to identify the geographic areas in the United States with the highest prevalence of at-risk populations for child trafficking, including children who are members of a racial or ethnic minority, homeless youth, foster youth, youth involved in the child welfare system, and children and youth who run away from home or an out-of-home placement.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H14CE2750A83946319FCFD8B4EB33EE30"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H16781C7CC0F84A54AE3646907ADDC9B2" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H6C0953380BB14D058213DCDC751C5C8C"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Criteria for selection</header><text>Grantees should be selected based on their demonstrated ability to—</text><clause id="H9EEB479BE76942F397F9B6F64588558A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>engage stakeholders, including survivors of human trafficking, and Federal, State, local, or Tribal partners, to develop the programs;</text></clause><clause id="H5D7D95E6866C4684B072ADD6EB91D34B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>train the trainers, guardians, K–12 students, teachers, and other school personnel in a linguistically accessible, culturally responsive, age-appropriate, and trauma-informed fashion; and</text></clause><clause id="H89AEBBA9026A43B0AA036AE768AF56B0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>create a scalable, repeatable program to prevent child labor trafficking and sexual exploitation and abuse including grooming, child sexual abuse materials, and trafficking transmitted through technology that—</text><subclause id="H7370754BF8E141A2BB59DCD766ABBD7B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>uses evidence-based (as such term is defined in section 8101(21)(A) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801(21)(A)</external-xref>)) best practices; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H8F20402562D44ADFA4609C567C652288"><enum>(II)</enum><text>employs appropriate technological tools and methodologies, including linguistically accessible, culturally responsive, age-appropriate, and trauma-informed approaches for trainers, guardians, educators, and K–12 students.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B0119045B3B4B79A97EC2CA9C35AF2D"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Train the trainers</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (E), the term <term>train the trainers</term> means having experienced or master trainers coach new trainers who are less experienced with a particular topic or skill, or with training overall, who can then teach the material to others, creating a broader reach, sustainability, and making efforts cost- and time-efficient (commonly referred to as <quote>training of trainers</quote>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92DB2869EFE5464A8C0BE2ABA437845E"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Data collection</header><text>The Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, and the Secretary of the Interior to determine the appropriate demographics of the recipients or of students at risk of being trafficked or exploited, to be collected and reported with respect to grants under this paragraph, which shall include data collection of, at a minimum, students who are economically disadvantaged, members of a racial or ethnic minority, homeless youth, foster youth, youth involved in the child welfare system, and children and youth who run away from home or an out-of-home placement.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59DFE29C14A241B592FAD5E8B1A2E0AD"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 540 days after the date of the enactment of this subparagraph, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to the Committees on Education and Labor, Energy and Commerce, and the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committees on the Judiciary and Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and make available to the public a report, including data on the following:</text><clause id="H8DDCB6E2E59E4FF8B6A607FB790A2C36"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The total number of entities that received a Frederick Douglass Human Trafficking Prevention Education Grant over the past year.</text></clause><clause id="HD8DF6D5C6234410D9C4FE12D6FD4CAC3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The total number of partnerships or consultants that included survivors, non-profit organizations specialized in human trafficking prevention education, law enforcement, and technology or social media companies.</text></clause><clause id="H69F7D6F3ACCF4FE2ADCDFDD81435E69C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The total number of elementary and secondary schools that established and implemented evidence-based (as such term is defined in section 8101(21)(A) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801(21)(A)</external-xref>)) best practices through programs developed using such grants.</text></clause><clause id="H7C6E3F919781458687B2CA39A591DE2D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The total number and geographic distribution of trainers, guardians, students, teachers, and other school personnel trained using such grants pursuant to this paragraph.</text></clause><clause id="HB74E62A253C148D1BE13542A67BA07A8"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The results of pre-training and post-training surveys to gauge trainees’ increased understanding of the scope and signs of child trafficking and child sexual exploitation and abuse; how to interact with potential victims and survivors of child trafficking and child sexual exploitation and abuse using age-appropriate and trauma-informed approach; and the manner in which to respond to potential child trafficking and child sexual exploitation and abuse.</text></clause><clause id="H95778DDE428F46B3AA5721341AA25713"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The number of potential victims and survivors of child trafficking and child sexual exploitation and abuse identified and served by grantees, excluding any individually identifiable information about such children and acting in full compliance with all applicable privacy laws and regulations.</text></clause><clause id="H18FB7BE285C64405AA6AED6FD2D3460D"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The number of students in elementary or secondary school identified by grantees as being at risk of being trafficked or sexually exploited and abused, excluding any individually identifiable information about such children.</text></clause><clause id="H73D6F3370F8940718EF053DA04B8873B"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The demographic characteristics of child trafficking survivors and victims, sexually exploited and abused children, and students at risk of being trafficked or sexually exploited and abused described in clauses (vi) and (vii), excluding any individually identifiable information about such children.</text></clause><clause id="HFA1752810FA34457A0E47F5BF346AED2"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Any service gaps and best practices identified by grantees.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H82D18F30A2D04EC580C98511B513B33C"><enum>102.</enum><header>Human Trafficking Survivors Employment and Education Program</header><subsection id="H32FE94E3F0184929A0F15C7918F27B77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services may carry out a Frederick Douglass Human Trafficking Survivors Employment and Education Program to prevent the re-exploitation of eligible individuals who have been victims of trafficking, by assisting such individuals to integrate or reintegrate into society through social services support for the attainment of life-skills, employment, and education necessary to achieve self-sufficiency.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAB5DBA0EA0C04A6A8959D213B046C573"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Services provided</header><text>Services offered, provided, and funded by the Program shall include (as relevant to the victim of trafficking)—</text><paragraph id="H46AA873CE7AF42B0969EF9DD2A729C5D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enrollment and participation in—</text><subparagraph id="H96804DDA06394938BCF99B230C7F016B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>basic education, including literacy education and English as a second language education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA29511B950C474CBD87F6C4904F0FC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>job-related skills training;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB277D1999DC94DFB97CCFD6637C7F773"><enum>(C)</enum><text>vocational and certificate programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D0D97499AB04E6CAEE864EA315C05BC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>programs for attaining a regular high school diploma or its recognized equivalent;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0236CD0362545DA9888F58375D6578E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>life-skill training programs, including management of personal finances, self-care, and parenting classes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CBE919B051446C9A091CC79A6E0370B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>résumé creation and review;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H921B3C273C0447D5889006CE9E7FB9ED"><enum>(4)</enum><text>interview coaching and counseling;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA887203776840E4ABD04B885F9F9AA2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>assistance with expungement of criminal records when such records are for nonviolent crimes that were committed as a consequence of the eligible individual’s victimization, including assistance with credit repair;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B4F1795563D49198F9AEF5C45004496"><enum>(6)</enum><text>assistance with enrollment in college or technical school;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF203AAB9A6564A3ABC04A26C16D3FA2D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>scholarship assistance for attending college or technical school;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69412E7BB1C4432BAFDC4908B262575C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>professional coaching or professional development classes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86CB31FE47EE400C8C530D932FBA47BF"><enum>(9)</enum><text>case management to develop an individualized plan with each victim of trafficking, based on each person’s needs and goals; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DF191F36AAA47D4A5208A5E0F3FB43D"><enum>(10)</enum><text>assistance with obtaining victim compensation, direct victim assistance, or other funds for mental health care.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H84CE324E716E4233A7E59425209F0177"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Service period</header><text>Eligible individuals may receive services through the Program for a cumulative period of 5 years.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2A0937F1FCAB4494AF1D72DCC74A6FBF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary shall enter into cooperative agreements with one or more eligible organizations to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF3401BC9334643659C2BE412DCC9A8B1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HDA436C809FE04BDDA182A19352F55EBD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible individual</header><text>The term <term>eligible individual</term> means a domestic or foreign victim of trafficking who—</text><subparagraph id="H0F1C51924A4A4B1CA8B0443E849021F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has attained the age of 18 years; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8131AF55BCFD4CEDBA30E530971BC611"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is eligible to receive services under section 107(b) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7105">22 U.S.C. 7105(b)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD118DEBB24FE4D7E944DD3E1341B7035"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible organization</header><text>The <quote>eligible organization</quote> may include a nongovernmental organization and means a service provider that meets the following criteria:</text><subparagraph id="H2C9C39032CBE4EE5954B89277D6077FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Experience in using national or local anti-trafficking networks to serve victims of trafficking.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC01B182BA5634FD9A1F6AD74E7366C23"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Experience qualifying, providing, and coordinating services for victims of trafficking, as described in subsection (b), that is linguistically accessible, culturally responsive, age-appropriate, and trauma-informed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H269A137312E546C99D0B9E7705695734"><enum>(C)</enum><text>With respect to a service provider for victims of trafficking served by the Program who are not United States citizens, a provider that has experience in identifying and assisting foreign-born victims of trafficking, including helping them qualify for Continued Presence, T–Visas, and other Federal, State, and local services and funding.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H222922F0775C44FFA99AD0CE47957FFE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>With respect to a service provider for victims of trafficking served by the Program who are United States citizens and legal permanent residents, a provider that has experience identifying and assisting victims of trafficking, as such term is defined in section 103 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102</external-xref>), especially youth and underserved populations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H448A0AFE10E94C2384CA0C5C86D58514"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>Program</term> means the Frederick Douglass Human Trafficking Survivors Employment and Education Program established under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H575B2332EBCD4B87A68DB64606151C00"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="HCDEB24E320E84C3D808AFE101774884A"><enum>II</enum><header>Fighting Human Trafficking Abroad</header><section id="H035D7C8DB5F343FDB321AF9C1FAEFB87"><enum>201.</enum><header>Modifications to program to end modern slavery grants</header><subsection id="H708CB847FBC9489D98B4A44AFEE911AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1298 of the National Defense Authorization Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7114">22 U.S.C. 7114</external-xref>) is amended as follows:</text><paragraph id="HFCADACA399D94064ADF3A9F373F92CCF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In subsection (g)(2), by striking <quote>2020</quote> and inserting <quote>2029</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BE555C506C942BBBA3F79E6DA5294F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In subsection (h)(1), by striking <quote>Not later than September 30, 2018, and September 30, 2020</quote> and inserting <quote>Not later than September 30, 2025, and September 30, 2029</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H120C018FD7884B15943132D65FEE2DE6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Award of funds</header><text>All grants awarded under the authority provided by section 1298 of the National Defense Authorization Act of 2017, as amended by subsection (a), shall be—</text><paragraph id="H84A36C62BB6D43E981A724E5FBB67C47"><enum>(1)</enum><text>awarded on a competitive basis; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DD9F631E7294027A095BF94CD2BC8BF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to the regular congressional notification procedures applicable with respect to grants made available under section 1298(b) of the National Defense Authorization Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7114">22 U.S.C. 7114(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H54656987C78B4E29A1D58CC9A838D9EA"><enum>202.</enum><header>Amendments to tier standards</header><subsection id="HE1D250FADC434FE492B76F556A54A60B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Modifications to tier 2 watch list</header><text>Subsection (b)(2) of section 110 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7107">22 U.S.C. 7107</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HBAAEDE94D10046049B1015DA1522A752"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">special</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">tier 2</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2314F76658DF4470A9E499660528F3EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H083D2CFD84AC4D9DBAE5EBD1340EBE67" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HEAD65A3A01044A5B902C1197137463A6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Submission of list</header><text>Not later than the date on which the determinations described in subsections (c) and (d) are submitted to the appropriate congressional committees in accordance with such subsections, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a list of countries that the Secretary determines require special scrutiny during the following year. The list shall be composed of countries that have been listed pursuant to paragraph (1)(B) pursuant to the current annual report because—</text><clause id="H9E4035BD1D264FB2B9730E76750BE3C9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the estimated number of victims of severe forms of trafficking is very significant or is significantly increasing and the country is not taking proportional concrete actions; or</text></clause><clause id="HB675D771E8BB45BABF4E418D552BB30D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>there is a failure to provide evidence of increasing efforts to combat severe forms of trafficking in persons from the previous year, including increased investigations, prosecutions and convictions of trafficking crimes, increased assistance to victims, and decreasing evidence of complicity in severe forms of trafficking by government officials.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H26EBAD784D9D47F68371369ED26089B5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Modification to special rule for downgraded and reinstated countries</header><text>Subsection (b)(2)(F) of such section 110 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7107">22 U.S.C. 7107</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H81CDD5E4EDF34AA099379EBDB4F14260"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>the special watch list</quote> and all that follows through <quote>the country—</quote> and inserting <quote>the Tier 2 watch list described in subparagraph (A) for more than 2 years immediately after the country consecutively—</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H918A88F719D9476CAF5C7CA0BA23A680"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (i), in the matter preceding subclause (I), by striking <quote>the special watch list described in subparagraph (A)(iii)</quote> and inserting <quote>the Tier 2 watch list described in subparagraph (A)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF87CD7B1E844055A17506F456DC51A8" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by inserting <quote>in the year following such waiver under subparagraph (D)(ii)</quote> before the period at the end.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE3687E74F641446C8C0A62E65F3A6C1E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments to the trafficking victims protection act of 2000</header><text>Subsection (b) of such section 110 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7107">22 U.S.C. 7107</external-xref>) is amended as follows:</text><paragraph id="HC424B94518BD4580B239AA175EDB5AA5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In paragraph (2), as amended by subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="HDD30D8C62E15444EB5B7DDF3B5FAACF6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>special watch list</quote> and inserting <quote>Tier 2 watch list</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC189F26025E841FB8ADC94F537F04DD4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>special watch list</quote> and inserting <quote>Tier 2 watch list</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DEFBE056FF94AF4927698D1A195911F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)—</text><clause id="H64BD45910EBA47F3829A3464B2183769"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">special watch list</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">tier 2 watch list</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HEA2482CDBE4C43B687EC1CD5F4F7F0AC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>special watch list</quote> and inserting <quote>Tier 2 watch list</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4A02F47D02B440CA3B25AD0463A14A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In paragraph (3)(B), in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>clauses (i), (ii), and (iii) of</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BC1F5874E464D6090648BD61DB86F42"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In paragraph (4)—</text><subparagraph id="H6E59D2DBF1B744ECA2EB9FA90A3B35B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>each country described in paragraph (2)(A)(ii)</quote> and inserting <quote>each country described in paragraph (2)(A)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40F9CCA9680D44BFA6B0BB11199EE36E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)(ii), by striking <quote>the Special Watch List under paragraph (2)</quote> and inserting <quote>the Tier 2 watch list under paragraph (2)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD0A52695C6B948D7BDDD1E82906025CC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendment to the frederick douglass trafficking victims prevention and protection reauthorization act of 2018</header><text>Section 204(b)(1) of the Frederick Douglass Trafficking Victims Prevention and Protection Reauthorization Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/425">Public Law 115–425</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>special watch list</quote> and inserting <quote>Tier 2 watch list</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8E50D50DBA144822A2F62484213F94C4" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conforming amendment to the bipartisan congressional trade priorities and accountability act of 2015</header><text>Section 106(b)(6)(E)(iii) of the Bipartisan Congressional Trade Priorities and Accountability Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/26">Public Law 114–26</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4205">19 U.S.C. 4205(b)(6)(E)(iii)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>under section</quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote>under section 110(b)(2)(A) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7107">22 U.S.C. 7107(b)(2)(A)</external-xref>)</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="H00B72B54CA6C43339B4DF9A032FA54BE"><enum>203.</enum><header>Counter-trafficking in persons efforts in development cooperation and assistance policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HDD60813D675E4C2EB0CE6A717A7370EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 102(b)(4) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151-1">22 U.S.C. 2151–1(b)(4)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="HE2B8D9795E8E42E2B511A96D599D619E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H313C9A5AFD7A4CEF967834C321D783BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (G), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E11D09B59DC41DA993CA982E1805F49"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H0A28A1A81D684C9BBD5ADB6102B04AD1" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HB17AC31E073247A09C54ECDB52DF27AA"><enum>(H)</enum><text>effective counter-trafficking in persons policies and programs.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H12400B4B3EAE4228B3F1DD2747D43D7A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 492(d)(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2292a">22 U.S.C. 2292a(d)(1)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="HA8F1067B1FD844A9A7C626FCED8A4C3E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H585A43235BB64F0FB922F9882C1CAA93"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>that the funds</quote> and inserting the following:—</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8F270F33E3204086A2A975D9B0C107AE" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text>that—</text><subparagraph id="H15FEA482418C44CF96995F5BD8ACAB3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the funds</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5339037333854B29B19A960A708820C7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H972ED99263234FE98446B191B52E4C6C" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HE4CC30FDAEDC497FBA9D15674EB93925"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in carrying out the provisions of this chapter, the President shall, to the greatest extent possible—</text><clause id="HC53725E4FBD443578DADD48E8EA8B7FA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ensure that assistance made available under this section does not create or contribute to conditions that can be reasonably expected to result in an increase in trafficking in persons who are in conditions of heightened vulnerability as a result of natural and manmade disasters; and</text></clause><clause id="H2CEC140782294A1298B803B75152F993"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>incorporate appropriate protections into the planning and execution of activities authorized under this chapter.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H1DE4EC235FF54FECB0AA7CCD87913B77"><enum>204.</enum><header>Clarification of nonhumanitarian, nontrade-related foreign assistance</header><subsection id="H5F0E243F798D4BE5A2F25C4E64E20E4A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Clarification of scope of withheld assistance</header><text>Section 110(d)(1)(A) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7107">22 U.S.C. 7107(d)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="HB8C6996BD51B468FB79CFA83F5D4F2C2" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H165C3ED5033541A7B997F3227C002AA5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the United States will not provide nonhumanitarian, nontrade-related foreign assistance to the central government of the country, or any funding to facilitate the participation by officials or employees of such central government in educational and cultural exchange programs, before the end of the first fiscal year beginning after such government complies with the minimum standards or makes significant efforts to bring itself into compliance; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H8CB997B797C843A3A354996427F353A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of nonhumanitarian, nontrade-Related assistance</header><text>Section 103(10) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102(10)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="HB651F28DC483429DA0E75612CB7D9A6A" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H1131C22575B740B0A1B3B4F83DD42715"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Nonhumanitarian, nontrade-related foreign assistance</header><subparagraph id="HDFD34BC57592459597DC4E00F0F3DF2C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>nonhumanitarian, nontrade-related foreign assistance</term> means—</text><clause id="H8C61FB7B9FD646EE8AC3B5C0A3BF211A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>United States foreign assistance, other than—</text><subclause id="HEB0EABC168104F2FBF8D02889CA28F92"><enum>(I)</enum><text>with respect to the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961—</text><item id="HC26324FA4AA54CC6937F32702A9C3D17"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>assistance for international narcotics and law enforcement under chapter 8 of part I of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2291">22 U.S.C. 2291 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></item><item id="HED65E8E954EA4E3E9B791FE6CFA2226E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>assistance for International Disaster Assistance under subsections (b) and (c) of section 491 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2292">22 U.S.C. 2292</external-xref>);</text></item><item id="HA9632A05865743B79A6FAC7765651481"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>antiterrorism assistance under chapter 8 of part II of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2349aa">22 U.S.C. 2349aa et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></item><item id="H17B7DBF1A74E41EFB9B0B52254BB4F22"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>health programs under chapters 1 and 10 of part I and chapter 4 of part II of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H6A3169B26AB4481984BC50653129268F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>assistance under the Food for Peace Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1691">7 U.S.C. 1691 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subclause><subclause id="HD62456CB47CA44F48E861EF0A03A0897"><enum>(III)</enum><text>assistance under subsections (a), (b), and (c) of section 2 of the Migration and Refugee Assistance Act of 1962 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2601">22 U.S.C. 2601(a)</external-xref>–(c)) to meet refugee and migration needs;</text></subclause><subclause id="H39D5147B8F4149758A1D9A2DAA2C15E8"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>any form of United States foreign assistance provided through nongovernmental organizations, international organizations, or private sector partners—</text><item id="H389978AC2DAC4A3E97A4E4468D32345F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to combat human and wildlife trafficking;</text></item><item id="HCE558DCDF9D7419EB399FE7B382EB9AA"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to promote food security;</text></item><item id="H85EF1282EC7349DD8B39FF2033F65CBC"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>to respond to emergencies;</text></item><item id="H5C2857062B4E40228FACD2FEC6696AE3"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>to provide humanitarian assistance;</text></item><item id="H64F98A5D51DD4EA8B594E3796A6699B7"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>to address basic human needs, including for education;</text></item><item id="HA21CF1C7BAA6453489257A591A531D51"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>to advance global health security; or</text></item><item id="H0CAB93C3683C40C88A9D7F0E7D125158"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>to promote trade; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H82909E1EA6EE49B883BCE1284CF5133C"><enum>(V)</enum><text>any other form of United States foreign assistance that the President determines, by not later than October 1 of each fiscal year, is necessary to advance the security, economic, humanitarian, or global health interests of the United States without compromising the steadfast United States commitment to combatting human trafficking globally; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HA8BF1CCA39904431863B8907E1C31556"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>sales, or financing on any terms, under the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2751">22 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.</external-xref>), other than sales or financing provided for narcotics-related purposes following notification in accordance with the prior notification procedures applicable to reprogrammings pursuant to section 634A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2394-1">22 U.S.C. 2394–1</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H183523B9559F41F69EBA298E76B6E39F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <term>nonhumanitarian, nontrade-related foreign assistance</term> shall not include payments to, or the participation of, government entities necessary or incidental to the implementation of a program that is otherwise consistent with section 110 of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H309C3C08373942D8AAA41777AEC07BB4"><enum>205.</enum><header>Trafficking for the purposes of organ harvesting</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 110(b)(1) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7107">22 U.S.C. 7107(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H3576ABBFC09543D283217DAB51D532B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (G), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36206D3DF07044A8990E21F492DA87BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88F3D2F01A054237878D3B6FCF8186BA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (H) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H65B027402BA14015BCAF1BF85CDBCED9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HAF48D37D85E842F598D1579AC5DFBC62"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information about the trafficking in persons for the purpose of organ removal, including cases and steps governments are undertaking to prevent, identify, and eliminate such trafficking.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H802A900650D34D90964BF44383E37653" commented="no"><enum>206.</enum><header>Elimination of duplicative reporting</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 106(b)(6) of the Bipartisan Congressional Trade Priorities and Accountability Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/26">Public Law 114–26</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4205">19 U.S.C. 4205(b)(6)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H9648FB0B8330443D854520B3F643D321"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (C); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBA0CB00E59D4C7CB22ADA8893D251F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (D) and (E) as subparagraphs (C) and (D), respectively.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H90AA5704B3334EF99FEB722947C067FD"><enum>207.</enum><header>Effective dates</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Sections 202(b) and 205 and the amendments made by those sections take effect on the date that is the first day of the first full reporting period for the report required by section 110(b)(1) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7107">22 U.S.C. 7107(b)(1)</external-xref>), as so amended, after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section><section id="H8552D26E508C4BD3BB48CAB190DB52B9" commented="no"><enum>208.</enum><header>Printed version of the annual tip report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 107(c) of the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7107">22 U.S.C. 7107</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/457">Public Law 110–457</external-xref>; 122 Stat. 5050) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H3DD8491D1D9E4FF0AAC7AC4639312A64" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF07DCEA2E5D412B8F0544BD70D0F4F5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EF9EE12FEB94788B7C1D1B1ADAE0436" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H66516671531140C797B5824E4792385D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H1D2DFDCB56AE4430AE60D5E29E351058" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that a printed hardcopy format of the annual report submitted under section 110(b) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7107">22 U.S.C. 7107(b)</external-xref>) is made available to the public.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></title><title id="H199B338DF5904A1D858C2794C5897694"><enum>III</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><section id="H9BFC59CDC43647B39DCD69C41B03A266"><enum>301.</enum><header>Extension of authorizations under the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 113 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7110">22 U.S.C. 7110</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H96D14D7758B0490F999D92D6916AFECF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2021, $13,822,000</quote> and inserting <quote>for each of the fiscal years 2025 through 2029, $23,000,000</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CC6F76F3CC74907ABF4BC7E8C013A36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="H67A8254ACB8C47A481EA751BDEC2C80A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>To carry out the purposes of sections 106(b) and 107(b),</quote> and inserting <quote>To carry out the purposes of sections 106(b) and 107(b) of this Act and sections 101 and 102 of the Frederick Douglass Trafficking Victims Prevention and Protection Reauthorization Act of 2023,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8D9B08FA75140488AACEC2BC1ABFCF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$19,500,000</quote> and all that follows, and inserting <quote>$30,755,000 for each of the fiscal years 2025 through 2029, of which $5,000,000 is authorized to be appropriated in each fiscal year for the National Human Trafficking Hotline and for cybersecurity and public education campaigns, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, for identifying and responding as needed to cases of human trafficking.</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4F71ACC7FD1436595CC94E815CB736C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="H97B6AA2D8DA840B680F3909A9A9B23ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>2018 through 2021, $65,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>2025 through 2029, $111,000,000</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H92D86797F7C34B9A81EB4316C6BDE496"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (c) by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H334BAE7EE0854570B4EAB9E3F7655B5B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HA3465E91E5D24B689AF83F41D77C7145"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Programs to end modern slavery</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amounts authorized by paragraph (1) to be appropriated for a fiscal year, not more than $37,500,000 may be made available to fund programs to end modern slavery.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E810A3A5661435EA086B25392491233"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1), by striking <quote>2018 through 2021</quote> and inserting <quote>2025 through 2029, of which $35,000,000 is authorized to be appropriated for each fiscal year for the Office of Victims of Crime Housing Assistance Grants for Victims of Human Trafficking</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H46E214434ACB48D7B3224B9101506DFF"><enum>302.</enum><header>Extension of authorizations under the International Megan’s Law</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 11 of the International Megan’s Law to Prevent Child Exploitation and Other Sexual Crimes Through Advanced Notification of Traveling Sex Offenders (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/21509">34 U.S.C. 21509</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2018 through 2021</quote> and inserting <quote>2025 through 2029</quote>.</text></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

