<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD1FD7A3DCCA6400DAC0BE48552A456C6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2613 IH: Next Generation Pipelines Research and Development Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2613</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250402">April 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve public-private partnerships and increase Federal research, development, and demonstration related to the evolution of next generation pipeline systems, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7C6DE4A5D3A4455ABB36E0A7D2297BAD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H09B9D1D37FDE4BAA936DD58AC269604F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Next Generation Pipelines Research and Development Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H20E7BE33E9DD4C67BCCE1C371DF57B0D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H4E25E87BE4A9409BA8C09C9B689E1DD5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <quote>Department</quote> means the Department of Energy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE8EF4F16E0304C8AB13EEDEBEE983B3A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1DF16C36AE604C33816406CBDAFC4A45" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an institution of higher education (as such term is defined in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>)), including historically Black colleges and universities (within the meaning of the term <quote>part B institution</quote> in section 322 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1061">20 U.S.C. 1061</external-xref>)), Tribal colleges and universities (as such term is defined in section 316 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c</external-xref>)), and minority serving institutions (including the entities described in any of paragraphs (1) through (7) of section 371(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q(a)</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H15F393DCD7084F83B90C000D730FFBFD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a nonprofit research organization;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE8E5799F24F24FAC86826280D28933EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a National Laboratory (as such term is defined in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H373D44A18E6B47FE874F5EDBEB2A4D04"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a private commercial entity;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA16DD3148AF94384935B68B49EA06A00"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a partnership or consortium of two or more entities described in subparagraphs (A) through (D) that leverages existing Department efforts; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H10DBDA1821544F868411D98F83E18048"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other entity the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3836649A6EDC4C558CBD628ACC80A690"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5DA178FC2DD43CEB618A23333A925F9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Technical standards</header><text>The term <quote>technical standard</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 12(d)(5) of the National Technology Transfer and Advancement Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/272">15 U.S.C. 272</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H2EBDBAD2DAD248429E926739C69E0E90" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In carrying out this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H1BE502DDC1434804B38BE4112D465A51"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary shall avoid unnecessary duplication and achieve shared mission goals by coordinating with the Administrator of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration of the Department of Transportation and across all relevant program offices at the Department of Energy, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1774B24A5BFD4836AB9CB9D5560F5979"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Office of Science;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7593884D4DE44F07A244034FC38FE94F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Office of Fossil Energy and Carbon Management;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEFB52884C86E4C6FA87AE41FB80DC2B8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB73C7741055B409BA33E135F693B98E1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Office of Cybersecurity, Energy Security, and Emergency Response;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H487BAEEA96EC491D8249632986A88D91"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Advanced Research Projects Agency–Energy;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFB4AAC4CFD6F4454B0E55437774560FD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Office of Clean Energy Demonstrations; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9C1E00911EC14455AFDF8D547136D1A5" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any other cross-cutting program office determined appropriate;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E62F99F5D0140A7B7B6EA9945362E05"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of Transportation shall ensure participation of and coordination with the Secretary of Energy of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H82E7ACBE9D964D04B42CBC76CDECF814" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration of the Department of Transportation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA351935F13F41388CC18C110A84D07E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other program office of the Department of Transportation determined appropriate; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H387EA4F176D34117B2B57D6A4DF56973"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Secretary shall coordinate with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Secretary of the Interior, and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H575E5743FABF4683BB4555B0D44C88E7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Advanced pipeline materials and technologies demonstration initiative</header> <subsection id="H70EDA09904104FEA8257BD3AD61B6D13"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle E of title III of division D of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HF28CDFDC3FE44CB6B7F029A50C180024"> 
<section id="H252C1981EBAC4C8BB5D14B3017C6A468"><enum>40344.</enum><header>Advanced pipeline materials and technologies demonstration initiative</header> 
<subsection id="H6420152FFD9647DB9CC5BB5AF7056424" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of initiative</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a demonstration initiative (in this section referred to as the <quote>Initiative</quote>) under which the Secretary, through a competitive merit review process, shall award financial assistance to eligible entities to carry out demonstration projects on low- to mid-technology readiness level subjects to achieve deployment of technologies that—</text> <paragraph id="HBCB308BA67FE45AABE1D50C4A2457BAA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are applicable to pipelines and associated infrastructure, including liquefied natural gas facilities and underground and above ground gas and liquid fuel storage facilities; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3301CED578FF4A5E90928DFD791D5F73" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>involve the development of next generation pipeline systems, components, and related technologies.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1EA315265F95468A839A2B846D69CC32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Demonstration project focus areas</header><text>In carrying out the Initiative, the Secretary shall select demonstration projects that best advance research undertaken by the Department and the Department of Transportation and incorporate a range of technology focus areas, which may include the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H25FFBA7056C54406B19A7093B6372624"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Advanced leak detection and mitigation tools and technologies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5FB86286C21A429F83571E839EE32FDF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Novel materials, including alloy and nonmetallic materials, to improve integrity for new and existing pipelines, such as pipeline coatings, sleeves, and liners, and corrosion resistant materials, including maximum and minimum flow rates and immunity to electrical discharge processes.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H35739454DFD34C06A84C0EC55FCF382E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Technologies and methods for retrofitting existing pipelines, resolving material compatibility issues, and minimizing leakage, such as field protective coatings and material treatment.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28CDF5943DFE4327BB3E43923F566993" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Advanced manufacturing approaches for producing, fitting, and coupling pipelines, including the fabrication of higher performance pipeline materials and new extrusion technologies or methods to join ultra-high strength and corrosion resistant materials at a scale for distribution.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA48B0C952E78499280CEF4343D949EF8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Advanced sensor technologies and processes that enable real-time or in situ monitoring of pipeline assets to assess and mitigate leaks, both internal and external to the pipeline, which may include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H9964B74BF5414C459520ECE8A02ADFE2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Wireless sensors, such as surface acoustic wave sensors.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H01607AC9C28E4C2F8C8A7B38B174DAF5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Advanced and cost-effective electrochemical sensors.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8E5D83E95BE74C9BA79F12E57F40850E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Distributed fiber optic sensors.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2026238871F542A6A8B9BB11B976A53A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Autonomous sensor systems, including uncrewed aircraft.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H05791C60FAA149D19053767B927912E9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Optical methods.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5178474196A342B485FC706E729AA5F2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Multi-use platforms for diverse sources.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2D8BA798EB334B2880265284216827E4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Hybrid data-analysis platforms.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HABF141ADA4194DDFB9D313AECAA36CFF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Advanced computational, data analytics, and machine learning models to achieve the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HD06CD1D7E58047F9BE41AEA8012EA300"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Multiscale modeling, characterization, and optimization of transmission and distribution systems and components to aid in planning for optimized and resilient infrastructure.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1B0215421426439E8E64B09CF32F3A75"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Correlation between sensor and emissions data at all operational points and across a variety of scales to assure system integrity spanning large areas.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1FFCE52A65324814950A301564BF85A1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Accurate material lifecycle predictions and simulation platforms to forecast pipeline health.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H29B52152EEB0423AA611C94787DC5957"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Secure real time autonomous monitoring and repair capabilities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC540A6A401BE450286CF772E2C47DB97"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Mapping and monitoring of structural health parameters, such as corrosion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFDC0E75D9E59453699E6B3F5F636940E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Self-healing and self-repair functionalities, including by chemical treatment methods.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FD2A59E486B4B20AA3CF593262B3D00"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Autonomous robotic and patch technologies for inspection and repair.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9713CB9283AF4A4BB53EA29D1562E9D1"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Dynamic compressor technologies, including retrofit kits for existing compressor systems.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H26381AB455D54B43B2ABC1952231D6E0"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Strategies and technologies for integrated cybersecurity considerations and countering cyberattacks.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H47D82304DA144EC2BE9118DCD7378F26" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Technologies and methods to reduce potential environmental impacts, including at the atmospheric and subsurface level, associated with pipelines, liquefied natural gas facilities, and gas and liquid fuel storage facilities, such as equipment failure.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H188C8C6949F1445AB9873BC3E86AA69E"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Tools to evaluate geographical pipeline data for the feasibility of repurposing existing infrastructure for safe and effective transport and use of alternative fuels, blends, and carbon dioxide.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAC07A11168734FCE82F72348A553F2F7"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Tools and technologies applicable to improving the safety, operation, and efficiency of liquefied natural gas facilities and gas and liquid fuel storage facilities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H01BE2356911348D89B2912CA9480A6F6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection requirements</header><text>In selecting eligible entities for demonstration projects under the Initiative, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, take the following actions:</text> 
<paragraph id="HCF6FC6DE2B1B490EA8EAB3193957121C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Encourage regional diversity among eligible entities, including participation by such entities located in rural States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F847EF81C6B4EFEB9F5E7798657339F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Prioritize technological diversity among eligible entities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFEA573E1448948989C50786662535C41"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Prioritize a diverse mix of energy, substances, fuel sources, and byproducts, including the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H2F3CA8FCF91F4CC2BEDD067CB1C99250"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Gas and liquid hydrocarbons, including natural gas, renewable natural gas, methane, ethane, and liquefied natural gas.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7B81C832F12D4DD286121B31BFA418DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Carbon dioxide.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H52E5DF3E921E41FB8FDBEF7D7096BD0E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Hydrogen.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8FA52119578440F19ECC6568C45F956D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Biofuels.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF7C00A2934414A1AA98373B6B7197EB9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Water.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD491CE14230C42138E828B33A09840F7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Substances in the hydrogen supply chain, including ammonia and liquid organic hydrogen carriers.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H669B4B4CAF164385AD87716CBF874FD2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Blends of gases or liquids, including hydrogen blends.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2C7CD0DAF6544E7E860EEA0F2666B88F"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Any other source the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEABCCD73D05D4C4FAA304DBEA89DC113"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Prioritize projects that leverage and are complementary to existing energy infrastructure.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB2619B70ED2748478509281D5BCA1B13"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Prioritize projects that leverage matching funds from non-Federal sources.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAE76EA71141545EDBF98E3D077A50A61"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Ensure that selected projects are coordinated with or expand on the existing technology demonstration programs of the Department.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H736E8F950E7E4CC0B1694FBA9555D619"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Evaluate projects and topics for technical performance and economic feasibility as part of lifecycle assessments for return on investment impact.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H865FBB11F7A24FD883C0D9C57587E087"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prioritize projects that can quantifiably reduce the environmental impacts of pipelines and associated infrastructure on air, water, or soil quality in all regions of the United States, especially in underserved and rural communities.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD8CCF63F949F4217984587F7E811CE94" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Location</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the maximum extent practicable, demonstration projects under the Initiative shall be located on sites with existing research infrastructure or with the ability to coordinate with existing Department user facilities and research centers.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBBF670A48780490E97643E9CD9BBA183" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Out of funds authorized to be appropriated for—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9C005D4E49594C95A81EEA7C27B69779" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H463B1AB639E14C7ABD98E5969053D8A8" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Office of Fossil Energy and Carbon Management,</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection" commented="no">pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (6), respectively, of section 10771 of subtitle O of title VI of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (enacted as division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/167">Public Law 117–167</external-xref>), there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Energy to carry out this section $45,000,000 for fiscal year 2026, and $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030.</continuation-text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD8CFA6881FC344D3997E2F66B2B2115A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall terminate five years after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H4E8E4DBCB4674E8AB35103913BF89016"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 40343 the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB920A28CB6FF4E29A5909410B9B452BF" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 40344. Advanced pipeline materials and technologies demonstration initiative.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="HDFBD1827146D412C929D298945D26741"><enum>5.</enum><header>Joint research and development program</header> 
<subsection id="H22E26FB816994416B28ED204E329A5E6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation and the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and in coordination with the demonstration initiative established pursuant to section 40344 of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>), as added by section 4, shall establish within the Department a joint research and development program (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Joint Program</quote>) to carry out research projects that—</text> <paragraph id="HF2E44A7896214F9EA4D8B474E4644A0F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop cost-effective advanced materials and technologies for pipeline transportation systems at different scales;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD18D297C8D8D4449A6C5996AAA65109D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enable the commercialization of innovative materials and technologies for pipeline transportation systems;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCFF0B3DCD5664310ABA61EC148DD8A4A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support the development of technical standards of innovative materials and technologies for pipeline transportation systems; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF5251F02DA1D49ECAC754B2F1C77261B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>are at a low technology readiness level and not pursued by the Pipeline Safety Research Program of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration of the Department of Transportation.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA106DD6DAB3F438FBD9A9B018243FD7F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall enter into or update an existing memorandum of understanding with the Secretary of Transportation and the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to administer the Joint Program. Such memorandum shall require each participating agency to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFC8A64547388480CB470EC1CDFB3B958"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify unique research capabilities to contribute while avoiding duplication of existing efforts; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE138122D6174DBBBEE4E796A9E1696E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include cost sharing and cost reimbursement abilities among participating agencies, including any reviews, approvals, trainings, or resource outlays that will be required.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2D315BFC753B4465898F71F15F111FD9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Infrastructure</header><text>In carrying out the Joint Program, the Secretary, the Secretary of Transportation, and the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall—</text> <paragraph id="H3EDBF589C97E4AEA943558191112F8D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>use existing research infrastructure at—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB625DDB4205445C8AF654A6EF7B3C155"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Department of Energy facilities, including National Laboratories;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE5C4F63D9EDC43E0AD43D81248103C26" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Department of Transportation initiatives, including any such initiatives carried out through the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H36C9D99CF46F415B9439F6EB1C7FAECC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the National Institute of Standards and Technology; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD5BA680C2AD147248AF94C66B949B119"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop new infrastructure for potential projects, if appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H738A6CFF8E724A0293B95E488C9952EE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Goals and metrics</header><text>The Secretary, the Secretary of Transportation, and the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall develop goals and metrics for each agency, respectively, in meeting technological progress under the Joint Program, consistent with existing United States energy safety, resilience, and security policies.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H93587D4F78F040B189A77F9BD5D6D6A8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Selection of projects</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary, the Secretary of Transportation, and the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall ensure the following with respect to the Joint Program:</text> 
<paragraph id="HEB32A22A28B0424586E4FDF65D9CB785"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Projects are carried out under conditions that represent a variety of geographies, physical conditions, and market constraints.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H197589E294674D6EBA639BE01EF48C4A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Projects represent an appropriate balance of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCE2F3E90DCA040D8A87C66F60357ED77"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Larger, higher-cost projects.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H77DE4740A4914FF2ACDF39B81A73E137"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Smaller, lower-cost projects.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA6C378BCCD5F4468863D5B1C0DAB027D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To the maximum extent practicable, projects are transferred between participating agencies based on the stage of research and capabilities of each agency.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0B659969BA2E436B98881434D692C367" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the Joint Program, the Secretary, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and the Secretary of Transportation shall, through consultation with the demonstration initiative established pursuant to section 40344 of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>), as added by section 4, identify and advance areas of research most needed for demonstration projects under such demonstration initiative, give priority to research and demonstration projects that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H55249AD3104943B296C6AB0FE7365ACB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are likely to be of value to such demonstration initiative; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3E4CE6A4FD749AEBF5D394701B7EC0C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are done in coordination with, or advance knowledge critical to, the National Pipeline Modernization Center established pursuant to section 6.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB0D2B1CF25704E82BB891C1832FCBA78"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Relation to existing law</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to change existing agency roles, responsibilities, or areas of expertise as described in section 12 of the Pipeline Safety Improvement Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/355">Public Law 107–355</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/60101">49 U.S.C. 60101</external-xref> note).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1EE46425D9E04A2B976E13BAA0B52B90"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall terminate five years after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC4B7A696DBFC42D0A05669F990CC65AA"><enum>6.</enum><header>National Pipeline Modernization Center</header> 
<subsection id="H220FA40AEE554F24900077B0DD930608"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the demonstration initiative established pursuant to section 40344 of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>), as added by section 4, and the Joint Program and subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary shall establish a National Pipeline Modernization Center (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Center</quote>), which shall focus on collaborating with industry and stakeholders to coordinate and carry out research, development, and demonstration projects focused on commercializing cost-effective products and procedures aligned with the goals and priorities set forth by the Department.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1CADFBAB47CD4D6BAD50F5713813ECE9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The Secretary shall administer the Center in conjunction with an eligible entity pursuant to an agreement between the Department and such entity. Such entity shall be selected on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2B40D0418EC64C4FBEEAF52609BE989C" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Existing centers</header><text>In administering the Center, the Secretary shall prioritize higher education energy-related research centers in existence as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBC06AE60509E4D2CBE2FC614249C907A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Period of performance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agreement under subsection (b) shall be for a period of not more than five years, subject to the availability of appropriations.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFB8616A7C70442ABAAE563EC3F24562A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Location</header><text>The Center shall be located in proximity to critical transportation infrastructure connecting to an existing national pipeline transportation system and other Department monitoring assets, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H63737A45C06541838F0E1EDF6C60154C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Coordination with training and qualifications center</header><text>In carrying out the functions described in subsection (a), the Center shall coordinate and collaborate with training centers of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration of the Department of Transportation to facilitate knowledge sharing among, and enhanced training opportunities for, Federal and State pipeline safety inspectors and investigators.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H01D4CC76EC204389A0DA7537E729BEED" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Duplication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure the coordination of, and avoid unnecessary duplication of, the activities under this section with the National Center of Excellence for Liquefied Natural Gas Safety established pursuant to section 111 of the Protecting our Infrastructure of Pipelines and Enhancing Safety Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/60103">49 U.S.C. 60103</external-xref> note; enacted as division R of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>)).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H1758845C5D6C42349E0AEC24BC226D2C"><enum>7.</enum><header>NIST pipeline metrology</header> <subsection id="HAD71F6931622466EB3AF54E0DACC4474"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall carry out a program of measurement research, development, demonstration, and standardization to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7102AF9B306D4277A3FA998ED29C501F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure the integrity of pipeline facilities; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D89F53CD00E42E5B477CDE6C3199F9C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support pipeline safety, security, efficiency, sustainability, and resilience.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBD02A030AC2549AEA1C761BBBA342704"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Testing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, in collaboration with the Secretary of the Department of Transportation and in consultation with the private sector and international standards organizations, shall support testing, evaluation, and research infrastructure to support the activities described in subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDF0B3EA409BA4072AC1F4A196D53BB2B" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Allocation of appropriations</header><text>From amounts appropriated or otherwise made available for the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall allocate up to $2,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030 to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HE361A920DDC846A0A80E7D55C7B6BD4E"><enum>8.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> 
<subsection id="HAB1B1C55AD1C483E8AC7C4AA50511BE6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Out of funds authorized to be appropriated for the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy and the Office of Fossil Energy and Carbon Management pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (6), respectively, of section 10771 of subtitle O of title VI of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (enacted as division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/167">Public Law 117–167</external-xref>), there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out—</text> <paragraph id="HCBE0DB33A1EB4BD0A2C2F5B6141E3695"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 5, $20,000,000 for fiscal year 2026, and $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBEDDFE337E794C93B3D311BA961C49E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>section 6, $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2026, and $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF06DEB4DC02341B6BE161F9A5F2F209E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Offset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 10771 of subtitle O of title VI of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (enacted as division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/167">Public Law 117–167</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0EC39CD36B734D4FA33903C2F5A3B322"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H396CF9100FBC4256A56BF0C71D418875"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>2026</quote> and inserting <quote>2030</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD70CE9BADF6F4A74AD24357AF8DF3DE7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>1,200,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$1,100,000,000</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5829E8AD40B44D92947A7C606CAC4D3B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (6)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H465A71C53E1944DE9E283CE6562C9D6A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>2026</quote> and inserting <quote>2030</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1E7C4DBD7AA146CD9342099001EF3B2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>600,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$445,000,000</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2588F1626E3F491696FF29287797DCBB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> <clause id="HE8AF183616E746FD96FF36C543E5D5AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>200,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$100,000,000</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H162792A8E3C64560B9BE92DD04864285"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H86986B7C0BEC463FA85EF534557F7DA2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text> 
<clause id="HCF04193E337C498686BF12A4B58D2F5C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>1,000,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$900,000,000</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD3B243327EF2400E962A5252B5259262"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and </text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCC11155BFF1945ACACCCAD882A8FBF37"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE698A0DC264341C7A21853A697F36D36" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H751061A932EC40F48C7F34A157C1621B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$455,000,000 to carry out pipeline research, development, demonstration, and commercial application activities.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

