<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCC25804-Y3W-9S-DWF"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2106 IS: Safe Environment from Countries Under Repression and Emergency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2106</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250618">June 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide a process for granting lawful permanent resident status to aliens
            from certain countries who meet certain eligibility requirements, and for other
 purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short titles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe Environment from Countries Under Repression and Emergency Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SECURE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id59c3fd9498564a848a609ae998b03d76"><enum>2.</enum><header>Adjustment of status of certain foreign nationals</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id05d5c66b1ec5442c9aabf477a8c6e1b4"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Chapter 5 of title II of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1255">8 U.S.C. 1255 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 245A (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1255A">8 U.S.C. 1255A</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c644ca7b24e4c1fba5c8097b9bb48f7"><section id="idEFD9BD62B7C54C3882F67F347A25DE8F"><enum>245B.</enum><header>Adjustment of status of certain foreign nationals</header><subsection id="id72684ecd8b664ccea5fe29f0bdeb6c3b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="idc9bd536e3e414820acf08997cf06d953"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization</header><subparagraph id="id482B4F2C4A854993AEC4519F01B3F8DA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 245(c), the status of any alien described in subsection (b)(1) shall be adjusted by the Secretary of Homeland Security to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence if the alien—</text><clause id="idb78ad0d1caa048eb884b686281f4495c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not inadmissible under paragraph (2) or (3) of section 212(a);</text></clause><clause id="id117882E92EC04D34976FEE31B96791B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not deportable under paragraph (2), (3), or (4) of section 237(a); and</text></clause><clause id="id491711634345463dbd280c0027cb8dc5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is not described in section 208(b)(2)(A)(i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4D4AD12A11D84F0B9ECB458C7F8FB5FD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of expunged convictions</header><text>In this section, the term <term>conviction</term> does not include a judgment that has been expunged or set aside that resulted in a rehabilitative disposition or the equivalent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idDD44CF64594F438C92328B6AD9CB9F18"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6A718121A4C84D579851E9250B6E6C1E"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), any alien who is physically present in the United States may apply for adjustment of status under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5C45448086FC47248B2F35B0017C7608"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applications from outside the united states for certain
 aliens previously removed or who departed</header><text>In the case of an alien who, on or after September 28, 2016, was removed from the United States or departed pursuant to an order of voluntary departure, the alien may apply for adjustment of status under this section from outside the United States if, on the day before the date on which the alien was so removed or so departed, the alien was an alien described in subsection (b)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF5B580112ADD48EBB322862B85E7698B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Fee</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAC54345A92F94E4A89DB7E52B9CD58C6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall require any alien applying for permanent resident status under this section to pay a reasonable fee that is commensurate with the cost of processing the application. Such fee may not exceed $1,440.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF097C2D2C8A3441E94FAA4CE37DDB335"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Fee exemption</header><text>An applicant may be exempted from paying the application fee required under clause (i) if the applicant—</text><subclause commented="no" id="HBD6553B0D68C4607BFF57E30438CBF17"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is younger than 18 years of age;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HE99A14220235471C8E8A352373E416F0"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">received total income, during the 12-month period immediately preceding the date on which the applicant files an application under this section, that is less than 150 percent of the Federal poverty line;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H329CA235595842D1A6C5CAA07A2C3349"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is in foster care or otherwise lacking any parental or other familial support; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H14827206BFDA4E7BB2A7CDCF523F8BDD"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cannot care for himself or herself because of a serious, chronic disability.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id850ced5c80434ff7bc983b728c757403"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Relationship of application to certain orders</header><clause commented="no" id="idBDA5075EDDC548B68EE99C763BFBFFBF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Motion not required</header><text>An alien described in subparagraph (A) or (B) who has been the subject of an order of removal or voluntary departure may not be required, as a condition of submitting or approving an application under such subparagraph, to file a motion to reopen, reconsider, or vacate such order.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idA277BBBF0BB2485697C8CC6F26DE0E79"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Approval</header><text>If the Secretary of Homeland Security approves an application submitted by an alien under this paragraph, the Secretary shall cancel any order of removal or voluntary departure to which the alien is or was subject.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idE94510F6F9C64DC1974A322A16F47A98"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Denial</header><text>If the Secretary of Homeland Security renders a final administrative decision to deny an application submitted by an alien under this paragraph, any order of removal or voluntary departure to which the alien is subject shall be effective and enforceable to the same extent as if such application had not been made.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc76d67a94d834bb2a9fc70de55651c2e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Aliens eligible for adjustment of status</header><paragraph id="idE7EFC9987E884501999F5438F5CD079C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An alien is described in this subsection if the alien—</text><subparagraph id="id3e0f3ee170c3404eac209c7342257547"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a national of a foreign state that was at any time designated under section 244(b);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5cdfd6e9674540b7ae4259ea9fd057c6"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idCECAEB1D5BCC4F4F9E4538B0A611C5C5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is in temporary protected status under section 244;</text></clause><clause id="idE2303F92BF9243249362DF682CADAEC0" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>held temporary protected status as a national of a designated foreign state described in subparagraph (A);</text></clause><clause id="idD9292814AD064011ADCCC3EEFBB1565F" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>qualified for temporary protected status on the date on which the last designation or extension was made by the Secretary of Homeland Security; or</text></clause><clause id="id5F3D0B63CA2B4CF5A431B643FC4918DC" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>was present in the United States pursuant to a grant of deferred enforced departure that had been extended beyond or was issued after September 28, 2016;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id105139f61c5e44c6b5c44b3008fbcf6c"><enum>(C)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idE5AC0A0D3B344E8D9B030C4C1000CA0F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has been continuously present in the United States for not less than 3 years and is physically present in the United States on the date on which the alien files an application for adjustment of status under this section; or</text></clause><clause id="id5EF8B5DFCA5B486E9AC5A4EA91CC71BD" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of an alien who, on or after September 28, 2016, was removed from the United States or departed pursuant to an order of voluntary departure, was continuously present in the United States for a period of not less than 3 years before the date on which the alien was so removed or so departed; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0B89508A1B454038828E3AA62562882E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>passes all applicable criminal and national security background checks.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idC71A4706E6AB475DA9D03D4F5A60EE9D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Short absences</header><text>An alien shall not be considered to have failed to maintain continuous physical presence in the United States under paragraph (1)(C) by reason of an absence, or multiple absences, from the United States for any period or periods that do not exceed, in the aggregate, 180 days.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d330535fc9245fa9a57d0351e28faab"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Waiver authorized</header><text>Notwithstanding any provision of this Act, an alien who fails to meet the continuous physical presence requirement under paragraph (1)(C) shall be considered eligible for adjustment of status under this section if the Attorney General or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as applicable, determines that the removal or continued absence of the alien from the United States, as applicable, would result in extreme hardship to the alien or to the alien’s spouse, children, parents, or domestic partner.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd94b743e025d4e3faf41a354b3bc84ae"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Stay of removal</header><paragraph id="id007541006d58401cbade7791bf0b4751"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), an alien who is subject to a final order of removal may not be removed if the alien—</text><subparagraph id="idBAE32263B2A545AAA1C06677A4CF86AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has a pending application under subsection (a); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id38C2918A6FFA4ADEA72B9967A706DA82"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id28EDEBB8A67C4835B28D80B6D8B56197"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is prima facie eligible to file an application under subsection (a); and</text></clause><clause id="idE36538C523FA4508A6494EB4B2AD3F61" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>indicates that he or she intends to file such an application.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide95caa099f6440d3b49e2b7f8ca9184b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to any alien whose application under subsection (a) has been denied by the Secretary of Homeland Security in a final administrative determination.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf19fa180e0a74dbd95522188b714d6cf"><enum>(3)</enum><header>During certain proceedings</header><subparagraph id="idD9FC0A8EA48845D28D5E13ED0B973630"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B) and notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security may not order any alien to be removed from the United States if the alien raises, as a defense to such an order, the eligibility of the alien to apply for adjustment of status under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF33F3385F5A04D4D814837AF28DA5977"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to any alien whose application under subsection (a) has been denied by the Secretary of Homeland Security in a final administrative determination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc93f9a46f8cc4ac2b1c39fa1bcbb842a"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Work authorization</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security—</text><subparagraph id="id3C2F9A2751E44414A91E53491C6D2EAF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall authorize any alien who has applied for adjustment of status under subsection (a) to engage in employment in the United States while such application is pending; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9F6226A376E64F098AD7F1D7D84A9469"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may provide such alien with an <quote>employment authorized</quote> endorsement or other appropriate document signifying such employment authorization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id673c46d193784a79a0cf436c75e87451"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Advance parole</header><paragraph id="idF0D6C62832994FD3B302A3E6C72CD4A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the period beginning on the date on which an alien applies for adjustment of status under this Act and ending on the date on which the Secretary of Homeland Security makes a final decision regarding such application, the alien shall be eligible to apply for advance parole.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id214863CCB3ED4B6499F95B5812E6E7FF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Section 101(g) shall not apply to an alien granted advance parole under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id89AB1C4BA0A342AD9CC83C7362337E0E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Adjustment of status for spouses and children</header><paragraph id="id5a125bacfa91470999bb35eb0cd3578a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 245(c) and except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall adjust the status of an alien to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence if the alien—</text><subparagraph id="ide98cd4a628154dc797ccb1d078110a6a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is the spouse, domestic partner, child, or unmarried son or daughter of an alien whose status has been adjusted to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence under subsection (a);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id760d1a6dad194403822ef9cfdd53a2fd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is physically present in the United States on the date on which the alien files an application for such adjustment of status; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id84fc3be81afb4a509307872ef8c6c636"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is otherwise eligible to receive an immigrant visa and is otherwise admissible to the United States for permanent residence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5a93d2813d6c433486eb79c0c280e89a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continuous presence requirement</header><subparagraph id="id2B8608CF24CF46CEA8E987CE7CDFD167"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The status of an unmarried son or daughter referred to in paragraph (1)(A) may not be adjusted under paragraph (1) until such son or daughter establishes that he or she has been physically present in the United States for at least 1 year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA9E38AEF70E249639BAF5981E19D3922"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Short absences</header><text>An alien shall not be considered to have failed to maintain continuous physical presence in the United States under subparagraph (A) by reason of an absence, or multiple absences, from the United States for any period or periods that do not exceed, in the aggregate, 180 days.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2E41402EFF0340FDBD1749523834A2EC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>In determining eligibility and admissibility under paragraph (1)(C), the grounds for inadmissibility under paragraphs (4), (5), (6), (7)(A), and (9) of section 212(a) shall not apply.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5B2D74D216834780AC2ABFB48EEE1BDD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Availability of administrative review</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide applicants for adjustment of status under subsection (a) the same right to, and procedures for, administrative review as are provided to—</text><paragraph id="id76a31d2a6d374ebba100296f18bdff5c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>applicants for adjustment of status under section 245; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida448d7969aad47228ffb033df27c6e91"><enum>(2)</enum><text>aliens who are subject to removal proceedings under section 240.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6b4b221703d54da4a1d8106252fb3c55"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exceptions to numerical limitations</header><text>The numerical limitations set forth in sections 201 and 202 shall not apply to aliens whose status is adjusted pursuant to subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id20c2492d324a4f00b8fe7cd63a57560d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification of inspection and admission under Temporary Protected
 Status</header><text>Section 244(f)(4) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1254a">8 U.S.C. 1254a(f)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>as having been inspected and admitted into the United States, and</quote> after <quote>considered</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf061e69c5e014e9a87afce65b3747010"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 245A the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="idaecae3cf-a50c-435a-8fc6-92a37b7d4e8b"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="idEFD9BD62B7C54C3882F67F347A25DE8F">Sec.
 245B. Adjustment of status of certain foreign nationals.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="HC7788045539D4302B4812079A5BF1116"><enum>3.</enum><header>Confidentiality of information</header><subsection id="H1E1AF786CE6745C5B11D5A4FBF4556D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may not disclose or use information provided in applications filed under section 245B of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by section 2, for the purpose of immigration enforcement.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H96EBA98392AB490BAA3E630C3E20FD97"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Referrals prohibited</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not refer any individual who has been granted permanent resident status under section 245B of the Immigration and Nationality Act to U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, U.S. Customs and Border Protection, or any designee of either such entity.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H5D6D8D3D11484A198CBC78CB5C1C2443"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limited exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b), information provided in an application for permanent resident status under section 245B of the Immigration and Nationality Act may be shared with Federal security and law enforcement agencies—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H3C3435B68DC14C44B8B72025D0891015"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for assistance in the consideration of an application for permanent resident status under such section;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA7A77584A25E444A815FDE0615E0F671"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to identify or prevent fraudulent claims;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H83F42BE3D0F7483B81E421F29E255B81"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for national security purposes; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBDA5EF0D88DC46369A5DDC9379B69C30"><enum>(4)</enum><text>for the investigation or prosecution of any felony not related to immigration status.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC993D24C555C4AE29262B993AF4C13C7"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who knowingly uses, publishes, or permits information to be examined in violation of this section shall be fined not more than $10,000.</text></subsection></section><section id="id94ee0daeb08648ac899988fdd16ccceb"><enum>4.</enum><header>Additional reporting requirements regarding future discontinued eligibility of
 aliens from countries currently listed under temporary protected status</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 244(b)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1254a">8 U.S.C. 1254a(b)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id2975CC14C70E4648ADE92EBD50861485"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A)—</text><subparagraph id="idE6336F448D91417B9767E4A899DC0759"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>Secretary of Homeland Security</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id00035597F8114EFEA35766520846ED62"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>(including a recommendation from the Secretary of State that is received by the Secretary of Homeland Security not later than 90 days before the end of such period of designation)</quote> after <quote>Government</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5EECCDDCDA3D4C25B14EC429ADFC584B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B)—</text><subparagraph id="idEF1AE779ED184F35B5EE86ABEEFB868E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>If the Attorney General</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAE8AFBE958B54B61A94EDA975FDB687C"><clause id="idE9A6EBBDFCE543D69F6F49C8B6768451"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary of Homeland Security</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA23CF1D5B251493C9FD42AD93C90B4A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (i), as designated by subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> and inserting <quote>Secretary</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5BFA4CC837B643878CF961B472D55E88"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49AC45EDBB00402E84431FCBF335EA66"><clause id="id4E11044030EE47A98FF8BE6E20966DAD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 days after the publication of the Secretary’s determination in the Federal Register that a country’s designation under paragraph (1) is being terminated, the Secretary shall submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that includes—</text><subclause id="id4bde6b34deb145b994e0d5178346ecd0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an explanation of the event or events that initially prompted such country’s designation under paragraph (1);</text></subclause><subclause id="id6f40bc1cf7e44236a0ea7d2d7c7f26bb"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the progress the country has made in remedying the designation under paragraph (1), including any significant challenges or shortcomings that have not been addressed since the initial designation;</text></subclause><subclause id="id2e375f327e6647058835a34ea607e28d"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a statement indicating whether the country has requested a designation under paragraph (1), a redesignation under such paragraph, or an extension of such designation; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idEF01FAC1199F4B618D0F3C463FE69D3D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>an analysis, with applicable and relevant metrics, as determined by the Secretary, of the country’s ability to repatriate its nationals, including—</text><item id="id90a0befef8da462a8cf591c254dbfb63"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the country’s financial ability to provide for its repatriated citizens;</text></item><item id="id12f07d5040ce413f80128f55eaacf417"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the country’s financial ability to address the initial designation under paragraph (1) without foreign assistance;</text></item><item id="idc016bc1d839b4d71ae057df96177ea86"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the country’s gross domestic product and per capita gross domestic product per capita;</text></item><item id="idCF01CE0612484F639B4CFD63964027E4"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>an analysis of the country’s political stability and its ability to be economically self-sufficient without foreign assistance;</text></item><item id="id94edbb67f8f04fa28cb2b21bd9aaf5ed"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>the economic and social impact the repatriation of nationals in possession of temporary protected status would have on the recipient country; and</text></item><item id="id9ed3dcdd2f514420a61e8655afcf368b"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>any additional metrics the Secretary considers necessary.</text></item></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id1a99beb5b93f4223b38900358e29e676"><enum>5.</enum><header>Other matters</header><subsection id="id90E39695D8A4485CB846639994690A76"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Application of Immigration and Nationality Act provisions</header><text>Except as otherwise specifically provided in this Act, the definitions under section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>) shall apply when such terms are used in this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="id82F2C8DC20584D1A88524249154D03B7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this Act, or the amendments made by this Act, may be construed to repeal, amend, alter, modify, effect, or restrict the powers, duties, functions, or authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security in the administration and enforcement of the immigration laws.</text></subsection><subsection id="id54EF5F0B9EBD4A39919338E3946A6905"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility for other immigration benefits</header><text>Any alien who is eligible to be granted the status of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence under section 245B of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by section 2, may not be precluded from seeking such status under any other provision of law for which the alien may otherwise be eligible.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

