<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDB085527B3FA49968330FEC77521F025" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3899 IH: Clarifying Federal General Permits Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3899</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250611">June 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act with respect to general permits under the national pollutant discharge elimination system, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H61BEDCA4D2534EE2B7AD053799102D35" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA0D391B278C94AF7A5D6D5FF283BDFA8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Clarifying Federal General Permits Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HC1C97C17C6EC40B4A2D5C2E3A59F65E3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal general permits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 402(a) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1342">33 U.S.C. 1342(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H41FDDA8B4CEE431FBD4D1E876D3AB8A8" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HEA26EDC2CD204463AB3BF8370A466F8F" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum> <subparagraph id="HE5CEDD71DE754ABEB45F48D1AC7343B1" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Administrator may issue general permits under this section on a State, regional, or nationwide basis, or for a delineated area, for discharges associated with any category of activities, which discharges are of similar types and from similar sources.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFAAE00524D644392B9FF6B9BD49B687C" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If a general permit issued under this section will expire and the Administrator decides not to issue a new general permit for discharges similar to those covered by the expiring general permit, the Administrator shall publish in the Federal Register a notice of such decision at least two years prior to the expiration of the general permit.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H107B9EA695FE4BFDB66C45294C8C3CFD" indent="up1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum> <clause id="H7A6776C6C1234B258F297A6155B8A8F2" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>If a general permit issued under this section expires and the Administrator has not published a notice in accordance with subparagraph (B), the Administrator shall, until the date described in clause (ii)—</text> 
<subclause id="HA81B6C26BB8D46138995181AF2C28509" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>continue to apply the terms, conditions, and requirements of the expired general permit to any discharge that was covered by the expired general permit; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H697661D30A57475ABE41E325E7E73CD9" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>apply such terms, conditions, and requirements to any discharge that would have been covered by the expired general permit (in accordance with any relevant requirements for such coverage) if the discharge had occurred before such expiration.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H3D468E563B6245668799F26D9674EF46" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The date described in this clause is the earlier of—</text> <subclause id="H8E626E93056A4CCC96D15DC88050031D"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which the Administrator issues a new general permit for discharges similar to those covered by the expired general permit; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H3C4D864F0C4D445AA87D8FED6242C25F"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that is 2 years after the date on which the Administrator publishes in the Federal Register a notice of a decision not to issue a new general permit for discharges similar to those covered by the expired general permit.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

