<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H17DADC8A37DB4874A3932B1E722CFCD2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4586 IH: African Diaspora Investment and Development Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4586</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250722">July 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a comprehensive strategy to support African and Caribbean diaspora engagement in development through reduced remittance costs, investment incentives, and institutional partnerships.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3F80C5554CDA4E808CC5A1CBC7DD38D2" style="OLC"><section id="H85A7353FF08546848CB8A7ECC4208F58" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>African Diaspora Investment and Development Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>AIDA</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8A0676F6B37F4513B8D82FB729954E3E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H608C5C5F9CAB45BE8F3DC667F0806F05"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States is home to approximately 6,600,000 first generation African and Caribbean immigrants, nested within a broader population of 46,000,000 African Americans, representing vast economic, intellectual, and cultural capital, with longstanding economic and cultural ties to their countries of origin.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22CDBA58BEFB42CC822EF60DAB33B0B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Many members of these and other diaspora and immigrant populations annually transmit to their countries of origin or descent portions of their incomes or other earnings—transfers known as remittances—that in the aggregate often are large and significantly contribute to economic growth, development, and human welfare in recipient countries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC81691F84E8941D1BB24A6B31DE8AA5D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Remittances to Africa were estimated at over $91,000,000,000 in 2023—transfers which sustain families, fund education and healthcare, finance small businesses, and fill gaps in national infrastructure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66518A66BECB45058BEBA768AD929A96"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An estimated $19,499,000,000 was remitted to the Caribbean in 2023, with those countries receiving billions in essential family and community support.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84B4FF6313A94D579C95F99C0C941FCD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Sub-Saharan Africa remains the most expensive region for sending remittances, with average costs of 7.73 percent to send $200 in Q1 2024. In contrast, the average cost for Latin America and the Caribbean is 5.97 percent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D037FD639A546FC93F22CF89FCBADE3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>If the global average cost of remittances is reduced to the Sustainable Development Goal target of 3 percent, developing countries could save between $5,000,000,000 and $32,000,000,000 annually and redirect such resources to international economic growth and development investment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7908DB5C9FEB402EAFB599876F7075DE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The global remittance market was valued at $784,250,000,000 in 2022 and is projected to reach $1,330,000,000,000 by 2032, creating significant employment and economic activity across the financial services industry.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1601198B815145E8BD39FDA1A7A4A18C"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As the Economist noted on April 24, 2025, <quote>Emigration from Africa will change the world</quote>—not as a threat, but as a mutual opportunity for global growth, shared prosperity, and demographic balance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDE03F935F0C4EB089200FC1B368F82C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Yet the United States lacks a coherent framework to channel this economic power into formal investment, leaving diaspora members to operate in fragmented, uncoordinated environments with limited access to incentives or protections.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB07173989B294600B30FE866187BB4ED"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The future of United States-Africa relations does not rest solely on diplomatic summits or state-to-state aid. It lies in the millions of quiet financial acts made every month by diaspora citizens: a tuition payment, a clinic donation, a loan to launch a cousin’s shop. These flows deserve the full support of United States law and policy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H611D2AE4B409457CA8372238A58D79F2"><enum>(11)</enum><text>By embracing the diaspora not only as emotional kin but as strategic co-investors, this Act positions the United States at the frontier of global economic cooperation. It affirms that America's strength abroad rests not only in its institutions—but in the networks of commitment and capital held by its people.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HFE7C0DEF8B444C9AA1DF1DE939CE058A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to—</text><paragraph id="H9F974A4F9A0547E1B58A49194FDBD905"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognize African and Caribbean diaspora communities as legitimate partners in United States foreign economic policy, development assistance, and national investment strategy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5A4879E6D2B4B90A837D36AF36C2B6D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognize the role of regional and country-specific diasporas in cultural diplomacy, people-to-people ties, and various diasporas’ expanding contribution to socioeconomic development;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36CE73AC5EF14C7F8E9E451C52664446"><enum>(3)</enum><text>endeavor to reduce the cost of sending remittances including through policies aimed at increasing competition within the international financial transfers sub-sector and reducing related taxes or other administrative costs and maximize their potential to foster inclusive economic growth;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52AAD380F3954929A7DE5E1CCFBFFBDA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>safeguard the integrity and affordability of remittance flows, including by prohibiting taxation on personal remittances;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C602BB966BF4986979EB77DA88CF08B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>promote financial inclusion and reduce transaction costs through market competition, fintech innovation, and diaspora-owned remittance platforms;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01418594B6B44150A22BEBB0323EC83A"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">incentivize formal, productive investment in diaspora countries of origin through targeted United States tax policy, finance instruments, and legal safeguards; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE38704EBEBD144E1AC048C876276AB75"><enum>(7)</enum><text>pursue the global Sustainable Development Goal of reducing the average cost of remittances to 3 percent, especially for low-value transfers and high-cost corridors, through market incentives, innovation, and competition rather than price controls.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H3394D13749764BA5A86C08075A3ED63F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Support for diaspora investments from the United States International Development Finance Corporation</header><subsection id="H45D54EB09D654C1DBD693C7BD094B8FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief Executive Officer of the United States International Development Finance Corporation shall carry out a program to support, in the form of matching up to $5,000 (adjusted for inflation) in funds per taxpayer, investments that the Chief Executive Officer, in coordination with the Secretary of the Treasury, determines are investments by the African diaspora or investments in Caribbean countries that meet measurable development goals in health, education, agriculture, clean energy, or youth employment in Africa or the Caribbean countries, respectively.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF2244769E65F4BFE82A012BA3085931A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Investments by the African Diaspora in certain issuers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Securities and Exchange Commission shall issue rules to treat a member of the African Diaspora who is not an accredited investor as an accredited investor for purposes of the securities laws with respect to securities offered or sold by an issuer, if—</text><paragraph id="H083F2A12D6EA4B7BA374D622F0ABF82C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States International Development Finance Corporation or another qualified development finance institution holds an investment in the issuer, as determined by the Commission;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37F76572766A4F628491AC9658174211"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no more than 25 percent of the total funds raised by the issuer in the applicable offering of securities is purchase by members of the African Diaspora in reliance on this subsection; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47B70F9DE6ED455183B105246DBD23BE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the issuer discloses to the public the amount of securities, in the aggregate, purchased by members of the African Diaspora in reliance on this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B83FB81733648D9B1925AEC2A9B34A5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special window for diaspora-Led investment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the program described in subsection (a), the Chief Executive Officer of the United States International Development Finance Corporation shall, using applicable authorities provided by the BUILD Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9601">22 U.S.C. 9601 et seq.</external-xref>), establish a special window to provide support to diaspora-led investment funds, social enterprises, and infrastructure projects in African and Caribbean countries.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5E15D835A5624DDDBFE124C48B08BDDD"><enum>5.</enum><header>Diaspora infrastructure bond framework</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury and the United States International Development Finance Corporation are authorized to provide support for the issuance of diaspora bonds by African and Caribbean nations through credit enhancement, technical assistance, and co-marketing with diaspora investment vehicles.</text></section><section id="H0693B7DDC4174749B1DB7328018EF43B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Market expansion for remittance providers</header><subsection id="H23D3182E5B4047A2BDE43E3CC6501609"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Removing regulatory barriers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall issue rules to remove undue regulatory barriers applicable to remittance providers that—</text><paragraph id="H7A895D5C19A84EBD8DBE5AB71228685D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are owned by members of the African Diaspora; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE3041236E06489A850713096B1A78B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are fintech-driven.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H82DCEEF55FA845FCB54DD3875B7255C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Remittance Innovation Fund</header><paragraph id="H87A3B0C387284FCD9B296BC9F95B695B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Treasury a fund to be known as the <quote>Remittance Innovation Fund</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EE4995021D84AFF944977CC1470B869"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall use amounts in the Remittance Innovation Fund to promote low-cost, secure, and traceable financial transfers by—</text><subparagraph id="H800C4D9F22F745729FC0A43815F5A25B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing technical support to remittance providers described in subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D94A0DD9F6F4329A264B45E400F2CEF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing seed funding to persons seeking to establish a remittance provider described in subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2A39CCF02ACE40F5A18E9068AAF981C1"><enum>7.</enum><header>Deduction for remittances used for qualified purposes</header><subsection id="H26FFA11FB3D7450998A6710FA731CEB9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part VII of subchapter B of chapter 1 of subtitle A of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 223 the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H83341D7D3BD54EA29639B1A92C73A361" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HE6E7FE8A1F394A2D8151BC01127F6DB5"><enum>223A.</enum><header>Deduction for remittances used for qualified purposes</header><subsection id="H7514421C65544D529667503C0A19FFD9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deduction allowed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual there shall be allowed as a deduction an amount equal to so much of the qualified remittance transfers made by the taxpayer to recipients residing in a covered country during the taxable year as do not exceed $3,000.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6554E01EC1A148519AEEF87C125410C0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified remittance transfer</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>qualified remittance transfer</term> means a remittance transfer which is used by the recipient for housing, agriculture, education, healthcare, or small enterprise support.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE9828D16837E449EBB77D4351BFD46AB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered country</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>covered country</term> means a member state of the African Union or a member state of the Caribbean Community (CARICOM).</text></subsection><subsection id="H82E11E45ED1F465D99C3C49E417200DE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC79AEBFC9C4E4747B81597248E358494"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for part VII of subchapter B of chapter 1 of subtitle A of such Code is amended by inserting the following new item after the item relating to section 223:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H59943CB8D5394EBF85EAE925864552DE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="yes-regeneration"><toc-entry idref="HE6E7FE8A1F394A2D8151BC01127F6DB5" level="section">Sec. 223A. Deduction for remittances used for qualified purposes.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H49ECB4537E064B708B889B61F40F9BF2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to remittances made after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H57396ADCD5BD48FCBA8B5FB3FF937647"><enum>8.</enum><header>Exclusion of income attributable to certified diaspora investments</header><subsection id="H64063F61A4014D73B9703E0F3C4AFA2E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 1 of subtitle A of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subchapter:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB099C08A4D924CB4A9A97010640A8431" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subchapter id="H8DEE3FD6D93143A2B5F85246625CCF92"><enum>AA</enum><header>Certified diaspora investments</header><toc container-level="subchapter-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H8DEE3FD6D93143A2B5F85246625CCF92" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H3776A6BCC66A4726B2108DE871159046" level="section">Sec. 1400AA. Certified diaspora investments.</toc-entry></toc><section id="H3776A6BCC66A4726B2108DE871159046"><enum>1400AA.</enum><header>Certified diaspora investments</header><subsection id="H9AD30A23D0F74715B04BA8A9615A1D02"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a certified diaspora investment—</text><paragraph id="H5E6E03511A8B4D2EA0B1C1120EF7FCE3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>gross income for the taxable year shall not include any dividend or interest payments received with respect to such investment, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE33FD06E5CE44F89AF37FB9AB9FF36CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the basis of such property shall be equal to the fair market value of such investment on the date that the investment is sold or exchanged.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4981361EA8B481791141B2204AD5474"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The sum of the amount of payments taken into account under paragraph (1) of subsection (a) and the amount of the increase in basis of assets of the taxpayer under paragraph (2) of such subsection for any taxable year may not exceed $12,000.</text></subsection><subsection id="H31C6F68AAE31440386B9A87CCB07B855"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified diaspora investment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section the term <term>qualified diaspora investment</term> means any equity, debt, or blended capital investment in a company or project based in a covered country (as defined in section 223A) and duly registered with such country’s securities authority or channeled through a fund recognized by a United States development finance institution.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5F5A5E46EB7243448B549090D3AC0D80" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><paragraph id="H18D7695CD7414069B15A99A6A0953DCC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any taxable year beginning after 2025, the $12,000 amount in subsection (b) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text><subparagraph id="H501EB2B5C45448B28342CB7EBECF0E2A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD791588D53F847A09175BD77399C62B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2024</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB33E9413714473CA283E62C73DF0E6B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>If any increase under paragraph (1) is not a multiple of $100, such increase shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $100.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H91117151ABE7480E98A2C73C727E6881" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H2378BD36F5CA49FAA8CCE8AD11E08E5F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of subchapters for chapter 1 of subtitle A of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to subchapter Z the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9B1E8B2AB09442E0A2B833E57DA97E30" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Subchapter AA. Certified diaspora investments.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H07F385A9A3504890946DAFDD995B0A9E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to investments made after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HEB7F772DDCDA44829E02301428FD3908"><enum>9.</enum><header>Repeal of remittance excise tax</header><subsection id="HF89469F10EAC4568B6106076B35E91C9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/36">Chapter 36</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by repealing subchapter C (and the table of subchapters for such chapter is amended by striking the item relating to such subchapter).</text></subsection><subsection id="H7665B1C6EDEB4E5395F3E764CB34161E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to transfers made after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section><section id="H76E837AD23E947179A1633826A5A88F5"><enum>10.</enum><header>Report</header><subsection id="HC7260C349A3149149E291906C0DA2EA0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual report required</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury, acting through the Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve, and the Secretary of State, in consultation with the stakeholders described in subsection (b), shall submit to the relevant congressional committees a report that addresses—</text><paragraph id="HC2FFC0EF5841420097E20A3AADBDE39E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>progress toward and a strategy for encouraging remittance and reducing transaction costs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B672AF5255D4DAF919AF2F3F51972B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>remittance cost trends and barriers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC52ADF45E1348648E0D0E761612A0A6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>impact of United States tax policy on diaspora investments;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H95075A30141C4890A9F7DDBC2E5DA11D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>institutional collaboration with African governments, governments of Caribbean countries, and diaspora-led ventures;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A13A0CC73544E3AB4B7BF7CCFA2908A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>uptake and effectiveness of financial instruments created under this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29EFA0B257654D8D922260CCB20CB232"><enum>(6)</enum><text>challenges and obstacles associated with achieving the aforementioned goals; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EFD32753E024FC285610A6EFEC784FD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>recommendations relating to programmatic or appropriations measures that could potentially enhance the implementation of the strategy, including legislative or executive policy changes for such enhanced implementation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H177324CAE63049D487E7F60A1EE844C4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultations</header><text>In developing the report required by this section, the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of State shall, as appropriate and practicable, consult with—</text><paragraph id="H56BCC2C894444E59A748DD996E6A2FB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>stakeholders in the United States and in Africa and Caribbean from the private sector, civil society, and African diaspora;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E36948A46A2400CADE0E5AD3310FA55"><enum>(2)</enum><text>relevant agencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7C182F298E44CE9AA9DDF5728EB7AAB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>State, local, and Tribal governments; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1C4E29304364E79AC501EE613ED41E2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>other relevant United States development agencies and entities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED01F9E234C2435E812F73068C5BEAE9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 10 years after the date of the submission of the initial report required by subsection (a), the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that assesses progress over the preceding decade of the strategy. Such report shall also include the following:</text><paragraph id="H1FC3EFAD7ECA4B02AD9FC80CCAB3A3BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of the progress made in the implementation of the strategy over the preceding decade with respect to each of the goals described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90712CC131CC45669DB4CD7FD9DB31A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the successes, challenges, and effectiveness of the strategy and its implementation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC331200683574D909CC5667EA9D4E392"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Recommended legislative or executive policy changes relevant to addressing any gaps, policy or program shortcomings, or other outstanding challenges relating to the goals of the strategy, along with descriptions of prospective follow-up activities necessary to address such challenges.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19ED56D74D2B4E878211B36918D1CF2B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recommendations relating to programmatic or appropriations measures that could potentially enhance the implementation of the strategy, including legislative or executive policy changes for such enhanced implementation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1FF08F1746C5472FAD6AE5D24FFF6D20"><enum>11.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H2ABB9CC3630B4137A91F9157789B71A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HBD9C63ED2601400B87ADF2B470EA7C76"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Ways and Means, and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2C52BF91D204D8E9BC8DFF640D0C2D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Finance, and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H553345BD410A40EF98E75A19C4DEE316"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Africa</header><text>The term <term>Africa</term> means the 54 countries recognized by the African Union.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66395AA348574D3CBD7AA75479A64C10"><enum>(3)</enum><header>African diaspora</header><text>The term <term>African Diaspora</term> means individuals of African or Caribbean descent residing outside their countries of origin, including first-generation immigrants and descendants.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE7EDD909D5948D7A250B44643CA7425"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Caribbean countries</header><text>The term <term>Caribbean countries</term> means the 15 countries of the Caribbean Community (CARICOM).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD537BCE125514A969855FA401D498770"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Remittances</header><text>The term <term>remittances</term> means personal transfers made across borders for family support or micro-investment, and does not include corporate or institutional capital flows.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

