<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HC9078F8F4A294308A192959612C90A20"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4804 IH: To authorize an annual strategic dialogue to return democratic rule to Belarus, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4804</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250729">July 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize an annual strategic dialogue to return democratic rule to Belarus, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFA1A2EF33C5F4248B6A16DF2644BC8A2"><section id="H24A1CF22F8114F08A7736EC4011CDAA0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>U.S.–Belarus Strategic Dialogue</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State is authorized to facilitate an annual strategic dialogue with the Belarusian democratic movement that seeks to—</text><paragraph id="H1F99140CC5474C64AFEE959A4C0CE04C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consider the efforts needed to return to democratic rule in Belarus, including the efforts needed to support free and fair elections in Belarus;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD150F9EFAA04EC2B95D1617E8A1BF83"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support the day-to-day functions of the Belarus democratic movement, which represents the legitimate aspirations of the Belarusian people;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B5480127B2A4FD89D52CD8F6D20D04C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that Belarusians living outside the territory of Belarus have adequate access to essential services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72F21495BED34803BC294C3A5B286F98"><enum>(4)</enum><text>respond to the political, economic, and security impacts of events in Belarus and Russia on neighboring countries in the wider region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7C82534868043CC9F977922B1AB63F3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>ensure accountability, including through sanctions, for the regime of Alyaksandr Lukashenka for its human rights abuses and support for Russia’s war of aggression in Ukraine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6024D92D568492DB84872492296CC56"><enum>(6)</enum><text>facilitate the release of political prisoners and other wrongfully detained individuals in Belarus including journalists; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78F668E33D9545EEA783FECC20E33E1A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>support Belarusian language and cultural programs, including by supporting Belarusian language independent media programs, and Belarusian civil society, including through efforts to restore democracy and the regular function of democratic institutions in Belarus.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

