<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6F47EFCFAF6C46ECB20FBFB9F379C1AE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2769 IH: American Gas for Allies Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2769</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide that, for a 3-year period, applications for the exportation of natural gas to member countries of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization be granted without modification or delay, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDC5712677E2E40D68FDADD40969AA3D6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H64B7564B24874949946630FB1EA094C1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Gas for Allies Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB01E329632634EECAE38DCA9DBBADA63"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3B0AC5C10A454A70891FEDF031A562D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States has been a critical member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization since 1949.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD8B33698CD514A6686600D4742B6B74A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The North Atlantic Treaty Organization has provided safety and security for the United States and its European allies for decades.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H10F535CAD41146AFA9B61609BCC402BE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ukraine has been a crucial strategic partner for the North Atlantic Treaty Organization since the early 1990’s, and the North Atlantic Treaty Organization has long held that Ukraine’s future includes full membership in the alliance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H273CB4C38B2F4B0AAF543CB752CF2E87"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Russia’s unprovoked 2022 invasion of Ukraine presents a security threat to all the North Atlantic Treaty Organization allies, including the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF89D2BE72DFB4F17B19916ABB64986E5"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The North Atlantic Treaty Organization supports Ukraine’s right to self-defense and its right to choose its own security arrangements.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC62E2E61D2C4024AE2EE223B47EE59C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The United States maintaining a strong partnership with Ukraine is vital to the security of both countries.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA0D9FC31066B440DA58A90021F38942F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Liquified natural gas imported from the United States has provided Ukraine a critical lifeline during Russia’s unprovoked invasion.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E3F9819B07644AF8863D541AA25A469"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A dependable supply of energy is vital to the economic and national security of all of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization countries.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2C70680B007845F98682432EA5995471"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is in the national security interest of the United States for the North Atlantic Treaty Organization countries to acquire energy resources from the United States, rather than foreign adversaries.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H61A347426CD7448697F1F2A58146A867"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The United States National Energy Technology Laboratory has concluded that United States liquified natural gas supplied to Europe has up to 56 percent less total greenhouse gas emissions than European coal, while Russian natural gas delivered to Europe has up to 22 percent more greenhouse gas emissions than European coal.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9CE3231F92144609A2A126E817978B48"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States liquified natural gas industry has contributed more than $400,000,000,000 to United States gross domestic product and supported more than 270,000 United States jobs on average, annually since 2016.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H50D0A55EE8ED4115B016CB284BA89F00"><enum>3.</enum><header>Temporary treatment of certain applications for the exportation of natural gas</header> <subsection id="HAA0AE4B7CD3C4E4DAA5EE0F939BD9F39"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period described in subsection (c) of this section, for purposes of section 3(a) of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717b">15 U.S.C. 717b(a)</external-xref>), the exportation of natural gas to a foreign country described in subsection (b) of this section shall be deemed to be consistent with the public interest, and applications for such exportation shall be granted without modification or delay.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H30297F8401644A62A4F006EE5221C4A2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Foreign countries</header><text>A foreign country described in this subsection is—</text> <paragraph id="HBAA627114EFA4BB1ACC1027FCFDAD609"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a member country of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB09EA38D7BA24A68938B46E3C30FB3D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Ukraine.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H25FBB660B1C647CD835BA4E64546F144"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall apply with respect to applications for the authorization to export natural gas under section 3 of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717b">15 U.S.C. 717b</external-xref>) to a foreign country described in subsection (b) of this section that are pending on the date of enactment of this Act, or filed during the period that begins on such date of enactment and ends on the date that is 3 years after such date of enactment.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

