<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8A1050120EE04D1799FC29296BF8B456" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3705 IH: Fog Observations and Geographic Forecasting Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3705</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250604">June 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere to conduct a project to improve forecasts of coastal marine fog, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB78709AC459B47ABAE8DE87BD7053B1F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9D094816187344409482E6DF6E903F5B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fog Observations and Geographic Forecasting Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB57A430EE7BD49B89C02CA2F835716DA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Project to improve forecasts of coastal marine fog</header> <subsection id="HA90DA1A6677143EB9A6EC895DEBFDABA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere shall conduct a project to improve forecasts of coastal marine fog.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H283B7F9F29E9413AB6BB6CFFF0817BFA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Goal</header><text>The goal of the project required under subsection (a) is to enhance vessel safety and reduce the economic impact of coastal marine fog events, with a focus on—</text> <paragraph id="H59EE7104153B4697AECC660A7066E4C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increasing the number of marine-based observations through additional Federal platforms and commercially acquired observations in locations where impacts from marine fog and reduced visibility have major safety and economic impacts, including through the use of—</text>
<subparagraph id="H2A56EBB88CE94E78A522E307DCAA18E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>buoys;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE0EB3EDADDE344DB961B2D6217522721"><enum>(B)</enum><text>meteorological stations measuring visibility, temperature, dewpoint, and wind speed and direction as a stand-alone or co-located with water level sensors, such as those that are part of the physical oceanographic observation system program of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H38EDBF9F0104423592236009FF199355"><enum>(C)</enum><text>stationary platforms or drifting instruments;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA4D1334EED224C14BE86888E2183CCF0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>vessels;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H493D15589E354DA7B0286DB836DB0196"><enum>(E)</enum><text>unmanned systems;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA262E227D924A358588440E8A8545B8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>remote sensing technologies, including rapid refresh hyperspectral satellite imagery; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H885A97B6A3044BFC93A533B19898A84F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>advanced algorithms that extract actionable information from observational data, including early detection and regular monitoring of marine fog;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFB04FCC0893946B2A2A430C215398595"><enum>(2)</enum><text>advancing geographic coverage, resolution, skill, and accuracy of marine fog modeling, including, when feasible, additional locations and advancements in marine channel forecast capability;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB43983837C9A4EB8A634E0585BE60624"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improving communication of marine fog advisories by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E301990E517468DA6DDC8AD11637C8D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>communicating risks posed by hazardous marine fog events in a way that maximizes informed decision making by the public; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3E268938583C4B2E8F89236C7C6F944F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>providing decision support services based on environmental information that is actionable to the recipient of a marine fog advisory.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3CF36464AC4B44CF9B8CA26AEA0116A9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Stakeholder engagement</header><text>In implementing the project required under subsection (a), the Under Secretary shall meet with public and private stakeholders regarding the planning, development, and implementation of the project.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H7392480E1CC1437DA3881491FB0B0E99"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Tribal engagement</header><text>The Under Secretary shall meet with Indian tribes (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>)) regarding the planning, development, and implementation of the project required under subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCF5655C9D3F1450E809B1186D5FD7852" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Project plan</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary shall develop a plan for the project required under subsection (a) that details the specific research, development, and technology transfer activities, as well as corresponding resources and timelines, necessary to achieve the goal set forth under subsection (b).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

