<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-joint" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-DAV25900-290-P3-L8J"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SJ 51 IS: Providing for congressional disapproval of the proposed foreign military sale to the Government of the United Arab Emirates of certain defense articles and services.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. J. RES. 51</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250515">May 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>) introduced the following joint resolution; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing for congressional disapproval of the proposed foreign military sale to the Government of the United Arab Emirates of certain defense articles and services.</official-title></form><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the following proposed foreign military sale to the Government of the United Arab Emirates is prohibited: </text></section><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H989ECF5139D54D76ADB5C1A2622B7489"><paragraph id="H3097CF3D5718499F8467A0E4F8AB6418"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The sale of the following defense articles and services described in Transmittal No. 25–25, submitted to Congress pursuant to section 36(b)(1) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2776">22 U.S.C. 2776(b)(1)</external-xref>), and published in the Congressional Record on May 13, 2025: The following non-Major Defense Equipment: Common Munitions Built-in-Test Reprogramming Equipment (CMBRE); munitions support equipment; night vision device (NVD) support and spare equipment; spare parts, consumables and accessories; repair and return support; classified and unclassified software delivery and support; classified and unclassified publications and technical documentation; site surveys; studies and surveys; transportation support; U.S. Government and contractor engineering, technical, and logistics support services; aircraft components, spares, and accessories; and other related elements of logistics and program support.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

