<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-NEW25268-VWV-9W-T0T"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 122 IS: Recognizing the contributions of AmeriCorps members and alumni and AmeriCorps Seniors volunteers in the lives of the people and communities of the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 122</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250310">March 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the contributions of AmeriCorps members and alumni and AmeriCorps Seniors volunteers in the lives of the people and communities of the United States.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas 32 years ago Congress established the Corporation for National and Community Service, now known as AmeriCorps—</text><paragraph id="id79211b207697476f90ac908e7a176c39"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to unite national service programs under 1 agency;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98387d85ede24db7a6cc05c0d5d3b4ac"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to create service opportunities that strengthen communities; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2fadc73c033d436496c8fc7f33893a00"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to expand pathways to education, careers, and civic participation for those who serve;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since their inceptions, AmeriCorps and AmeriCorps Seniors national and community service programs have proven to be highly effective ways—</text><paragraph id="idcb0415d981a34aa798e593a7970614e5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to unite and engage the people of the United States in meeting a wide range of local and national needs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc045286749ed45dcba05ab9feddb3cf6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to promote greater civic engagement; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id98b2c6a5a87841f298793b08ca6c4a87"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to provide pathways to education and careers;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas each year 200,000 individuals serve in AmeriCorps and AmeriCorps Seniors at nearly 40,000 locations across the United States to give back in an intensive way to communities, States, territories, Tribal nations, and the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas AmeriCorps and AmeriCorps Seniors funds have been invested in nonprofit, community, educational, and faith-based organizations, as well as local governments and Tribal nations, and those funds have—</text><paragraph id="id75a4fd8cfaf149a3bc67fa351621bbb5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>leveraged hundreds of millions of dollars in outside funding and in-kind donations each year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5ca83e1acb914004a6bc75079cdd3e92"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expanded the capacity of local and national programs to deliver on missions that strengthen the communities of the United States;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas AmeriCorps members and AmeriCorps Seniors volunteers have provided millions of hours of service across the United States, helping—</text><paragraph id="id5293c75ff9c544d4b8bc18e192035d70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to improve the lives of the most vulnerable people of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id90ec940f4f4c441f9e5d34dfbc86e6a0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to protect the environment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7077d1e163674e0eaa3fd7f69e45b90b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to contribute to public safety;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id742dd9a373e54bae802ea9ad4a6289df"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to respond to disasters and public health emergencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2216786ba023438fb4a3db13ac72b30b"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to strengthen the educational system of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1f76709c888545eb96e0831fcfdcc3aa"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to expand economic opportunity for all;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas service in AmeriCorps promotes bridge-building, collaboration, and leadership skills, and AmeriCorps programs bring the people of the United States together from different backgrounds, generations, and geographic locations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas AmeriCorps funds, conducts, and disseminates research on the civic health of the United States and the return on taxpayer investment in national service programs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas AmeriCorps members and AmeriCorps Seniors volunteers recruit and supervise millions of community volunteers, demonstrating the value of AmeriCorps as a powerful force for encouraging people to become involved in community service;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for more than 5 decades, millions of AmeriCorps Seniors volunteers in the RSVP, Foster Grandparent, and Senior Companion programs have played an important role in strengthening communities by sharing their experience, knowledge, and accomplishments with the individuals they serve;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, over the past 30 years, nearly 1,300,000 individuals have taken the AmeriCorps pledge to <quote>get things done for America</quote> by becoming AmeriCorps members through the AmeriCorps State and National, AmeriCorps VISTA, and AmeriCorps NCCC programs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas AmeriCorps members throughout the United States, in return for completing their service terms, have earned more than $4,500,000,000 to use to further their own educational advancement and career readiness at colleges and universities across the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas AmeriCorps is a proven pathway to employment, providing members with valuable career skills, experience, and contacts to prepare them for the 21st-century workforce;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas leaders across political parties and ideologies recognize the value that national service provides to their communities and country, leveraging the power of AmeriCorps members and AmeriCorps Seniors volunteers to meet the most urgent and pressing needs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas national service programs have engaged millions of people in the United States in results-driven service in the most vulnerable communities of the United States including in rural, urban, and suburban communities, providing hope and help to individuals with economic and social needs; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas AmeriCorps Week, observed from March 9 through March 15, 2025, is an appropriate time for the people of the United States—</text><paragraph id="id8c8d6ab2d57846b692c9ee8e4a6d502b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to salute current and former AmeriCorps members and AmeriCorps Seniors volunteers for their positive impact on the lives of people in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb38bbb5e9ed84f569e8d6d46baf2c4a0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to thank the community partners of AmeriCorps and AmeriCorps Seniors for making the programs possible;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcc77331391054e969a32d750671506c5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to encourage more people in the United States to become involved in service and volunteering; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2d7d009fa6df4989a0a21ed2293a3557"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to celebrate the lasting impact of AmeriCorps and AmeriCorps Seniors programs over the last 30 years: Now, therefore, be it </text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id45b44e9d43a8492dbaf19f2107c242f8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to join in a national effort—</text><subparagraph id="idd0b082e088434689ada821fc13108c0d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to salute AmeriCorps members and alumni and AmeriCorps Seniors volunteers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc9cf6eb5e4514b9faceeef2a40433eb8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to raise awareness about the importance of national and community service;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf5201c3c7be6444a8f026ecb69d85131"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acknowledges the significant accomplishments across a 30-year history of the volunteers, members, alumni, and community partners of AmeriCorps and AmeriCorps Seniors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3c55d2d0c58743cfbc41989a642ebb04"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the important contributions made by AmeriCorps members and alumni and AmeriCorps Seniors volunteers to the lives of the people of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idab8b8c67f43b454c83becb41680e759a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages individuals of all ages to consider opportunities to serve in AmeriCorps and AmeriCorps Seniors. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

