<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H33C20EE603FD4F0C860FD039EA2DAEE1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5270 IH: Stress Testing Accountability and Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5270</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to issue rules to establish certain methodologies and scenarios used in stress testing, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEB5D7B3A1C5942C798613021E4C75268" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA89218183AE5434C9DD66EF2C27404C4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stress Testing Accountability and Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H8BDF6FB4C76D4CFF8C400301C2CAEF4A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rulemaking related to stress capital buffer requirements</header> 
<subsection id="HD327CBA92766493CA02B588B2BE8658D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Board</quote>) shall issue a rule to establish any models, assumptions, formulas, or other decisional methodologies that are used to determine any component or subcomponent of the stress capital buffer requirement for a bank holding company.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H765F197715D04E96BDFACB483D422EDD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Changes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board may only make changes to the rule issued under subsection (a) through notice and comment rulemaking.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H973F5AAE6D4B49478C446ED6727E4341">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>No double-Count</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall ensure no double-count of capital requirements for the same risks in the stress capital buffer requirement and the risk-based capital requirements.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H55022AD7D25C4160AE63707D16ACAD0D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Stress capital buffer requirement defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>stress capital buffer requirement</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 225.8(d) of title 12 of the Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H50A7BF9ADEBB4D24BCEDCD117EC78648"><enum>3.</enum><header>Rulemaking relating to stress testing</header> <subsection id="HE1637C429E1C4815841107E34ABF4423"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning in the first calendar year beginning after the date of the enactment of this section, the Board shall, not less than 30 days before conducting a stress test pursuant to section 165(i) of the Financial Stability Act of 2010, issue a rule to establish each scenario to be used in such stress test.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFDD169DE3EA34A728892D3B2D8167ECE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board may not, by rule or otherwise, subject any nonbank financial company to a climate-related stress test using the authority provided in section 165(i) of the Financial Stability Act of 2010.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H7788145A71FF4A0089565A35219A2226"><enum>4.</enum><header>GAO report</header> <subsection id="H9377D23D931143C5959A9CD81046EDEF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall, every 3 years, conduct a study and submit a report to the Congress with respect to the stress tests conducted by the Board under section 165(i) of the Financial Stability Act of 2010 in the 3 most recent calendar years.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBF0A030C6F424837865F8663B4A6C201"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report submitted to the Congress under subsection (a) shall consider the effectiveness of the stress tests in evaluating—</text> <paragraph id="HD578C914898543C28F7BDE26CFFBCC8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the safety and soundness of the nonbank financial institutions subjected to stress tests;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H38EADE5153FD4CD6A0E7C194186646EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the stability of the United States financial system.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

