<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H11951FAF82A94288B75F6C9C0586F2C5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 646 IH: Build Housing with Care Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 646</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250123">January 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001094">Ms. Hoyle of Oregon</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000635">Ms. Dexter</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a grant program to address the crises in accessing affordable housing and child care through the co-location of housing and child care, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFC639BF8BF654FB59DA41AABF94A4B83" style="OLC"><section id="HB616C4DE38F0490D894260C4E76EE501" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Build Housing with Care Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8557584906F84E99B6ABEB7017852B9F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to expand access to affordable housing and child care through the establishment of a grant program to promote the co-location of housing and child care providers.</text></section><section id="HBCF2776B68BE42978BEF4A14C4D23921"><enum>3.</enum><header>Housing and child care provider co-location grant program</header><subsection id="H5C4D006BFB0143348A50A972A05AF8D3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall establish a program (hereafter in this section referred to as <quote>the Program</quote>) to award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to facilitate the design, planning, construction, conversion, retrofitting, preservation, or renovation of a co-location facility.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0A353E389EB84BB38756C2D299A7D3D1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing the Program, the Secretary shall consult with—</text><paragraph id="H16B29AE17E674533A5C2DCA6C793AD21"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Assistant Secretary of the Administration for Children and Families;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H62E8E727D948482FA1F4AFCF8560133E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Treasury, acting through the Director of the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAEAAAB519B9481FAD4EC88E6D1248AA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Under Secretary for Rural Development.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF816B9A932FD4991A98CC2CB54493397"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under the Program, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary determines appropriate, including the following:</text><paragraph id="H3F221C54FD244B8EAF32DA1234111D9C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A certification that the eligible child care provider associated with such application is eligible to receive vouchers or assistance under the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9857">42 U.S.C. 9857 et seq.</external-xref>), or in the case of an application to construct a new facility, or an application when the eligible entity intends to subgrant or capitalize amounts provided, a commitment to—</text><subparagraph id="HD6B1AED256FB43C2A2A48702A1561988"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish a partnership with an eligible child care provider not later than 1 year after the date on which funding is received;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA539E69F49924AC8A2743D5835732164"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit to the Secretary a certification of such eligibility of said provider to receive vouchers or assistance under the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9857">42 U.S.C. 9857 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1030D95577FB44EC96B25EBD336A3E6C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">clearly establish a project pipeline, and submission of a certification to the Secretary that a child care provider associated with a co-location facility project receives vouchers or assistance under the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9857">42 U.S.C. 9857 et seq.</external-xref>) or the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</external-xref>). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H77CFB8157A494DE28ECECF4707439924"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A certification that activities funded by grant amounts will not result in the eviction of residents of the housing facility associated with such application.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H293544A62DA645D090B745A01D09E6D9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of a plan to inform and engage residents of the housing facility associated with such application about the proposed use of grant amounts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51D0DA7E6969413882BE14AD1B284616"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A certification of compliance with required Federal, State, and local environmental laws and State and local land use policies, unless the eligible entity—</text><subparagraph id="H2074FB710CF5466E973282866138FB64"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">intends to use grant amounts to facilitate the planning or design required for permit approval; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B1EB60107B94C78B25D8665AE1FFC87"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrates that the construction, preservation, conversion, retrofitting, or renovation of an existing facility does not require environmental review.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5DF8B3639BD42A3A708F0300476C729"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A business plan for the eligible child care provider associated with such application, submitted at the time of application or not later than 1 year after the date on which the application is submitted, including—</text><subparagraph id="H66845AA950D84336AFCBAB5B38672563"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a budget or, in the case of a new eligible child care provider, a proposed budget;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB857079171274834BFD1AA20D262F82A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">appropriate State and local licensing or, in the case of a new eligible child care provider, a copy of the application of such provider for appropriate State and local licensing; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73DD3D9E7A1F4B09A355E72AFAA2F7AC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">copies of contracts between such provider and a local, county, regional, State, or Federal governmental entity, to facilitate—</text><clause id="HDB9A641AFE484C19ACAB90084231BA40"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the business operations of such provider; or</text></clause><clause id="H3B242BF63420418E90579E0C079D74B1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the enrollment of children from low-income families with such provider.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H237E2AE6B1BC4861B97F235E58B055EC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Awarding of grants</header><paragraph id="H5E7CDFEFACF941D8AE78B257F52C90CA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under the Program, the Secretary shall give priority to each eligible entity that demonstrates that the eligible child care provider associated with the application of such entity will—</text><subparagraph id="HE73F214B85054A87BE01692048B68CB4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">operate in a child care desert, in a low-income community, or a rural area as determined by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77E7BA2261234E63A9C6AA17709DD5DA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certify designation as a Head Start provider, Early Head Start Provider, Migrant and Seasonal Head Start Provider, American Indian and Alaska Native Head Start Provider, or enroll at least 10 percent of children from very-low income families; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A413B2D70AE43719B20BEE2A97ACB11"><enum>(C)</enum><text>demonstrate a partnership with a community development financial institution, including through the provision of financial or technical assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA1D1046AA5D4D92BA3A9A4835EE12EE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity may be awarded not more than $10,000,000 under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2278937B5C94409C8F11B01BE6752790"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of amounts</header><paragraph id="H98228D11F2DC48A0B8C662AA2FE3D8BC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity may only use grant amounts provided under the Program to facilitate the design, planning, construction, acquisition, preservation, conversion, retrofitting, long-term leasing, or renovation of a new or existing co-location facility.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC9825D385C646028D9FF814199C675F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity receiving a grant under this section may distribute grant amounts to a government entity, a nonprofit organization that develops housing, a public housing agency, a Tribally designated housing entity, or other appropriate entity as determined by the Secretary, to carry out activities in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71E8167BD79C4B6CA0930E26E0ABD4B0" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A community development financial institution receiving a grant under this section may capitalize amount received to create financial products, including loans, to carry out activities in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C534AE73DC949C7BBF4885016C0E6C3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An eligible entity may use—</text><subparagraph id="HDB8FDED71FB64031A810994F325C102A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not more than 10 percent of amounts awarded to facilitate the pre-development phase of a new facility, including planning and design; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3E1C35F4B7E4DA18983EF8FDDB182A3" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not more than 10 percent of amounts awarded to partner with a community development financial institution that provides technical assistance and capacity building to help the eligible entity to submit applications to the Program, support an eligible child care provider that is home-based with meeting relevant State and local licensing and quality standards, and conduct pre-development activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFB7EFA0ECEE744EC9A3AEFF89FEF4FFD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Assistance</header><text>The Secretary shall provide technical assistance and publish best practices online to facilitate the operation of co-location facilities.</text></subsection><subsection id="H640B8B5D2B8C42ABAF7B43DE085EF16A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for the duration of the Program, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committees on Financial Services and Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate regarding the implementation of the Program, including—</text><paragraph id="HE152FE4B98E945A2B3458E4274BD111D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of grants awarded;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H182D8FFC7C0B43FA820E03CF06300C7E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the activities funded;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70C6ABA499024C249F83AB9235CC3D54"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of child care slots created, including the number of child care slots serving children from low-income families or children who are dual language learners;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD790D3355FD40808B296E9390DA349B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of child care slots preserved that were at risk of elimination due to a child care center closing or proposed price increases; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5370DFCF45334D0A923C8C6CD6507ACE"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number and percentage of residents in a co-location facility that use or are employed by the associated child care program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H179CC966149E433C89A6734BB22C7343"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the number of staff employed by the child care provider; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC596F2D24D94D6C83B10460050734AF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>demographic data of residents of housing facilities associated with the Program; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B51B2D40EE9416CAC0C0120AE642866" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number and type of projects facilitated through eligible uses of amounts described in subsections (e)(2) and (e)(3);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE150E122045049C8A2D09A6510CFC1F1" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of early childhood providers supported with funds from the program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21024600661F4EA984FCBF5E00429B22"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of eligible entities of each type that receive grant funding under the Program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD3BA2AE46EF04C6DA0EBBBC632B89E48"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2030.</text></subsection><subsection id="H94446DB8BF794DBB89F090652372E1B1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H8918BB7897C044E2AA8BA051B966ED06"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Caregiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>caregiver</term> has the meaning given such term in section 658P of the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9858n">42 U.S.C. 9858n</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67188563A844463B80D17B4AF31879FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible child care provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible child care provider</term> has the meaning given that term under section 658P of the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9858n">42 U.S.C. 9858n</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A96FB88F9164307A37AD336F0E17938"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Child care desert</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>child care desert</term> means a census tract that contains not less than 3 times more children than the licensed child care providers in such census tract have the capacity to care for, or a census tract where there are no licensed child care providers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H000B1569E9714708A7EA68FBD37D8D0B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Co-location facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>co-location facility</term> means a housing facility that contains an eligible child care provider within, on the premises of such facility or nearby such facility, where such provider serves the residents of such housing facility.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H470822161DD64B10B44195247A0C0190"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Community development financial institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community development financial institution</term> has the meaning given such term in section 103 of the Community Development Banking and Financial Institutions Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4702">12 U.S.C. 4702</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B8708C4AF0D42D18D6296CAEF02D446"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Community Development Corporation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community development corporation</term> has the same meaning as when used in the Cranston-Gonzalex National Affordable Housing Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H839D5A8205544AA7957F5726A935378F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Community housing development organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community housing development organization</term> has the meaning given in the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act of 1990.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6864847D42A3471CB6CA01FAA52A6373"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HB57BE638C7FF4EEEA0F4067D37E50F81"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a community development financial institution;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H105D36CFE6BC470CAEA1C9DD2B581D10"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an eligible child care provider;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE849D6D5222546BAB7C5F0CA529523CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a public housing authority;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC56C55FB397F4B929FA5867611C47C08"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a government entity including a public housing agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67B03D3DBC6D4CCA89581A5473EE2762"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an Indian Tribe or a Tribal organization;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6A017FE0181454196A737617C6DC30E"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a community development corporation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H850083883A294ED7AFE6A7C45974EE81"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a housing developer using—</text><clause id="HC8A27CDBA1C04EE9B87A868BEB828DA1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>low income housing tax credits; or</text></clause><clause id="H0D0802EAA30F4B6D9AFA014B516E032C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>new market tax credits;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11BC58731FE24B0BA3F9E506BBAE22AE"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization that develops housing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6C53B02488344BBB8E59E7E3C40A428"><enum>(I)</enum><text>community housing development organization; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2AFC154F3994F86AAA81DF03485F702"><enum>(J)</enum><text>a consortia of 2 or more entities under this paragraph; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE9FF9517BE14882A148169D81D9B4C4"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">another entity identified as appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5D448A2A53F47C5BEA2F7FBBB235747"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Indian Tribe; Tribal organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>Indian Tribe</term> and <term>Tribal organization</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>) and shall include tribally designated housing entities (as such term is defined in section 4 of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4103">25 U.S.C. 4103</external-xref>)) and entities that serve Native Hawaiians (as such term is defined in section 338K(c) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254s">42 U.S.C. 254s(c)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC19EBB540AAA42468AE1A049A30380D6"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Low-income family</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>low-income family</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3(b) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H523756F5DC6B485B9A0560FAA9A51FD7"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Public housing agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>public housing agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3(b)(6) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)(6)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C8013A506BA4F6EB8D11E76EEB9073D"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Very low-income family</header><text>The term <term>very low-income family</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3(b) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB47D868EE9134BAEBCD9C3CEE8A07E00"><enum>4.</enum><header>GAO study and report regarding child care access for residents of public housing</header><subsection id="H13A6FAFC0F964DB891576E03BD721024"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study regarding the availability and affordability of child care for residents of public housing dwelling units, that shall include—</text><paragraph id="HB685950E680543A6B1D97A759A2C2C84"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of how amounts from the following programs have been used by eligible child care providers to establish, renovate, or improve facilities—</text><subparagraph id="HD2364E61313844B09A7CCA145E11835F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Community Development Block Grant funds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BAA8BA3C69140619B5EAD5C1956F780"><enum>(B)</enum><text>New Market Tax Credits;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3ECEF69D61384A5486762573C96217E6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Community Development Financial Institution Program funds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53F95D5DFB044CB88F7BBB8866DA0446"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Low Income Housing Tax Credits;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H547F93FE59624776A3395869A4FD33AC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Capital Management Fund funds; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4850BDDA7F084559A520C5EFF311E146"><enum>(F)</enum><text>HOME Investment Partnerships Program funds;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE16B2735E07B47658203C86D6335F8FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evaluation of the effects of housing and child care costs on the economic outlook of residents of public housing dwelling units;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BDB726A5B07406C9815A6522FAAD92F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an evaluation of what percentage of residents of public housing dwelling units are both—</text><subparagraph id="HD842A2DF44354507B209AFE279BFF588"><enum>(A)</enum><text>cost-burdened, as defined by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD15B0A2CCF5D4312B0F8D3697B60AE39"><enum>(B)</enum><text>part of a household where not less than 7 percent of the income of such household is spent on child care;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFBC806EF23F470B9B107E4710119EA9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identification and analysis of State or local laws that are barriers to building or maintaining a facility for use by eligible child care providers within or near a public housing dwelling unit;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H238B915ED49541D18C29E7D74A80377C"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of how housing assistance provided under the program for rental assistance under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f</external-xref>) affects the ability of residents of public housing dwelling units to afford child care and other essential expenses, including—</text><subparagraph id="H1205795FF850473E805402381DC26FD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>food;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H325F1CB9E8174ED9BAA6F0A1F9E21EBF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">telecommunications services and equipment such as broadband internet connectivity and cellular phones; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F701D53972143069FE2C33B5C13B68B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>means of transportation such as automobiles, bicycles, or public transportation;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H65EAE823CDD34BAE8E1625A39D34A691"><enum>(6)</enum><text>an evaluation of the efficacy of the Child and Dependent Care Tax Credit, Earned Income Tax Credit, Child Tax Credit, and Dependent Care Flexible Spending Account for residents of public housing dwelling units, including—</text><subparagraph id="H5F642A3C821543E29F470A3B0A228989"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the degree of public knowledge about such programs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8851EB204F3E48F8B07CBADA8A298523"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the degree of success of outreach or public education programs regarding such programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBECEF1ABB4A49B683F3F639CB23EF84"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an assessment of the sufficiency of each program to cover the costs of child care;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2866684E4BA547D38BFBA8E3C630B861"><enum>(7)</enum><text>an evaluation of the extent that residents of public housing dwelling units receive information regarding child care resources from Federal agencies or public housing agencies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H763BF20E6DE3458B81A8FBD3151A71E6"><enum>(8)</enum><text>recommendations to improve access to child care within and near public housing dwelling units and to improve awareness of the availability of Federal programs to assist with the costs of housing and child care.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H44A782BCA1034894A0E8C183C3C9541D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit a report to the Committees on Financial Services and Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, describing the results and conclusions of the study required in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H6F2670BF1A6F44D9A83E2BB5548D8848"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="HD9A28D33C689475C9CC5762C36CC9F06"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible child care provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible child care provider</term> has the meaning given such term in section 658P of the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9858n">42 U.S.C. 9858n</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H58C5AF3869144D258E6CE97781477D6C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public housing dwelling unit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>public housing dwelling unit</term> means a dwelling unit assisted under the public housing program under the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437">42 U.S.C. 1437 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6CC36E4AD6A4D51B8B59CEFF288EB70"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public housing agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>public housing agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3(b)(6) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)(6)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

