<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25154-PW0-02-XN9"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S363 IS: Stifling Transnational Operations and Proliferators by Mitigating Activities that Drive Narcotics, Exploitation, and Smuggling Sanctions Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 363</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250203">February 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S434">Mr. Moreno</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To impose sanctions with respect to foreign governments that resist efforts to repatriate their citizens who have unlawfully entered the United States and foreign governments and foreign persons that knowingly facilitate unlawful immigration into the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stifling Transnational Operations and Proliferators by Mitigating Activities that Drive Narcotics, Exploitation, and Smuggling Sanctions Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STOP MADNESS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id57dbb2b4788f4ea0a27622728f3eac93"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="id6098eb6070ee4330ab8a84be3f2bc741"><enum>(1)</enum><text>migrants who have unlawfully entered the United States—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc935f400ba8d446f808eda2da0fceb62"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are a threat to national security; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb24f66b3f22748019cc3854f3d3cf3ab"><enum>(B)</enum><text>should be repatriated to their countries of origin;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb18295a3457f42799fa2f6861f70659a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if a country of origin resists repatriation of its citizens that unlawfully entered the United States, that country should be subject to economic sanctions, denying the country access to the United States financial system; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id669b1dcb103744cf86fa094f3c8086f9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any country, entity, or individual that knowingly facilitates unlawful immigration into the United States should be subject to economic sanctions, denying them access to the United States financial system.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idc87433167f874ef2b19bb047dbd3d35d"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id50761cc701b34d35902213b5bd87945a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id1cd8302a4e7a4cc69a948d98e0a80924"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id05519e8c6ac44715981c3de2682030cf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id866e6df68859460baf0c62e286deb90d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign government</header><text>The term <term>foreign government</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd6d70473ab184ce193199c870045a698"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any governing body or political organization that exercises control over a foreign country or a substantial portion of a foreign country; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc251884331b64924b3c298c95e115f7a"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8360b45176964bd0ae8ddc558b29a831"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a ministry, department, agency, or instrumentality of a body or organization described in subparagraph (A);</text></clause><clause id="id97a1dbec3ef141238e447e673bfa6e2b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an official, representative, or other individual acting on behalf of such a body or organization, including an individual who holds a formal or informal role of authority; and</text></clause><clause id="id2dda339b281240ce9fa58e1cdb7fb003"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an entity—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb7f5722106cf4c4da01d5135dc5f14bb"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">owned or controlled by such a body or organization; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddda39df70bbb450fb2e110f557b203fb"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that acts on behalf of or is directed by such a body or organization.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id91b168e40edc4d8db909b1b1f2d17036"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term>—</text><subparagraph id="ideb413538a21b400e8475f65aea206d07"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an individual or entity that is not a United States person; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0c3573af1d2c4e60865a557112403fdf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a foreign government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idae3f364e76fb4541bdb89eabc4346d58"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Knowingly</header><text>The term <term>knowingly</term>, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person has actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3913cade19d14cc99b96c9cff4492bfa"><enum>(5)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id9324b65b45e84dcaad57972eb524f0c0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef8cfa1c30f84ec1bcd0821f94d3da84"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2ef3d82faa8347a8858bb0bb21e62e19"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an alien lawfully admitted to the United States, including any alien admitted for temporary residence, tourism, or employment, or to pursue a course of study; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbfe95af755b9408096eea0815f26a965"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="idcfd1d979aa4a42a9bc20d5dc89c2e800"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sense of Congress; statement of policy</header><subsection id="id14f5c2c3808f42a48ea5a40e4dc1ba44"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="id703a1ce9c79645e581a415186e847110"><enum>(1)</enum><text>foreign governments that refuse or obstruct the efforts of the United States to repatriate their citizens who have unlawfully entered the United States constitute an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States, and pose a national emergency; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8b587e5610904b0b8cfcf71d70e92f19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>foreign governments and foreign persons that knowingly facilitate unlawful immigration into the United States constitute an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States, and pose a national emergency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8b3cbb1ab4f54ca2b352651b226dd2ea"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States, in order to protect the national security of the United States, to apply economic and other financial sanctions with respect to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76a3948561514654b428f284006f9b8b"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">foreign governments that resist efforts to repatriate their citizens who have unlawfully entered the United States; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida749a51d9792488c9bddecaca99628db"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">foreign governments and foreign persons that knowingly facilitate unlawful immigration into the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idac2e033b19ad4c9d93ce62869091407b"><enum>5.</enum><header>Use of national emergency authorities; reporting</header><subsection id="id4c6b7539dac24de3a3e0a543058bebe4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc371c0da8ec1459c898308482866fe76"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report required</header><paragraph id="id8cc44941a2c8425a89dae1ef94cd1146"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter until the date that is 7 years after such date of enactment, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on actions taken by the executive branch pursuant to this Act and any national emergency declared with respect to the facilitation of unlawful immigration to the United States, including—</text><subparagraph id="id3d2b0d9bfbf14a3a9e53b6dd337a66e4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the issuance of any new or revised regulations, policies, or guidance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9b6f390ad6ca400aaae41f69606d6e4d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the imposition of sanctions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1dbc5496830649feb627aed7abab4e9d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the collection of relevant information from outside parties;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c8da2c5e3394d8891780ffb7e16d1fb"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the issuance or termination of general licenses, specific licenses, and statements of licensing policy by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id75ee6de11f6e4f93b448abab0c5a3571"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any pending enforcement actions; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5adccc2e442d4eb89acd9e56d73772ad"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the implementation of mitigation procedures.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id55ca1dcc0c6246228ae7003b063c1847"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>Each report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include the matters required by subparagraphs (C), (D), (E), and (F) of that paragraph in a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idab4a0b2a851943fba23b0201df2b4ce0"><enum>6.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to efforts to resist repatriation or facilitate unlawful immigration</header><subsection id="ide3cf0fa6a35140cb805022259bd45897"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0525f118fdfa4dd0973e9c159197c7d6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any foreign government the President determines knowingly refuses or obstructs the efforts of the United States to repatriate its citizens who have unlawfully entered the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3B0DEC5E33CC4C43ACB1CB348C84C1D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any foreign government or foreign person the President determines knowingly facilitates unlawful immigration into the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0bb8be8dc8994dbbb179da60b62a718b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The President may, pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>), block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of a foreign government or foreign person described in subsection (a) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></subsection><subsection id="id989bb88a89a141a0b8ae3aa0584bdec8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter until the date that is 7 years after such date of enactment, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on actions taken by the executive branch with respect to the foreign governments and foreign persons identified under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="id582937f6051544f288c6de19b5cfc113"><enum>7.</enum><header>Penalties; waivers; exceptions</header><subsection id="id0f207a9db24445a2ad6ba9d9a70b507a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of this Act or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out this Act shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3cbeb473dcb04d6a988b43e01c7f5a0b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National security waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of sanctions under this Act with respect to a foreign government or foreign person if the President determines that the waiver is in the national security interest of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="id47e707d93ca84ad196923c8709d5a7d5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions for intelligence and law enforcement activities</header><text>This Act shall not apply with respect to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2a81bec035964fe5ba83898a91f38a96"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">activities subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091 et seq.</external-xref>) or any authorized intelligence activities of the United States; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id95829db1b1df41048f527bd014f61745"><enum>(2)</enum><text>activities necessary to carry out or assist law enforcement activity of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

