<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCG25673-0X2-CY-SJH"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2095 IS: Preventing Abusive Routine Tax Nonsense Enabled by Rip-offs Shelters and Havens and Instead Promoting Simplicity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2095</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250617">June 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to improve the rules related to partners and partnerships, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id1414E26C4A9B4B138365900FAD069D6B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Reference, etc</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idca5cebca9bff4431b0dcc46c0d315447"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Abusive Routine Tax Nonsense Enabled by Rip-offs Shelters and Havens and Instead Promoting Simplicity Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PARTNERSHIPS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idca587786da8b436495fb806aa84e9aa2"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise expressly provided, whenever in this Act, an amendment or repeal is expressed in terms of an amendment to, or repeal of, a section or other provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to a section or other provision of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc4cc13061a4e4e1d9bdcf992a59d5817"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="id1414E26C4A9B4B138365900FAD069D6B">Sec. 1. Reference, etc.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id10cd4454ab984e309a2306fe4b5c55e9">Sec. 2. Determination of partner's distributive share.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id6A489F9A3BA5460C9E09AD39FE5E0068">Sec. 3. Allocation of built-in-gains with respect to contributed property.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id50EB9E8F5D5D4398A718FC0AF9D15D61">Sec. 4. Treatment of revalued property.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id0792dcec7dc8416898759537850b8deb">Sec. 5. Repeal of time limitation on taxing precontribution gain.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ida13db0b60a9c464c99e07387238935ed">Sec. 6. Repeal of rules relating to certain liquidating distributions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id118FEE599DEF4C389A84EBF198FA4A7C">Sec. 7. Clarification of rules relating to payments to partners for property or services.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id54DAA1F1DBD04D52AF2DECDD0A169B58">Sec. 8. Elimination of preformation expenditure exception to partnership transaction rules.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id0309F192AEA74A268434560CE1405EE4">Sec. 9. Partnership terminations.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id9602464259784e988c2605f33117b9a1">Sec. 10. Repeal of requirement that inventory be substantially appreciated in certain partnership distributions treated as sale or exchange.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id496AED0CF4D648FFBD2797EE10B1A396">Sec. 11. Treatment of partnership debt.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id9469F92A22B044E3A63FE7875BF8A87F">Sec. 12. Adjustments to basis of partnership property.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HF63B4E1DA4C6481BB523DFC6C8EB8408">Sec. 13. Application of net investment income tax to trade or business income of certain high income individuals.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="IDB34352B1CED54790BA3342A2ED6ED363">Sec. 14. Recognition of gain on transfers to swap funds.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HE143C08A47C04EC8A414BA10D2E0CCA5">Sec. 15. Modifications to treatment of certain losses.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id5828e01105734b2f8acc2480c43c8c0e">Sec. 16. Codification of anti-abuse rule.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10cd4454ab984e309a2306fe4b5c55e9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Determination of partner's distributive share</header><subsection id="id34ADA5EFA69543CFB2DCB698AE7D01C1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/704">Section 704(b)</external-xref> is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE71708D4E19F442D82E6B16A6DB96A6C"><subsection id="id82729ADF01E5464F9927B8BB14F03BAD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination of distributive share</header><paragraph id="id64B130F689494CFD8F2787B57E1F713B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), a partner's distributive share of income, gain, loss, deduction, or credit (or item thereof) shall be determined in accordance with the partner's interest in the partnership (determined by taking into account all facts and circumstances), if—</text><subparagraph id="id1fbbdba1669f494398dbd7f507d31ff4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the partnership agreement does not provide as to the partner's distributive share of income, gain, loss, deduction, or credit (or item thereof), or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfefc8b964f4f496d87e067e6324f881b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the allocation to a partner under the agreement of income, gain, loss, deduction, or credit (or item thereof) does not have substantial economic effect.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id25B646A63CCD491BAA41D30E37C9AC04"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required use of consistent percentage method for certain partners</header><subparagraph id="id17EBAFFF21AD4B8BA20A0B921DC2E911"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter or by the Secretary, in the case of any covered partner which is a partner in a partnership which is a covered partnership for the taxable year of such partnership, such covered partner's distributive share of the covered partnership's applicable items for such taxable year shall be determined using the consistent percentage method.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA491A7A9BD9D4BBAAF0ACD43A15D00D6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered partner; covered partnership</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph—</text><clause id="id78AAF624EA554162B069CEE4075D0613"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Covered partnership</header><text>The term <term>covered partnership</term> means any partnership if, during any day during the taxable year of the partnership—</text><subclause id="id79415387B94B41F9A819190A3154D142"><enum>(I)</enum><text>two or more members of a controlled group (within the meaning of section 267(f)) own (within the meaning of section 267(e)(3)) 50 percent or more of the capital or profits interests in such partnership, or</text></subclause><subclause id="idA137EEFE1D4D4D8AB8DC7574F526F694"><enum>(II)</enum><text>it is a partnership which is specified by the Secretary in regulations or other guidance as being of a type to which this subparagraph applies in order to prevent the avoidance of the purposes of this paragraph.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id4A639B3509CD4AB399A93DFA9D966612"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Covered partner</header><text>The term <term>covered partner</term> means—</text><subclause id="idEB6191F126644CFAAB7F80D3E3A0F21C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of a covered partnership described in clause (i)(I), any partner which is a member of a controlled group described in such clause or any other partner any ownership interest (other than a de minimis interest) in which is held directly or indirectly by a member of such a controlled group, and</text></subclause><subclause id="id4B38600635BB4FB5879FB162A07F224A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of a covered partnership described in clause (i)(II), any partner which meets such specifications as prescribed by the Secretary under the regulations or guidance referred to in such clause.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idAC2C760EF56546F68B388DA866D2DE1C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Reporting rule</header><text>Each covered partnership shall submit to the Secretary, at such time and in such manner as prescribed by the Secretary—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id249d4f2845574b33838a829afde33321"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a statement that such partnership is a covered partnership, and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0149081113a54bacaabeb61e612e30f1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary shall require.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1AAAC20F9A3C4D0E8F514929DC3F2715"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consistent percentage method</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>consistent percentage method</term> means a method under which—</text><clause id="id6d210f5953c546f0bddec72725671f60"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a covered partner’s distributive share of any applicable item of a covered partnership bears the same ratio to the aggregate distributive shares of such item for all covered partners in such partnership (determined without regard to this paragraph) as—</text><subclause id="idA658119DA72B450EA68B7A9E08AA46A0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the covered partner's net equity in the covered partnership, bears to</text></subclause><subclause id="id343341F665284A45A0A83687A0B87BA7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the net equity of all covered partners in the covered partnership, and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id713502d0fe114cb1add696016976c5dd"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the covered partner is allocated the same share of each applicable item of the covered partnership.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">Clause (i) shall only
                  apply to an applicable item if it is included in the distributive share of at
                  least 1 covered partner (determined without regard to this
 paragraph).</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id229C873AAC8A4BCB835A34468746D257"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Net equity</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph—</text><clause id="id4FFEC9AE48CD47569D74DF7E67C9209E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>net equity</term> means, with respect to any covered partner in a covered partnership, the contributed equity of such covered partner, properly adjusted to take into account any revaluation event described in subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), (D), or (F) of subsection (f)(3).</text></clause><clause id="idF19DC0FD2E604BB6B37DCAA0F229A25E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contributed equity</header><text>The term <term>contributed equity</term> means, with respect to any covered partner in a covered partnership, the excess of—</text><subclause id="idDB44FDBFC1714246AF9E74EAF62D0503"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the sum of the value of all property and money contributed by the covered partner (or any predecessor of such partner) to the covered partnership plus the amount of liabilities (within the meaning of section 752) of the covered partnership that are assumed by the covered partner (or any predecessor of such partner), over</text></subclause><subclause id="idF26F8D49DDB345F3B60F9371566AF7E8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the sum of the value of all property and money distributed to the covered partner (or any predecessor of such partner) by the covered partnership plus the amount of liabilities (within the meaning of section 752) of the covered partner (or any predecessor of such partner) that are assumed by the covered partnership.</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">For purposes of this clause, a
                    predecessor of a partner includes any person treated as transferring an interest
                    to such partner in a transaction described in section
 707(d)(1)(A).</continuation-text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBA7F811C7DB84406A5F6A8335707B152"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Applicable items</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>applicable item</term> means, with respect to any partnership, any item of income, gain, deduction, loss, or credit.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF6B78A32498D466C81557B87E34C9E30"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Cross-reference</header><text>For the treatment of covered partners in the event of certain rights or distributions not in accordance with the consistent percentage method, see section 707(d).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idB4D978F80EC44301931EB70E60628C18"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of certain rights and distributions not in accordance with consistent
 percentage method</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/707">Section 707</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9F7ABC0E12264FE0ACDD4F299DBEF962"><subsection id="idF9404EEE3DC0475688CFCEE8C9956068"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deemed transfers in certain cases where certain rights do not reflect partnership distributive share</header><paragraph id="id8C16224B69244A04BA03D31B6D097737"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a covered partner has an excess share with respect to any covered partnership on any applicable date—</text><subparagraph id="id060D7846019247EB91B5549CC35B390B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such partner shall be treated as having received an interest in the partnership in a transaction between 2 or more partners acting other than in their capacity as members of the partnership, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id142A035720084CF1B33D5ED9AB831D61"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter—</text><clause id="id8D05C009927642C39CD97BCCBEFB6E50"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the value of such interest shall be included in the gross income of the covered partner receiving such interest in such transaction, and</text></clause><clause id="idE80594868C6B494C97F6B38FE6F2EC88"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>no deduction or loss shall be allowed with respect to such transfer to any covered partner treated as transferring all or a portion of such interest in such transaction.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idD69EDBDD63E5404B9EC76818CC9F16D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Excess share</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="idF96B8512C6E145E7A4F6D92E9B256C53"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>excess share</term> means, with respect to any covered partner, the amount by which—</text><clause id="id9c154446755f4efa89de91d4d7989106"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the covered partner’s interest in partnership assets distributable to such covered partner upon liquidation of the covered partnership as of any applicable date, exceeds</text></clause><clause id="id4e4c31bef9bc4f428929ef646d9ffba5" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the covered partner’s interest in partnership assets, determined as if the amount distributable upon liquidation to all covered partners as of such applicable date were distributable to each covered partner based on the ratio of—</text><subclause id="id32D2C0CE401843B2AE9EEAB3E00F62BC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such covered partner's net equity (as defined in section 704(b)(2)(D)) in the covered partnership on such applicable date, to</text></subclause><subclause id="id2CC5527591704BDDBBEC7B83E71ED61B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the net equity (as so defined) of all covered partners in the covered partnership on such applicable date.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id512A0E09B5074839AE37BA94EFC27DD6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicable date</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>applicable date</term> means any of the following:</text><clause id="id3F7A1CB6A7664F119BB4B22D2EA12102"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The last day of any taxable year of the covered partnership.</text></clause><clause id="idB504429B1C2249739E6D01328EF8C26D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The date of any revaluation event (as defined in section 704(f)).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id26C4013FA7CC4AE7B0D92AF847D1521B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered partner; covered partnership</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the terms <term>covered partnership</term> and <term>covered partner</term> have the meanings give such terms under section 704(b)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id457a4e52ba044e3abdab89393ec1b254"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regulations and guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations and other guidance as necessary to carry out the purposes of this subsection, including regulations or other guidance providing exceptions to the application of paragraph (1) to the extent such exceptions are consistent with the purposes of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id99477CCF81484153A158C3D2C6A190A7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations and guidance</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/704">Section 704</external-xref> is amended by redesignating subsection (f) as subsection (g) and by inserting after subsection (e) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE349E9DDE322452C89E959DB6B73181D"><subsection id="idee140ff089914fd4b729f5e88e0b62bf"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations and guidance</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations and other guidance as necessary to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations or other guidance for the application of this section to one or more tiers of entities.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id6D77D2760056401199E92953C6F71291" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting penalties</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6724">Section 6724(d)(1)(B)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of clause (xxvii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of clause (xxviii) and inserting <quote>or</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id11D0B3691A1F409ABBB18821C37929E8"><clause id="idB89136D0B39E4F1597028B8FDE98A681" commented="no"><enum>(xxix)</enum><text>section 704(b)(2)(B)(iii) (relating to reporting rule for required use of consistent percentage method), and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id2555233E968D48DF9B2C491FC6ED3980"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="id50405A159ABF4F0EBEDB7E813C68FE1C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/168">Section 168(h)(6)(B)(ii)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>section 704(b)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 704(b)(1)(B)</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id707B573FC3214A3BB1E88DB4CCB06118" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/514">Section 514(c)(9)(E)(i)(II)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>section 704(b)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 704(b)(1)(B)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id30F5748353D94CBFB46A9C346219C75A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years of partnerships beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="id6A489F9A3BA5460C9E09AD39FE5E0068"><enum>3.</enum><header>Allocation of built-in-gains with respect to contributed property</header><subsection id="idBC60B0E2A64F4E958239197902775877"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subparagraph (A) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/704">section 704(c)(1)</external-xref> is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB735E29E7F43412D833F7BF2213378DC"><subparagraph id="idCDE05D26054049439D4BD168A246C64F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>income, gain, loss, and deduction (including notional items thereof) with respect to property contributed to the partnership by a partner shall be shared among the partners under the remedial method prescribed by the Secretary so as to take into account all of the variation between the basis of the property to the partnership and its fair market value at the time of contribution,</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id8696825A58B1491FB921E4A4CF1BDF0C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to property contributed to a partnership after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="id50EB9E8F5D5D4398A718FC0AF9D15D61"><enum>4.</enum><header>Treatment of revalued property</header><subsection id="idD4A17A81F50C4FA2AAEDEAB0D9AA8691"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/704">Section 704</external-xref>, as amended by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/2">section 2,</external-xref> is amended by redesignating subsections (f) and (g) as subsections (g) and (h), respectively, and by inserting after subsection (e) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2FE2A99534854603B9F45A5D87350C71"><subsection id="id7B182BC39035479DA8D73F0CBAE28C26"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Revalued property</header><paragraph id="id11EE053BB8EE419DB98A907F6D05421C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (1)(A) and (1)(C) of subsection (c) shall apply to any property held by a partnership at the time of a revaluation event.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idCF09A8DB318F4395B68C3D86DBD2AC3A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to any revaluation event which occurs during a taxable year in which the partnership meets the gross receipts test of section 448(c) unless the partnership elects, at such time and in such manner as prescribed by the Secretary, to not have this paragraph apply.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE2FA501ED3DE4EDABD0CB87D9F448EA8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Revaluation event</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>revaluation event</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id1d056bd1742d41779a087c5dbd7f8287"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any disproportionate contribution of money or other property (other than a de minimis amount) to the partnership,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id147ee1c1aa1847efb9a0cf5e0915d5ab"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any disproportionate distribution of money or other property (other than a de minimis amount) by the partnership,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idabb2f14e02384b6c9ab66e7e043c6af1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any grant of an interest in the partnership (other than a de minimis interest) as consideration for the provision of services,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0343374bd1664634b5ed22a534e39d7b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any issuance by the partnership of a non-compensatory option (other than an option for a de minimis partnership interest),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4b78255d601c4b479bb2487ac746cc2f"><enum>(E)</enum><text>except as provided by the Secretary, any agreement to change (other than a de minimis change) the manner in which the partners share any item or class of items of income, gain, loss, deduction, or credit of the partnership, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbb94639d2ff24e86a65523dc7f5451cc"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other event prescribed by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idCA52EF6643B94C26853F59FBC723269A" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Application to tiered entities</header><text>If—</text><subparagraph id="idf7942c5e8b194ef3b8f8f7813917ea7f" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a partnership (hereinafter in this paragraph referred to as the <quote>upper-tier partnership</quote>) is a partner in another partnership (hereinafter in this paragraph referred to as the <quote>lower-tier partnership</quote>), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id89cb8acfcf8c4149912805460a6d206b" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the upper-tier partnership holds more than 50 percent of the capital or profits interests in the lower-tier partnership,</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph" commented="no">then a revaluation event with respect to the upper-tier partnership shall be treated as a revaluation event with respect to the lower-tier partnership.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id3406EC93B1CF482CB27106954851AA9C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="idF2406560B2564FD5B66CA0D923F33050"><enum>(1)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/168">Section 168(h)(6)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>section 704(c)</quote> each place it appears in subparagraphs (B) and (C) and inserting <quote>subsections (c) and (f) of section 704</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2135A589C0D147D3AF4D2A0F76E37F41"><enum>(2)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/514">Section 514(c)(9)(E)(i)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>section 704(c)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (c) and (f) of section 704</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idDE61769C73C9421EA08457322821E57B"><enum>(3)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/613A">Section 613A(c)(7)(D)</external-xref> is amended by inserting after the fourth sentence the following new sentence: <quote>In the case of any revaluation event (as defined in section 704(f)), section 704(f) shall apply in determining such share.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD3EBF410694F4C7FA38EBB457EF83C58"><enum>(4)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/743">Section 743(b)</external-xref> is amended by inserting after the third sentence the following new sentence: <quote>In the case of any revaluation event (as defined in section 704(f)) which occurs before such transfer, section 704(f) shall apply in determining such share.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idDB635FC5A7BA4C699AE628B8A84760CC"><enum>(5)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/897">Section 897(k)(4)(C)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>section 704(c)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>subsections (c) and (f) of section 704</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1315701788F34EC9B08D84EF07683910"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to revaluation events (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/704">section 704(f)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as added by this section) occurring after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="id0792dcec7dc8416898759537850b8deb"><enum>5.</enum><header>Repeal of time limitation on taxing precontribution gain</header><subsection id="idd9c6c1cb80134bda8ca3cbf7cd777c3f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subparagraph (B) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/704">section 704(c)(1)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>within 7 years of being contributed</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="idd87846972d9a44a980ec633700ff9322"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Paragraph (1) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/737">section 737(b)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>within 7 years of the distribution</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="idfe4aecfdd9ba4222a05b3080ef2f92ea"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to property contributed to a partnership after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="ida13db0b60a9c464c99e07387238935ed"><enum>6.</enum><header>Repeal of rules relating to certain liquidating distributions</header><subsection id="id08ea0b1e12a24199aca2ae478aaa1134" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart B of part II of subchapter K of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> is amended by striking section 736 (and by striking the item relating to such section in the table of sections for such subpart).</text></subsection><subsection id="id2ca9149510ec4376b4dc7501ffaed6f9" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Retired partners and successors in interest of deceased partners treated as partners until liquidation</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/761">Section 761(d)</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>For purposes of this subchapter, any retired partner or any deceased partner’s successor in interest shall be treated as a partner until the complete liquidation of such retired partner's or successor's interest in the partnership.</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="id121d50d7dd5d4990ba4f653a0f866227" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="id06667e744b0c4172b3976cebd21f88ab" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/357">Section 357(c)(3)(A)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>payment of which either—</quote> and all that follows through <quote>then, for purposes of</quote> and inserting <quote>payment of which would give rise to a deduction, then, for purposes of</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcd127a4c3a66480b867e4cd740ca27e8" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/731">Section 731(d)</external-xref> is amended—</text><subparagraph id="id602cc9100ff8422babb2ec027fad4469" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 736 (relating to payments to a retiring partner or a deceased partner’s successor in interest),</quote>, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0f65a90a0f2a45468ad0fdf73d83bbdf" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>items), and</quote> and inserting <quote>items) and</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idad2ec415c7f040b29cd7a9aab29c01da" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/751">Section 751(b)(2)</external-xref> is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id39EF59EAE5C44770BAB0CDD47F3146A3"><paragraph commented="no" id="idD816F0FAAA2244BCB2D64559B5C5D6C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to a distribution of property which the distributee contributed to the partnership.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id5ea62e40e4f84fa2af7827d8f73a659d" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idc7f9a23459344d7fb8a0a27c56521a5a"><enum>(A)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/753">Section 753</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>The amount includible</quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote>For treatment of income in respect of a decedent, see section 691.</quote></text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id48d689da81564c34919e8bff137a87cc" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/691">Section 691</external-xref> is amended by striking subsection (e).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1637516b14744af8b8de9d361de16648" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to partners retiring or dying after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="id118FEE599DEF4C389A84EBF198FA4A7C"><enum>7.</enum><header>Clarification of rules relating to payments to partners for property or services</header><subsection commented="no" id="id7710B591B3984DB3B5C1E2BF234BBBB8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/707">Section 707(a)(2)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary—</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided by the Secretary—</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idED3A871F72494E61A4B1B34E813AB123"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to services performed or property transferred after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id7F9B94F24FFC4AE6AD9348C5C3544ADF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No inference</header><text>Nothing in this section or the amendments made by this section shall be construed to create any inference with respect to the proper treatment under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/707">section 707(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to payments from a partnership to a partner for property transferred or services performed on or before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="id54DAA1F1DBD04D52AF2DECDD0A169B58"><enum>8.</enum><header>Elimination of preformation expenditure exception to partnership transaction rules</header><subsection commented="no" id="id22CD7A6248AA41CFB4B26E324828BA49"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/707">Section 707(a)(2)(B)</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>For purposes of the preceding sentence, a transfer of money or other property by a partnership to a partner or by a partner to a partnership will not fail to be characterized as part of a sale or exchange of property because such transfer is made to reimburse the partner or partnership for an expenditure chargeable to capital account (determined without regard to any election under this chapter).</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idB61EE642959E49C4B31299086BB16190"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><paragraph commented="no" id="idEF7E56587BD646AC8EC843CF37BB74BA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to property transferred after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id718e89e44a004612848689f7a843e2b1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Binding contract exception</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall not apply to a transfer of property described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/707">section 707(a)(2)(B)(i)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 if such transfer is pursuant to a written binding contract in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act, and at all times thereafter before the transfer.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="id0309F192AEA74A268434560CE1405EE4"><enum>9.</enum><header>Partnership terminations</header><subsection commented="no" id="id701D81B65E7D47C5BCF048FD7FAE1DF5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/708">Section 708(b)(1)</external-xref> is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="idF0BB5FFDF43B4689BA5D1539A2001906"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>by any of its partners</quote> and inserting <quote>by any of its historic partners (or any related person to any of its partners)</quote>, and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idB24C38ADE35F4CFEA027D99612C11A2D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following sentence: <quote>For purposes of the preceding sentence, a person is a related person to another person if the relationship between such persons would result in a disallowance of losses under section 267 or 707(b).</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id711D54A5B1AE4656A6490C14CDACA580"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="id5090edef75a0474eb91b366a3feeb0cb"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No inference</header><text>Nothing in this section or the amendments made by this section shall be construed to create any inference with respect to the proper treatment under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/708">section 708(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to the activities of persons related (as determined under the last sentence of section 708(b)(1) of such Code, as added by subsection (a)) to partners for taxable years beginning on or before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="id9602464259784e988c2605f33117b9a1"><enum>10.</enum><header>Repeal of requirement that inventory be substantially appreciated in certain partnership distributions treated as sale or exchange</header><subsection id="id2a277a8d53e9461fb22b53418a34e2b9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Clause (ii) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/751">section 751(b)(1)(A)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>which have appreciated substantially in value</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="id0cd3b71d40fa43349a62bf0e38a518a5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/751">Section 751(b)</external-xref> is amended by striking paragraph (3).</text></subsection><subsection id="idc9ef414e0d3e4bb9b2c7d68ac65d5771"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to distributions after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="id496AED0CF4D648FFBD2797EE10B1A396"><enum>11.</enum><header>Treatment of partnership debt</header><subsection commented="no" id="id0F6C10B96C404FA78D916B60A8619679"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/752">Section 752</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69667041751D4A39B57EE22BD73293CA"><subsection commented="no" id="id139E998DB2784CAB994BD45EB46C1C12"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Treatment and allocation of partnership liabilities</header><paragraph commented="no" id="id1C15354E3FF04C36B27D5F9217C22A0C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) or by the Secretary, all liabilities of a partnership shall be allocated among partners in accordance with each partner's share of partnership profits.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id7602C57B85A743188CB6044E930E3C46"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="id9603824836FA4C219886B5F36E4EA4ED"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to bona fide indebtedness of the partnership to a partner or to any related person to a partner. For purposes of the preceding sentence, a person is a related person to another person if the relationship between such persons would result in a disallowance of losses under section 267 or 707(b).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id8222FB887FB24278BDC71517367C2621"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Nonapplication to guarantees</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to any guarantee or similar arrangement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc1e113c2a0314b62adbe8edade17a033"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Regulations and other guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations and other guidance as necessary to carry out the purposes of this subsection, including regulations or other guidance with respect to arrangements that are similar to guarantees for purposes of paragraph (2)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id6E57F3BDA5C14353BC093E752136AEBC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection><subsection id="idD7D76A4C510D4D55B5E484C9F6AC5E36" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment of gain</header><paragraph id="id2F51DD052B4D4E9687835A332C1ED5FD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a taxpayer which recognizes gain by reason of the application of the amendments made by subsection (a) with respect to its first taxable year beginning after December 31, 2025, such taxpayer may elect to pay the net tax liability under this subsection in 6 equal annual installments over the 6-taxable year period beginning with the first taxable year beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3E0AF31943F6421188683A6360A4D63C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Date for payment of installments</header><text>If an election is made under paragraph (1), the first installment shall be paid on the due date (determined without regard to any extension of time for filing the return for the return of tax for the taxable year described in paragraph (1)) and each succeeding installment shall be paid on the due date (as so determined) for the return of tax for the taxable year following the taxable year with respect to which the preceding installment was made.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id169A1DFDC4A54C5B8BBFD5E212F7F4D5" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Acceleration of payment</header><text>If there is an addition to tax for failure to timely pay any installment required under this subsection, a liquidation or sale of substantially all the assets of the taxpayer (including in a title 11 or similar case), a cessation of business by the taxpayer, or any similar circumstance, then the unpaid portion of all remaining installments shall be due on the date of such event (or in the case of a title 11 or similar case, the day before the petition is filed). The preceding sentence shall not apply to the sale of substantially all the assets of a taxpayer to a buyer if such buyer enters into an agreement with the Secretary under which such buyer is liable for the remaining installments due under this subsection in the same manner as if such buyer were the taxpayer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5281682ECC28422FB36B368A79F8F336" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Proration of deficiency to installments</header><text>If an election is made under paragraph (1) to pay the net tax liability under this subsection in installments and a deficiency has been assessed with respect to such net tax liability, the deficiency shall be prorated to the installments payable under paragraph (1). The part of the deficiency so prorated to any installment the date for payment of which has not arrived shall be collected at the same time as, and as a part of, such installment. The part of the deficiency so prorated to any installment the date for payment of which has arrived shall be paid upon notice and demand from the Secretary. This subsection shall not apply if the deficiency is due to negligence, to intentional disregard of rules and regulations, or to fraud with intent to evade tax.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9C96DCAFCEB34725BF82A1C681121BE8" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Election</header><text>Any election under paragraph (1) shall be made not later than the due date for the return of tax for the first taxable year beginning after December 31, 2025 and shall be made in such manner as the Secretary shall provide.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idC3C947FC7D93415197655017C5A7D8C4" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Net tax liability under this subsection</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="id2324D398C8D2462B92B4313306BE6DD1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The net tax liability under this subsection with respect to any taxpayer is the excess (if any) of—</text><clause id="idE408C0CC1ECC4D3B813127C679F4F87C" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such taxpayer's net income tax for the taxable year beginning after December 31, 2025, over</text></clause><clause id="id4E08067EE9E74C4FB3A2820910D3A754" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such taxpayer's net income tax for such taxable year determined without regard to any amount included in gross income by reason of the amendments made by subsection (a).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEA134D10DB4148618E57F1C0F987D9BF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Net income tax</header><text>The term <term>net income tax</term> means the regular tax liability (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/26">section 26</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) reduced by the credits allowed under subparts A, B, and D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8F00F680F944BD68CD9DEECE2C341CD"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Installments not to prevent credit or refund of overpayments or increase estimated taxes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an election is made under paragraph (1) to pay the net tax liability under this subsection in installments—</text><subparagraph id="H8E5B3DA7DE27484080249C1DF109CEFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no installment of such net tax liability shall—</text><clause id="H2BA04759D64E447FB7C62A4AC9B38E5E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a request for credit or refund, be taken into account as a liability for purposes of determining whether an overpayment exists for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6402">section 6402</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 before the date on which such installment is due, or</text></clause><clause id="H240C413377DB422A923168780052505F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for purposes of sections 6425, 6654, and 6655 of such Code, be treated as a tax imposed by section 1 of such Code, section 11 of such Code, or subchapter L of chapter 1 of such Code, and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51390600754B466E80B1B2DDFE5A18DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the first sentence of section 6403 of such Code shall not apply with respect to any such installment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="id9469F92A22B044E3A63FE7875BF8A87F"><enum>12.</enum><header>Adjustments to basis of partnership property</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9349D1F08D5D402E932BCD8C50E29EFA"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 754 elections limited to qualified small business partnerships</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/754">Section 754</external-xref> is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id39C12035356D4289A7AA0982CEC6D6FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>If a partnership files an election</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3F6163607D864924B8ABCEE8AA363C09"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id21157995B4C0493691D467FA5F5D6F28"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a partnership which is a qualified small business partnership files an election</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>, </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCE817B7083594D15A10F169B84285415"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>with respect to which such partnership is a qualified small business partnership</quote> after <quote>all subsequent taxable years</quote>, and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id71DAB016E0EF4520BA5DDFE6A14D33F2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id914B1644663E4052B86D253E779C53F2"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id220E41FA66CD46B8AFADE4D60EA257DD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified small business partnership</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1CA27FF80ADD446FB68FEE8AE6BACA4C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified small business partnership</term> means, with respect to any taxable year, any partnership which meets the gross receipts test under section 448(c) (determined with the modification described in paragraph (3)) for such taxable year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idef73f9f5fb4b4520ba303b703616f8c3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception not to apply to partnerships previously failing test or tax shelters</header><subparagraph id="id61447E9450464FA8AC8E6F5910433C2E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Partnerships failing test disqualified prospectively</header><text>If a partnership fails to meet the gross receipts test described in paragraph (1) for any taxable year which begins after the date of the enactment of this subsection, paragraph (1) shall not apply to such partnership (or any successor) for such taxable year or any succeeding taxable year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA8CFA46CA1B14A6B9E1566CB78730261"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Tax shelters</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to a tax shelter prohibited from using the cash receipts and disbursements method of accounting under section 448(a)(3), except that, for purposes of applying this subparagraph, a syndicate (as defined in section 1256(e)(3)(B)) shall not be treated as a tax shelter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id198FCF597CB3412F81EC47275FDEBFD7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Modification</header><text>In applying section 52(b) to section 448(c)(2) for purposes of this subsection, the term <term>trade or business</term> shall include any activity treated as a trade or business under paragraph (5) or (6) of section 469(c) (determined without regard to the phrase <quote>To the extent provided in regulations</quote> in such paragraph (6)).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idBA17D5C41E3D41CF91D109C056DBC283" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adjustments in the case of transfer of partnership interests</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96d88c46419b4fd59520831728f9694b"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/743">Section 743</external-xref> is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddc856a319c8544f28dd4c49e6f662440"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1b8353bf1bca47b9988e31bc0404e2ce"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0c0d68038d7f42ed9ece6e7d90c40249"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General rule</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id66bee3c40a9f41f39d4fb73381a79302"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Adjustments required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), in the case of a transfer of an interest in a partnership by sale or exchange or upon the death of a partner, the basis of partnership property shall be adjusted as provided in subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide60950046a0040e9b754ac6319176390"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for qualified small business partnerships</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to a qualified small business partnership (as defined in section 754(b)) if—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85176fa9cfca4d14876f77b708e33ac6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the election provided by section 754 (relating to optional adjustment to basis of partnership property) is not in effect with respect to such partnership, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id162a233f35e442f0be4d854fff88e01c"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a transfer, the partnership does not have a substantial built-in loss immediately after such transfer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>, and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb128520793d146ab89827dbfb69f668b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>with respect to which the election provided in section 754 is in effect or which has a substantial built-in loss immediately after such transfer</quote> and inserting <quote>a partnership which is required to adjust the basis of partnership property under subsection (a)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id802713510FD14DFB9BC99304E6E35B78"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reporting</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="id77E19F9D4156486DB4A6632EBCE6DC17"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6050K">Section 6050K</external-xref> is amended—</text><clause commented="no" id="id1EF8BBE61DB74346B74A9776432DC0BB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>described in section 751(a)</quote>,</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id18F32F531721430FA8EC8067C6B38E82"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, the amount received, and such other information as the Secretary may require. Such notification shall be furnished at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require.</quote>, and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id882298E8BC9C444D87EFC6143EAFC6B5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="section">certain</header-in-text></quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id33BFBB8CB1AC46FE854EBD2B0186798C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The item relating to section 6050K in the table of sections for subpart B of part III of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/61">chapter 61</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>certain</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id96C3A7950C8349A09B657F462930E840" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><subparagraph id="idBAF892D530DB490CB4BCEB003AA85CD2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/732">Section 732(d)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>his interest</quote> and inserting <quote>an interest in a qualified small business partnership (as defined in section 743(f))</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0D162E42E8FA4F349801FA3F4FCCCCAF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idD00A0190764748688E1F9B2CD96516FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The heading for <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/743">section 743</external-xref> is amended to read as follows: <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="section">Adjustment to basis of partnership property</header-in-text></quote>.</text></clause><clause id="id3194512967B7497E94A35311C1268720" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/761">Section 761(e)(2)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>optional</quote>.</text></clause><clause indent="up1" id="id805C46A724124501B4DBCACFFF81B915" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The item relating to section 743 in the table of sections for subpart C of part II of subchapter K of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE10D3B76C184445A8BA5848B78F88EA3"><toc><toc-entry level="section" bold="off">Sec. 743. Adjustment to basis of partnership property.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb216a698d0ae4af68cc2721cbe0c42a8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Adjustments to basis of undistributed partnership property</header><paragraph id="id0AD63AE83A12436AB8EA2160F991A490" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/734">Section 734</external-xref> is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a53f3b7faab496299d973299735edf7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsections (b) through (e) as subsections (c) through (f), respectively, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2558aedbdc294dc9b89501310f4302a9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1513D984B8F747D59791BB764EEA8023"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id82131d9098204451bd5a4273c57f1a24"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General rule</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd62f3697518f4e68b1fc86d34d9bbcae"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mandatory adjustment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), in the case of a distribution to a partner, the partnership shall adjust the basis of partnership property in accordance with subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id338c6835857c428aa366d0b86fe804aa"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for qualified small business partnerships</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a distribution to a partner by a qualified small business partnership (as defined in section 754(b))—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5472f449eb4d4b198257412cef4da328"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if there is an election provided in section 754 in effect with respect to such partnership or if there is a substantial basis reduction with respect to such distribution, the partnership shall adjust the basis of partnership property in accordance with subsection (c), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0ce241d803ad44799ef35f694d5297e4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if subparagraph (A) does not apply, no adjustment shall be made to the basis of partnership property as the result of such distribution. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5E075718A82F4B16860F2E22FC872165" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>General method of adjustment</header><paragraph id="id822A62D369BD44F3A3A5280EB252BF56" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any distribution to a partner to which subsection (a)(1) applies, the partnership shall adjust the basis of partnership property such that each remaining partner’s net liquidation amount immediately after such distribution is equal to such partner’s net liquidation amount immediately before such distribution. For purposes of the preceding sentence, a partner's net liquidation amount immediately before a distribution shall be calculated after taking into account any adjustment to the basis of property required by section 704(c)(1)(B) or 737 with respect to such distribution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7254715701B04F8E9E55610FCD014236" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distributions other than in liquidation of a partner’s interest</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="idA45B9296C5494AB98883816516723C54"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any distribution to a partner other than in liquidation of such partner’s interest, proper adjustment shall be made under paragraph (1) with respect to such partner to take into account—</text><clause id="idFFFC19A59EA743FCA239656F3455DC3B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of any gain recognized by such partner with respect to such distribution under section 731(a), and</text></clause><clause id="idBDF2514DE21244FA8BC9A85C83C160E7" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of any gain or loss which would be recognized by such partner if such partner sold the property distributed at fair market value immediately after such distribution.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id110038290CA24233BCCC83CB2EB09380" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may require such reporting as necessary to carry out this subsection. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id368D3ABC85B34ACD8EDC5C21797140B4" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Net liquidation amount</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>net liquidation amount</term> means, with respect to any partner, the net amount of gain or loss (if any) which would be taken into account (including gain or loss that would be taken into account by reason of subsections (c)(1)(A), (c)(1)(C), or (f)(1) of section 704) by the partner if the partnership sold all of its assets at fair market value (and no other amounts were taken into account under such section).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idA38507E0AA524236BC88593FD76FFF8D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd9a87f50b9a14483997c082ea7722717"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 734(c), as redesignated by paragraph (1), is amended by striking <quote>by a partnership with respect to which the election provided in section 754 is in effect or with respect to which there is a substantial basis reduction</quote> and inserting <quote>by a partnership to which subsection (a)(2)(A) applies</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa8178857def48b397485c6a45d4048d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 734(d), as redesignated by paragraph (1), is amended by striking <quote>subsection (b)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (b) or (c)</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc7e506ff1c5344e997d8aab7b6510a61"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/755">Section 755</external-xref> is amended—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idddc30877786d412aae877f0ca89c0625"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a), by striking <quote>section 734(b) (relating to optional adjustment to the basis of undistributed partnership property)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (b) or (c) of section 734 (relating to adjustment to basis of undistributed partnership property)</quote>, and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f2cfc60cecd477e968e05630a225052"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c), by striking <quote>section 734(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (b) or (c) of section 734</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf10050adc1cd4848a7345dcb0bb19dcd"><enum>(D)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id9b71e7d1c5d94de0b08536aab8b4fe3a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The heading for <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/734">section 734</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="section">where section 754 election or substantial basis reduction</header-in-text></quote>.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id02deecf11d0c4ef9a0dafb10d0d304b3" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The item relating to section 734 in the table of sections for subpart B of part II of subchapter K of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>where section 754 election or substantial basis reduction</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF745D3141E3546FBA4B2A48C0C1A8265" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to distributions after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HF63B4E1DA4C6481BB523DFC6C8EB8408"><enum>13.</enum><header>Application of net investment income tax to trade or business income of certain high income individuals</header><subsection id="HDF6AF9372C6842D4A1D51CFADAE3C4E3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1411">Section 1411</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA0FA0C98682548B4BC4C09B369BEA03C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H44F86856021348058A9AB3E6BC1C20E7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Application to certain high income individuals</header><paragraph id="HA75B9C8371AE4898A5410A6A9FE707FF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any individual whose modified adjusted gross income for the taxable year exceeds the high income threshold amount, subsection (a)(1) shall be applied by substituting <quote>the greater of specified net income or net investment income</quote> for <quote>net investment income</quote> in subparagraph (A) thereof.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75616330CFE7466381D22B969C86063F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Phase-in of increase</header><text>The increase in the tax imposed under subsection (a)(1) by reason of the application of paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not exceed the amount which bears the same ratio to the amount of such increase (determined without regard to this paragraph) as—</text><subparagraph id="HC64A81FCF1954527BF71D1A161E486D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the excess described in paragraph (1), bears to</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AFD83368A3C4B9482B8A15F93AA0D52"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$100,000 (<fraction>1/2</fraction> such amount in the case of a married taxpayer (as defined in section 7703) filing a separate return).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F53251942A643DDBD2DDF040AFFB595"><enum>(3)</enum><header>High income threshold amount</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>high income threshold amount</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HAD9871DF1D01409A86FBF1BDF69A9625"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in subparagraph (B) or (C), $400,000,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FDD2DC08B654BC5B1B8ECAC51034134"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a taxpayer making a joint return under section 6013 or a surviving spouse (as defined in section 2(a)), $500,000, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFAC9B5D217B4D118594563E70A4B964"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a married taxpayer (as defined in section 7703) filing a separate return, <fraction>1/2</fraction> of the dollar amount determined under subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BF744BEB55448F784FCCA5B063717C1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Specified net income</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>specified net income</quote> means net investment income determined—</text><subparagraph id="H827ED0235C7E4F93B6D616AB9A8952E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>without regard to the phrase <quote>other than such income which is derived in the ordinary course of a trade or business not described in paragraph (2),</quote> in subsection (c)(1)(A)(i),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9CA3477F495445F9DFA93B4AC551B09"><enum>(B)</enum><text>without regard to the phrase <quote>described in paragraph (2)</quote> in subsection (c)(1)(A)(ii),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0891E12E548A4B6DB986B07C2B139282"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">without regard to the phrase <quote>other than property held in a trade or business not described in paragraph (2)</quote> in subsection (c)(1)(A)(iii),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H453C0D6922654DC795FC48768D602440"><enum>(D)</enum><text>without regard to paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of subsection (c), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2003DFC7C4CD48F19E1EA17D1FAC4832"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by treating paragraphs (5) and (6) of section 469(c) (determined without regard to the phrase <quote>To the extent provided in regulations,</quote> in such paragraph (6)) as applying for purposes of subsection (c) of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H05437617A355402B844A81BFDAF94FAC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application to trusts and estates</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1411">Section 1411(a)(2)(A)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>undistributed net investment income</quote> and inserting <quote>the greater of undistributed specified net income or undistributed net investment income</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H33D0C893EFC8410F9F84BCFEC6353329"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clarifications with respect to determination of net investment income</header><paragraph id="H0A7ABE0860BA412DBFC44EF42233497C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certain exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1411">Section 1411(c)(6)</external-xref> is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2C4718161F434BAAA3536CCCE2E7283A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H67E004FC89A64B4499249E389144DBC1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Special rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Net investment income shall not include—</text><subparagraph id="H674838A2DDD34CC2928815A305BD104A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any item taken into account in determining self-employment income for such taxable year on which a tax is imposed by section 1401(b),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A083A56221F457996F9E8C87F513089"><enum>(B)</enum><text>wages received with respect to employment on which a tax is imposed under section 3101(b) (determined without regard to section 3101(c)) or 3201(a) (including amounts taken into account under section 3121(v)(2)), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB3D23DF56694586BDBFB7CFCCB54474"><enum>(C)</enum><text>wages received from the performance of services earned outside the United States for a foreign employer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C0F782CE3F24010874BC775CFF263FF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Net operating losses not taken into account</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1411">Section 1411(c)(1)(B)</external-xref> is amended by inserting <quote>(other than section 172)</quote> after <quote>this subtitle</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE032E044E317442F94F7963A1E25AF53"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inclusion of certain foreign income</header><subparagraph id="HD92CB8ADB689489AB0E3B0F0F3D3EBE8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1411">Section 1411(c)(1)(A)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of clause (ii), by striking <quote>over</quote> at the end of clause (iii) and inserting <quote>and</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4D332752E31F4F018563F0261A5EF4A0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="HE7B57C20FE7F4A1BBD0F181B8D686105"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any amount includible in gross income under section 951, 951A, 1293, or 1296, over</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E3EFA3105C44C65A9FA43ECEB2E29A5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Proper treatment of certain previously taxed income</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1411">Section 1411(c)</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0420DDFE3F7C48078C7D8A0E76FB7AEA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H1DF2B1DFB8A1440A9CF3DDB9507D7275"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Certain previously taxed income</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue regulations or other guidance providing for the treatment of—</text><subparagraph id="HAD76E1077F694C73A225365FA10F1D80"><enum>(A)</enum><text>distributions of amounts previously included in gross income for purposes of chapter 1 but not previously subject to tax under this section, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92DA7B8152004B68BC5D4FFCA48F82E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>distributions described in section 962(d).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD10B497586B646C2BB4AB336568A2E6C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0B856DF25EEE4FF4B4F5A92182785C03"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Transition rule</header><text>The regulations or other guidance issued by the Secretary under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1411">section 1411(c)(7)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added by this section) shall include provisions which provide for the proper coordination and application of clauses (i) and (iv) of section 1411(c)(1)(A) with respect to—</text><paragraph id="H75D1E3DD9331422D836B04ACB065C416"><enum>(1)</enum><text>taxable years beginning on or before the date of the enactment of this Act, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88AE94020E0B4C208291F244D9AD7279"><enum>(2)</enum><text>taxable years beginning after such date.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="IDB34352B1CED54790BA3342A2ED6ED363"><enum>14.</enum><header>Recognition of gain on transfers to swap funds</header><subsection id="ID2975720078F24006A4F5F18604E4325F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Interests similar to preferred stock treated as stock</header><text>Clause (vi) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/351">section 351(e)(1)(B)</external-xref> is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="ID6FD5DE02281F475CAF78BDE165237E6B" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><clause id="ID13A6DB92EAB944FCAE5F498EA8916A48"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>except as otherwise provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary—</text><subclause id="ID5BCBC141BCB54D18A687F75D4956EF59"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any interest in an entity if the return on such interest is limited and preferred, and</text></subclause><subclause id="ID2B9FF235E3F8452A88CCD9859BBF99EA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>interests (not described in subclause (I)) in any entity if substantially all of the assets of such entity consist (directly or indirectly) of any assets described in subclause (I), any preceding clause, or clause (viii).</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="ID5EC34875B86C411AB100DDB794067707"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certain transfers deemed To be to investment companies</header><text>Subsection (e) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/351">section 351</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="ID560FAAC0677D4ABBB69B023BDE331B8E" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><paragraph id="ID687EF83795F249B7A71AE1B73DD01484"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transfers of marketable securities to certain corporations</header><text>A transfer of property to a corporation if—</text><subparagraph id="ID5BF812D7A8B849D980F12914024F2739"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such property is marketable securities (as defined in section 731(c)(2)), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID8F238CAEED174EF19273F371DBEB7D6F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such corporation—</text><clause id="IDDCCCADAD4F7640F588826C3B84D23A3F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is registered under the <act-name parsable-cite="ICA40">Investment Company Act of 1940</act-name> as an investment company, or is exempt from registration as a investment company under section 3(c)(7) of such Act because interests in such corporation are offered to qualified purchasers within the meaning of section 2(a)(51) of such Act, or</text></clause><clause id="ID72CBE1DCD4954AA5B6E27C4081A40A2D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>allows persons who have blocks of marketable securities with significant unrealized appreciation to diversify those holdings.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="IDEC14FF44DDF84D95BA00EA3E65701AC1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transfers to partnerships</header><text>Subsection (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/721">section 721</external-xref> is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="ID77C1F6C7F6974EE68CDB7B025212DAD1" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><subsection id="ID25EFE429BA13479C874FF48E4A3C72B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to gain realized on a transfer of property to a partnership if, were the partnership incorporated—</text><paragraph id="IDBCE574CB46DF499AA7813B7C318AA34E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such partnership would be treated as an investment company (within the meaning of section 351), or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="IDCE4780DEEDE14926BD59655C121AF0E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>section 351 would not apply to such transfer by reason of section 351(e)(3).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="ID98ACB9CA7A3B458E88C140AB65BB0694" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to transfers after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE143C08A47C04EC8A414BA10D2E0CCA5"><enum>15.</enum><header>Modifications to treatment of certain losses</header><subsection id="H26CEC3758B324A689A71920B859D2ECC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Losses from certain capital assets which become worthless</header><paragraph id="H745D1D61EC68437F83A7AF2EFC1E16E8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>When treated as loss</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/165">Section 165(g)(1)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>on the last day of the taxable year</quote> and inserting <quote>at the time of the identifiable event establishing worthlessness</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF1D0F3E902C40029C600B709EAC5ECB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of partnership indebtedness</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/165">Section 165(g)(2)(C)</external-xref> is amended by inserting <quote>, by a partnership,</quote> after <quote>by a corporation</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6673B6DECFB4432386B3D47EDB029A05"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment of abandonment</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/165">Section 165(g)</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB4FD67384723477CBEDCC7774CC6FF34" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H6FA67A30BEE44000B82E14EB401BE140"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Treatment of abandonment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection and subsection (m), abandonment shall be treated as an identifiable event establishing worthlessness.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H663673AFD9AB4876BB400ADDFAAB38DB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Treatment of partnership interest</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/165">Section 165</external-xref> is amended by redesignating subsection (m) as subsection (n) and by inserting after subsection (l) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC3ED25CF8468493BBC75BB8B4F1A7B77" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H279E7C0FF0EF41E190BB3D2C62BD5B19"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Worthless partnership interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any interest in a partnership becomes worthless during the taxable year, the loss resulting therefrom shall, for purposes of this subtitle, be treated as a loss from the sale or exchange of the interest in the partnership at the time of the identifiable event establishing worthlessness.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H243976A6109E4E07ACDECD175AE2B311"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to losses arising in taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5828e01105734b2f8acc2480c43c8c0e"><enum>16.</enum><header>Codification of anti-abuse rule</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc54da8db13a4b1fa28ee4adfba75f7b"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/701">Section 701</external-xref> is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbaa10b46c3af40a69324f7a553ea3ac5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>A partnership</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida423f55cece74fd1894aed72e039b8da"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf76e6d1cb4094ce5bf63b6a079684a51"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A partnership</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>, and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcba8fa5a837e4bb8ad9f0fab94fc5b84"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id64ade426e7924b28b580d374de6e1e12"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf81089a9304c485bb9753fe3c872b3ad"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under regulations established by the Secretary, in the case of a transaction involving a partnership, the Secretary may recast, disregard, or otherwise modify such transaction for purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 unless—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd4d0baf2c2d4df6b7b7dfee8579097f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the tax consequences to each partner and the partnership reflect the partners' economic agreement and clearly reflect the partners' income, </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id800752ed010445e4b88bb6f72c0fbc81"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the form of such transaction is consistent with it substance, and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd38aeb0e74b1413cb3d95d48ec576940"><enum>(3)</enum><text>there is a substantial purpose (apart from Federal income tax effects) for entering into such transaction.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2612d9d2c1d842a896520e0a77204580"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No inference</header><text>Nothing in this section or the amendments made by this section shall be construed to create any inference with respect to the authority of the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary's delegate) to regulate transactions described in section 701(b) of the Internal Revenue Code (as added by subsection (a)) without regard to the provisions of such section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


