<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC32A35B0CABA4BE1AC1CE02FDD555947" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 193 IH: Censuring Representative Al Green of Texas.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 193</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001102">Mr. Harris of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001316">Mr. Burlison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001116">Mr. Clyde</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSO00">Committee on Ethics</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Censuring Representative Al Green of Texas.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the annual State of the Union address is a momentous occasion for the President to address the Nation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the speech is a respectful occasion, conducted within the framework of democratic institutions and traditions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on March 4, 2024, during the joint session of Congress convened pursuant to House Concurrent Resolution 11, the President, speaking at the invitation of the House and the Senate, had his remarks interrupted by Representative Al Green of Texas, Mr. Green;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Representative Green continued his interruption, despite admonition from nonpartisan staff of the House of Representatives and from the Speaker;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Representative Green was removed from the joint session by the Sergeant at Arms;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the conduct of Representative Green was a breach of decorum and degraded the proceedings of the joint session, to the discredit of the House; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the actions of Representative Green were not only a breach of civility but also an affront to the dignity of the House and Senate, and to the principles of mutual respect that are essential for the functioning of the legislative process: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H2FE262AB6A444B30ACF0FF2FD291A4D6"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H940FE82ED8F14AEEA4505A37F2641B55"><enum/><text>That —</text><paragraph id="H5C280419C9F247B98BAB18E62BEACAFD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Representative Al Green of Texas be censured;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEF1842594F74170838E961D9E7F5B0D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Representative Al Green forthwith present himself in the well of the House of Representatives for the pronouncement of censure; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CFEB2A4D1374A54B8184A0F95E17804"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Representative Al Green be censured with the public reading of this resolution by the Speaker.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

