<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H38D9D8AB7D0D4AA9AE303A965EC83EF4" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 114 IH: Directing the Secretary of Homeland Security to transmit to the House of Representatives certain documents relating to Department of Homeland Security policies and activities related to domestic preparedness and collective response to terrorism and the Department’s cybersecurity activities.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 114</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250205">February 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Directing the Secretary of Homeland Security to transmit to the House of Representatives certain documents relating to Department of Homeland Security policies and activities related to domestic preparedness and collective response to terrorism and the Department’s cybersecurity activities.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HAACCB81773944025861D8ADF2FFE304F"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA1A8D5E02A9D42F0B91A6529ADB4ED1C"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That not later than 14 days after the date of the adoption of this resolution, the Secretary of Homeland Security is directed to transmit to the House of Representatives copies of any documentation, including any document, record, memo, correspondence, or other communication, or any portion of any such documentation, of the Department of Homeland Security relating to domestic preparedness and collective response to terrorism and the Department’s cybersecurity activities, to the extent such documentation or any portion thereof is in the possession of the Secretary, that refers or relates to the following:</text><paragraph id="H80C12C377A544B8F8F02BC3FD6FE0409"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any documentation related to any pause of Department grants, loans, or other financial assistance contemplated or ordered on or after January 20, 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE591A4C270954DBA968490CD94231672"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any documentation related to the implementation of Executive Order 14159, Executive Order 14169, Executive Order 14162, Executive Order 14154, Executive Order 14151, Executive Order 14168, Executive Order 14182, and Office of Management and Budget Memorandum M–25–13 at the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3237C70E57A4F7D8E0562A50322FCB1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any documentation related to the evaluation of potential risks to domestic preparedness and collective response to terrorism or the Department’s cybersecurity activities related to directives contemplated or ordered to pause Department grants, loans, or other financial assistance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H517C164FED7447D2897BC6DEE433DB40"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any documentation related to the evaluation of potential risks to domestic preparedness and collective response to terrorism or the Department of Homeland Security’s cybersecurity activities related to the Department’s implementation of Executive Order 14159, Executive Order 14169, Executive Order 14162, Executive Order 14154, Executive Order 14151, Executive Order 14168, Executive Order 14182, and Office of Management and Budget Memorandum M–25–13.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0CF1C0E93F8482B981180520E832A97"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any documentation related to communications with organizations outside the Department related to the pause of Department grants, loans, or other financial assistance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1731306D1496421EB171449547A17EAA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any documentation related to communications with organizations outside the Department related to the implementation Executive Order 14159, Executive Order 14169, Executive Order 14162, Executive Order 14154, Executive Order 14151, Executive Order 14168, Executive Order 14182, and Office of Management and Budget Memorandum M–25–13 at the Department.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

