<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR25342-92W-V7-JD0"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1166 IS: Excess Urban Heat Mitigation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1166</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to establish an excess urban heat mitigation grant program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H102B6452D4BB4DF19A60AC0234E2B818"><section section-type="section-one" id="H85363D8FAE0448A990F70992F79AC888"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Excess Urban Heat Mitigation Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA25F840602234993BD2790941B956831"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HB4394107FEF649CAB4E5908B9FB691B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Heat stress is a leading weather-related cause of death in the United States, with more than 600 people killed in the United States by extreme heat every year, and many more experiencing respiratory problems and heat-related illness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C90E3E1BC3C49598D9C7AAC229688E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Urban areas are likely to experience higher temperatures than surrounding areas due to design-related attributes of the built environment, including manmade factors such as low solar reflectance, low vegetation and tree cover, high building density, high impervious surface cover, and waste heat emissions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB2E0C8549AB41FDBD204CBFABA3F049"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Underserved communities are disproportionately impacted by extreme heat. In the United States, low-income census blocks have 15.2 percent less tree cover and an average land surface temperature that is 1.5 degrees Celsius hotter than high-income blocks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC88928EE01E4C90A9285FF808059623"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Studies show that in 97 percent of the largest urbanized areas in the United States, people of color live in census tracts with higher surface urban heat intensity than non-Hispanic Whites, indicating that heat exposure is unequally distributed by race.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3BB56884991461FBFCFF2F337F809F1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Urban heat is not only a public health threat but also an economic one, as rising heat leads to increased roadway maintenance costs, higher residential and commercial summer energy costs, and lost labor productivity, as well as the cost to patients and health care infrastructure for heat-related hospitalizations and emergency department visits.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H459ECDA080714AFD9095D87986598B29"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Excess urban heat causes increased energy consumption, elevated emission of air pollutants and greenhouse gases, and impaired water quality.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42F6D8836C3543F884711F1BD0240F8E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Heat waves are expected to not only occur more frequently in the United States but also be of longer duration, lasting 10 to 20 days longer by the end of the century.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB55AA5F301D44BE98A9A7921EEBD6526"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Solutions exist that communities can implement now to mitigate the challenge of urban heat. One example is the planting of urban trees to offset or reverse the urban heat island effect. Studies in multiple cities in the United States have shown that urban trees can offset projected increases in heat-related mortality in 2050 by 40 to 99 percent.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HAB71F17C3AA444D8874DFD7143BE17D3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H6D786F10B94E4805B144E99D03470E20"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered census tract</header><text>The term <term>covered census tract</term> means a census tract with a poverty rate of not less than 20 percent, as measured by the 5-year data series available from the American Community Survey of the Bureau of the Census for the period of 2019 through 2023, including such a census tract that includes an area that was designated as <quote>hazardous</quote> or <quote>definitely declining</quote> in maps drawn by the Home Owners’ Loan Corporation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E3778F56A214F4589B215FE3B9F5C0A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered grant</header><text>The term <term>covered grant</term> means a grant awarded under section 4(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF14A87A30832473DB9569B3CD9574F3F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H433485AE995E4CB0BA79931AAFCFD657"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State (as defined in section 102 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5302">42 U.S.C. 5302</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CD08CBA065049728F221620745FCEBE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a metropolitan planning organization;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93821B9336784F4A8F71E4FEEF8A20CB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a unit of general local government (as defined in section 102 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5302">42 U.S.C. 5302</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FBF1E1109514446B16BEF2323C12C11"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an Indian tribe (as defined in section 102 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5302">42 U.S.C. 5302</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10096DA4D3EB45BD90AA8FAB7D7CCF77"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a territorial government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F91D204C88346BE9D1D271359CE45E6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization working in coordination with an entity described in subparagraphs (A) through (E); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3F1C6C1F2C9481093B8D344DD11188A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a consortium of nonprofit organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H77A879D513D14FB79674D1D6845CEC39"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible project</header><text>The term <term>eligible project</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HADA6541B6931470589171C91CABF8F90"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a project designed to mitigate or manage heat in an urban area by—</text><clause id="H2880C4827ACC46F59E31AA07572E8776"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">working to mitigate the causes of higher temperatures; or</text></clause><clause id="H905678E05208495C9574E3EF7ABABFDF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>managing the impacts of higher temperatures or other extreme weather events; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3796C20322A4303B130C5589F5A2A27"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes the implementation, construction, or maintenance of—</text><clause id="H890D06542BBD4623A98FD2A50E4C9BD1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>tree planting and maintenance with, wherever possible, preference for—</text><subclause id="HF1038F36040D486C8CAD8ECF00BCA003"><enum>(I)</enum><text>native tree species;</text></subclause><subclause id="H7E50328DA66A4D82B28C78E0EAFDBF75"><enum>(II)</enum><text>tree species with high shade production and carbon sequestration; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H77029E58E5AE45EFB69D21F9934E37C7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>tree species that are valuable for food production;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H9E61FED4C7A34644B09B3CDB2159E843"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>cool pavements;</text></clause><clause id="H3A1561778AA8428F9EAB5D49FCF8A7E4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>cool roofs;</text></clause><clause id="H72D7158F4E6C42A3B98EF3C3164C5510"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>green roofs;</text></clause><clause id="H6EC96E9311E84EB69FC9A2175C63BB0D"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">bus and other transit stop shelters;</text></clause><clause id="H553D331C062B48BD8F6E361DB8FD39A9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>shade structures;</text></clause><clause id="H83077256D72D46AE848D269D5645450C"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>cooling centers with, wherever possible, preference for—</text><subclause id="HF7394E26B99B4FDFA238BEDAD9DB2EAB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>cooling centers that collaborate with existing community centers and spaces;</text></subclause><subclause id="H734C41C91D7242B1844502F9A3825562"><enum>(II)</enum><text>cooling centers with year-round accessibility, and</text></subclause><subclause id="H7B2FE20EBA6D417CACF92F4DAE8CF134"><enum>(III)</enum><text>cooling centers that utilize renewable energy;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HAE99BB41641A4A66800911F28C153824"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>community gardens, including agroforestry practices;</text></clause><clause id="H20978081A72E482AB63EC93F9BBD9643"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>outreach to communities about resources available under this section;</text></clause><clause id="H2D62F80E8E6541AF943F571B981BD356"><enum>(x)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">local heat mitigation and management education efforts;</text></clause><clause id="H0703B03D100B4D5EADEF0C64C70AD9F2"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>urban forestry master plans;</text></clause><clause id="HEF4A93E523DC45929DB2CBF3D9E44036"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>urban tree canopy assessments;</text></clause><clause id="H5DA5D7E780E04CB5B69906B485E52A2D"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>arboriculture training;</text></clause><clause id="HAF7C0DD6EF664A5EAB3B12CBF00EE7BF"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>maintenance of existing urban trees; or</text></clause><clause id="HD15A6A95A2204EED8D7C7CD0B49D5F4D"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>other actions the Secretary determines appropriate to mitigate or manage excess urban heat.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H403E569E5A2A4BF1B108149AB9E04791"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Environmental justice</header><text>The term <term>environmental justice</term> means the fair treatment and meaningful involvement of all people regardless of race, color, culture, national origin, income, and educational levels with respect to the development, implementation, and enforcement of protective environmental laws, regulations, and policies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H743AC868607443559985A18C62B115B1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Excess urban heat effect</header><text>The term <term>excess urban heat effect</term> means the phenomenon of local urban warming, resulting from manmade factors such as low solar reflectance, low tree cover, high building density, high impervious surface cover, and waste heat emissions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E8A56E8BEDB46C99FAE1F771572CEA6"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Extreme heat</header><text>The term <term>extreme heat</term> means a prolonged period of excessively hot weather, with temperatures well above climatological normals for a given location and season.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C0A6F0718504822A44DDC5A95C6DA80"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Nonprofit organization</header><text>The term <term>nonprofit organization</term> means an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8C80B6D3A134A2A9BFE375AF7DE9C98"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H22170AC02269494189B7E0655B885F33"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Urban area</header><text>The term <term>urban area</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101(a) of title 23, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD547E1D647B44BC9AAD09554FE049DC5"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Urban forestry master plan</header><text>The term <term>urban forestry master plan</term> means a strategic plan that establishes the overall vision, goals, objectives, and implementation tools to evaluate, maintain and expand the urban tree canopy with the intention of building resilience to extreme weather events, reducing the urban heat island effect, mitigating stormwater runoff, reducing nutrient runoff, addressing air quality, and preserving biodiversity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA19CD32DF23F4457A15E0C303B884511"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Urban tree canopy assessment</header><text>The term <term>urban tree canopy assessment</term> means a measure of a community’s tree canopy coverage as a percentage of the total land area that serves as a baseline for setting community tree canopy goals and measuring progress.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5C53DA7361CE4683B836C0FB035894B2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Urban Heat Mitigation and Management Grant Program</header><subsection id="HBD518B1B5A2F4C0D817F1A415B8FB277"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, acting through the Office of Community Planning and Development, in coordination with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Chief of the Forest Service, and the Director of the Climate Program Office of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, shall establish an urban heat mitigation and management grant program to award grants to eligible entities to implement eligible projects.</text></subsection><subsection id="H36BB250A674E4375AF4BC866B49D5FFB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Set-Aside</header><text>Not less than 75 percent of the amounts of covered grants awarded for a fiscal year shall be awarded to eligible entities to implement projects in a covered census tract.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB5C03B40A5FB418B85AFE471875D1916"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><paragraph id="H04EFC671FDF0444990237ECB9BF0963D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not more than 3 percent of amounts appropriated to carry out this section may be used to provide technical assistance to eligible entities applying for or implementing a covered grant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC16146896ABC4F4D81FD5D65B13D9212"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Preference</header><text>In providing technical assistance under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall give preference to eligible entities that intend to serve communities—</text><subparagraph id="HD3BCFA48C7994D87B33875D557CDB212"><enum>(A)</enum><text>located in a covered census tract; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H986C6B8389F54C7C854B87BA193E1256"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with lower-tree canopy and higher maximum daytime summer temperatures compared to surrounding communities, as determined by the Secretary, based on publicly available information. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2B0FCAF910F46E8BB31F6B32A6C2762"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>Technical assistance provided under paragraph (1) may include—</text><subparagraph id="H953A4C216A5745E39D90825987351602"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assistance developing a complete application;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6401FB557B84C549089F427F5A18EFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>financial analysis and budget development;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H375BAA0EE8B047E9800348D6E2985DCB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>support for project integration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA443B503CF6B4EB182719E0B7B7C248A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assessment of project readiness; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C78DB1F6202406D8602E8C068AD905A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>technical assistance implementing activities once a covered grant is received.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE9F5B1F76ECA498CB845DF112D2E5BC0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><paragraph id="H9704CBF653D34FBDBD3F8B9234EB961A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity desiring a covered grant shall submit to the Secretary an application, at such time and in such manner as required by the Secretary in guidance, that includes, at a minimum—</text><subparagraph id="H8D85FA3C3BDF4510919355876378E2C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how the eligible entity will use the covered grant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8359823B63B44A38D05C3549F2F77AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how the eligible projects funded will combat extreme heat or excess urban heat effects and improve quality of life for impacted communities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBBBCAA12ED840789A2575B50E3F665E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a robust engagement plan that—</text><clause id="HE54E96C98F5A4EE4ACA187F70C53AC04"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">outlines how the eligible entity will meaningfully and inclusively engage with the communities in which the eligible projects take place throughout project implementation; and</text></clause><clause id="H2C6B7B7367124B5A95B4C43B802EB75C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>demonstrates how the eligible entity plans to—</text><subclause id="H38DA13138A9144228D65BC13CBEA1387"><enum>(I)</enum><text>foster meaningful, reciprocal relationships with community-based organizations;</text></subclause><subclause id="H26561495C49B4CB8B3B6F4DD70DBB579"><enum>(II)</enum><text>engage in respectful, good-faith consultation with diverse community stakeholders; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H04F488131EB34BE4928B440971B4EA9C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>empower members of the community to participate in decision making; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H741267108DB84D449589401BD5D805C3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>how the eligible entity will address the intersection between human health, environment, and built environment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AB3AF6223E24CF78908B525A94C0909"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue the guidance described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F1B9E6229E74BC4BEDDC9468A4D8EDB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><paragraph id="H088025999C2340508EB89F106AF736E2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Federal share of the cost of an eligible project carried out with amounts from a covered grant shall be not more than 80 percent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1FCD36506F8491EBBFB5E90F519E8A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary may increase the maximum Federal share described in paragraph (1) from 80 percent to 100 percent for an eligible project carried out by an eligible entity that demonstrates economic hardship, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H166C9318DB68481795061BF7C7CF5C9E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding covered grants, the Secretary shall give priority to an eligible entity that serves—</text><paragraph id="H4B3A0740B3184165A01524DA2B3417A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a community located in a covered census tract; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H741664B4D6474065A7BB8E9A6A4DD297"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a community with lower tree canopy and higher maximum daytime summer temperatures compared to surrounding communities, as determined by the Secretary, based on publicly available information.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDC56F6A61D4E4BC0B1E3287814E981B9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>The Secretary shall submit an annual report to Congress that identifies the recipients of covered grants and the geographic and economic distribution of those recipients.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2A5A6D26B9BB4FA5829317AE54915C5A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Oversight</header><paragraph id="H9C1BE2ED01E24411AFA2FE2D739D68FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order to ensure the effectiveness of projects that are carried out using covered grants, the Secretary shall use not more than 5 percent of any amounts appropriated to carry out this section to establish an oversight board to help—</text><subparagraph id="H6D6725E3A4F54BA9A4C576F307CA2823"><enum>(A)</enum><text>select recipients of covered grants; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32257D3DEC814AFFB59A972CC497CACE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>review the progress made by recipients of covered grants on a yearly basis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5549ACB1617D4D77A2BE6A2358EEB055"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The board established under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="HD3255DFDBFF94025B3CE6A45D3869A3E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop and apply a rubric to evaluate the success of projects carried out using covered grants in reaching their objective to combat the causes and effects of excess urban heat; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H197A067153694791B9CB989845614848"><enum>(B)</enum><text>serve the Secretary in an advisory capacity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD90CBC792F3943FCB9ABEA5346E52439"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Membership</header><subparagraph id="HCB3BD4716CA849558D0D4D9274D31CCB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Members of the board established under paragraph (1) may include—</text><clause id="HE93ECB79C36047CF8E8261499F8FBA60"><enum>(i)</enum><text>representatives from the Environmental Protection Agency, particularly from the Heat Island Reduction Program;</text></clause><clause id="H59033AA0FA4D4D1CBC1815B9DDF8FE7C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>representatives from the Department of Health and Human Services, particularly from the Office of Climate Change and Health Equity;</text></clause><clause id="H4390C64C2BBF42FB9B17647132BA270B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>representatives from the Department of Energy, particularly from the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy;</text></clause><clause id="HBA5471CD3F334C33A80A320E38DDC9BB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>representatives from the Department of Agriculture, particularly from the Urban and Community Forestry Program; </text></clause><clause id="H13A6B6797620442FB6B254E57AE4D20A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>subject to subparagraph (B), representatives from nonprofit organizations with proven leadership in urban heat mitigation or environmental justice, as determined by the Secretary; and</text></clause><clause id="H8B29BFEF7CB348829AB1B3A6048B1423"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>subject to subparagraph (B), representatives from academia and research studying the effects of and mitigation of excess urban heat, environmental justice, or related areas.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A0DBAEA2E9E4EC0996C3CC7C7863B99"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certification required</header><text>In order to be a member of the board established under paragraph (1), a representative described in clause (v) or (vi) of subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall certify that the representative does not possess any conflict of interest with respect to projects being considered for a covered grant or being carried out using a covered grant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE8023E5914A24D459D3B0183E494DF23"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2033.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

