<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7B7F352CE6E0439891E7320CB7ED2A42" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 618 IH: Commending the Coast Guard, Air Station Corpus Christi, and the crew of CG–6553 for their heroic efforts and courageous response to the catastrophic flooding across central Texas.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 618</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250729">July 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001051">Mr. Carter of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commending the Coast Guard, Air Station Corpus Christi, and the crew of CG–6553 for their heroic efforts and courageous response to the catastrophic flooding across central Texas.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, beginning in the predawn hours of July 4, 2025, heavy rainfall resulted in catastrophic flooding that devastated many Texas Hill Country communities, resulting in the tragic loss of life;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Guadalupe and Colorado Rivers, and their surrounding waterways, rose rapidly and perilously, immediately endangering the life of thousands as they slept;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nearly 12 inches of rain fell in the headwaters of the South Fork of the Guadalupe River, upstream of Camp Mystic, Kerrville, Hunt, and Comfort, Texas, resulting in the river rising over 26 feet in 45 minutes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, at 5:30 a.m., Coast Guard Air Station Corpus Christi launched a search and rescue crew aboard an MH–65 Dolphin helicopter, call sign CG–6553;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the crew of CG–6553 consisted of aircraft commander Lieutenant Ian Hopper, copilot Lieutenant Blair Ogujiofor, flight mechanic AMT3 Seth Reeves, and rescue swimmer AST3 Scott Ruskan;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CG–6553 was unwavering in their response despite severe weather and poor flying conditions that caused 3 aborted landing attempts due to inadvertent instrument meteorological conditions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on the fourth landing attempt, the crew of CG–6553, with their unique weather radar capabilities, successfully led numerous rotary-wing assets into the disaster zone;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during his first rescue mission, AST3 Scott Ruskan became the only first responder on scene when he was inserted into the flood zone at Camp Mystic, and for over 3 hours, he triaged and coordinated the rescue of 165 lives, working with local, State, and military airframes across 3 landing zones;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Lt. Ian Hopper, Lt. Blair Ogujiofor, and AMT3 Seth Reeves continued to airlift and evacuate 15 lives from the disaster area aboard their MH–65 Dolphin helicopter;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Coast Guard aggressively sustained continuous operations through the deployment of 54 Coast Guard personnel, numerous air assets consisting of 8 MH–65 Dolphin helicopters and 2 HC–144 Ocean Sentry fixed-wing aircraft, and resources from Coast Guard Air Stations Corpus Christi, Houston, and Miami;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the crew of CG–6553 and the Coast Guard carried out one of the most consequential rescue operations this country has ever seen, bringing hope to the helpless;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the face of tragedy, our Coast Guard servicemembers reminded Texas and the Nation of what makes this country strong: selflessness, courage, and professionalism by those willing to step into danger to protect others; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the actions of aircraft commander Lieutenant Ian Hopper, copilot Lieutenant Blair Ogujiofor, Aviation Maintenance Technician Petty Officer Third Class Seth Reeves, Aviation Survival Technician Petty Officer Third Class Scott Ruskan, and all of the Coast Guard personnel who deployed into the disaster zone exemplified the courage and devotion to duty in keeping with the highest traditions of the Coast Guard: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H227FC58CE2FD4D738993F3C94F5EAF23"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H938722E70A7645DF8C635C0E96452FB1"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HA64C87A8C5D34B7F875DEB72079C55D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commends the Coast Guard for its courageous and swift response to the flooding disaster in Texas;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21E7022430F24229A35DBDE8287815A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses its profound and deep appreciation for the extraordinary Coast Guard members who risked their lives to save hundreds from the floods; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B50F7D79E6C4BF0874B64F101871AAE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>extends its deepest gratitude to all of the Federal, State, and local first responders and volunteers who have responded to this horrific tragedy to help Texas in its time of need.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

