<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL25112-85P-R0-2G0"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S518 IS: Defund Government-Sponsored Propaganda Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 518</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250211">February 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit Federal funding for the Public Broadcasting Service and National Public Radio and to provide for the transfer of certain Federal funds that would have been made available to those organizations to reduce the public debt, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HDE1DD71A7AA04DCCA3C78C57791C37AF"><section section-type="section-one" id="HE0C197290C1E46FF91D505AF52E6B2EF"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Defund Government-Sponsored Propaganda Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA32E4D1113B242739A803237DC41772B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on Federal funding for Public Broadcasting Service and National Public Radio</header><subsection id="H768795DB856246408B669D8DCAAC979E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the date of enactment of this Act, no Federal funds may, directly or indirectly, be made available to or used to support an organization described in subsection (b), including through the payment of dues to or the purchase of programming from the organization by a public broadcast station using Federal funds received by the station.</text></subsection><subsection id="H25B9912FE7E6407FA5360201D63D4459"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Organizations described</header><text>The organizations described in this subsection are—</text><paragraph id="idC6FDA8339B8B402093061A014B840354"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the organization known, as of the date of enactment of this Act, as the <quote>Public Broadcasting Service</quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA7A48DC335C4F3BB11DDF9ED5D570B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the organization known, as of the date of enactment of this Act, as <quote>National Public Radio</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4759CED639694DDAB75F5B4696A443EF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any successor organization to an organization described in paragraph (1) or (2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H91889FC79E4E467B829326CFF5F746F7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transfer of certain funds To reduce the public debt</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal years 2025, 2026, and 2027, the Corporation for Public Broadcasting shall transfer to the account established by section 3113(d) of title 31, United States Code, an amount equal to the sum of the amounts allocated under clauses (ii) and (iii) of section 396(k)(3)(A) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/396">47 U.S.C. 396(k)(3)(A)</external-xref>) that would have been made available to an organization described in subsection (b) but for the prohibition in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

