<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4F3576FF52AF4BAE8D8A5A19CB750FCB" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 576 IH: Censuring Representative Andy Ogles.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 576</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250710">July 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSO00">Committee on Ethics</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Censuring Representative Andy Ogles.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Representative Andy Ogles has publicly and repeatedly used racist rhetoric to demean the House Democratic Leader Hakeem Jeffries, a highly respected African-American Member of Congress, as <quote>Discount Dollar Store Obama</quote>, mocking his identity and diminishing his leadership through racist tropes;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Representative Ogles has used anti-Muslim rhetoric to attack the Democratic nominee for Mayor of New York City, New York State Assemblymember Zohran Mamdani;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Representative Ogles has repeatedly called for the deportation of Assemblymember Mamdani, solely on the basis of his political beliefs and religion;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Representative Ogles is abusing his office by calling on United States Attorney General Pam Bondi to deport a Muslim-American Democratic nominee, whom he disparages as <quote>little Muhammad</quote>, simply because Assemblymember Mamdani is Muslim;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Representative Ogles’s public statements suggest a willingness to silence political positions and target naturalized citizens by weaponizing the Department of Justice and our Nation’s immigration laws;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas targeting a political candidate or any American citizen for deportation based solely on their lawful political views represents an authoritarian impulse contradictory with the Constitution of the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas anti-Muslim hate, racism, and ethnic slurs have no place in public discourse, and only serve to divide and endanger diverse communities as well as subject public officials across the country to harassment and death threats;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Representative Ogles’s statements are un-American, antithetical to the values of a pluralistic and multiethnic democracy, and beneath the dignity of the House of Representatives; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the House of Representatives has a responsibility to uphold standards of conduct and condemn hate speech that undermines the legitimacy and safety of public service: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H4DD305F39B234D12BC49F9920EAF07BE"> <section id="HDC3045FCC55043BF8D7C7203B18D32D8" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCBEEF19B39CF40C4933D947D155576EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Representative Andy Ogles be censured;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD71CE553E8FC406DBA4451DE237380BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Representative Andy Ogles forthwith present himself in the well of the House of Representatives for the pronouncement of censure; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBCCBA7A656014FFAB8FD6F1DEE272F46"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Representative Andy Ogles be censured with the public reading of this resolution by the Speaker.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

