<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4233D3B43F5E41CEAF0C8D7E3C476DD4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2370 IH: Taiwan Travel and Tourism Coordination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2370</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250326">March 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve the cooperation between the United States and the authorities of Taiwan with respect to travel and tourism.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4179AB33BCE34FFD9C3E8A2F3EDCD1A4" style="OLC"><section id="HABA62C54724A40E091AA0634CD2711D7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Taiwan Travel and Tourism Coordination Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7C157D6858C74752866671B734432797"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEEA9A61B1B78494A8509F2ECA7A08517"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H309FF77ED6BC4802A5462A0BB5B354D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3EE1471FFD1240AFB779D17A9F08847B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7F5A511DFE64FF9B4ED468FF1281AE4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;</committee-name></text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H56B20A817FEC4A8CA043DB21DE954588"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA37394E0DD9406E841B86E1585C8665"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE63EFCF3F59449EBFFF0D8C486F6FB2"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</committee-name>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCD600BDE2DDB4E2CA3C75D6AC40B7187"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistant secretary</header><text>The term <term>Assistant Secretary</term> means the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Travel and Tourism.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2825E3892D6345C48981CB033DB06BA1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Tourism cooperation with Taiwan</header><subsection id="HDA075DECC717419F86ED71E453E9BCED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of State, shall seek to engage the authorities of Taiwan with respect to expanding cooperation between the United States and such authorities on travel and tourism.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF877F20D34F1481EACDAC19334A2E628"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cooperation efforts</header><paragraph id="HBDE8D7A6E06F4BBD8CBEC7F88388F4E5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In seeking to expand cooperation under subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary, consistent with the Taiwan Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3301">22 U.S.C. 3301 et seq.</external-xref>) and applicable export regulations, shall carry out efforts to identify and pursue opportunities for—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10591E563B0C478C8C71FF2ADDB03473"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enhancing travel between the United States and Taiwan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H869CD621AE1F455AA6972F93826BFCBB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strengthening the tourism industries of both the United States and Taiwan in areas of mutual benefit to the United States and the authorities of Taiwan, including by—</text><clause id="H6B6EA013C8CD449583F9F52969B1D8CE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>facilitating events and coordination between travel and tourism industry partners, the United States, and the authorities of Taiwan, including hotel accommodations, restaurant or foodservice, the small business or retail sector, travel distribution services, the attractions and recreation sector (including outdoor recreation) city convention and visitors' bureaus, State tourism offices, the commercial and private passenger air travel sector, and the land and sea passenger transportation sector, and other industry partners, as determined by the Assistant Secretary; </text></clause><clause id="H2D96BE6F11334A1CAAEBA761067CAC47"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>advising on the preservation and incentivization of travel to interact with cultural heritage, artifacts, and landmarks;</text></clause><clause id="H214E9CE0C9D44677A4A9F9C0647D162E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>coordinating on the safety and security of international visitors; and</text></clause><clause id="HB407DDC54A6540B4911C75DAFEC4101B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>conducting activities of mutual benefit relating to travel and tourism.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF18660EEFE66421EBD65B321920AB124"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Protection of sensitive and proprietary information and economic interests of the united states</header><text>In carrying out the efforts and activities described in paragraph (1), the Assistant Secretary, the Secretary of Commerce, and Secretary of State shall take all appropriate measures to protect sensitive information, intellectual property, trade secrets, and the economic interests of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3BF4AB5A650742458AC19071DBF9DE8C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="H02DAF29E073D4E19A1C4449BD86C0484"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for the subsequent five years, the Assistant Secretary, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of State shall jointly submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that describes the implementation of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EC66A0336B240EFA2CCF18107BDF1E6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Each report required under paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H594B5DF06758456D99666430302EC5BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the cooperation efforts and activities carried out pursuant to subsection (b)(1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97EE558ADA3F4E03BAC7A7BE2B4781E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the identification of any challenge or resource gap that needs to be addressed to expand cooperation between the United States and the authorities of Taiwan with respect to travel and tourism; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E3710D277904652AC6586F3C1A8716B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other matter the Assistant Secretary, the Secretary of Commerce, or the Secretary of State considers relevant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H37F77E34992241DDB0ABACFB3CAF77A1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on preclearance facilities in Taiwan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of State, shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that—</text><paragraph id="H3BC55B9D8BD04F8D8C0BC2F9B5DA9FF6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>analyzes the feasibility of, and the advisability for, the establishment of a preclearance facility in Taiwan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4F0264070A74F848F49CDB894FFA1DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describes the plan for the establishment of a preclearance facility in Taiwan or in other locations in the Indo-Pacific region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52A495F5CFE54DCD83056B7B0E72547F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assesses the impacts that preclearance operations in Taiwan will have on—</text><subparagraph id="H3AE2BA7BEF344132BCFA3DD46D32864B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>trade between the United States and Taiwan, including the impact on established supply chains;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26B0F0AD62A2467A8A115AFDB83B4EEB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the tourism industry in the United States, including the potential impact on revenue and tourist-related commerce;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78793F3487E74C159AC441C5318CFD25"><enum>(C)</enum><text>United States and foreign passengers traveling to the United States for business-related activities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67324E8D53044F56B771D32CDFC4464D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>cost savings and potential market access from expanding operations into the Indo-Pacific region;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8DC6EC820B64E739257268C6B7E16DD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>opportunities for government-to-government collaboration available in Taiwan after preclearance operations are established;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B0EF3F90F43404BB5C79AA7C7D1CA89"><enum>(F)</enum><text>U.S. Customs and Border Patrol international and domestic port of entry staffing; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DAFFEC4BB014DE2927200E4E5AB718E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the foreign policy objectives of the United States in preserving and promoting extensive, close, and friendly commercial, cultural, and other relations between the people of the United States and the people of Taiwan; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C3D50A72E1B49A59C8BDC3B99C8C42A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>includes specific information on the anticipated homeland security benefits and the security vulnerabilities associated with conducting preclearance operations in Taiwan.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

