<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA55AF1C140604820A0CAAE1AFFCA887C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5028 IH: Security and Accountability For Everyone Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5028</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250822">August 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend section 552a of title 5, United States Code, to provide for the liability of Federal personnel for intentional or willful violations of such section, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAF5C800D9EAB4401AC0A39D0E9BB00A4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA8B5A9A6A5ED4C05AC0B80988ED6422B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Security and Accountability For Everyone Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAFE Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H61276BB9A99649DEBE90708CBDF0C795"><enum>2.</enum><header>Liability of the United States and Federal personnel under the Privacy Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 552a of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA7A6510E3F984598997AA0E9E86E36F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H79369587011442AABE2DAAF29B729BB6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (12), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H954C87F82BC54EE8A42CBE260A1E73A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (13), by inserting striking the period at the end and inserting the following: <quote>, and covered special Government employees; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE0F74686D5AA44A48C03FB482A34B71F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HB366C04F7945441791FDFA430E2E66CA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H784EC72DCD47428FB794D1B640417537"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>covered special Government employee</term> means a special Government employee (as such term is defined in section 202 of title 18) who—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB34E9BC870A440F0A5A9AB4C527805D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not serve on an advisory committee (as such term is defined in section 1001);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDEE6A82D170541E898A8AF60F8DDE52E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>serves in a position listed in level GS–13 or higher of the General Schedule, an equivalent position in the Senior Executive Service, a senior level position, a scientific or professional position, or an equivalent position in an agency-specific pay scale; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H92A8E951CA804635AB8ECF75F83F3F87"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not serve in a position that is designated for an intern or unpaid student volunteer serving pursuant to section 3111, or similar statutory authority. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H60C1460D99D94399A42320A76352532A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (g)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE72625670E8F4E7B9C95E298021B92ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="H95C7751AD80244D6BD333563979AF536"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>, and consequently a determination is made which is adverse to the individual</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H917337187991482F9AD8AB4A89102756"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>, in such a way as to have an adverse effect on an individual</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDA5419C4EB0C4FB89C503FA36351B931"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC3292A8B5DA548EFA45048FBE2EC3430" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H78DDDC1B5038424392C6E2F4FF95FAB2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Intentional or willful violations by Federal personnel</header> 
<subparagraph id="HB9CE08B4BBF044898E6DC3D01E0B4BAA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whenever Federal personnel engages in conduct described in subparagraph (C) or (D) of paragraph (1) that is intentional or willful and that results in demonstrable harm to an individual, the individual may bring a civil action against the Federal personnel, and the district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction in the matters under the provisions of this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8521582653344F6B9385A8771303FB2C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No immunity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall not be a defense to an action under this paragraph alleging intentional or willful conduct that the Federal personnel is immune from liability.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H49A548CB04154D448C1220FEE18DF88C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Remedies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In an action brought under this paragraph, the Federal personnel shall be personally liable to the individual in an amount equal to the amount authorized under paragraph (4). The United States shall not be liable for such amount. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE396A726C15411EA4967B533E6A3311"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Reimbursement of Department of Justice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an attorney for the Department of Justice represents Federal personnel in an action under this paragraph, and the Federal personnel is found to have engaged in conduct described in subparagraph (C) or (D) of paragraph (1) that was intentional or willful, the court shall enter an order requiring the Federal personnel to pay to the Department of Justice an amount that is equal to the cost of such representation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD4E936719A140E0BCD4843F37C6A5A6"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Parens patriae</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which the attorney general of a State has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of that State has been or is threatened or adversely affected by conduct described in subparagraph (C) or (D) of paragraph (1) that is intentional or willful, the attorney general of the State, as parens patriae, may bring a civil action against the agency or the Federal personnel, as applicable, on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate district court of the United States to obtain appropriate relief. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

