<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MUR25484-0D2-ST-7RT"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2064 IS: Helping Tobacco Users Quit Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2064</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title XIX and XXI of the Social Security Act to provide coverage of comprehensive tobacco cessation services under such titles, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HE7CEF8F374C344D1B45A418517F86ABE"><section section-type="section-one" id="H853C54F888914A5FADFD02E85180AFC0"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Helping Tobacco Users Quit Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H441D91336D1D4922B9325FDC3BC88559"><enum>2.</enum><header>Coverage of comprehensive tobacco cessation services in Medicaid</header><subsection id="H4333884B49E74B40905AF80A98B69E52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requiring Medicaid coverage of counseling and pharmacotherapy for cessation of tobacco use and temporary enhanced FMAP for coverage of tobacco cessation services</header><text>Section 1905 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HA01532257249481A8157A31B45F92182"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending subsection (a)(4)(D) to read as follows: <quote>(D) counseling and pharmacotherapy for cessation of tobacco use by individuals who are eligible under the State plan (as defined in subsection (bb));</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4B4180B268140F886AA7D9D5530E62A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by inserting <quote>(bb)(2),</quote> after <quote>(aa),</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD85EB3E6F0264C81A947DA06322719E5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subsection (bb) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5B2E74290EBA4D10A37A60186A4D6CB6"><subsection id="H2DB3FF86D5C44C538ABB763C3077546A"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Counseling and pharmacotherapy for cessation of tobacco use</header><paragraph id="H5B73D54261DF4999AEB94B65454695A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this title, the term <term>counseling and pharmacotherapy for cessation of tobacco use by individuals who are eligible under the State plan</term> means diagnostic, therapy, and counseling services and pharmacotherapy (including the coverage of prescription and nonprescription tobacco cessation agents approved by the Food and Drug Administration) for the cessation of tobacco use by individuals who use tobacco products or who are being treated for tobacco use that is furnished—</text><subparagraph id="H4FE41ADA51144708A80E25EB779E9E4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by or under the supervision of a physician; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA5C0E44B3E4473A9A4AD28BA391B462"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by any other health care professional who—</text><clause id="HDC2F547F3BB741648BA6580039F40791"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is legally authorized to furnish such services under State law (or the State regulatory mechanism provided by State law) of the State in which the services are furnished; and</text></clause><clause id="HCF2C2142F41A4E2CB8B49D5344BD6AE6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is authorized to receive payment for other services under this title or is designated by the Secretary for this purpose,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph"> which is recommended in the guideline entitled, <quote>Treating Tobacco Use and Dependence: 2008 Update: A Clinical Practice Guideline</quote> published by the Public Health Service in May 2008 (or any subsequent modification of such guideline) or is recommended for the cessation of tobacco use by the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force or any additional intervention approved by the Food and Drug Administration as safe and effective in helping smokers quit.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E7A0C306BFC4570A3DA9E090771341B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Temporary enhanced FMAP for coverage of tobacco cessation services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (b), for calendar quarters occurring during the period beginning on the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Helping Tobacco Users Quit Act</short-title> and ending 5 years after such date, the Federal medical assistance percentage with respect to amounts expended by a State for medical assistance for counseling and pharmacotherapy for cessation of tobacco use by individuals who are eligible under the State plan (as defined in paragraph (1)) shall be equal to 90 percent.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H54AF44FF89AB430B943B6E4D93F102F3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No cost sharing</header><paragraph id="HF2A5210976584E768D3CB31FC8A9301F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsections (a)(2) and (b)(2) of section 1916 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396o">42 U.S.C. 1396o</external-xref>) are each amended—</text><subparagraph id="H4AB07FBB6559445AAE62E7996A087765"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>, and counseling</quote> and all that follows through <quote>section 1905(bb)(2)(A)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED0F7C5AA0574388B708CC533DF7D886"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FD6DBA680494939BEE1F84F57297543"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (J), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0A375BD0CF949CF8DF79386464536F7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H45E27814D6B342C6ABB0626B6EF23F81"><subparagraph id="H2226EB8665D946779955228A58E54B98"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">counseling and pharmacotherapy for cessation of tobacco use by individuals who are eligible under the State plan (as defined in section 1905(bb)) and covered outpatient drugs (as defined in subsection (k)(2) of section 1927 and including nonprescription drugs described in subsection (d)(2) of such section) that are prescribed for purposes of promoting tobacco cessation in accordance with the guideline specified in section 1905(bb); and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B85A93D785F4E8DA88E9A4DD5C4E44D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application to alternative cost sharing</header><text>Section 1916A(b)(3)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396o-1">42 U.S.C. 1396o–1(b)(3)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HF5B1536E566C42FEB20836751994B453"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>, and counseling and pharmacotherapy for cessation of tobacco use by pregnant women (as defined in section 1905(bb))</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26ED701CF09E4031A12D058953A1E529"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA26BC831B60D4D63B3E6B666E39B6F16"><clause id="HBDD827B17FC344B4BFC2EC62E4CFB706"><enum>(xv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Counseling and pharmacotherapy for cessation of tobacco use by individuals who are eligible under the State plan (as defined in section 1905(bb)) and covered outpatient drugs (as defined in subsection (k)(2) of section 1927 and including nonprescription drugs described in subsection (d)(2) of such section) that are prescribed for purposes of promoting tobacco cessation in accordance with the guideline specified in section 1905(bb).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF886F06A58AC485A926533F1C9F9194E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception from optional restriction under Medicaid prescription drug coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1927(d)(2)(F) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8(d)(2)(F)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFE2EAFEC75544916826860B11D730609"><subparagraph id="HF8208D5F9E4C49AF872500CBA6C89ABA"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nonprescription drugs, except, when recommended in accordance with the guideline referred to in section 1905(bb), agents approved by the Food and Drug Administration for purposes of promoting tobacco cessation.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HBBADFA55B69A477CB370E2BB0701D231"><enum>(d)</enum><header>State monitoring and promoting of comprehensive tobacco cessation services under Medicaid</header><text>Section 1902(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HEE3CFE41DFDE43C8BA5745AA6041BA6C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (86), by striking at the end <quote>and</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H571DDABE1D21443A83C21A9E5B274FAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (87), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BFF9B4D732A4477A7DE3F2DC7376D72"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (87) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3E7E52198CE8422A864CBFDFFF1163CE"><paragraph id="HA3D09E818E3748319AAA7EC373FC5AE0"><enum>(88)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide for the State to monitor and promote the use of comprehensive tobacco cessation services under the State plan (including conducting an outreach campaign to increase awareness of the benefits of using such services) among—</text><subparagraph id="H1D1C84C00B294EC4BD0DE304EA6CB9E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>individuals entitled to medical assistance under the State plan who use tobacco products; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E4C0E26EAEC47FFAB6B97C886553BD8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>clinicians and others who provide services to individuals entitled to medical assistance under the State plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H85B90C7A55B3485D92958D42B4551DE3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal reimbursement for outreach campaign</header><text>Section 1903(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HC6580A1CDF6E407D90FF40D9D821C2C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; plus</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14D9D27194E147FE8ACBE87FB80227F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (7) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB4C6E68E461A4877BEBE0B66203A3BAD"><paragraph id="H82A497E5D0834296AAD19A5B3522A056"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the development, implementation, and evaluation of an outreach campaign to—</text><subparagraph id="H1525C6791A3445CAA178B629ED79B509"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increase awareness of comprehensive tobacco cessation services covered in the State plan among—</text><clause id="HB272F0177B3C431799786652014AEE50"><enum>(i)</enum><text>individuals who are likely to be eligible for medical assistance under the State plan; and</text></clause><clause id="HCD35ACDFD96A4F34B6907230F4C38F13"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>clinicians and others who provide services to individuals who are likely to be eligible for medical assistance under the State plan; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04D33B0DFF264BCA9F704480D4D30A6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increase awareness of the benefits of using comprehensive tobacco cessation services covered in the State plan among—</text><clause id="H94DD5B904C424B11A5F432DF156AE872"><enum>(i)</enum><text>individuals who are likely to be eligible for medical assistance under the State plan; and</text></clause><clause id="H9D022AD65EC747B0BF5E28AC8964B7BD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>clinicians and others who provide services to individuals who are likely to be eligible for medical assistance under the State plan about the benefits of using comprehensive tobacco cessation services,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">for calendar quarters occurring during the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this paragraph and ending on 5 years after the date of enactment of this paragraph, an amount equal to 90 percent of the sums expended during each quarter which are attributable to such development, implementation, and evaluation, and for calendar quarters succeeding such period, an amount equal to Federal medical assistance percentage determined under section 1905(b) of the sums expended during each quarter which are so attributable.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H779100F1BDB340F998D7B842BDBA6F17"><enum>(f)</enum><header>No prior authorization for tobacco cessation drugs under Medicaid</header><text>Section 1927(d) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H589725C6E3F046F7BF1DA0CFB9EF14C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A), by striking <quote>A State</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (8), a State</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2817971B53554B769D757275AA2B1B14"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9DA54C48732E409CA418DEF3DF1A7233"><paragraph id="H181F646694F44A5F96BEC6A911BC18A3"><enum>(8)</enum><header>No prior authorization programs for tobacco cessation drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State plan may not require, as a condition of coverage or payment for a covered outpatient drug, the approval of an agent to promote smoking cessation (including agents approved by the Food and Drug Administration) or tobacco cessation.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBA41D85081614A96919BDAD86A15E8DD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exclusion of enhanced payments from territorial caps</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for purposes of section 1108 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1308">42 U.S.C. 1308</external-xref>), with respect to any additional amount paid to a territory as a result of the application of section 1905(bb)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(bb)(2)</external-xref>)—</text><paragraph id="H849F99B5B26049B4A47F96A681B369AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the limitation on payments to territories under subsections (f) and (g) of such section 1108 shall not apply to such additional amounts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H29CA7E1D573A421EBD1B3172A8A096EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such additional amounts shall be disregarded in applying such subsections.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F7E3E865FAC4698A4E08DC0BDDE7002"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the first day of the first fiscal year that begins on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H23AEB5F5B29C4233BDF7053AFC0468FA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Coverage of comprehensive tobacco cessation services in CHIP</header><subsection id="H08F07B42076F40559845BD5300E41F52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requiring CHIP coverage of counseling and pharmacotherapy for cessation of tobacco use</header><paragraph id="H69D4016EDF7744C0A9D6DE6AA33F015F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 2103(c)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397cc">42 U.S.C. 1397cc(c)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C5144EB86F5453A89C2CB6692CC6463"><subparagraph id="HF4555EA0833F45B79EF452C68BD73E5A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Counseling and pharmacotherapy for cessation of tobacco use by individuals who are eligible under the State child health plan.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H696496A539CD4387A6E2A5DD8CB1BF2D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Counseling and pharmacotherapy for cessation of tobacco use defined</header><text>Section 2110(c) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397jj">42 U.S.C. 1397jj(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE2FA126AB1C48B3AC42F4038CA335C7"><paragraph id="H7CD3D5C6D965427190B429C9B5AF9581"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Counseling and pharmacotherapy for cessation of tobacco use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>counseling and pharmacotherapy for cessation of tobacco use</term> means diagnostic, therapy, and counseling services and pharmacotherapy (including the coverage of prescription and nonprescription tobacco cessation agents approved by the Food and Drug Administration) for the cessation of tobacco use by individuals who use tobacco products or who are being treated for tobacco use that are furnished—</text><subparagraph id="H3FC24DE789294AB0B29B4124C831B026"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by or under the supervision of a physician; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72CE92C6AF674AE4A183001232CA9AEC"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>by any other health care professional who—</text>
                <clause id="H6E92F83676D64F96A21AC12D76501951">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>is legally authorized to furnish such services under State law (or the State regulatory mechanism provided by State law) of the State in which the services are furnished; and</text>
                </clause>
                <clause id="HB084FFB7FE1E4CFF9DD376E0EE7A1007">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>is authorized to receive payment for other services under this title or is designated by the Secretary for this purpose</text>
                </clause>
                <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">which is recommended in
                  the guideline entitled, <quote>Treating Tobacco Use and Dependence: 2008 Update: A
                    Clinical Practice Guideline</quote> published by the Public Health Service in
                  May 2008 (or any subsequent modification of such guideline) or is recommended for
                  the cessation of tobacco use by the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force or any
                  additional intervention approved by the Food and Drug Administration as safe and
                  effective in helping smokers quit.</continuation-text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H65E1F6F57AAA436681433DA4C1C4EB24"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No cost sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2103(e) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397cc">42 U.S.C. 1397cc(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE2605E7DF4546EBBE7A52E76A91540D"><paragraph id="HEF5169CC2A5049978A9FF8FC5932E11D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>No cost sharing on benefits for counseling and pharmacotherapy for cessation of tobacco use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State child health plan may not impose deductibles, coinsurance, or other cost sharing with respect to benefits for counseling and pharmacotherapy for cessation of tobacco use (as defined in section 2110(c)(10)) and prescription drugs that are covered under a State child health plan that are prescribed for purposes of promoting tobacco cessation in accordance with the guideline specified in section 2110(c)(10)(B).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HBABE27A22EEC47AF894151804168F6AE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception from optional restriction under CHIP prescription drug coverage</header><text>Section 2103 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397cc">42 U.S.C. 1397cc</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8966B9E4C9594A8081B7996461A8D477"><subsection id="HB8848F15EA6C4CBA8E570D738513B909"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exception from optional restriction under CHIP prescription drug coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State child health plan may exclude or otherwise restrict nonprescription drugs, except, in the case of—</text><paragraph id="H2DD5E3EB1DB84074BA472503CF23BD0E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pregnant women when recommended in accordance with the guideline specified in section 2110(c)(10)(B), agents approved by the Food and Drug Administration for purposes of promoting tobacco cessation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF512D28688B74478A2DE4AD3E5ECF945"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">individuals who are eligible under the State child health plan when recommended in accordance with the Guideline referred to in section 2110(c)(10)(B), agents approved by the Food and Drug Administration for purposes of promoting tobacco cessation.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H3C34DD4352FE462195970DEE2D6198A8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>State monitoring and promoting of comprehensive tobacco cessation services under CHIP</header><text>Section 2102 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397bb">42 U.S.C. 1397bb</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC153E93F71454B8A9C71B86FA0C4FE3A"><subsection id="H5B3934A645164A2AAFB838700B3B4F4C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>State monitoring and promoting of comprehensive tobacco cessation services under CHIP</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State child health plan shall include a description of the procedures to be used by the State to monitor and promote the use of comprehensive tobacco cessation services under the State plan (including conducting an outreach campaign to increase awareness of the benefits of using such services) among—</text><paragraph id="HE56A8B3A16DA4A67B43CC8C585109CBB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>individuals entitled to medical assistance under the State child health plan who use tobacco products; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72BC0BCE3155417CBA86FCCEFD24D3A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>clinicians and others who provide services to individuals entitled to medical assistance under the State child health plan.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HB63D83957B1E4865B02913630FEA47A0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal reimbursement for CHIP coverage and outreach campaign</header><paragraph id="H20DA6C5B3A3F48FBB9FD3BE855767100"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 2105(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397ee">42 U.S.C. 1397ee(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB0C71EBB6584B9AA0EF6A3652E86935"><paragraph id="H51ACCBF77A68479185C34DE813EAC7A3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Federal reimbursement for CHIP coverage of comprehensive tobacco cessation services and outreach campaign</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the payments made under paragraph (1) for calendar quarters occurring during the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this paragraph and ending on 5 years after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary shall pay—</text><subparagraph id="H54A195F25B544A5789B2581DA757CA94"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an amount equal to 90 percent of the sums expended during each quarter which are attributable to the cost of furnishing counseling and pharmacotherapy for cessation of tobacco use by individuals who are eligible under the State child health plan (net of any payments made to the State under paragraph (1) with respect to such counseling and pharmacotherapy); plus</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0193D8FC651945DE8B1755A6E8399C2D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amount equal to 90 percent of the sums expended during each quarter which are attributable to the development, implementation, and evaluation of an outreach campaign to—</text><clause id="H187BECCD9B524651AAA3DE2248A3D802"><enum>(i)</enum><text>increase awareness of comprehensive tobacco cessation services covered in the State child health plan among—</text><subclause id="H22BE764D604C4355B85A8CEE69D175F1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>individuals who are likely to be eligible for medical assistance under the State child health plan; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HEBD34D84233A476789651C73F16C0DD4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>clinicians and others who provide services to individuals who are likely to be eligible for medical assistance under the State child health plan; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H1C1CF6904B6643DCBBFF13E10691B4B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>increase awareness of the benefits of using comprehensive tobacco cessation services covered in the State child health plan among—</text><subclause id="HB368AA4C8236498CAC48913BEE529799"><enum>(I)</enum><text>individuals who are likely to be eligible for medical assistance under the State child health plan; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H67CBF72283B24E73A54516529F50FC1C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>clinicians and others who provide services to individuals who are likely to be eligible for medical assistance under the State child health plan about the benefits of using comprehensive tobacco cessation services.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1C3C8128A434865A18D7DFB5D53107B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adjustment of chip allotments</header><text>Section 2104(m) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397dd">42 U.S.C. 1397dd(m)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HCE6184AE51A049F9A715AE96C413967E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(B), by striking <quote>and (12)</quote> and inserting <quote>(12), and (13)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6DD7E103D6049FA99743328040C4AB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H36E39AAD17DB44ACACBDA340CBB6ED0C"><paragraph id="H348C8621DC344CA0B27BF87E5BEE8157"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Adjusting allotments to account for Federal payments for CHIP coverage of comprehensive tobacco cessation services and outreach campaign</header><text>If a State (including the District of Columbia and each commonwealth and territory) receives a payment for a fiscal year under section 2105(a)(5), the allotment determined for the State for such fiscal year shall be increased by the amount of such payment.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE179BCEEBFF4294AF3191FF9808DD86"><enum>(f)</enum><header>No prior authorization for tobacco cessation drugs under CHIP</header><text>Section 2103 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397cc">42 U.S.C. 1397cc</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (c), is further amended—</text><paragraph id="HFDACE8117ED547518FBA25679675C960"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(2)(A), by inserting <quote>(in accordance with subsection (h))</quote> after <quote>Coverage of prescription drugs</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC4DC3B7DFD14747B926A754B8AA91B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H90DDFCDE31BA41C282C15286EA28898B"><subsection id="H83D48DB86C164A5AAB650AC8EFDDE464"><enum>(h)</enum><header>No prior authorization programs for tobacco cessation drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State child health plan may not require, as a condition of coverage or payment for a prescription drugs, the approval of an agent to promote smoking cessation (including agents approved by the Food and Drug Administration) or tobacco cessation.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB190909296B4362918C3D73E4E99371"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the first day of the first fiscal year that begins on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H01E6A9FC446C4B538366DF8EBC11B952"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">None of the amendments made by this Act shall be construed to limit coverage of any counseling or pharmacotherapy for individuals under 18 years of age.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

