<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD61B1133CC6046BF862C9D698B107184" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 637 IH: Commemorating the 69th anniversary of the continuous operations of the Mauna Loa Observatory.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 637</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250805">August 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commemorating the 69th anniversary of the continuous operations of the Mauna Loa Observatory.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Mauna Loa Observatory (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>MLO</quote>) is an atmospheric baseline station of the Global Monitoring Laboratory within the Earth System Research Laboratories (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>ESRL</quote>) organized under the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration’s Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the mission of the ESRL is to measure atmospheric constituents that are capable of forcing adjustments to the climate of the Earth and those that may deplete the ozone layer;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the mission of the ESRL is primarily accomplished through long-term tropospheric measurements of key atmospheric parameters such as carbon dioxide, carbon monoxide, methane, chlorofluorocarbons, ozone, sulfur dioxide, nitrous oxide, radon, aerosols, optical depth, and a spectrum of solar radiation parameters;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the MLO, due to its location on the north flank of Mauna Loa Volcano, on Hawaii Island, is the premier long-term atmospheric monitoring facility on Earth for sampling the troposphere as it protrudes through the strong marine temperature inversion layer present in the region;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the MLO, constructed in 1956 and continuously in operation since, is the site where the ever-increasing concentrations of global atmospheric carbon dioxide have been observed;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the MLO has been home to hundreds of atmospheric research programs—</text> 
<paragraph id="id37206ca7c23146238e3a79655d05e772"><enum>(1)</enum><text>with national and international universities and government organizations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc4d9ab4a916c4ae384f9d3f12919c455"><enum>(2)</enum><text>related to a diverse spectrum of research categories; and</text></paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> Whereas the MLO and its 4 sites on Hawaii Island, including the critical administrative office in Hilo, is home to a dedicated workforce committed to their mission to acquire, evaluate, and make available accurate, long-term records of the atmosphere in a manner that allows the causes and consequences of change to be understood: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H1927A3B5124D43F789970C761B7D6C4C"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HEA2F5ED63E914E299F14A35AC8713F76"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD5233C79442246B3860651D56907657F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commemorates the 69th anniversary of the continuous operations of the Mauna Loa Observatory (referred to in this resolution as the <quote>MLO</quote>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H661D577E4E5E41948555B3E82CD3F5D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the monumental contributions that the research conducted at and data produced by the MLO has provided to the global leadership in atmospheric research of the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB89DC02C5F8E4A1D889F0885A967A713"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirms the House of Representative’s strong support for the critical ongoing operations of the MLO, including its 4 sites on Hawaii Island; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3275A19D91C64636AE1377BB37652109"><enum>(4)</enum><text>honors the cultural significance of Mauna Loa to the Native Hawaiian community.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

