<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H032BE97455E5480899C072274F71206E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4676 IH: Modern Firearm Safety Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4676</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001216">Mr. Mills</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the imposition of requirements that handguns have certain features generally absent from firearms in common use, and to restore the civil and natural rights of Americans in States hostile to liberty, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H657F993D35E141A08D46C6348C5ACDDC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H90E732C8D244428CBAD682B85CDF17F4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Modern Firearm Safety Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA77184387FAA489A80A7BEBDA8F61D1B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds that State and local governmental requirements for handgun design that mandate features not ordinarily present on the affected models limit the selection of handguns available to law-abiding citizens in these jurisdictions; artificially inflate the price of constitutionally protected arms; present safety concerns by altering the intended design and function of the affected models; violate the Second Amendment to the Constitution of the United States; and pose an unacceptable restraint on interstate commerce. The purpose of this Act to is preempt any such requirements that exceed those imposed by Federal statute.</text></section> 
<section id="H1576505BE05F4DD88CEFC4D35E58BF59"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on imposition of requirements that handguns have certain features generally absent from firearms in common use</header> 
<subsection id="H294B739993804A2DA363F68F4599E9EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 927 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HEC052DD506E4428F9BAD96ECF0DF90BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>No</quote> and inserting <quote>(a)<header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC"> In general.—</header-in-text>Except as provided in subsection (b), no</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2F1EEDD672724B14BFE3994AE90D791E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HC421D1E0239645BF812AC669ECBCEA11" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HEEDE6007433149F18D6AD1984F4554BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on imposition of requirements that handguns have certain features generally absent from firearms in common use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States, or of any State or political subdivision of a State, may not implement or enforce any provision of law or regulation that requires or has the effect of requiring, or promulgate any provision of regulation that would require or have the effect of requiring, a handgun that is in, or has been shipped or transported in, interstate or foreign commerce to incorporate any design feature, functionality, safety mechanism, or performance standard that is not required by Federal statute as a condition for the lawful manufacture, sale, or receipt of the handgun, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7F14298D69DC4BB5B021C9DA32F83034"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a device that indicates whether the handgun is loaded;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7081A8E18F6B408ABBA2AA9890A8D781"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a mechanism that prevents a handgun from being fired if an ammunition magazine is not fully inserted into the handgun;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H079FDB009AC244448E91B91AB48DBF81"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the capability of imprinting the cartridge casing or projectile of ammunition fired from the handgun with characters meant to identify the handgun from which the ammunition is fired;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF48937824E541028820D98764420392"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any device, mechanism, or technology that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFB26348372D94371BE95DB58EF39E8F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is designed or intended to perform any function described in the preceding provisions of this section; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6A848445E75042B2923EF58A12577B0B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be readily converted to be capable of performing any such function; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H590F558DE8F04AADB4FD4E91F29880C8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the capability of accepting the attachment of any device or mechanism described in paragraph (4).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

