<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0D0358FE2C02417CA14EFFDCD1985E5F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4724 IH: Corporate Crime Database Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4724</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of the Bureau of Justice Statistics to establish a database with respect to corporate offenses, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H710340E9996C47E6B5DD8A1E09E27C68" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H1A12D6086D2B4F67AA87DB5DF4A6C179"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Corporate Crime Database Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEA0FA74A9F544556BFC9C86D47146D7F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Corporate crime database at the Bureau of Justice Statistics</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H80F1A7B2FBDE4F0995A9422784E53FF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part C of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10131">34 U.S.C. 10131 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H97A3DFEA0B184E6684830FFE82A08247"> 
<section id="H3952FAB4C7774559961AEE21CD6EF680"><enum>305.</enum><header>Corporate crime database</header> 
<subsection id="H6146B75CB92442AD82383C4DF827A448"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H4DECF5B02E654516B9E97DCC923DD233"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Business entity</header><text>The term <term>business entity</term> means a corporation, association, partnership, limited liability company, limited liability partnership, or other legal entity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBC66725781F04741B6F408579ECE8220"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Corporate offense</header><text>The term <term>corporate offense</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H2625B18E0416472F8A9C7E2C1C9EA9E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a violation or alleged violation of Federal law committed by—</text> 
<clause id="H228E5E784A7741C2A2958D874E99E894"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a business entity; or</text></clause> <clause id="HEA79E3C3892148E09AFB8C6DBACE98F9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an individual employed by a business entity within the conduct of the individual's occupational role; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFE9594C9153B44A9B728925AF381CE23"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other violation determined by the Director to be a corporate offense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF2A4AEC1B87C4913B82D32C89AA1A7E3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Bureau.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC47AC0A9C6BF4FD19E643D57C4C0051B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Enforcement action</header><text>The term <term>enforcement action</term> includes any concluded administrative, civil, or criminal enforcement action or any declination, settlement, deferred prosecution agreement, or non-prosecution agreement entered into by a Federal agency to enforce a law or regulation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD621DD8D2DE74B38BFA2697CD8A4A700"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Federal agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal agency</term> has the meaning given the term <term>agency</term> in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCFD0C400880D49B8BC8651B562F3A51A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Beginning not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Corporate Crime Database Act of 2025</short-title>, the Director shall—</text> <paragraph id="H52CFE49A178044CD9150F116CF721033"><enum>(1)</enum><text>collect, aggregate, and analyze information regarding enforcement actions taken with respect to corporate offenses; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9CFD484472324B1887ABD7A2FDD6C460"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publish on the internet website of the Bureau a database of the enforcement actions described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H08554AD188434C2886D409222E14C595"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Information included</header><text>The database established under subsection (b) shall include the following information on an enforcement action with respect to corporate offenses:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE4EC2D9096C440B88D858706859448A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Each business entity or individual identified by the enforcement action.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF3C0EBE4A104330ACF3FDC82044069F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The employer of an individual identified under paragraph (1), as determined relevant by the Director.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68B8C85992144FEAB410AA9DAFA3748B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The parent company of a business entity identified under paragraph (1) or the parent company of any employer identified under paragraph (2), as determined relevant by the Director.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H885CD22F87E847729A93D12011228E73"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The type of offense or alleged offense committed by the business entity or individual.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HABA66A9A01DE4A81AB858B2CF75C3FB7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any relevant statute or regulation violated by the business entity or individual.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD1AD9611EA9A42CCAC8180A5E255CBC2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Each Federal agency bringing the enforcement action.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H53A4957C31724FAEB8B987DA9412F089"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The outcome of the enforcement action, if any, including all documentation relevant to the outcome.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA596B8389824597B27011CB72DD6DDC"><enum>(8)</enum><text>An unique identifier for each business entity, individual, employer, or parent company identified by the enforcement action.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDD05BEB5DF34418AA183B98831C92F0F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Any additional information the Director determines necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAD57C718820948C5B0D2C539F860754A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Information collection by Director</header> <paragraph id="HE9FD25A329CD48D492ADFD97A6DDE511"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Corporate Crime Database Act of 2025</short-title>, the Director shall establish guidance for the collection of information from each Federal agency that carries out an enforcement action with respect to corporate offenses, including identification of each Federal agency that shall submit information to the Director and the manner in which, time at which, and frequency with which the information shall be submitted.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0DFF680EDF7C4909A51BF1BF40B61347"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cooperation by Federal agencies</header><text>Each Federal agency identified in the guidance established under paragraph (1) shall submit to the Director the information specified by the Director, in accordance with that guidance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA526DB4C3B034E9DA424ECE6E552DA82"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Timing of information included</header><text>To the extent to which information is available, the database established under subsection (b) shall include the information described in subsection (c) on each enforcement action with respect to corporate offenses taken by a Federal agency before, on, or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Corporate Crime Database Act of 2025</short-title>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9D1CD9F2D39C4D31BB52501E242C0224"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Publication details</header> 
<paragraph id="H5BA83C77C53A4373BF6F5C91C23EAC74"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Corporate Crime Database Act of 2025</short-title>, the Director shall publish on the internet website of the Bureau the database established under subsection (b) in a format that is searchable, downloadable, and accessible to the public.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H651EA458BFBC40BAB2AC3AD4D6D79A10"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Update of information</header><text>The Director shall update the information included in the database established under subsection (b) each time the information is collected under subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBA4F2A25A95843D8A390C7D9714E3474"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the publication of the database established under subsection (b), and annually thereafter, the Director shall submit to Congress a report including—</text> <paragraph id="H5674597704DD4835881C01DF95197DCB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the data collected and analyzed under this section related to corporate offenses, including an analysis of recidivism, offenses and alleged offenses, and enforcement actions;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H405A645E880741EC9D20BD9D41DFE130"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an estimate of the impact of corporate offenses on victims and the public; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H00172432C760445E9132EC6B77F65EEC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations, developed in consultation with the Attorney General, for legislative or administrative actions to improve the ability of Federal agencies to monitor, respond to, and deter instances of corporate offenses.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H15BD9B377F3348B48FCB342FC0542F3A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Chief Data Officer Council</header><text>Section 3520A(b) of title 44, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC18A8D623BD04D1A92D8923E70C9AADC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC42E9B104F4A402292F333351A21A382"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2A38CFE09068403C885DB951D6AB4531"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12C2E45FE07342EE881AB96C57451AA9"> 
<paragraph id="H3C7374D347584C99BB16ACBDB6EFFF18"><enum>(6)</enum><text>identify ways in which a Federal agency (as defined in section 305 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968) that carries out an enforcement action (as defined in that section) with respect to a corporate offense (as defined in that section) can improve the collection, digitalization, tabulation, sharing, and publishing of information under that section, and the standardization of those processes, in order to carry out that section.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

