<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25566-5GL-NL-N9N">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1655 IS: Protecting Veterans in Crisis Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>S. 1655</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20250507">May 7, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title>To expand congressional oversight of the operation of the Veterans Crisis Line of the Department of Veterans Affairs, to improve workforce protections for all Veterans Crisis Line personnel, and to ensure robust performance standards that fulfill the Veterans Crisis Line mission and meet caller demand, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H05016EDA8B38497D9E0369DF660E726E">
<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Veterans in Crisis Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="id40ffea801e4943b9b8e12da4243d2988"><enum>2.</enum><header>Oversight of Veterans Crisis Line</header> <subsection id="idf8f3a18ae3c34cb5bea410d986a823bc"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notification of pending termination of Veterans Crisis Line employees</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id74237e41f7d04f28bdcfd4b73699c16a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 48 hours before terminating the employment of any employee of the Veterans Crisis Line, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a notification that provides—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd87a3ec77aef4c3a8675012db9f9c1cd"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a justification of cause for such termination;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a9f445378da487488215f4af49465f7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a clarification on whether the employee is a veteran or military spouse; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c4abc24c3bd49d5b81d138fe87262a0"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detailed plan to ensure continuity of the mission readiness of the Veterans Crisis Line in the event of such termination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idba149da5e2bf4556a90bf9f2711b0c70"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This subsection shall terminate on January 20, 2029.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="id8877bdc795bb416fa3153c99ee85e85f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on Veterans Crisis Line personnel</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report that includes the following:</text> <paragraph id="idcd0ae6e8c7804afb87534755a57e0303"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of employees working for the Veterans Crisis Line on January 20, 2025, which shall include a breakdown by job category, probationary status, whether the employee is a veteran, whether the employee is a military spouse, status of employment on the date of submission of the report, and date of reinstatement.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idd69620919fc34958b41a6d43bed2376a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of employees terminated from the Veterans Crisis Line on or around February 13, 2025, which shall include a breakdown by job category, probationary status, whether the employee is a veteran, whether the employee is a military spouse, status of employment on the date of submission of the report, and date of reinstatement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id39e2cc06266f49e4bcec20f594feeac5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of employees terminated from the Veterans Crisis Line on or around February 24, 2025, which shall include a breakdown by job category, probationary status, whether the employee is a veteran, whether the employee is a military spouse, status of employment on the date of submission of the report, and date of reinstatement.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idb51d9aa0693f44128e14ad5caa239d0a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The number of employees working for the Veterans Crisis Line on the date of submission of the report, which shall include a breakdown by job category, probationary status, whether the employee is a veteran, and whether the employee is a military spouse.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="idf5298152428e47e2a204446046ebb39e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on Veterans Crisis Line operations and performance</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 30 days thereafter until January 20, 2029, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report that includes the following:</text>
<paragraph id="id39b04a433ea44d789e7f5412bcebcf7d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of the performance of the Veterans Crisis Line, as compared to the previous month and the same month of the previous calendar year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id78ae6b7f8a22430ead460f35decee91f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Average wait times for a caller to connect with an operator and the volume of unanswered calls.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id2b637b6cdd9c470eac11d60aba8c68b8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Ratios of callers to phone operators, both in-person and remote, trainers, and all other positions affiliated with the Veterans Crisis Line.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idccfe9548ea564d29bd9c09940bd20315"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A report on resources used and outstanding.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id8a5aa93cbfaf44758d5f01b8f5afbe34"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A staffing report broken down by job category.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="id77d43d65075845b6b8605ef04d48f9f8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Comptroller General report on improvements to Veterans Crisis Line</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report on the operation and performance of the Veterans Crisis Line, including recommendations for improvement.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4cafc16f29ef4b629e0d89e92c3de272"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Veterans Crisis Line defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Veterans Crisis Line</term> means the toll-free hotline for veterans established under section 1720F(h) of title 38, United States Code.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

