<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6DE11751D131453F9BBBF9908805FA30" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3755 IH: Safe Stay Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3755</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250605">June 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 to update the fire prevention and control guidelines to require the mandatory installation of carbon monoxide alarms in all places of public accommodation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H01356910CD074A09A10DC13D2FE7E73C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H465D337C989748608ECE3DF4273393A5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe Stay Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4B5622309A114399B8D8AB348165257E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Updating fire prevention and control guidelines to require mandatory installation of carbon monoxide alarms in places of public accommodation</header> <subsection id="H69D54AF7F2CF4F86818EF97A8BB82CCD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 29(a) of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2225">15 U.S.C. 2225(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8ECCE4EA7018400CBA6DA17C58B55374"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H9B8D608FDF174E7C9DDBEE94F8A2C806"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Standard 74</quote> and inserting <quote>Standard 72</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6A2890C0064C403EA500B4EAB276B49D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC6656175838C4D7C8553C2B19608F774"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3C15A02ACA054379A1E1FD67EE8F053E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8E401584BC8A4F95922DD668A9399B8F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HD2415426716D449DAA19D5E5B6D53E6C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a requirement that compliant carbon monoxide alarms shall be installed in each sleeping or dwelling unit within each place of public accommodation affecting commerce.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEFED6897E6D044CA96DD01F3C0F7E9FA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 29(d) of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2225">15 U.S.C. 2225(d)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC4FCC277B7984EB7886E48FA8D835CB6" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H8C6BDEF23F904F498DEA83D19ACD213A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>compliant carbon monoxide alarm</quote> means a carbon monoxide alarm or detection system installed in accordance with the International Fire Code or National Fire Protection Association Standard 72, and the applicable UL standards referenced therein.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H96774F402BC1407B9CB290F5312578E4"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>National Fire Protection Association Standard 72</quote> refers to the latest edition of the National Fire Alarm and Signaling Code published by the National Fire Protection Association Standard, or any successor standard relating to the proper installation of carbon monoxide alarms.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F47D2E8D86249D2813BE35CC1BF487C"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>International Fire Code</quote> refers to the latest edition of the International Fire Code published by the International Code Council, or any successor code relating to the proper installation of carbon monoxide alarms.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H17214FC3FDB64EC99C532C685298864A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Dissemination of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 30 of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2226">15 U.S.C. 2226</external-xref>) is amended in the first sentence—</text> <paragraph id="H4E1CC081CFC04E1CB1E002C363AA5F0B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and automatic smoke detection systems</quote> and inserting <quote>, automatic smoke detection systems, and compliant carbon monoxide alarms (as such term is defined in section 29)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA1480733EB243A3993FE554E258C0CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>and compliant carbon monoxide alarms</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2DAD614F01404551A8C9B0496D9547C7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Updating of lists</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall take such steps as may be necessary to ensure that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2E977A5EDDC74CCA83AE15A8EC14700A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each State updates the list submitted to the Administrator pursuant to subsection (a) of section 28 of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2224">15 U.S.C. 2224</external-xref>) to reflect the amendments made by this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H157983C18A174D28BE37472385ACB5B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the master list published under subsection (b) of such section is updated to reflect the changes to the State lists made pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5CE0AE75591745538552A1ECA6352AA9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Interpretation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act may be construed to prohibit the application of standards with respect to the installation of carbon monoxide alarms or detection systems in places of public accommodation that are higher than the standards under the latest edition of the International Fire Code or the National Fire Protection Association Standard 72, and the applicable UL standards referenced therein (as such terms are defined in section 29 of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2225">15 U.S.C. 2225</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (b)).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H02A7066EFFD24A09AABD2796A743602A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Notice of compliant carbon monoxide alarms</header> <subsection id="HB666E6334C6B4D3C81D2B705213ED98A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The owner or operator of a place of public accommodation affecting commerce (as such term is defined in section 4 of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2203">15 U.S.C. 2203</external-xref>)) shall provide to each guest of such place of public accommodation, upon check-in, written notice attesting that such place of public accommodation is in compliance with the requirement described in paragraph (3) of section 29(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2225">15 U.S.C. 2225(a)</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE46F3FFB005048098ADAB6756CA7C5B5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header> 
<paragraph id="H3816950D8BC1479899357FE9A736A40D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of subsection (a) or a regulation promulgated under such subsection shall be treated as a violation of a regulation under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C0DA9C3A65E4A0580A92413B15AC13A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce subsection (a) and the regulations promulgated under such subsection in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section. Any person who violates such subsection or a regulation promulgated under such subsection shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF0A5B63C3EE44609DBA57DF2F8DFEC4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission may promulgate regulations under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, to carry out subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCBA807D5DB20488492A51F8688E7CFC3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

