<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6D225B6C2FD34E7182787975EE31114E" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 174 IH: Impeaching Amir Hatem Mahdy Ali, a judge of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 174</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Impeaching Amir Hatem Mahdy Ali, a judge of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HF6EC89FAE08B4DD4AA9426873688EF46"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H2F623C601FD24DE79A7652A198C4EE6B"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That Amir Hatem Mahdy Ali, a judge of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, is impeached for high crimes and misdemeanors, and that the following article of impeachment be exhibited to the Senate:</text><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC145526B410A46D48DDF5B172C8FD722"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Article of impeachment exhibited by the House of Representatives of the United States of America in the name of itself and of the people of the United States of America, against Amir Hatem Mahdy Ali, a judge of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, in maintenance and support of its impeachment against him for high crimes and misdemeanors.</text></subsection></section><section id="H2921CC3E626C482CBB257C95A3A48553" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum/><header>Article I</header><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0908DDEFD6144AA483F55DA0F15913DF"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amir Hatem Mahdy Ali, a judge of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, engaged in a pattern of conduct that is incompatible with the trust and confidence placed in him as a Federal judge, as follows:</text></subsection><subsection id="HC3C5B213258F4A43801BA9BC75F61C1D"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Judge Ali, in a 2024 written statement to the Senate Judiciary Committee, asserted that a <quote>judge must decide issues based on an impartial and objective application of the law to the record before the court</quote>. In issuing a temporary restraining order against the <quote>pausing</quote> of funds promulgated in Executive Order 14169, Judge Ali has without merit marginalized the President’s Article II authority, which vests the power to conduct foreign policy in the President of the United States, and has further compromised the President’s fiduciary obligation to review federal agencies and programs. This patent violation of Constitutional precedent—which necessarily precludes an explanation based on ignorance of the supreme law of the land—is entirely inconsistent with serving the United States as a district court judge.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8E04EA2F7ABB481E899964447CF51A34"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Judge Ali, in mandating the immediate outlay of funds in contradiction of subsection (a) of Section 3 of Executive Order 14169, has done so in a manner that is arbitrary and capricious. The understood purpose of the President’s Executive order was to review such funds for consistency with United States foreign policy. By mandating immediate funding disbursement of funds paused by the President’s Executive order, Judge Ali did so with no consideration for the troubled history of foreign assistance through the United States Agency for International Development (USAID). A March 2021 GAO report indicates that from FY2015 until FY2019, USAID did not consistently ensure that subawards provided for projects in the Gaza Strip and Judea and Samaria complied with regulations aimed at preventing financial support for terrorism. More recently, in November 2024, USAID was found to have financed hundreds of thousands of meals for al-Qaida affiliated fighters in Syria. While arguing that the Trump administration funding pause caused <quote>irreparable harm</quote>, Judge Ali failed to consider that his decision could easily inflict <quote>irreparable harm</quote> on Americans and American interests.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1F7123676A02454DAF5AAD5A7B29552F"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Accordingly, Judge Amir Hatem Mahdy Ali has engaged in conduct so utterly lacking in intellectual honesty and basic integrity that he is guilty of high crimes and misdemeanors, is unfit to hold the office of Federal judge, and should be removed from office.</text></subsection></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

