<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2AC1C2ECCECD4D36AC3A9DA33E32566D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 1052 IH: Undoing Nationwide Programs and Limiting Unnecessary Grants for Electric Vehicles Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1052</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250206">February 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001316">Mr. Burlison</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000596">Ms. Greene of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000609">Mr. Palmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000829">Mr. Wied</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001317">Mr. Brecheen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To rescind certain unobligated balances relating to charging and fueling grants and national electric vehicle grants.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBFBB6DFF7D254B93A7F246E80ABFA9AF" style="OLC"><section id="H36A0AF13315B46AEA2BE60140B7D6320" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Undoing Nationwide Programs and Limiting Unnecessary Grants for Electric Vehicles Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>UNPLUG EVs Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H46595992D8D547CDB53DF14F49A5159E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rescission of unobligated charging and fueling grant funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The unobligated balances of amounts appropriated or otherwise made available to carry out section 151(f) of title 23, United States Code, are hereby rescinded and shall be deposited into the general fund of the Treasury for the sole purpose of deficit reduction.</text></section><section id="H61230991EDEE473F83B9D29130BC76EB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Rescission of unobligated national electric vehicle formula program funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The unobligated balances of amounts appropriated or otherwise made available to carry out the National Electric Vehicle Infrastructure Formula Program pursuant to paragraph (2) under the heading <quote>Federal Highway Administration</quote> of title VIII of division J of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>) are hereby rescinded and shall be deposited into the general fund of the Treasury for the sole purpose of deficit reduction. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

