<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H802F32C8B5DE400BABE4381388887B48" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4914 IH: Unhoused VOTE Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4914</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250805">August 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To remove barriers to the ability of unhoused individuals to register to vote and vote in elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB78297534D1A4367BD8DB58AC09E61FC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6A6CA34CA9754A648FA33C096667C877" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
<subsection id="HF0D0425E99344702B14D60DB7B28271A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Unhoused Voter Opportunity Through Elections Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>Unhoused VOTE Act</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6062ECE22E1A443A90BD24A0F87F4EDB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text>
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded">
<toc-entry idref="H6A6CA34CA9754A648FA33C096667C877" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H851D0A6A0333435A896B9A250F95E579" level="title">Title I—Voting Rights of Unhoused Citizens</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H00AE8EED62884AD1A1E019E258073BCF" level="section">Sec. 101. Voting rights of unhoused citizens.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H4DAB86F417984A2BBBF748729A7FA171" level="section">Sec. 102. Enforcement.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H50D6E46C951D4ECFA7AA1EA6E73F4664" level="section">Sec. 103. Relationship to Voting Rights Act of 1965.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H314FF17026A44552973406A343B8FDB7" level="section">Sec. 104. Definitions.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H1DC62C95F5B2499999212B8C621AE08F" level="title">Title II—Protections and Best Practices for Protecting Access to Voting and Voter Registration for Unhoused Individuals</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H6E5670FE30194D129B973BA20D4235E3" level="section">Sec. 201. Description of protections.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H2981465DC65E4A229D3D857A221F366B" level="section">Sec. 202. Special requirements for voter registration.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H0A2A44CAE94944DFBCF81643EF0E4EE4" level="section">Sec. 203. Inclusion of information on voter registration and voting in surveys conducted by recipients of HUD homeless assistance.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H28817518181F45EBB4C513495E15CE9A" level="title">Title III—Grants to Support Access to Voting for Unhoused Individuals</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H1B49CF46852148599459D1DF6E338551" level="section">Sec. 301. Grant program described.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H628E80C154A046748607EB59CBF8D7CC" level="section">Sec. 302. Eligibility.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H56058784C4CC4819A3ADBA6137783E37" level="section">Sec. 303. Definition.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HBE8B7EA219524B68A447A8E57F4C50E5" level="section">Sec. 304. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HB7E71123526B4BEE8919495F2D64C8E4" level="title">Title IV—General Provisions</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H813FA852372545909A5EC51438B60583" level="section">Sec. 401. State defined.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HD779555419EB45179688476FB4CFF0FF" level="section">Sec. 402. Effective date.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section>
<title id="H851D0A6A0333435A896B9A250F95E579"><enum>I</enum><header>Voting Rights of Unhoused Citizens</header>
<section id="H00AE8EED62884AD1A1E019E258073BCF"><enum>101.</enum><header>Voting rights of unhoused citizens</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No voting qualification or prerequisite to voting, or standard, practice, or procedure shall be imposed or applied by any State or political subdivision to deny or abridge the right of any citizen of the United States to vote because that citizen resides at or in a nontraditional abode.</text></section> <section id="H4DAB86F417984A2BBBF748729A7FA171"><enum>102.</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <subsection id="HFAF815DFAB1C40C2A5E80DA13D5902ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Action by Attorney General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may commence in the name of the United States a civil action (including an action against a State or political subdivision) for declaratory or injunctive relief against a violation of this title.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H7D2FADCCACCD42B3B9DD6E35E1E922C4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text>A person who is aggrieved by an alleged violation of this title may bring a civil action in an appropriate district court for declaratory or injunctive relief with respect to the violation.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H50D6E46C951D4ECFA7AA1EA6E73F4664"><enum>103.</enum><header>Relationship to Voting Rights Act of 1965</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this title may be construed to impair any right guaranteed by the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10101">52 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></section>
<section id="H314FF17026A44552973406A343B8FDB7"><enum>104.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">As used in this title, the term <term>nontraditional abode</term> includes—</text> <paragraph id="H572C6172CA9246EF957AF7FE9AF996A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a supervised publicly or privately operated shelter designed to provide temporary living accommodations (including welfare hotels, congregate shelters, transitional housing, substance abuse treatment facilities);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H840678AC505D42689706FE6690EE7233"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a public or private place not designated for, or ordinarily used as, regular sleeping accommodation for human beings;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88D12F6DF9AB4D95B3B9CD539A972F5F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any location in which, because an individual resides in the location, the individual is considered to be a homeless individual for purposes of section 103 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11302">42 U.S.C. 11302</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H972119E5406F4AC9A62E54F3B968898B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in the case of a State in which an individual incarcerated in a prison is eligible to register to vote and vote in elections for public office, a prison.</text></paragraph></section></title> <title id="H1DC62C95F5B2499999212B8C621AE08F"><enum>II</enum><header>Protections and Best Practices for Protecting Access to Voting and Voter Registration for Unhoused Individuals</header> <section id="H6E5670FE30194D129B973BA20D4235E3"><enum>201.</enum><header>Description of protections</header> <subsection id="H9923A962FAF041CE8972D715D7181FF9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Description</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title III of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21081">52 U.S.C. 21081 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subtitle:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H81C021E8DE634DB081C41A54EF03F7B5" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subtitle id="H561C46C04C2A43F3A85CABC5DBD7C70A"><enum>C</enum><header>Access to Voting for Unhoused Individuals</header>
<section id="H17B396EA9892460C9E97E8C28A5A92FC"><enum>321.</enum><header>Promoting use of drop boxes by unhoused individuals</header>
<subsection id="H7C20166EFA704A7D907FF6802DCEC2FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Drop box accessibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a jurisdiction responsible for the administration of an election for Federal office in a State permits individuals to drop off voted ballots in the election in drop boxes, the jurisdiction shall ensure that the drop boxes are available for in-person use and are accessible and clearly labeled.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H82B5163BE9BE4F04ADF98E8969EADB03"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applying criteria based on greatest access by unhoused individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing the location, number, and time of operation of the drop boxes described in subsection (a), the appropriate election official of a jurisdiction which is subject to such subsection shall take into account the need to provide access to such drop boxes by unhoused individuals, based on consultation with persons who provide services for unhoused individuals and other relevant stakeholders.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HF5637AFEF56540A6926CCB894AF34D5B"><enum>322.</enum><header>Acceptance of certain documentation of residence and identification</header>
<subsection id="HB5CC720A866B48D6A5DD324F34A04EF0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Residence</header>
<paragraph id="H7AAD2837E71442C9A1ABF955067C9885"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Attestation</header><text>If a State imposes a requirement that an individual who desires to vote in an election for Federal office in the State provide the appropriate election official with documentation of the individual’s residence, the State shall consider the individual to meet that requirement if the individual provides the official with a written attestation of the individual’s residence, signed under penalty of perjury.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6F37706CFDC4E32A5BAAC3E889AE6AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of shelter as residence for voting purposes</header><text>A State may not prohibit an individual who is residing in a homeless shelter from using the shelter as the individual’s residence for purposes of voting in an election for Federal office which is held in the jurisdiction in which the shelter is located.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC1D23B595E5942478FE27658A9AE9E6C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Identification issued by entities of criminal justice system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a State imposes a requirement that an individual who desires to vote in an election for Federal office in the State provide the appropriate election official with documentation of the individual’s identification, the State shall consider the individual to meet the requirement if the individual provides the official with a document containing the individual’s name which is issued by an entity of the criminal justice system, including a correctional facility, court, probation officer, or parole officer.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H824CF0FEB5D545499596A1E28D1DBF54"><enum>323.</enum><header>Outreach to unhoused individuals</header> <subsection id="HB7ABAA2237314DDC9CD6EAB858678C24"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Information on websites of election officials</header> <paragraph id="H518276CC4E174A48B8AB6C192461F22D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Information required</header><text>The chief State election official shall ensure that the official public website of each election official of the State includes an accessible, clear, and separate hyperlink to simple information on how unhoused individuals may register to vote and vote in elections for Federal office held in the State.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE36B8AB881ED48DF986A8DE34925A26B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability in language other than English</header><text>If a State or political subdivision is required under section 203 of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10503">52 U.S.C. 10503</external-xref>) to provide voting materials in a language other than English, the appropriate election official shall ensure that the information provided under paragraph (1) is provided in that language as well as English.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDC8F7E708E074031B7DA60340A335FED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification</header> <paragraph id="HF48F85B6F18745ACAD5515BE236E5EAD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Voter registration deadlines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days prior to the deadline for registering to vote in an election for Federal office held in a State, the chief State election official shall send a notification of the deadline to each homeless shelter in a jurisdiction of the State in which the election will be held, local social services agencies which commonly serve unhoused individuals, and other entities which provide services to a significant population of unhoused individuals in the jurisdiction.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H899D130CF6644FCDA1D91C1F6D071FC4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dates of elections</header><text>Not later than 30 days prior to the date of an election for Federal office, the chief State election official shall send a notification of the election to each homeless shelter in a jurisdiction of the State in which the election will be held, along with the other agencies and entities to whom the chief State election official sent notice of the registration deadline under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HDAA6DAA89F1D4966B6665617A9E1E76D"><enum>324.</enum><header>Development of best practices</header> <subsection id="H496DDDE1DDA545B7A12B2712171A38AB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Development and publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In consultation with the United States Interagency Council on Homelessness, the Commission shall develop and regularly update recommendations for the best practices for State and local election officials to follow to protect and promote the access of unhoused individuals to voter registration and voting in elections for Federal office.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H2FC0FD9A397840568A906FE01903DED9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Specific elements</header><text>The Commission shall include in the best practices developed and updated under this section—</text> <paragraph id="HEFD10B75ABB249DAA9C67F8243D3B381"><enum>(1)</enum><text>methods to ensure that unhoused individuals are aware of the procedures and locations for registering to vote and voting;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5FE7C07618A948C8AC4B60D153C044C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>methods to help election officials comply with requirements for providing access to voter registration and voting for people with disabilities, including requirements established and enforced by the Department of Justice;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC46D12DDCF474FD6B89A23F2A78C9DE3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>methods to train election officials, including poll workers, in recognizing and responding to the challenges faced by unhoused individuals in registering to vote and voting;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0B7EBEEB7E164E879749D322D921ED18"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">methods to ensure that individuals who are not eligible to register to vote, including individuals who are not citizens of the United States, and individuals who are eligible but who do not wish to register to vote are not denied access to services provided by homeless shelters and local social services agencies which commonly serve unhoused individuals; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H91A37D51ADAF4DC9A616C50AECF1A193"><enum>(5)</enum><text>such other practices as the Commission considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H83CDA4EFB47B4A24A9E5084148BF880F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing and updating the best practices under this section, the Commission shall consult with individuals who have experience in being unhoused and with homeless shelters and local social services agencies which commonly serve unhoused individuals, including shelters and agencies with experience in serving unhoused individuals who are not citizens of the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD204F903B5354D1BA1D3059B2C701D87"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The Commission shall develop the first set of best practices under this section not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the Unhoused VOTE Act.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HB70C1A313DC443BF9DDD8A16A16EB09B"><enum>325.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subtitle—</text> <paragraph id="HA315ABC80C164BB982EEE5D928DB6B91"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>homeless shelter</term> means an emergency shelter under section 321 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11351">42 U.S.C. 11351</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0578CFFBFC894DEBA579843C6CB369EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>unhoused individual</term> means a homeless individual, as defined in section 103 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11302">42 U.S.C. 11302</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section></subtitle><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H53E29E77F6E04253A34E66C81EA37F1F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment relating to enforcement</header><text>Section 401 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21111">52 U.S.C. 21111</external-xref>) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, and subtitle C of title III.</quote>.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H10C3D842D4254E6DAFBD7257DDB1D249"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by adding at the end of the items relating to title III the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H62E02786B4CD416BB979AB6C09772780" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="yes-regeneration"> <toc-entry idref="H561C46C04C2A43F3A85CABC5DBD7C70A" level="subtitle">Subtitle C—Access to Voting for Unhoused Individuals</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H17B396EA9892460C9E97E8C28A5A92FC" level="section">Sec. 321. Promoting use of drop boxes by unhoused individuals.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HF5637AFEF56540A6926CCB894AF34D5B" level="section">Sec. 322. Acceptance of certain documentation of residence and identification.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H824CF0FEB5D545499596A1E28D1DBF54" level="section">Sec. 323. Outreach to unhoused individuals.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HDAA6DAA89F1D4966B6665617A9E1E76D" level="section">Sec. 324. Development of best practices.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HB70C1A313DC443BF9DDD8A16A16EB09B" level="section">Sec. 325. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H2981465DC65E4A229D3D857A221F366B"><enum>202.</enum><header>Special requirements for voter registration</header> <subsection id="H7D7A7F2D204F4A9CB4823EBF3212ADD8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Treatment of shelters as voter registration agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7(a)(2) of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20506">52 U.S.C. 20506(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H02B36390A0F84E1B989A7B716FD57FFF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (A);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC43A8A44037B4C76B14D1E5F27060CA2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (B) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H94DC2382E5924EE094571C33758990BB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H953222B12EA74663BB959EF86B225780" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="HC10FA203D8FA442EA0329671E367692D" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all emergency shelters in the State under section 321 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11351">42 U.S.C. 11351</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H68607DAE368B41F1B2E27FEBB0D57D19"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Permitting applicants To mark location of residence on Federal voter registration application forms and alternative forms used by States</header><text>Section 9(b) of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20508">52 U.S.C. 20508(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD1FDC52C343248C1A9309B1EFA49D459"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (3);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD9590FA0B38E499380F13D034A0A7E90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (4) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H863A5A68778A433BABD51ACEECBB9C7D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA2A4D5724019435BABA98F36868A4757" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<paragraph id="H7D9AE2C1A7674832A7AAE03C14DFD737"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include a drawing of an intersection on which the applicant may mark by hand the location of the applicant’s residence, including by writing in the names of the crossroads on the drawing and indicating any nearby landmarks.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCF712066CB0A47C3A801A686219641AD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Permitting unhoused applicants To use unsheltered street location as address</header><text>Section 8(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20507">52 U.S.C. 20507(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H6D691FBBD11B4A3B8CB73D168D1D8CC3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (5);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBB0EEBB29FC44D9B750DA67F3CAC962"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (6) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H55C463BC3D2E45069339A718E41A4D8C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8E16E4B10A3A459F966D4904BFD727A1" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H991CBEFCCA1245EDAB479923BDEECC86"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">permit an applicant who is an unhoused individual (defined for purposes of this paragraph as a homeless individual under section 103 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11302">42 U.S.C. 11302</external-xref>)) to use an unsheltered street location as the individual’s place of residence for purposes of the application.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H0A2A44CAE94944DFBCF81643EF0E4EE4"><enum>203.</enum><header>Inclusion of information on voter registration and voting in surveys conducted by recipients of HUD homeless assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 402(f)(3) of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11360a">42 U.S.C. 11360a(f)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H742AEB4813554F858C0CA9748D5124B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (C);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H35BF430209734782991582D3A38764A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (D) as subparagraph (E); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8CF92BD5B39C4A8A88BD0D2F9DE5CF93"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following new subparagraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDB3367CE561E48B09A12ECFEE67BEAEC" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subparagraph id="HA4D7CECF4C2A4620836871F7EA962F0E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collects information on the extent to which individuals experiencing homelessness are able to register to vote and vote in elections for Federal office; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></title> <title id="H28817518181F45EBB4C513495E15CE9A"><enum>III</enum><header>Grants to Support Access to Voting for Unhoused Individuals</header> <section id="H1B49CF46852148599459D1DF6E338551"><enum>301.</enum><header>Grant program described</header> <subsection id="H9D3EA145D39E4B4DBA7FAE129DD7DCEA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Election Assistance Commission shall make grants to eligible States and units of local government for programs and activities, such as operating mobile voting centers and providing direct outreach to unhoused individuals, to support the access of unhoused individuals to registering to vote and voting in elections for Federal office.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H4D369824974E4B789FF0AF4231850473"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds for grants to private entities</header><text>A State or unit of local government which receives a grant under this title may use the funds provided by the grant to enter into contracts with private entities with experience in providing assistance to unhoused individuals to provide services to such individuals which will assist them in registering to vote and voting in elections for Federal office.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H628E80C154A046748607EB59CBF8D7CC"><enum>302.</enum><header>Eligibility</header> <subsection id="H37495FA2407B482D80A9EEF7C563B3C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or unit of local government is eligible to receive a grant under this title if the State or unit submits to the Election Assistance Commission, at such time and in such form as the Commission may require, such information and assurances as the Commission may require, including assurances that the State or political subdivision has a plan to engage stakeholders with a demonstrated experience of serving unhoused individuals.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H85DE270A9B0740B382BED53216C5C2A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special condition regarding protection of documents</header><text>In order to be eligible to receive a grant under this title, a State or unit of local government shall include with the information and assurances required under subsection (a) specific information and assurances that if funds provided by the grant are used to produce documents for the use of unhoused individuals, including under a contract with a private entity as described in section 301(b), the documents will be produced in a manner which ensures that they will remain readable and usable even if they are subject to extended exposure to the elements.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H56058784C4CC4819A3ADBA6137783E37"><enum>303.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title, the term <term>unhoused individual</term> means a homeless individual, as defined in section 103 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11302">42 U.S.C. 11302</external-xref>).</text></section>
<section id="HBE8B7EA219524B68A447A8E57F4C50E5"><enum>304.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this title such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2026 and each succeeding fiscal year.</text></section></title> <title id="HB7E71123526B4BEE8919495F2D64C8E4"><enum>IV</enum><header>General Provisions</header> <section id="H813FA852372545909A5EC51438B60583"><enum>401.</enum><header>State defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></section>
<section id="HD779555419EB45179688476FB4CFF0FF"><enum>402.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided, this Act and the amendments made by this Act shall apply with respect to elections for Federal office beginning 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></title> </legis-body></bill>

