<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEED601A517064020880D670B961B037D" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 796 IH: Expressing support for the designation of October 9 through October 16, 2025, as “National Dyspraxia/Developmental Coordination Disorder (DCD) Awareness Week” and a commitment to raise awareness of dyspraxia/DCD in the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 796</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251008">October 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of October 9 through October 16, 2025, as <quote>National Dyspraxia/Developmental Coordination Disorder (DCD) Awareness Week</quote> and a commitment to raise awareness of dyspraxia/DCD in the United States.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas developmental coordination disorder (DCD), also referred to as dyspraxia, is a neurodevelopmental condition that does not affect cognition, but affects fine and gross motor skills such as balance, coordination, and manual dexterity;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the National Institutes of Health, dyspraxia/DCD is a lifelong disorder;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas dyspraxia/DCD is as common as attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) and affects approximately 5 to 6 percent of the population (approximately 20,000,000, or 1 in 20, Americans), yet is unfamiliar to many parents, teachers, and health care professionals and is consequently underdiagnosed, misdiagnosed, and largely untreated;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there is a need to spread awareness among educators and employers about the disorder and for well-trained health care and school-based professionals capable of conducting proper diagnosis and treatment;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there is no cure for dyspraxia/DCD, but it can be managed through various types of therapies (speech, physical, and occupational therapies as well as mental health counseling);</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there has been little research of this condition in the United States compared with many other developed countries, which has led to a lack of diagnostic and treatment services for individuals affected by dyspraxia/DCD in this country;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas individuals with dyspraxia/DCD often experience symptoms related to speech production and intelligibility, attention, processing speed, and executive functioning (planning, organizing, and time management), and it commonly co-occurs with other neurodevelopmental disorders including ADHD and learning disorders;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas dyspraxia/DCD profoundly affects quality of life and presents significant challenges at school and in the workplace that can be mitigated with early diagnosis, treatment, and appropriate support at home, school, and work;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas secondary consequences of undiagnosed dyspraxia/DCD often include social, emotional, behavioral, and mental health issues including low self-esteem, social isolation, anxiety, and depression; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas low-income and minority communities are particularly underserved by existing dyspraxia/DCD resources: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HD81B032D0F544935BBA6C52D9C3EC8B5"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H80B35E2BE2EB47DE8403135B9170ADEC"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HD08F8F745E234D988EDBE9124651FDBA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the need for greater public awareness of dyspraxia/developmental coordination disorder (DCD) and commits to supporting these efforts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EFF9A67F3BC4D478D39710A5DB82D71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses support for the designation of <quote>National Dyspraxia/Developmental Coordination Disorder (DCD) Awareness Week</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51A0E8AE9CC14EFD82FB09160DC181A8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports the goals of <quote>National Dyspraxia/Developmental Coordination Disorder (DCD) Awareness Week</quote>, which are to raise awareness of dyspraxia/DCD among the general public, improve services and care for persons affected by dyspraxia/DCD, and accelerate research on dyspraxia/DCD;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4114EB5870B04495B7DD22BFA9C45ED0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recognizes individuals with dyspraxia/DCD and their families who face challenges due to their diagnosis; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8454E7ACE654AC08374E42BA48F9B47"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages States, territories, and localities to support the goals of <quote>National Dyspraxia/Developmental Coordination Disorder (DCD) Awareness Week</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

