<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEL25058-VXX-5W-RJ7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S247 IS: Choices for Increased Mobility Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 247</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250124">January 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to clarify payment rules for manual wheelchairs under part B of the Medicare program.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="HB48DEA2826824DECA65CB5549A08CE1D"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Choices for Increased Mobility Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id1926d13f3d204b77b1d610efe38fc684"><enum>2.</enum><header>Special rules related to treatment of certain manual wheelchairs under the Medicare program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1834(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida1a21587a3d64d498a34ced01e0a6946"><paragraph id="id76746965db9d4ddeba2de4d2fe821479"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Special rules related to treatment of certain manual wheelchairs</header><subparagraph id="id58a14765b9904067b6bd8b33264fa438"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement to establish separate HCPCS codes for certain manual wheelchairs</header><text>With respect to ultralightweight manual wheelchairs payable under this subsection furnished on or after January 1, 2026, the Secretary shall establish two or more HCPCS codes, as determined appropriate by the Secretary, for the base of such a wheelchair depending on the construction material used in such base (with 1 or more such codes for such a base with titanium or carbon fiber construction material and 1 or more such codes for such a base without such materials).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd61d83363d79486d876cffa07651fb4b"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Payment and beneficiary protections</header><clause id="id3bb099a109064a3ca904a8313d822db6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Payment</header><text>On or after January 1, 2026, in the case where an individual purchases or rents from a supplier an ultralightweight manual wheelchair that has titanium or carbon fiber construction material used in the base of such wheelchair, payment to the supplier shall be made in the frequency and amount as would otherwise be made under this subsection (as described in paragraph (1)(A)) for such wheelchair.</text></clause><clause id="id7d23eb3e9fcb418c9b243607c3d6c2b8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Beneficiary charges</header><text>The supplier may charge the individual the difference between the payment amount described in clause (i) for such wheelchair and the supplier's actual charge for such wheelchair.</text></clause><clause id="idcc1b0527e6494fd5a951417107a3380a"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Beneficiary protections</header><text>In order to inform an individual of their potential financial liability under clause (ii), the Secretary may require a supplier to issue a notice to the individual (in a form and manner determined by the Secretary) prior to the purchase or rent of such ultralightweight manual wheelchair by such individual.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

