<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BOM25540-P5Y-G0-MNN">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2330 IS: Preparing And Retaining All (PARA) Educators Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2330</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr.
                    Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr.
                    Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, and
                    <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>) introduced the following
                bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and
                Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To direct the Secretary of Education to carry out a grant program to support
            the recruitment and retention of paraprofessionals in public elementary schools,
            secondary schools, and preschool programs, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H1BE5683806D446A0A57229E96A44E99C">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="id2936574ef7a544d28976dde374b2824a">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preparing And Retaining All (PARA) Educators Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="HBA6A37C366EB4B8FA7FBAAB31A1EE8A2">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Grants to support efforts to recruit and retain paraprofessionals in
                schools</header>
            <subsection id="HD57B985CCE114926963001DD78348265">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education shall carry out a program under which the Secretary makes allotments to State educational agencies to assist States, local educational agencies, and educational service agencies in recruiting and retaining paraprofessionals in public elementary schools, secondary schools, and preschool programs.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H8AFEF8D57DEA4148B08E995AC6FAEE36">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>State-by-State allocation</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State educational agency that has an application approved by the Secretary under subsection (e)(1) shall be allocated an amount that bears the same relationship to the amount appropriated to carry out this Act for each fiscal year as the amount received by all local educational agencies in the State under part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311 et seq.</external-xref>) for the previous fiscal year bears to the total amount received under such part for such fiscal year by all local educational agencies in every State.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H4BB13DDE05A24E4298EE3C4352C67D5D">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Use of funds</header>
                <paragraph id="H241F411CE8EF42C4AC52D25281724429">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>State reservation</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State educational agency that receives an allotment under subsection (b) may reserve not more than 5 percent of the allotment for administrative activities relating to the grant program under paragraph (2) and to carry out statewide activities to support the recruitment and retention of paraprofessionals in public elementary schools, secondary schools, and preschool programs in the State.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H99713E7A7A654A369AD4341FD6F9DC36">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Subgrants to eligible entities</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From amounts received under subsection (b) and not reserved under paragraph (1), a State educational agency shall make subgrants to eligible entities, on a competitive basis, to support the recruitment and retention of paraprofessionals in public elementary schools, secondary schools, and preschool programs, which may include activities such as—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H1A0DFFA3E6444142863C98EF8B59CB37">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing paraprofessional leader induction and mentoring programs that are evidence-based (to the extent a State determines that such evidence is reasonably available) and designed to—</text>
                        <clause id="HF573F1BF39E846F194B693EA75A7A76C">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>improve classroom instruction and student learning and achievement, including through improving school leadership programs; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HECF2830F822B4F7A8BAC2AD4FAB45F1D">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>increase the retention of paraprofessionals;</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2C3C41B11EE42FB8C8BAEEFD6FE386F"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing and implementing high-quality professional development programs to recruit and retain paraprofessionals in the elementary schools, secondary schools, and preschool programs served by eligible entities;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H5B777713C4A64209BB2776A831EBA3DF">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>providing paraprofessionals with the skills, credentials, or certifications needed to educate all students, such as—</text>
                        <clause id="HB015DE4CBA074294A5C77F2434E8B7F6">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>a special education certificate;</text> </clause> <clause id="H0A0404D216964DC79C709362AE1E7E17"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>an English learner certificate;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HDD99BF93D8A64978A9F06A8AC0BB6B85">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>an advanced paraeducator certification to support specialized instruction; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HF6A5526C5C1C44DE870E564D91072433">
                            <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>a certification in teaching; and</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB009209AA24C45868E22ADA5D0B9D24C"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>increasing wages for paraprofessionals or providing bonus pay incentives to retain and recruit paraprofessionals.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="iddd16f246f4b048158818a0f8be1447b7">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Priority</header>
                <paragraph id="id7673b790d1c94376a6d4213af8501044">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>In making subgrants to eligible entities under subsection (c)(2), a State educational agency shall give priority to entities—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="id073facc426ea414c9afe87a8fe320c1c">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>that serve greater numbers or percentages of children from low-income families;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id191bebf638de442486536ade8729c038">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in which all schools served by the entity are designated with a locale code of 41, 42, or 43, as determined by the Secretary of Education; or</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id90979ef54aa4462c9347a28fecc6ebb6">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>in which all schools served by the entity—</text> <clause id="id8b9bcde3c40e4fb887fa0120631d132d"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>receive special assistance payments under section 11(a)(1)(F) of the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1759a">42 U.S.C. 1759a(a)(1)(F)</external-xref>); and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id9a0c6ac6c69e419a84c3b440c92ca0f5">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>have an identified student percentage (as such term is defined in section 245.9(f)(1)(iii) of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations)) of not less than the applicable threshold under section 11(a)(1)(F)(viii) of the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1759a">42 U.S.C. 1759a(a)(1)(F)(viii)</external-xref>).</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id291c606e4efd4ac1a05812fe6c35098b">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Low-income family</header>
 <text>For purposes of paragraph (1)(A), the term <term>low-income family</term> means a family—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="id5c38fd34caaf43cf9bf4e670bd4b1009">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>in which a child is eligible for the school lunch program under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idadac23583ca94756abe835ea65cdc662">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in which the child is—</text> <clause id="id799d563bd8ff454aa54cb3a1cb54e9b0"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>enrolled in a school that receives special assistance payments under section 11(a)(1)(F) of the of the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1759a">42 U.S.C. 1759a(a)(1)(F)</external-xref>); and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="idf5c48e65c535414fbd7c8c89343dbc86">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>is an identified student (as defined in section 11(a)(1)(F)(i) of that Act);</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id23ed5e75caa24b33a9219e13f8d74154">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>receiving assistance under the program of block grants to States for temporary assistance for needy families established under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/601">42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idcb412373e58444d889ba79f161f36e1e">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>in which the child is eligible to receive medical assistance under the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H096681F668634A73AF92970DC8B90EA0">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Applications</header>
                <paragraph id="H04A33922DDD44D199E419D2E19A17D1B">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>State applications</header>
                    <subparagraph id="HF1B8B5EDFDAA48E4B7F41D55427C1D90">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                        <header>In general</header>
 <text>To be eligible to receive a grant under subsection (a), a State educational agency shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H85A1F9D2B13C4F329D330B95DB472F69">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <header>Required Assurances</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State educational agency submitting an application under subparagraph (A) shall include in such application an assurance that—</text>
                        <clause id="H91C6BD615E304B5EBAAC56DBBDED3D82">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>in making subgrants under subsection (c)(2), the State will give priority to eligible entities described in subsection (d); and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H18DCF352BFD14485836F68ED7EFEA5B4">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the State educational agency will comply with the reporting requirements under subsection (f).</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HECA1D31E025F48FC8C6CEAB5EB812423">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Eligible entity applications</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a subgrant from a State educational agency under subsection (c)(2), an eligible entity shall submit an application to the State educational agency at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the State educational agency may require.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H82C0645A873B4E10A557C638CD319DA7">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Implementation and Evaluation</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On an annual basis, in each fiscal year for which a State educational agency receives a grant under this section, such agency shall prepare and submit to the Secretary of Education a report that includes—</text>
                <paragraph id="HCAB65105E1284818BC67F1A7DAA764C1">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>updated average paraprofessional pay baselines for that fiscal year, disaggregated by the statewide average and the average within the schools served by each eligible entity in the State;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H8FAB2072617D437AA9B26B487A076BB2">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>a description of how the State and eligible entities in the State increased the average wages for paraprofessional baselines in a manner consistent with the statewide annual goals for the corresponding fiscal year;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H3B77969DD3A544879B796A9B08DFB92A">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>updated data on the number of paraprofessionals employed by eligible entities in the State—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="HEE292D1A91D44E0E899D3C66C7CF5B77">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>who earn less than the average wage for paraprofessionals in the State; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H3A25CB0A06194EF5A7A718BED34324A4">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who earn less than the average wage for paraprofessionals employed by the eligible entity concerned;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H92505F68CD1A4E6781631A09868847EC">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>identification of any eligible entity that used a subgrant under subsection (c)(2) to increase the number of paraprofessionals employed in the schools and preschools served by such entity;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HAD3CDF576C384D42947F0E689AA280E3">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>a description of the actions the State educational agency will take in the next fiscal year to support eligible entities experiencing a shortage of paraprofessionals; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H80D1DDD286CB48A5A8D864EE25DCC524">
                    <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>a description of any professional development activities used by eligible entities to recruit and retain paraprofessionals.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HABBFFB1D4D4842BA8C95511F21FBD604">
                <enum>(g)</enum>
                <header>Rules of Construction for Collective Bargaining</header>
                <paragraph id="H222389E026B048F6B7F4BD925D3C487D">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>Subject to paragraph (2), nothing in this section shall be construed to alter or otherwise affect the rights, remedies, and procedures afforded to school employees or employees of an eligible entity under Federal, State, or local laws (including applicable regulations or court orders) or under the terms of collective bargaining agreements, memoranda of understanding, or other agreements between such employers and their employees.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HB9D560A4F0C5465C83B2DA4808DD7B60">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Compliance</header>
 <text>Paragraph (1) shall not be construed to exempt a State, eligible entity, or school from complying with this section or from negotiating in compliance with State labor laws to comply with this section.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HA14FE3F69D474EDABC8C7AF8F21951A4">
                <enum>(h)</enum>
                <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H073CC44B228E4454A0419AF120ABA52D">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <header>Definitions</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H8068E8952A6946749F60336B9375A2B7"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Eligible entity</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="HEBA74D112EDE40FE9E181C579EAD0FA6">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>an educational service agency that serves a high-need school or a consortium of high-need schools; or</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H3DA58FFD625A4F089DF67762DB4430CB">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>a local educational agency.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H79ED8EBEE9FA43FEB1FBB42D41DA1036"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>ESEA terms</header> <text>The terms <term>educational service agency</term>, <term>elementary school</term>, <term>English learner</term>, <quote>evidence-based</quote>, <quote>local educational agency</quote>, <quote>secondary school</quote>, and <quote>State educational agency</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HCF010277BBD9441CA1E139F50F289F91">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>High-need school</header>
 <text>The term <term>high-need school</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2243(f)(2) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6673">20 U.S.C. 6673(f)(2)</external-xref>).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H5B7E4ED990074DBB8A395632B22E113D">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
                    <header>Paraprofessional</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>paraprofessional</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3201 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7011">20 U.S.C. 7011</external-xref>).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H0D1406C3DFA842859B53A20E72933171">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
                    <header>Preschool program</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>preschool program</term> means a program that—</text>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" id="H0DEA2540991E4A4C8680820BA550B436">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>provides for the care, development, and education of infants, toddlers, or young children age 5 and under;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" id="HBA8B4ACC16CC4D558CF0EA5A546666EE">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>meets any applicable State or local government licensing, certification, approval, and registration requirements; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" id="H51BBF4CFAAC4490B828E89041E2F76BE">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is operated by a public or private school that is supported, sponsored, supervised, or administered by an eligible entity.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

