<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF5FA569199BC4605B25DF2AD1591A8D0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 924 IH: National Origin-Based Antidiscrimination for Nonimmigrants Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 924</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250204">February 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000489">Mr. Turner of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Vel&#225;zquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. Garc&#237;a of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001094">Ms. Hoyle of Oregon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To transfer and limit Executive Branch authority to suspend or restrict the entry of a class of aliens.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEF4072DA118B45B3B927312009FEEE73" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8E4772CDDCAF42EE93F6A5EF12BF0429" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Origin-Based Antidiscrimination for Nonimmigrants Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>NO BAN Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB2D49B7A63E046E4BCE832E007523FBC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expansion of nondiscrimination provision</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 202(a)(1)(A) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1152">8 U.S.C. 1152(a)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H6DB75FE0E64E418E86EBC2D91CCD709A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Except as specifically provided in paragraph (2) and in sections 101(a)(27), 201(b)(2)(A)(i), and 203, no</quote> and inserting <quote>No</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1EC44EADBDBF40F18BB08DA6145DA04D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or a nonimmigrant visa, admission or other entry into the United States, or the approval or revocation of any immigration benefit</quote> after <quote>immigrant visa</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H923DDF330F7740DBAA31857EAD6B7987"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>religion,</quote> after <quote>sex,</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C8E4D70921C4E368D2877749A6DBC28"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>, except as specifically provided in paragraph (2), in sections 101(a)(27), 201(b)(2)(A)(i), and 203, if otherwise expressly required by statute, or if a statutorily authorized benefit takes into consideration such factors</quote>.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H263ACB32498843F28F79B1560866EBC5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Transfer and limitations on authority to suspend or restrict the entry of a class of aliens</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 212(f) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(f)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HB8977DCF3482440F9684B5206A9829A3" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H5BB0E37E6EA84FFBB23F2915F3BE8662"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authority To suspend or restrict the entry of a class of aliens</header> <paragraph id="H68C606459A284B238506708C6768FCFC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), if the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, determines, based on specific and credible facts, that the entry of any aliens or any class of aliens into the United States would undermine the security or public safety of the United States or the preservation of human rights, democratic processes or institutions, or international stability, the President may temporarily—</text>
<subparagraph id="H5C6D3812C76C481B81CBBD201B5AB33B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>suspend the entry of such aliens or class of aliens as immigrants or nonimmigrants; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H13C3A91B3264459B90C684D5FF57B06C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>impose any restrictions on the entry of such aliens that the President deems appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA27129A21D304153AF42CA79939A724E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the President, the Secretary of State, and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H0BFA9A902CDD4FED859C31C8A1FB4E7B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>only issue a suspension or restriction when required to address specific acts implicating a compelling government interest in a factor identified in paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H30DF685C4E4940CAB54AFCCAA56438C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>narrowly tailor the suspension or restriction, using the least restrictive means, to achieve such compelling government interest;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H95F1DB099B994A5295DDC8476DB1C9C6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>specify the duration of the suspension or restriction;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H48878ED24E96429AB71C3CF8B3B36361"><enum>(D)</enum><text>consider waivers to any class-based restriction or suspension and apply a rebuttable presumption in favor of granting family-based and humanitarian waivers; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF6DB12C6E6094EDEA2B9E02F9D48AB49"><enum>(E)</enum><text>comply with all provisions of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8B973C3F29504FA6A2D7BFC2CD6D3243"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Congressional notification</header>
<subparagraph id="HAC974999EC20418FA28EBEFC75B219C6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Prior to the President exercising the authority under paragraph (1), the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall consult Congress and provide Congress with specific evidence supporting the need for the suspension or restriction and its proposed duration.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H51BDD39DED67495AA0766CFF935A8717"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Briefing and report</header><text>Not later than 48 hours after the President exercises the authority under paragraph (1), the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide a briefing and submit a written report to Congress that describes—</text>
<clause id="H525A9AA8E35C418495FB58D3C2540BC5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the action taken pursuant to paragraph (1) and the specified objective of such action;</text></clause> <clause id="H8BD98BE940EB4619AB2CB4A91A6308ED"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the estimated number of individuals who will be impacted by such action;</text></clause>
<clause id="H8E00E4D71E854DCBAEA39B9F0E40303F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the constitutional and legislative authority under which such action took place; and</text></clause> <clause id="HAEAD8D9FBF2E4738BD99105DE504EDC5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the circumstances necessitating such action, including how such action complies with paragraph (2), as well as any intelligence informing such actions.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3E0BA0A95A7449228B7C5F055839C9E8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>If the briefing and report described in subparagraph (B) are not provided to Congress during the 48 hours that begin when the President exercises the authority under paragraph (1), the suspension or restriction shall immediately terminate absent intervening congressional action.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H289D229AF1E741DF9A93CFDCE34C0E3A"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>Congress</quote>, as used in this paragraph, refers to the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate, the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H22FFED1E3EFE455CBD8B7DD32F24CAED"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall publicly announce and publish an unclassified version of the report described in paragraph (3)(B) in the Federal Register.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF806585A75642E38BECBA07065E24F8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Judicial review</header> <subparagraph id="H2B3FECB0B790463D9BACE14AD81E77E8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an individual or entity who is present in the United States and has been harmed by a violation of this subsection may file an action in an appropriate district court of the United States to seek declaratory or injunctive relief.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9FBFC4282DC047C4AF8BF89C8E0FDE78"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Class action</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to preclude an action filed pursuant to subparagraph (A) from proceeding as a class action.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2EFF15F477B54603BBDE592A29AA75E5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Treatment of commercial airlines</header><text>Whenever the Secretary of Homeland Security finds that a commercial airline has failed to comply with regulations of the Secretary of Homeland Security relating to requirements of airlines for the detection of fraudulent documents used by passengers traveling to the United States (including the training of personnel in such detection), the Secretary of Homeland Security may suspend the entry of some or all aliens transported to the United States by such airline.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF892BD1C54EA49BF8EE9E8FF57E02171"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed as authorizing the President, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Homeland Security to act in a manner inconsistent with the policy decisions expressed in the immigration laws.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HA4F1E9CF0CD94AD0BF37A2F50378B712"><enum>4.</enum><header>Visa Applicants report</header> <subsection id="H9B4E2932E26D403F8211FAD13CAADC17"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial reports</header> <paragraph id="H3C8115A8869D4194BED0DB71C7D64489"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall submit a report to the congressional committees referred to in section 212(f)(3)(D) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as amended by section 3 of this Act, that describes the implementation of Presidential Proclamations 9645, 9822, and 9983 and Executive Order Nos. 13769, 13780, and 13815, during the effective period of each such proclamation and order.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9A9EC646E18C471FB37A3DE214D5E80F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Presidential proclamation 9645 and 9983</header><text>In addition to the content described in paragraph (1), the report submitted with respect to Presidential Proclamation 9645, issued on September 24, 2017, and Presidential Proclamation 9983, issued on January 31, 2020, shall include, for each country listed in such proclamation—</text> <subparagraph id="H9D80BCFDD50747049C96BCA81C9EA95D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total number of individuals who applied for a visa during the time period the proclamation was in effect, disaggregated by country and visa category;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H26195E302AFE44E2A796BD9313C6AA83"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total number of visa applicants described in subparagraph (A) who were approved, disaggregated by country and visa category;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H625D6943864D48559100F9FF8540F349"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the total number of visa applicants described in subparagraph (A) who were refused, disaggregated by country and visa category, and the reasons they were refused;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7D8CBAD42E1B49F3B742CD9665619FDD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the total number of visa applicants described in subparagraph (A) whose applications remain pending, disaggregated by country and visa category;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0026D0D40916461582EED47487829406"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the total number of visa applicants described in subparagraph (A) who were granted a waiver, disaggregated by country and visa category;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H771ADDDFF3BC484E9E59684BC2BC565E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the total number of visa applicants described in subparagraph (A) who were denied a waiver, disaggregated by country and visa category, and the reasons such waiver requests were denied;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE216A063D5D54143A97ACAA53D082358"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the total number of refugees admitted, disaggregated by country; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDBF3E77BE1434256ADCDAFC586995C50"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the complete reports that were submitted to the President every 180 days in accordance with section 4 of Presidential Proclamation 9645 in its original form, and as amended by Presidential Proclamation 9983.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H11C90479176442929372FB37C75EB6CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional reports</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the President exercises the authority under section 212(f) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(f)</external-xref>), as amended by section 3 of this Act, and every 30 days thereafter, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security and heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall submit a report to the congressional committees referred to in paragraph (3)(D) of such section 212(f) that identifies, with respect to countries affected by a suspension or restriction, the information described in subparagraphs (A) through (G) of subsection (a)(2) of this section and the specific evidence supporting the need for the continued exercise of presidential authority under such section 212(f), including the information described in paragraph (3)(B) of such section 212(f). If the report described in this subsection is not provided to such congressional committees in the time specified, the suspension or restriction shall immediately terminate absent intervening congressional action. A final report with such information shall be prepared and submitted to such congressional committees not later than 30 days after the suspension or restriction is lifted.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H96966195A9F74F098981B9C72F94D4A8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form; availability</header><text>The reports required under subsections (a) and (b) shall be made publicly available online in unclassified form.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

