<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H23BC66F4CD354BAE87208E19BDAD0C4D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 953 IH: United States Trade Leadership in the Indo-Pacific Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 953</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250204">February 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000585">Mr. LaHood</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To advance United States long-term trade competitiveness and economic leadership in the Indo-Pacific region.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H975917C6C9274E3395254BE15B50D8CC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0CBE95F0A87C459EAF9B07C2D55C45DF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States Trade Leadership in the Indo-Pacific Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC33DB5604D4B40D1862F39F2D33D009F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3DB9F966A217487ABD0F18E38F93A2B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States is an Indo-Pacific power.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBE2824FBDD0F403C93C4216F13B37E73"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Indo-Pacific region, spanning from our Pacific Coastline to the Indian Ocean, is home to over half the world’s people, including nearly 60 percent of youth, and is at the center of the 21st-century global economy, accounting for 60 percent of global gross domestic product and two-thirds of the world’s economic growth in 2022.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H79AA574FBC7A486ABC55A8D4051CE37E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Indo-Pacific region also includes some of America’s closest military allies and partners, several of the world’s largest militaries, and 5 nations allied with the United States through mutual defense treaties. The region also contains strategic rivals with growing military capabilities, in particular the People’s Republic of China (PRC). Our partners are critical for responding to potential threats in the region, maintaining credible deterrence, and for fostering peace.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF7915CBD65E742899EE39E652CC7D28C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>There is broad bipartisan agreement that the United States must have a strong and durable economic strategy in the Indo-Pacific to advance our commercial, geostrategic, and national security interests and support our allies and partners in the region.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2B2D90E9434243F1B03026B3A83C9BA2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>This is especially true and increasingly urgent in the face of heightened aggression and pressure from the PRC, which seeks to expand its influence by actively pursuing trade agreements with key partners in the Indo-Pacific that establish preferential treatment for goods and services, deepen supply chain integration, and establish rules based on the PRC’s state-led authoritarian economic model that undercut America’s workers, businesses, and economic security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HED2673B64A9E4FE597215035856802FF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>For decades, the United States has sought to persuade the PRC to eliminate harmful trade practices and act responsibly within the global rules-based trading system. Unfortunately, the PRC has not substantially changed its behavior and has instead used forced labor, subsidies and overproduction, intellectual property theft and the forced transfer of technology, authoritarian digital governance policies, economic coercion, and other unfair practices to advance an economic model that undermines human rights, American industries and workers, and market-based economies around the world.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H52DB5007A77945D49858328264FB8F2B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The PRC is now actively seeking to increase trade ties in the Indo-Pacific region as a means to increase its economic influence and increase supply chain dependency on the PRC. One of the most prominent examples of the PRC’s growing economic influence in the Indo-Pacific region is the Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership (RCEP), which entered into force in January 2022. RCEP is now the largest trade agreement in the world, encompassing 15 countries that account for 30 percent of the global economy. This agreement will increasingly put the United States at a competitive disadvantage as the economies of the PRC, Australia, Brunei, Cambodia, Indonesia, Japan, Korea, Laos, Malaysia, Myanmar, New Zealand, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand, and Vietnam grow more integrated.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4632E5874B9749EAB9569CF6428FF9D9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The PRC is also actively negotiating numerous other regional and bilateral trade agreements throughout the region and is attempting to accede to the Comprehensive and Progressive Agreement for Trans-Pacific Partnership (CPTPP) as well as the Digital Economic Partnership Agreement (DEPA).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H970D0A0A6B7842B6B0BCF6562E16CCC5"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The PRC’s aggressive assertion of its economic interests in the Indo-Pacific through the use of trade agreements underscores the need for the United States to provide a meaningful and credible alternative to achieve our economic and national security goals.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28C12211D00B42BAB3F57FA01D19A7EE"><enum>(10)</enum><text>American workers and businesses also face competitive pressures as other countries in the region pursue regional rules and preferential trade agreements without the participation of the United States. There are now more than 200 preferential trade agreements in force with at least one party from the region and over 100 more are under negotiation or pending ratification.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H56D638C9C2034FA2AAE681BBBD2B7745"><enum>(11)</enum><text>To inform future policymaking, Congress should work with the administration in a bipartisan manner to examine current United States economic policy toward the Indo-Pacific, the impacts of regional trade agreements on American competitiveness, and policies to advance United States objectives in the region.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A348000458843D6A333DA170AC07A46"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Through a more comprehensive trade and economic strategy toward the Indo-Pacific region, the United States could exert greater leverage to improve labor rights and help level the playing field for American workers, enhance environmental standards, counter non-market economies and authoritarianism, construct more resilient supply chains, better meet the needs of our allies and partners, and grow our economy by addressing barriers to trade for American products.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H15AB37DA67D94B7A849C6D21515D92C9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Investigation of impact of Indo-Pacific regional agreements on United States competitiveness</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the United States International Trade Commission shall conduct and conclude an investigation to examine—</text> <paragraph id="HD1097CEF3E7A469E9FCAE4A1B66EE3B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>how preferential market access provisions, including tariffs, quotas, and services commitments, in existing Indo-Pacific regional trade agreements, including the Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership (RCEP) Agreement and the Comprehensive and Progressive Agreement for Trans-Pacific Partnership (CPTPP), affect United States exports and growth opportunities in the Indo-Pacific region;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF128EA7747D44B7F8A06FE2F2A6D0ED0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how existing non-tariff barriers, including regulatory practices, relatively lower labor and environmental standards, different rules for sectors ranging from agriculture and the digital economy, and standard-setting in these areas as part of existing Indo-Pacific regional and bilateral trade agreements, impact the competitiveness of American workers and businesses;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H423522D63D534F868EDB51AF7BEAF750"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the impact of existing Indo-Pacific regional trade agreements on United States supply chain resiliency and connectivity, and in particular its impact on the People’s Republic of China’s role in key global supply chains; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H823D47B76E644999804800F33E9A3042"><enum>(4)</enum><text>differences between the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement (USMCA) and CPTPP, RCEP, or other regional trade agreements in the Indo-Pacific that would likely have a substantial impact on United States businesses and workers.</text></paragraph> </section> <section id="H596A286CB8FF44AE93F47B836FEC35D1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Indo-Pacific Trade Strategy Commission</header> <subsection id="H55B10CC1DACC4FAEA25E4F2520AE1C0C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header> <paragraph id="H4C6B9499322A47868B95E512300A25E6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is hereby established an independent commission to be known as the <quote>Indo-Pacific Trade Strategy Commission</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>), to develop findings and recommendations for a comprehensive trade strategy for the Indo-Pacific region for purposes of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7CA7446C3DC741029F15293386F031B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensuring sustained United States economic and geopolitical leadership in the Indo-Pacific region;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H74356DC32EBE4DE8B1916FAAE615B915"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promoting United States innovation, exports, and economic opportunities for workers and businesses;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3DC28E4D645E4B929960F0F6C1A326B0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>countering the People’s Republic of China’s aggressive trade agenda;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD330777946DD40E2A30E07D27AD60CD0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>promoting United States values, norms, and standards;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF9DD2DE7C03742E2B3E6E2FF516B9FD2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>strengthening the United States economy;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7FFB43F8984E4F93A77CDD0141910A4D"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">bolstering United States economic and national security, including by addressing the vulnerabilities identified in the G7 Leaders’ Statement on Economic Resilience and Economic Security of May 20, 2023; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAF35090A86F44E61937AE4FACA115C74"><enum>(G)</enum><text>promoting United States supply chain resilience.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9EE77149DE8146D6A27ADD75CC7C5405"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This subsection shall take effect on the date that is 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1984DABA52D947109EDC437629854EAE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header> 
<paragraph id="H72B40AFDA5B54E0FBB7EEA46AA46A802"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Number and appointment</header><text>The Commission shall be composed of 12 members appointed as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="H46CF0AA0EE1A4B2E959ADF5C9B4ED0CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>6 members appointed by mutual agreement of the Chair of the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Ranking Member of the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0B1067F03BDD47E8A059754DF23D1B16"><enum>(B)</enum><text>6 members appointed by mutual agreement of the Chair of the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Ranking Member of the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H125DB70CE8914F66B4C33D0FB335187F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>None of the appointed members shall be a Member of the House of Representatives or a Member of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA0CF114CF8784E368B80B87D2125BEB0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The members of the Commission shall be individuals who have well-documented expertise, knowledge, or experience in the Indo-Pacific region, and—</text> <subparagraph id="H7F81B9F528FC43A3AF209396A118B3C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>international trade;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB6713AB32DDD4822868591D1C8BE352B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>economic and supply chain issues;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB9E8C2D1BBC84F748202A0F3B327BF44"><enum>(C)</enum><text>labor matters; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H75048306602747D5B2B5DD6BDBD6BD80"><enum>(D)</enum><text>environmental policy.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HDFF799B4C53244178FC4EF95C5E2D098"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Commission shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB65FE6D9FA58426CB8C51BDDC1512449"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hold public hearings and meetings;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H41859DDD37174DCE86676C7BE600875D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>hold classified hearings or meetings, if necessary to discuss classified material or information;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H546C90522B1C4D5481E88D6D900548BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide an opportunity for public comment, including sharing of research and policy analysis, through publication of a solicitation for public comments during a period of not less than 45 days; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5920851098A44F9CBBC0CED2D9D0E189"><enum>(D)</enum><text>consult quarterly with Congress, specifically with members of the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and members of the Committee on Finance of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6318B6A939834629BECCCC57CB4332FB"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit, not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, a final report to Congress, specifically to the members of the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and members of the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

