<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MAR25237-8MW-9Y-98T"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2407 IS: Charting My Path for Future Success Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2407</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Secretary of Education to reissue the solicitation and award the contract relating to the Charting My Path for Future Success project.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H7183463927C24F9B9C17134DD57A7F18"><section id="idad2df7b1d26c4b288494e7e9d0a2f416" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Charting My Path for Future Success Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H042ABB982AA0477ABB5583E143A68E7F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Charting My Path for Future Success Project</header><subsection id="H875B950D14454FE68490CF6DCCD088C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education shall reissue the solicitation and award a contract described in subsection (b) as if the contract described in such subsection had not previously been awarded.</text></subsection><subsection id="H49A188F41DB04CA38320C269C8431CDD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contract description</header><text>The contract described in this subsection is the contract that was awarded, pursuant to section 664(e)(1) of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1464">20 U.S.C. 1464(e)(1)</external-xref>), to a nonprofit organization to carry out the <quote>Charting My Path for Future Success</quote> project that—</text><paragraph id="HE21D0F0522074F488592F4BF1B9829E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">aims to help families and high schools to support students with disabilities to reach their goals during and after high school, by training educators to assist such students to—</text><subparagraph id="H3D62B94D782B4CE48D2FBB9C42EC034F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">set goals that help build skills to be successful in school and life;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE099354DA45B4DCA9DF32A8824B3A436"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop action plans related to those goals; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H763D5E67A09D4B248ABB6CD0198D30A2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reflect on their progress toward those goals and adjust goals or action plans when needed; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD42A7BE0DB5C4607990580C3433F8045"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under which, in January 2025, following the completion of training with the project, 61 educators began to assist 1,600 high school students in 62 high schools in 13 local educational agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDB7BA23235804712BDAC2916059C025B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition of cancellation of contract</header><text>A contract awarded under this section may not be canceled without the approval of Congress.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

