<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF1BD0FCE0B19466E947D5A2A8D339E34" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4195 IH: the Foreign Service Voluntary Early Retirement Authority Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4195</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250626">June 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To modify the voluntary retirement requirements for members of the Foreign Service, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0F643D49C75E4D93AECADBC071972824" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB15FA0DBB7124A49BC334A7DD080BABB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>the Foreign Service Voluntary Early Retirement Authority Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HC977E47EA55B4929ADAA98923FC99448"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modification to voluntary retirement requirements for members of the Foreign Service</header> 
<subsection id="H64E86CDB940542BDB0392EF49364CDAC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 811 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/4051">22 U.S.C. 4051</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HFF7A892187944FF2A818E1440B776F37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Any participant who is at least</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) Any participant who is at least</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7A92E7A9A1CC471AB674578ABC3E6A9B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H98D399A435E845639E0F0716EFEC5E9D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H5D1F4263695445C2A3EDC634AA312E6D"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any participant (as that term is defined in section 853) who is not entitled to an annuity under subsection (a) of this section, or section 609(a)(2)(B) or 808 of this Act, and who is at least 43 years of age and has completed at least 15 years of creditable service and who is separated from the Foreign Service or any other agency utilizing the Foreign Service personnel system during a period in which, as determined by the Office of Personnel Management (upon request of the Foreign Service or such other agency), under regulations prescribed by the Office, that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HBE57183A616A4A7AB8192632B6F0A28D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Foreign Service or other such agency (or if applicable, the component in which the employee is serving) is undergoing substantial delayering, substantial reorganization, substantial reductions in force, substantial transfer of function, or other substantial workforce restructuring (or shaping);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H90BEF832CF774254A3FD0619A642C53D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a significant percentage of employees servicing in the Foreign Service or other such agency (or component) are likely to be separated or subject to an immediate reduction in the rate of basic pay (without regard to subchapter VI of chapter 53, or comparable provisions); or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H236E21E1DA864C1EA7AD81360AE9B287"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identified as being in positions which are becoming surplus or excess to the Foreign Service’s or other such agency’s future ability to carry out its mission effectively,</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">shall be entitled to, on the participant’s application and with the consent of the Secretary or the head of such other agency, be retired from the Service or other such agency and entitled to an annuity. Such annuity shall be computed in the same manner as an annuity for an employee under section 8415(e) of title 5, United States Code. </continuation-text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFC38E7C47B094C52968D3B8357C2D6C8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header> <paragraph id="H9F948B8A64F54E9E91C02D7CEA09B531"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall apply to individuals involuntarily or voluntarily separated from the Foreign Service during the period beginning on January 20, 2025, and ending on the date of enactment of this Act, and to individuals voluntarily separated from the Foreign Service after the date of the enactment of this Act, subject to the terms and conditions of subsection (b) of section 811 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/4051">22 U.S.C. 4051</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a)(2) of this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE0DF4B436A304764B04DAA933DE5BAF8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If amounts in the Foreign Service Retirement and Disability Fund are inadequate to pay benefits payable under such subsection (b), amounts in the general fund of the Treasury not otherwise appropriated may be used to pay for such benefits.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCF9F416F75B44222BFE46E68459AF7B5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that any individual who receives an annuity under subsection (b) of section 811 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/4051">22 U.S.C. 4051</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a)(2) of this Act, shall be eligible to retain health care benefits under the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program if such individual was enrolled in such Program on the date of separation.</text></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

