<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25572-86H-0K-VSL">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1716 IS: Vision Lab Choice Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 1716</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250512">May 12, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S419">Mr.
                    Mullin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and
                referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health,
                    Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To amend title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act to improve health care
            coverage under vision plans, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HDF245545ADDC482DBA90813CCB0316D1">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="H26B69B34358F454FA2129B7E797B6BE0">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Vision Lab Choice Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="H3D1F601B53D7468A8E912B811A772487">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Improving health care coverage under vision plans</header>
            <subsection id="H132C57305DBC44949014EA6E7E627831">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>Title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 2719A (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-19a">42 U.S.C. 300gg–19a</external-xref>) the following new section:</text>
                <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H14554769448745238FA98D07C2921F71">
                    <section id="HE388C39B013C49A2BE7B73D6FC5CCF8A">
                        <enum>2719B.</enum>
                        <header>Improving coverage under vision plans</header>
                        <subsection id="H2C4C88A41BC04597A60015799B82D307">
                            <enum>(a)</enum>
                            <header>In general</header>
 <text>With respect to a group health plan or individual or group health insurance coverage that provides benefits for items and services relating to vision care (including such a plan or coverage that offers limited scope vision benefits), the following shall apply:</text>
                            <paragraph id="HEC299390E01F4068B56582506347DBC4">
                                <enum>(1)</enum>
                                <header>Duration of limited scope vision plans</header>
 <text>In the case of a doctor of optometry who has an agreement or is the beneficiary of an agreement with respect to a group health plan or health insurance coverage that offers limited scope vision benefits—</text>
                                <subparagraph id="HCB10AB43542743E5A2FD5E8185104779">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the term of the initial agreement shall be not longer than 2 years;</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e5a3570a6bc4098a1bc4a975495fa01">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the agreement may be extended with the prior acceptance by such doctor for each such term extension, and any such extension may be for a term not longer than 2 years; and</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H550B8457992B49F9B19A74132DAE6C6C">
                                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>the agreement may be extended for unlimited terms, subject to subparagraph (B).</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H9F3455E2486C485C857F3A5F917F84DE">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
                                <header>No restrictions on choice of laboratories and sources and
                                    suppliers</header>
 <text>A group health plan or health insurance issuer offering such coverage may not, directly or indirectly, restrict or limit a doctor of optometry described in paragraph (1) with respect to choice of laboratories, or choice of source or supplier of services or materials provided by the doctor to an individual who is enrolled under the plan or coverage.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="HB7FF6C3072CF42F8934005D25F29C146">
                            <enum>(b)</enum>
                            <header>Notification</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall on an annual basis notify each State of the State’s authority to enforce the provisions of subsection (a) against a group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering health insurance coverage described in subsection (a) pursuant to section 2723(a)(1) and request confirmation from the State whether or not the State will enforce the provisions of subsection (a). If a State notifies the Secretary that the State will not enforce the provisions of subsection (a) or fails to respond within 90 days of the Secretary’s request, the Secretary shall treat such State as failing to substantially enforce such provisions for purposes of subsections (a)(2) and (b) of section 2723. </text>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="H72E8D6811F2C4D46B741A67484A6333F">
                            <enum>(c)</enum>
                            <header>Definition</header>
 <text>In this section, the term <term>doctor of optometry</term> means a doctor of optometry who is legally authorized to practice optometry by the State in which the doctor so practices.</text>
                        </subsection>
                    </section>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H72658FD6293D4128A90C7387366C499F">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Conforming amendment</header>
 <text>Section 2722(c)(1) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-21">42 U.S.C. 300gg–21(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(other than the requirements under section 2719B)</quote> after <quote>section 2791(c)(2)</quote>.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H3961DFB626A348A2B4BE735655586593">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Exclusive applicability of State law</header>
 <text>Notwithstanding any amendment made by this Act, State law that directly affects any standard or requirement relating to health insurance issuers and vision benefit plans, shall have exclusive application and the amendments made by this Act shall not apply to the extent that such State law conflicts with such amendments. The State shall retain exclusive jurisdiction over health insurance issuers and limited scope vision benefit plans that are directly governed by such State.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

