<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H713AF7C4DD3A4C3383889C9CAF6E1497" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5020 IH: Supporting Our Shelters Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5020</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250822">August 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Animal Welfare Act to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a program under which the Secretary will award grants to entities for purposes of supporting the capability of such entities to provide care to animals in their care, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H345544B0FA2E401CA1A0B0799FA4934A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2E00F1C8E8354E469A5965F35D51DCC6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Our Shelters Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFE1D60A4577F45E7888676CC609B3E01"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants to support animal shelters</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 28 of the Animal Welfare Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2158">7 U.S.C. 2158</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (d) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H338316BF4E35455EA70EF48AB3FD2723" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H9B2481ABCC8348B9B65377EAFC0AA771"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grants To support animal shelters</header> 
<paragraph id="H133C0903EB7044D89A83045774EC3A2C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a program under which the Secretary will award grants to entities described in subsection (a)(2) for purposes of supporting the capability of such entities to provide care to animals in their care, including feeding, sheltering, veterinary care, recreational activities, and the hiring, training, and retention of staff to provide such care.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2C71E668883477E8DF468E0ACA999FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Term</header><text>The term of a grant under this subsection shall not exceed 3 years. Such term is renewable if the grantee submits a report to the Secretary under paragraph (4) prior to the expiration of the respective term.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6B5E69AC167B40049DF79D4DA7D6B9D9">
                        <enum>(3)</enum>
                        <header>Report to Secretary</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 180 days after the date on which the first grant is awarded under this subsection and each year thereafter, each recipient of a grant under this subsection shall submit to the Secretary a detailed accounting of—</text>
                        <subparagraph id="H0C19066A0C01422E981CBA21BF472BF3">
                            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of each species taken into the shelter and the outcome for each species during the period covered by the report; and</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="HCE604D935FD0425CAFD30C63A3FC709A">
                            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>how the recipient of the grant used grant funds during the period covered by the report.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                    </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3C0EF6CC05874032A693EE24F221839D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Beginning not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection and each year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report on the program under paragraph (1), including an accounting of how the funds made available to carry out this subsection were used by recipients of grants under this subsection to improve animal care.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H407DF63201444AE68639C3F202BFBDBE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall promulgate regulations to carry out this section. Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of subsection (d), the Secretary shall promulgate regulations to carry out such subsection.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

