<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDDECA62263EC4DEBA1FE89DD8766399F" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 76 IH: Recognizing Gold Shield Families and affirming that their sacrifices and difficulties should not be forgotten.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 76</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250128">January 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000392">Mr. Kustoff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing Gold Shield Families and affirming that their sacrifices and difficulties should not be forgotten.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the United States owes an immeasurable debt of gratitude to the brave men and women who serve as first responders, courageously risking their lives to protect our communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the families of these valiant first responders exhibit unparalleled strength, resilience, and sacrifice, supporting their loved ones in their noble service to our Nation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the loss of a first responder in the line of duty is a profound tragedy that leaves an enduring impact on their families, necessitating unwavering support, and recognition from the Nation they served;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Gold Shield Families are defined as the families of fallen police officers, firefighters, emergency medical technicians (EMTs), correction officers, emergency dispatch officers, and emergency service providers who have tragically lost their lives in the line of duty protecting and serving their communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is essential to acknowledge and honor the dedication and sacrifices made by the families of fallen first responders, whose unwavering courage and resilience serve as an inspiration to us all; and </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the sacrifices and difficulties faced by Gold Shield Families in the aftermath of the loss of a loved one in the line of duty should not be forgotten, as they continue to endure hardships and challenges while upholding the legacy of their fallen heroes: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HB0AF12F2BCE44A248F23542415BA309A"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H0B7A5A2E1BB54A5F99059D3E62600883"><enum/><text>That by the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HE1896B1153E6436CA472D14BAABF14F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that Gold Shield Families, consisting of the families of fallen police officers, firefighters, emergency medical technicians (EMTs), correction officers, emergency dispatch officers, and emergency service providers, are hereby recognized and honored for their immeasurable sacrifices and steadfast support of their loved ones in service to our Nation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B6F8F7AC9D64BAEBE0912BA7F718AAB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that this recognition stands as a testament to the enduring gratitude and appreciation of the United States for the tremendous contributions and sacrifices made by Gold Shield Families; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1141D7EB40E489EB1AF3A4C900FE073"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that a copy of this resolution be transmitted to the President of the United States and made publicly available to honor and recognize Gold Shield Families for their sacrifices and unwavering support of our Nation's first responders and emergency service providers, affirming that their sacrifices and difficulties should not be forgotten.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

