<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA0ABBDB9F39B4B65B7DDEC9D9C547F4B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4279 IH: Prevent Regulatory Overreach from Turning Essential Companies into Targets Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4279</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250702">July 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000471">Mr. Fitzgerald</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit entities integral to the national interests of the United States from participating in any foreign sustainability due diligence regulation, including the Corporate Sustainability Due Diligence Directive of the European Union, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3991E7130B2E444CAC819779FEB938DF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0ABCFE15E58749C0913586C1AC593BC0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prevent Regulatory Overreach from Turning Essential Companies into Targets Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PROTECT USA Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7ECAD61BD60043F18F04B9A01AFDF04D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
<paragraph id="HA9E7439E81E3413591801FF0EE97CC6F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The ability of citizens of the United States to engage in international commerce is a fundamental concern of the policy of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1C4FE8B0216248BB9039A73D96A51486"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Entities in the extractive and manufacturing sectors contribute significantly to the prosperity of the United States and the growth of the world economy.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H32F6FC55ED9C4D4196BA082D62EDF559"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Maintaining and, in some cases, increasing access to certain supplies and materials from the extractive sector, including agriculture, energy, mining, and timber, and access to materials from the manufacturing sector, are critically important for promoting economic development and human progress in the United States and around the world.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4B2451F9C8844202907221FB67B7A70F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Restrictions, particularly restrictions adopted unilaterally by foreign countries that are substantially different from restrictions applied by the United States, that unreasonably hinder the ability of entities integral to the national interests of the United States to pursue their commercial activities can have serious adverse effects on employment, economic stability, scientific progress, and international trade, with the potential to impede domestic and foreign policy goals.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H939F41D89D46414EB13D91473419B928"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H80DFD216F35B4B5B9A17FDF72CF7ADDC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Entity integral to the national interests of the United States</header><text>The term <term>entity integral to the national interests of the United States</term> means any partnership, corporation, limited liability company, or other business entity that—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H68B8D9B869FB43DE99026C9B9CC6F3F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does business with any part of the Federal Government, including Federal contract awards or leases;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H908DB11FABB5451294BDBFBF7E768BAC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is organized under the laws of any State or territory within the United States, or of the District of Columbia, or under any Act of Congress or a foreign subsidiary of any such entity that—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2CA6EDCDB68B43EDB8AE189D7902F6BD"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">derives not less than 25 percent of its revenue from activities related to the extraction or production of raw materials from the earth, including—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCD54D5144D534678A491D7D40D5559AC"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cultivating biomass (whether or not for human consumption);</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA01DD3E9AB684330A8045B169A6CB97F"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">exploring or producing fossil fuels;</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE29EC0DCF8C4F5E83CB2D1E2DECC7D3"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">mining; and</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H04761C3B294F4334BB057F4318D1A55A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">processing any material derived from an activity described in subclause (I), (II), or (III) for human use or benefit;</text></subclause></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6FA8A019A7834174A5C9B395CA72A75B"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>has a primary North American Industry Classification System code or foreign equivalent associated with the manufacturing sector;</text>
                    </clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H136E19535DA84C37A7598DF6D82421AA">
                        <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">derives not less than 25 percent of its revenue from activities related to the mechanical, physical, or chemical transformation of materials, substances, or components into new products; and</text>
                    </clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57FF3FBE3BC34F159ED39D57EAF34BC7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is engaged in—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAB3B15F6514247A3946CA01754946EE3"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the production of arms or other products integral to the national defense of the United States; or</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H98E48B999AAB462181BA5FF527C71484"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the production, mining, or processing of any critical mineral; or</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H176A7294194B47D58932CFD2ADA27A37"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the President otherwise identifies as integral to the national interests of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H42D229D944A149BEB463F88FA566256F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Critical mineral</header><text>The term <term>critical mineral</term> includes—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC4D7E8FE8FB4E1BB276CF739E885F49"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any mineral identified as a critical mineral in section 7002(a) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(a)</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7652548EB4524439BF79EAA263761411"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any fuel mineral, including fossil fuels and any fraction, distillate, or other by-product of a fuel mineral.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H295C48D259E146B1B808EEA01714BDCC"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Foreign sustainability due diligence regulation</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF463CA1BD3C746E7A8E2F4B3A559E979"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>foreign sustainability due diligence regulation</term> means any law, regulation, or other legal instrument adopted by a foreign government that requires any person to undertake—</text>
                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H723B1ED0ECFE4A459E1517DD58904F91">
                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the environmental or social impacts of its operations or value chain;</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC079524D7B248B48EA45A93CD47B240">
                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">action to address any impacts identified in the assessment described in clause (i); and</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F43341C452A455B80892C5C38CE78D1">
                        <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reporting of the impacts and actions described in clauses (i) and (ii).</text>
                    </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9CD2091F834B4828AC9EB7A83D05A97E">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <header>Exception</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>foreign sustainability due diligence regulation</term> does not apply to any law, regulation, or other legal instrument that is substantively similar to a law, regulation, or other legal instrument that has been adopted or approved by an Act of Congress.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED7C115FC3AA472282C142C8EB18F2FD">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <header>Inclusion of Corporate Sustainability Due Diligence Directive</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>foreign sustainability due diligence regulation</term> includes—</text>
                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF30F28E800D748EBBC4A3C469A36FF48">
                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the entirety of the Corporate Sustainability Due Diligence Directive adopted by the European Union;</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E68BD35333D4DC985425D56436F6177">
                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any successor directive adopted by the European Union or any member country of the European Union; and</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6883194547DD4EB8805CA2A936B13F48">
                        <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any precursor directive adopted by any member country of the European Union.</text>
                    </clause>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph></section>
<section id="HACC9B93DA7AC4C328D9969A7A3A3EF8D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on compliance with foreign sustainability due diligence regulations</header>
<subsection id="H0A81186F9F334B68A831DDDD7F73E64B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), no entity integral to the national interests of the United States may comply with any foreign sustainability due diligence regulation.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H132A963BA6904BE59E5EFECB4FAFB64F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception for ordinary business activities</header><text>Subsection (a) does not prohibit an entity from undertaking actions that it may lawfully take—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9DEF5DE7628C478BADCE74832B965406"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to comply with a statute of the United States; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB1A484BE96241C5847E4C4623B02E4D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the ordinary course of business.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H061FA6942D7440458EBBFECAC13EA2C2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Hardship relief process</header>
<paragraph id="H9C9CE5C872BB4261AA5B117101D72345"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Petition for relief</header><text>Any entity integral to the national interests of the United States that believes it will experience particular hardship in connection with the prohibition described in subsection (a) may petition the President for an exemption from such prohibition.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H701AD00F5C374B6B986AB24F6650341C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Decision</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the President receives a petition from an entity submitted under paragraph (1), the President shall provide a written decision to the entity that—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H45AC44A4987C4E9DBA54A4E9D2E3D624"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">grants or denies the requested exemption;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12EFDD3EAD0547778F0B6018FA7F6D3A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contains a statement setting forth the basis for the decision; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65C0BAC9E1EC410CA7B79D9953854D48"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a granted exemption, describes any condition that the exemption is subject to, as determined by the President.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8DCE091D9D88481691FEF2BD185BB7F8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Factors to be considered</header><text>In making the decision required by paragraph (2), the President shall consider—</text>
<subparagraph id="HA917541FF2B74C2496EBECCB5C87F3E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the extent to which the denial of a petition submitted under paragraph (1) by an entity would result in the inability of the entity to participate in value chains associated with products essential for domestic use in the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1258947B8134467498E181B8AA8050DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>possible adverse effects on the economy in any locality or region of the United States, including adverse effects on employment;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD2B7B08147E440EBB3E33741E4A72552"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the degree to which granting the petition would impact, directly or indirectly, the United States; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB315897352F8409BB902E0DF49AD84A1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the extent to which denial of the petition would prevent the entity from divesting in a business formed under the laws of a jurisdiction subject to a foreign sustainability due diligence regulation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H972166A73EDC4267AC5B268D630E10CA"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prohibition against adverse action for compliance with this Act</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB69012262C1F438A9323B7C49E045E7F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person may take any adverse action towards an entity integral to the national interests of the United States for action or inaction related to a foreign sustainability due diligence regulation.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1BD77030AB954609880915C3CDA097F0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Judgments for foreign sustainability due diligence regulations</header><text>No judgment by a foreign court brought against an entity integral to the national interests of the United States in relation to any foreign sustainability due diligence regulation shall be recognized in the courts of the United States or of the States, unless otherwise provided by an Act of Congress.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H728324EBD043453F86A220E7F169FD96"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H139D533EFDC34A32869198D4ED440AAB">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Actions by the President</header>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H29AFFF1B0ACC4A1EB03A0E45F0BA972E">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                        <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall take any action the President determines is in the public interest to protect an entity integral to the national interests of the United States from an adverse action related to a foreign sustainability due diligence regulation.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAB1D3ABB004B4213A1D872A2E7CD5C34">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <header>Determination of public interest</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining under subparagraph (A) whether an action by the President is in the public interest, the President shall take into account the impact of the adverse action described in that subparagraph on—</text>
                        <clause id="HB1E76E44649F4BE887BC7C80872B2812">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>consumers and businesses in the United States;</text> </clause> <clause id="HE8B1DB87065849528B878E265B588221"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>the economic, energy, and environmental security of the United States; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HA77D305D68D248E89F3207F9948142FB">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>foreign relations of the United States, including existing international commitments.</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDBE9FAD56BC44BEA9B4AF051EADAF8F5" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Private right of action</header>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD896639D71A54FEDAFE68158D8F68236">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                        <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any entity integral to the national interests of the United States aggrieved by a violation of subsection (a) may bring a civil action against the person that violated subsection (a) in an appropriate district court of the United States.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H04BEA1BAB4FD4904B9910A8C9AD13D55">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <header>Relief</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a civil action brought under subparagraph (A) in which the plaintiff prevails, the court may award—</text>
                        <clause id="H188668E8F5B74D3ABD20A0E7D11FA96C">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>a writ of mandamus or other equitable or declaratory relief;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HA4A7E5EE4467403793CD208CD4F1EC90">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>punitive damages not to exceed the maximum penalty described in paragraph (3)(A);</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HC0B34393E52B4E5AABB8BFFE77657405">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>reasonable attorney fees and litigation costs;</text> </clause> <clause id="H6A050118D3CD4AE793E85771434BB330"> <enum>(iv)</enum> <text>compensatory damages, including any amount paid by the entity pursuant to the applicable foreign sustainability due diligence regulation; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H28B4EBE2C9314C9BAF4020E1FB3062DB">
                            <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>all other appropriate relief.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0F318973A43429C9373D3EF7FD67382"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates subsection (a) or a regulation issued pursuant to this Act—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD013B1D068914199BEB6228ECCC01A63"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $1,000,000; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4CD0054C0BE7448C977E1AF76F081F31"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may, at the discretion of the President, for a period of not longer than 3 years from the date on which the person is found in violation, be deemed ineligible to submit a bid for any Federal award or contract.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

