<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25D59-3WK-F2-RHP">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2583 IS: NOAA Weather Radio Modernization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2583</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250731">July 31, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr.
                    Sullivan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and
                referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce,
                    Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To require the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere to
            expand and modernize the weather radio system of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric
            Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>NOAA Weather Radio Modernization Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id7241de4ecb974df69c02300bce472fdd">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>NOAA Weather Radio</header>
            <subsection id="id431d4152b84f4603ba0b9bf7c92503c6">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8501">15 U.S.C. 8501 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
                <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd44df83c7d814e18b3794b4377625d15">
                    <title id="id21f5a6895cca4f499434c22afe752608">
                        <enum>VII</enum>
                        <header>NOAA Weather Radio</header>
                        <section id="idfdc348fa3e8240869f921bb33bac884e">
                            <enum>701.</enum>
                            <header>NOAA Weather Radio</header>
                            <subsection id="id28f1339b8eb0485095f0f7f416a0a0a9">
                                <enum>(a)</enum>
                                <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Under Secretary shall establish or maintain a nationwide weather radio network, to be known as <quote>NOAA Weather Radio</quote>, that—</text>
                                <paragraph id="id3ca72253c8ae44e68b5b27b25091bf5c">
                                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>broadcasts weather information, including emergency weather watches, warnings, and other hazard information;</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="id2fb8a6b4dd804a82a9712d4811a242ed">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>operates 24 hours a day, 7 days a week; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idfa193f7e63a74c63bbc40de96529a271"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>is resilient to emergency hazards, such as loss of power and cellular service.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="idf006b53e43364371ac720bda19507906">
                                <enum>(b)</enum>
                                <header>Coverage and reliability</header>
 <text>The Under Secretary shall ensure the reliability of NOAA Weather Radio by—</text>
                                <paragraph id="id2e12f8bdf3fe470dad7bbf2d8fd1fb31">
                                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>maintaining support for existing systems, especially those serving areas not covered by or having poor quality cellular service; and</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="id4fe65098e08d4111ad174ee91cddb09a">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>ensuring consistent maintenance and operations monitoring, with timely repairs to broadcast transmitter site equipment and antennas.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="id0c184aabc7b9491eb98f66554155449c">
                                <enum>(c)</enum>
                                <header>Modernization initiative</header>
                                <paragraph id="ida51b29d728bf454d90c7045fb4cfe5db">
                                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>To the maximum extent practicable, the Under Secretary shall expand the coverage of and modernize NOAA Weather Radio to ensure it remains valuable to the public, including by—</text>
                                    <subparagraph id="id2bc7f9f887a84ce9945906b0135f401f">
                                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>improving those methods of communicating the risks posed by hazardous weather events to the public that are most likely to result in informed decisionmaking regarding the mitigation of such risks;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="id037f83d4da444c749ec33a501fa6face">
                                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>improving communication of hazardous weather warnings and the urgency of such warnings to areas that experience a high frequency of such warnings;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="idc14fae983bc947fc9ca147d937885aff">
                                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>enhancing the ability to amplify non-weather emergency messages through NOAA Weather Radio as necessary;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="idf6d012b490dd4422bf7e281eb73e16cc">
                                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>acquiring additional transmitters as required to expand coverage to—</text>
                                        <clause id="id2c769be99f6f4bf89b482ad2cfa5b1ea">
                                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>areas at high risk for rapid onset weather disasters that require short-fuse warnings;</text>
                                        </clause>
                                        <clause id="idcb98dc2b32104e35bd4cd28056ed47ca">
                                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>communities without—</text> <subclause id="id7a9222ad818a4261bd8c91e2102e937c"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>mobile broadband internet access service (as defined in section 8.1(b) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation)) and as depicted by a map created under section 802(c)(1)(C) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/642">47 U.S.C. 642(c)(1)(C)</external-xref>);</text>
                                            </subclause>
                                            <subclause id="idc4ac12c6a2f548988ed48ff8a763f256">
                                                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>State or local emergency warning systems; or</text>
                                            </subclause>
                                            <subclause id="idc59e9f386d6f42a38e5f959354872ec2">
                                                <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text>satellite coverage; and</text> </subclause> </clause> <clause id="id6297c1ecfeb543249ef6d8c9c6ae1653"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <text>Federal lands, such as land in the National Park System or the National Forest System and National Recreation Areas;</text>
                                        </clause>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="idd841d8c542884a0b8c1d18c6e3b04e35">
                                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>adding the capability to disseminate NOAA Weather Radio alerts by satellite or through the cloud; and</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="ide94087b3a7d541ba9d52bb2d68c97de7">
                                        <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>modernizing the messaging system to enable more geographically specific warnings.</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="ideb5d1c50f5a541baa34b63a97c385066">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                                    <header>Elements</header>
 <text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Under Secretary shall—</text>
                                    <subparagraph id="id73fbba9b57c84d97bf58fb961a9baad5">
                                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>upgrade telecommunications infrastructure of NOAA Weather Radio to accelerate the transition of broadcasts to internet protocol-based communications over non-copper media;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="idc15d653930d14ca8bdf046be7167d982">
                                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>accelerate software upgrades to the Advanced Weather Interactive Processing System, or any relevant system successors, in order to implement partial county notifications and alerts;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="id8412659be66347ee95f7a391ccb78f76">
                                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>enhance accessibility and usability of data and feeds of NOAA Weather Radio with feedback from relevant stakeholders, including the private sector;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="idb1ce4a11456145cc8c9e102924e83edd">
                                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>develop options, including satellite backup capability and commercial provider partnerships, for continuity of service of NOAA Weather Radio in the event of an outage at a weather forecast office;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="idc76a99a7919447ebb3c3ca377ed42918">
                                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>research and develop alternative options to transmit NOAA Weather Radio signals to transmitters that are remote or do not have internet protocol capability;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="idba0ba5cb60774c438a35e763bcc6a124">
                                        <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>transition critical applications to the Integrated Dissemination Program, or any relevant program successors; and</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="iddd5ccaabf6eb443f8a9823a1f02d95e9">
                                        <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>work with the General Services Administration, and other relevant agencies, to develop new, alternative, or updated expedited mechanisms to secure priority space capacity, such as leased land and tower space, for NOAA Weather Radio transmitters and antennas that are best suited for the national security and public safety missions of NOAA Weather Radio.</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="id23bf94e3417b43cd9575dc9a37b2e527">
                                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                                    <header>Priority</header>
 <text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Under Secretary shall prioritize practices, capabilities, and technologies recommended in accordance with the assessment under subsection (d) to maximize the accessibility of NOAA Weather Radio, particularly in areas of the United States described in paragraph (1)(D)(i).</text>
                                </paragraph>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="id8177c00981ff4678bed8c79dbfcbb44b">
                                <enum>(d)</enum>
                                <header>Assessment for management and distribution</header>
                                <paragraph id="id524a30f0970d4cbb9f9b14634e81c347">
                                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Under Secretary shall complete an assessment of access to NOAA Weather Radio.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="id2718f70013364269946355d7d8580ae5">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                                    <header>Elements</header>
 <text>In conducting the assessment required under paragraph (1), the Under Secretary shall take into consideration and provide recommendations regarding the following:</text>
                                    <subparagraph id="id20e145ea98284f37a3c3e6d2c8e6b46b">
                                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>The need for continuous, adequate, and operational real-time broadcasts of NOAA Weather Radio.</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="id5c26e0bb7e0443189108652cca5f5806">
                                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>Input from relevant stakeholders that provide access to NOAA Weather Radio, including third-party platforms that provide online services, such as websites and mobile device applications.</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="idc7508ced111f444db0863206661ed6ec">
                                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>The manner by which existing or new management systems may promote consistent, efficient, and compatible access to NOAA Weather Radio.</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="ideca22b8a6c7d41a19ec62925d8fcf68d">
                                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>The ability of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to aggregate real-time broadcast feeds at one or more central locations, as a redundancy to the broadcast feed from the nearest weather forecast office.</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="id1344e965f5d14cf694e2ac3a9189a4fc">
                                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>Effective coordination between agencies with responsibilities relating to emergencies and natural disasters.</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="id23c34cf87bcc42079e6b131994d72e2c">
                                        <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>The potential effects of an electromagnetic pulse or geomagnetic disturbance on NOAA Weather Radio.</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                </paragraph>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="id122d30c2a02344b8a6fe20a105b050e1">
                                <enum>(e)</enum>
                                <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Under Secretary—</text>
                                <paragraph id="id9b71328743184c6ab70756b4c1593c4f">
                                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031, $25,000,000 to operate NOAA Weather Radio under subsections (a) and (b); and</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="iddef979d4b9dc42749ed6eb886fe3bfe8">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>for fiscal year 2026, $100,000,000, which shall remain available until expended, to carry out subsections (c) and (d).</text>
                                </paragraph>
                            </subsection>
                        </section>
                    </title>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idce5dbcbe74a448e28b547b26f4615f6f">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Weather ready all hazards award program</header>
 <text>Section 407 of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8546">15 U.S.C. 8546</external-xref>) is—</text>
                <paragraph id="id2ad637e570e64cc99b5387f6cdee6d2a">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>transferred to title VII of that Act, as added by subsection (a);</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id6b7b6d2eb90d42718b436e6716f7c711"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>inserted after section 701 of that Act, as added by subsection (a); and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idd7537839cd8448c6b1a370a0dea4f582">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>redesignated as section 702.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="id32d01819a75743c9997c628a9eb62168"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Clerical amendments</header> <text>The table of contents for the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 is amended—</text>
                <paragraph id="id02b4375546e3439597600f33bde80ede">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>by striking the item relating to section 407; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idf649c222ce664a1f96f5761d845f0686"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
                    <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida9810120953f4c71b915b97d6bd6afa0">
                        <toc>
                            <toc-entry level="title">TITLE VII—NOAA Weather Radio </toc-entry>
                            <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 701. NOAA Weather Radio.</toc-entry>
                            <toc-entry level="section" bold="off">Sec. 702. National Oceanic and
                                Atmospheric Administration Weather Ready All Hazards Award
                                Program.</toc-entry>
                        </toc>
                        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                    </quoted-block>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="id1f2f79ae17ec4a92b8f7dd19b8bc1429">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>National standards for weather warning systems in flash flood zones</header>
            <subsection id="idda213c265f994feea094d1d67720ffc4">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Under Secretary of Commerce for Standards and Technology, in consultation with the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere, shall develop standards for flash flood emergency alert systems within the 100-year floodplain (as defined in section 100202(a) of the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4004">42 U.S.C. 4004(a)</external-xref>)).</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id836c4235c38b468c9dbde5365cc69632">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Requirements</header>
 <text>The Director shall ensure that standards developed under subsection (a)—</text>
                <paragraph id="idfabd99c70e2043fd9426eebd976552eb">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>meet the needs of communities without—</text> <subparagraph id="idc76c211806d3492c8ab51bc623c02cb9"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>mobile broadband internet access service (as defined in section 8.1(b) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation)) and as depicted by a map created under section 802(c)(1)(C) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/642">47 U.S.C. 642(c)(1)(C)</external-xref>);</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id0ccb49f8394b488b9dcd7af6a2fc8d77">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>State or local emergency warning systems; or</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id89078b6d8fff4954bfc1aa22e3affd1b"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>satellite coverage; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id7a469bf5859240d284de49520e88f7c0">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>will result in reliable systems, especially during hazardous events.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id5315d1ee03df44cdb5c925a3b1544256">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Report required</header>
 <text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary of Commerce for Standards and Technology shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report that includes a summary of the standards developed under subsection (a).</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="id4612e519048c462985167fc56164a7ee">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>Classification of and staffing plan for employees and protection from hiring
                freezes</header>
            <subsection id="id51189720ff8144419bc0c11a89c1b94d">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>Title IV of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8541">15 U.S.C. 8541 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
                <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaeec1ebb91c7470488c891abe6dfc581">
                    <section id="id6e0a6cca31be4ed4b75b3fc729f8bf9f">
                        <enum>415.</enum>
                        <header>Classification of and staffing plan for employees and protection
                            from hiring freezes</header>
                        <subsection id="idc510bbfc1b3549d49eba556ef79ed9c7">
                            <enum>(a)</enum>
                            <header>Classification of certain employees</header>
                            <paragraph id="id008740eb4d304cf69bedcbda1323371a">
                                <enum>(1)</enum>
                                <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall categorize each position in the National Oceanographic and Atmospheric Administration specified in paragraph (2) as a protective service occupation under the Standard Occupational Classification System.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="idf2230e37c4054a3594d042e3c6a9b0bd">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
                                <header>Positions specified</header>
 <text>The positions specified in this paragraph are the following positions in the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, as defined by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management:</text>
                                <subparagraph id="idd2cd2247855840a29b610b074e368266">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>Meteorology Series (1340).</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id38b813f9923b4e75b5d936bd130c269f"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>Hydrology Series (1315).</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="id4d9a422a09084a3787f1be0e967d8300">
                                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>General Physical Science Series (1301).</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id2daf71cae3304cb2aeced928c299e9d6"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>Oceanographer Series (1360).</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="id3329ef413ca64a82a138ca8034ede3ee">
                                    <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>Electronics Technical Series (0856).</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="ide2a26533a8b949c8bf9824f2600aa548"> <enum>(F)</enum> <text>Information Technology Management Series (GS–2210).</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="idfae40a9d2bf641038d482dda885f0878">
                                    <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>Professional Mariners (as defined in section 269B of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Commissioned Officer Corps Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3079b">33 U.S.C. 3079b</external-xref>)) who are involved in the collection of data to support forecasts and warnings to protect human life and property (including Series 0865, 9901, 9916, 9920, 9923–24, 9927–28, 9931–34, 9944, 9954, 9960, 9965, 9968, 9971, 9973, and 9984).</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="id5558dcc3fd2543129c9c4121a42c6d54">
                            <enum>(b)</enum>
                            <header>10-Year staffing plan for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric
                                Administration</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Under Secretary shall submit to Congress a 10-year staffing plan for—</text>
                            <paragraph id="id651752bf378642c29970134d456f142a">
                                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the National Weather Service; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id38b234d6ab23485698d3aa9d3c36a773"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>any positions within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration that support forecasts and warnings to protect human life and property, including positions that involve—</text>
                                <subparagraph id="id2b89582087834ece9b58448437ef51ec">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>collection of data for incorporation into watches and warnings;</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="id5a8ffda674ca447cb412b1f45e8800a9">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>operation and maintenance of equipment for collection of data described in subparagraph (A);</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="idee7f71d096384ee1bef50751b75c1688">
                                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>maintenance of information technology systems;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id6f9e31a7be3d4abfbde88bc658ae90b1"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>modeling for forecasts and warnings; and</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="idfdb38cca7a254686a79e4b752513cfce">
                                    <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>research to improve forecasts, warnings, and communication of those warnings to better protect human life and property.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection>
                    </section>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="ida97eaf106036400eb96343cfb9eb5ee3">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Clerical amendment</header>
 <text>The table of contents for the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 414 the following:</text>
                <quoted-block style="OLC" id="idd679aa2a-a524-4f6f-a437-d47b24253b6a">
                    <toc>
                        <toc-entry level="section" idref="id6e0a6cca31be4ed4b75b3fc729f8bf9f">Sec.
                            415. Classification of and staffing plan for employees and protection
                            from hiring freezes.</toc-entry>
                    </toc>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

