<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAFF3863D24FE480FA7AB91A0B81A16B3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3413 IH: Physician and Patient Safety Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3413</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250514">May 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to issue regulations to ensure due process rights for physicians before any termination, restriction, or reduction of the professional activity of such physicians or staff privileges of such physicians.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF5ACA05034274E92956C9F64BDE53028" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4CBD1FE4CB524A0983E79543EA7FFD70" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Physician and Patient Safety Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFB72FF26B15540729C2D7AAED651EC49"><enum>2.</enum><header>Regulations to ensure due process rights for physicians</header> <subsection id="H63E0FFA27C31428192B047BB591A76B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue final regulations to provide that physicians who have been granted medical staff privileges at a hospital have a fair hearing and appellate review through appropriate medical staff mechanisms before any termination, restriction, or reduction of the professional activity of such physicians or staff privileges of such physicians at such hospital.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD32AB644A0AC46E09EF637D7030014BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements of regulations</header><text>The regulations described in subsection (a) shall provide that—</text> <paragraph id="H3CAEA52AF1694189982878897E908C7A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a hearing or appellate review may not be denied through a third-party contract;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82144941FAC94D78AAF44DFBBA1613B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a physician shall not be requested or required to waive their rights to such a hearing or appellate review as a condition of employment, either with the hospital or with a third-party contractor; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H886FC2AD714B472F88BDC2C26E69016B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any such hearing or appellate review shall be confidential and not reportable to any entity, including the National Practitioner Data Bank or future workplaces or employers, unless there is an ongoing threat to patient safety, or as otherwise required under the reporting requirements for hospitals established by the National Practitioner Data Bank.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD6696CADC13F4220936FA93F991DAAF8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The final regulations promulgated under subsection (a) shall take effect not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

