<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25H97-1N9-Y8-JXF"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2684 IS: United States-Taiwan Partnership in the Americas Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2684</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250902">September 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To support countries in Latin America and the Caribbean that maintain official diplomatic relations with Taiwan, to counter efforts by the People's Republic of China to coerce or pressure governments into breaking such ties, to deepen coordination with Taiwan on diplomatic, development, and economic engagement in the Western Hemisphere, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States-Taiwan Partnership in the Americas Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id1fa0dde0dddc4a4c94c27c1be2fdcb95"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd4dfa13de9274edf8a09805bd1d9dda7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Taiwan is a democratic partner of the United States, and countries that maintain ties with Taiwan often share our Nation's commitment to transparency, good governance, and human rights.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbdd117f36c47483690993ad0d0702d67"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The People’s Republic of China has pressured Taiwan’s remaining 7 diplomatic allies in Latin America and the Caribbean to sever diplomatic relations with Taiwan by leveraging opaque development deals and backroom pressure.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0183e95869e84576b058c701f9cbdd92"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States has an interest in ensuring countries in Latin America and the Caribbean can make sovereign foreign policy decisions free from coercion or financial manipulation by the People's Republic of China.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id96ff78cf751f4122afe7cfdf546cf6ec"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id04d41e50eec0469899f8ae66e93d87ed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to support countries in Latin America and the Caribbean that maintain diplomatic relations with Taiwan;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id543aaa17ffcd4af09e2f4fbee3135b12"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to counter efforts by the People's Republic of China to coerce or pressure governments in the region into breaking diplomatic ties with Taiwan; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida9c49d1ef3414a0a87e30eedce240b7d"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to deepen coordination with Taiwan on its development and economic engagement in the Western Hemisphere.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id7f2447f23c2b41b9893849078b373c6c"><enum>4.</enum><header>Monitoring the economic influence of the People's Republic of China</header><subsection id="id9f21068c3f334e09b7e9c07dcf3757a1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Infrastructure influence risk mechanism</header><text>The Secretary of State shall establish a mechanism to track and respond to infrastructure and development projects by the People's Republic of China in countries that maintain diplomatic relations with Taiwan.</text></subsection><subsection id="id71fd7b075d8a40a5b7d93d7f4f4ae1f3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The mechanism required under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="id3855f979cfff4b769d493326b30d0ce2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify projects referred to in such subsection that carry strategic risks or involve non-transparent financing;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ff020b3593b4f26a0491aa6df90e460"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinate appropriate United States diplomatic or technical responses to such projects; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id69371ca88deb405fb844d001a42d5177"><enum>(3)</enum><text>share relevant information with Congress and with United States allies.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id1a293bda15064a7f9d3569e89bb700b7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><subsection id="id32d4378675bc4c1eba6ad2e1a6aa1b8b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Semiannual status report</header><text>The Secretary of State shall submit semiannual status reports to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name> regarding governments in Latin America that have taken steps to discontinue diplomatic relations with Taiwan.</text></subsection><subsection id="id1f276782cc4f44a99cfacffa5ad77aee"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Diplomatic engagement plan</header><text>If the Secretary of State determines that a government in a country referred to in subsection (a) is taking steps to terminate diplomatic relations with Taiwan, the Secretary, not later than 30 days after such determination, shall submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that includes a detailed plan to support the maintenance of official diplomatic relations between such government and Taiwan.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7c5e82bf1f7e458eaa7a710f1ef39b19"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual report</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfcb2022d914a499ba176a2a8b12212d2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for the following 5 years, the Secretary of State shall submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that includes—</text><subparagraph id="id335223274787441ab120a30143598e2e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of the goals, investments, and interests of the People’s Republic of China in Latin America and the Caribbean that maintain diplomatic relations with Taiwan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0c15bb9e285d415cbf5eff815abf9371"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an overview of the pressure tactics and influence campaigns carried out by the People’ s Republic of China in countries in Latin America and the Caribbean that maintain diplomatic relations with Taiwan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida24f5cff89154916998190f06e533fec"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the actions taken by the Department of State during the most recent 12-month period to implement this Act by—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7b9d10153aac4c0b947450aa07dadd9c"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting Taiwan’s diplomatic partners in Latin America and the Caribbean; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79d554e981cd40a591d01acbf6978919"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">countering the efforts of the People’s Republic of China to isolate Taiwan from its Latin American and Caribbean allies.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfa769372a86f4f1297b60fd09b1d0890"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Each report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id6183cb4ddd504b3c97d3adbdb97104e4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Taiwan–Americas strategic coordination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State should take steps to expand United States coordination with countries in Latin America and the Caribbean with respect to Taiwan by—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcce8071f7b514b94ad3ed74f223e2df9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinating joint programming and technical cooperation with United States allies;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08fbe652e95f49508bfbf93e9cc8d548"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">aligning public diplomacy efforts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc89c67fc066248b5935e033d7f2137a7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encouraging collaboration between United States embassies and Taiwan's representative offices in Latin America and the Caribbean.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


