<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-HEN25A68-KTS-0W-F7R"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 412 IS: Authorizing the en bloc consideration in Executive Session of certain nominations on the Executive Calendar.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><calendar>Executive Calendar No. 2</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 412</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250918" legis-day="20250916">September 18 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was ordered to lie over, under the rule</action-desc></action><legis-type>EXECUTIVE RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Authorizing the en bloc consideration in Executive Session of certain nominations on the Executive Calendar.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="OLC" display-resolving-clause="yes-display-resolving-clause" id="H6588ACF116D4487BB0EB832A8A483074"><section commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H5A8A37B616754C00BF9B72B9E5A6BF5B"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it shall be in order to move to proceed to the en bloc consideration of the following nominations on the Executive Calendar:</text><paragraph id="id6fcd88192880483589ca4ab14d5aa0b7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Calendar Number 62: Paul Atkins, of Virginia, to be a Member of the Securities and Exchange Commission for a term expiring June 5, 2031 (Reappointment).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id96a41da5e1434a9e818ba121e025c513"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Calendar Number 86: James Baehr, of Louisiana, to be General Counsel, Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfe572ca13b7e42659bab3a65564cffe6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Calendar Number 92: Patrick David Davis, of Maryland, to be an Assistant Attorney General.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id70ab4b5e11c54b98914d62625bddd21a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Calendar Number 126: Leah Campos, of Virginia, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Dominican Republic.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id285e513315f04cbf9c227c23f36b28a6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Calendar Number 127: Brandon Judd, of Idaho, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Chile.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7fe2268f0f5843ce8c359c04c6ce3f5b"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Calendar Number 128: Joseph Popolo, of Texas, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Kingdom of the Netherlands.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5ab1ad2924934508ba3fabb6f0b09d13"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Calendar Number 143: Catherine Jereza, of Maryland, to be an Assistant Secretary of Energy (Electricity).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id199b7a6b760a4325947f08aa80af967f"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Calendar Number 155: Ned Mamula, of Pennsylvania, to be Director of the United States Geological Survey.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f674cc66c0648b78adbd58e011a5739"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Calendar Number 158: David Fink, of New Hampshire, to be Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd4a135eaf0da498e8d12dde622254edc"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Calendar Number 159: Pierre Gentin, of New York, to be General Counsel of the Department of Commerce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0c369be8b4a84cfea3fb721f31479dae"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Calendar Number 160: David Fogel, of Connecticut, to be Assistant Secretary of Commerce and Director General of the United States and Foreign Commercial Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc2941849557a4dd6bc4cbff5466b020c"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Calendar Number 163: Devon Westhill, of Florida, to be an Assistant Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id808e7a45271245d8a30268e88af51ca8"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Calendar Number 164: Kirsten Baesler, of North Dakota, to be Assistant Secretary for Elementary and Secondary Education, Department of Education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd77b38b982c84c5bb611c0e0b036c692"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Calendar Number 168: Wayne Palmer, of Virginia, to be Assistant Secretary of Labor for Mine Safety and Health.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf856a6fd119345938809b9267a3914c8"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Calendar Number 169: Julie Hocker, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida4d1df56ffb54f2c9a91803b7053deea"> <enum>(16)</enum> <text>Calendar Number 170: Marco Rajkovich, Jr., of Virginia, to be a Member of the Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission for a term of 6 years expiring August 30, 2030 (Reappointment).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idbfa2f4d2ed144cfba9f00ae08252c4cc"><enum>(17)</enum><text>Calendar Number 178: John Busterud, of California, to be Assistant Administrator, Office of Solid Waste, Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddc0040e3acdf4f7a9b4f840c6567f8c5"><enum>(18)</enum><text>Calendar Number 181: Stanley Woodward, Jr., of the District of Columbia, to be Associate Attorney General.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4f6206a9e8a34547a998d815df198f1c"><enum>(19)</enum><text>Calendar Number 196: Janet Dhillon, of Virginia, to be Director of the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation for a term of 5 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida8243ddbb818465f8411b4857187ac41"><enum>(20)</enum><text>Calendar Number 252: David Keeling, of Kentucky, to be an Assistant Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2c6c16ee25be4ae0a11e37a3489f4a86"><enum>(21)</enum><text>Calendar Number 253: Kimberly Richey, of Texas, to be Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights, Department of Education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfa0ac656b7f9480599b544738b4909be"><enum>(22)</enum><text>Calendar Number 255: Jonathan Berry, of Maryland, to be Solicitor for the Department of Labor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4fe6a5d23fe64208b282be0ba322b545"><enum>(23)</enum><text>Calendar Number 256: Andrew Rogers, of Virginia, to be Administrator of the Wage and Hour Division, Department of Labor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf4832eecc2294792afda5a337a58e0b7"><enum>(24)</enum><text>Calendar Number 265: Marc Andersen, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Army.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2297af7df42d48a79b648b5e7d0188eb"><enum>(25)</enum><text>Calendar Number 268: James Woodruff II, of Florida, to be a Member of the Merit Systems Protection Board for the term of 7 years expiring March 1, 2032.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id41bc70ed98944d7d997ec245f6662419"><enum>(26)</enum><text>Calendar Number 270: Kevin Rhodes, of Florida, to be Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1d13e62400194d548aea5c3e213e7bbe"><enum>(27)</enum><text>Calendar Number 272: Usha-Maria Turner, of Oklahoma, to be an Assistant Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id34acd183fb1e47558b31caf700d23a87"><enum>(28)</enum><text>Calendar Number 275: Hung Cao, of Virginia, to be Under Secretary of the Navy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4032eea162b94befbe9388433dcf4cb4"><enum>(29)</enum><text>Calendar Number 284: John Dever, of Illinois, to be General Counsel of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide10791e964e941949b17a702d10276b4"><enum>(30)</enum><text>Calendar Number 299: Joseph Barloon, of Maryland, to be a Deputy United States Trade Representative (Geneva Office), with the rank of Ambassador.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc31e0333fdcd4ff5be49aa340939e82d"><enum>(31)</enum><text>Calendar Number 300: Brian Morrissey, Jr., of Virginia, to be General Counsel for the Department of the Treasury.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbd28197893df4590ad576318601b1242"><enum>(32)</enum><text>Calendar Number 304: Craig Trainor, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide2db92c8052648b0bd9b28095d3ef00e"><enum>(33)</enum><text>Calendar Number 306: Francis Brooke, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id697d8c5e5d15429eb3dfd0f9eb23655c"><enum>(34)</enum><text>Calendar Number 307: David Peters, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Commerce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf4a1631395114fe8ad4b6947f012deb4"><enum>(35)</enum><text>Calendar Number 310: Mary Riley, of the District of Columbia, to be Assistant Secretary for Legislation and Congressional Affairs, Department of Education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5e4e03654bb848318b8aeec7cfafc496"><enum>(36)</enum><text>Calendar Number 311: Brian Christine, of Alabama, to be an Assistant Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id52a4b893c3d54a20a147a64259bf3ee6"><enum>(37)</enum><text>Calendar Number 312: Jonathan Snare, of Virginia, to be a Member of the Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission for a term expiring April 27, 2029.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8344ba7cbde54591ac98cbf85c1bf53b"><enum>(38)</enum><text>Calendar Number 313: David Brian Castillo, of Washington, to be Chief Financial Officer, Department of Labor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcbefeedf916b4580a36602e6429e3836"><enum>(39)</enum><text>Calendar Number 314: David Barker, of Iowa, to be Assistant Secretary for Postsecondary Education, Department of Education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbf224d70f6b3460998420011e91027df"><enum>(40)</enum><text>Calendar Number 315: Brittany Panuccio, of Florida, to be a Member of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission for a term expiring July 1, 2029.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id340f71d131a640dba8a9f84457aaa61d"><enum>(41)</enum><text>Calendar Number 323: Michael Boren, of Idaho, to be Under Secretary of Agriculture for Natural Resources and Environment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9d955d745bfd42c491f2cf3192b268f7"><enum>(42)</enum><text>Calendar Number 341: Audrey Robertson, of Colorado, to be an Assistant Secretary of Energy (Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb1d19fad8c9643dd84403cb52e00e374"><enum>(43)</enum><text>Calendar Number 342: Lanny Erdos, of Ohio, to be Director of the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide50a7b079e2543bf9ae539a13cb30fdf"><enum>(44)</enum><text>Calendar Number 345: Taylor Jordan, of the District of Columbia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Commerce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0dd7b721a63140daa7598319eb6514d2"><enum>(45)</enum><text>Calendar Number 347: Derek Barrs, of Florida, to be Administrator of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3bc79a26c7d14125b433b86fa0dc9927"><enum>(46)</enum><text>Calendar Number 348: Michael Rutherford, of Florida, to be an Assistant Secretary of Transportation (New Position).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id906649141e614ef2ba2ef85a9a2e470f"><enum>(47)</enum><text>Calendar Number 349: Gregory Zerzan, of Texas, to be General Counsel of the Department of Transportation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2413787e67454b04b54045212efc9169"><enum>(48)</enum><text>Calendar Number 355: Christopher Fox, of Virginia, to be Inspector General of the Intelligence Community, Office of the Director of National Intelligence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida64fd9b6526e42988b74fca1416624be"><enum>(49)</enum><text>Calendar Number 357: Alex Adams, of Idaho, to be Assistant Secretary for Family Support, Department of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide31f3837bb94449fbc826963409672b0"><enum>(50)</enum><text>Calendar Number 358: Jonathan McKernan, of Tennessee, to be an Under Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id03d6d2c684194b9a867eca0ee065526d"><enum>(51)</enum><text>Calendar Number 359: Macon Hughes, of Texas, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbfd462bdeab9495c9590bb1bd7b7377d"><enum>(52)</enum><text>Calendar Number 360: Philip Weinberg, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Air Force.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb1bb2930eeb34ab4bd2e4ed4f8f5986e"><enum>(53)</enum><text>Calendar Number 361: Timothy John Walsh, of Colorado, to be an Assistant Secretary of Energy (Environmental Management).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d7b81c05ef14e179ba97e73adfefd57"><enum>(54)</enum><text>Calendar Number 363: Gustav Chiarello III, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3adda6f806c240d0ad4faec2635ec93d"><enum>(55)</enum><text>Calendar Number 364: Michael Stuart, of West Virginia, to be General Counsel of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida94f36ee7ad347f896039a43ab518b73"><enum>(56)</enum><text>Calendar Number 367: William Kirkland, of Georgia, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc1ae920659894af3ae0d88ca941086ab"><enum>(57)</enum><text>Calendar Number 368: Laura Swett, of Virginia, to be a Member of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission for a term expiring June 30, 2030.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id76fa613c4fdb4283bb207af3fc76cbf5"><enum>(58)</enum><text>Calendar Number 369: David LaCerte, of Louisiana, to be a Member of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission for the remainder of the term expiring June 30, 2026.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6b5ec5dacb394584822f2c9269791d46"><enum>(59)</enum><text>Calendar Number 374: Arch Capito, of West Virginia, to be United States Attorney for the Southern District of West Virginia for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2e2cae1e8323410d8922851176cd2d29"><enum>(60)</enum><text>Calendar Number 375: David Dunavant, of Tennessee, to be United States Attorney for the Western District of Tennessee for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id813b1f2354ff4e04b2f1cb4bf48aa6e5"><enum>(61)</enum><text>Calendar Number 376: Matthew Harvey, of West Virginia, to be United States Attorney for the Northern District of West Virginia for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd27b20ba1e724ba1978edeed66b78b26"><enum>(62)</enum><text>Calendar Number 377: John Heekin, of Florida, to be United States Attorney for the Northern District of Florida for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4e0a03a2ee504a01a72ea178cc4c731e"><enum>(63)</enum><text>Calendar Number 378: Leif Olson, of Iowa, to be United States Attorney for the Northern District of Iowa for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc603542d0ad94a34a43ee648b2da5138"><enum>(64)</enum><text>Calendar Number 379: Adam Sleeper, of the Virgin Islands, to be United States Attorney for the District of the Virgin Islands for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf0bab0c3781d4c34820bbfa2fde083d8"><enum>(65)</enum><text>Calendar Number 380: David Toepfer, of Ohio, to be United States Attorney for the Northern District of Ohio for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3cd78e0f455446ed9b053e1b6a740ea4"><enum>(66)</enum><text>Calendar Number 381: Kurt Alme, of Montana, to be United States Attorney for the District of Montana, for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id289fe739a00c473e884a55391d18e046"><enum>(67)</enum><text>Calendar Number 382: Nicholas Chase, of North Dakota, to be United States Attorney for the District of North Dakota for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id00c3eb7730ed426aabc8b62da3d4fce4"><enum>(68)</enum><text>Calendar Number 383: Bart McKay Davis, of Idaho, to be United States Attorney for the District of Idaho for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida712b11ac3954a8fa397cbafa8715080"><enum>(69)</enum><text>Calendar Number 384: David Metcalf, of Pennsylvania, to be United States Attorney for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0c3c9a7e63924fe598c6d8c88a0bb687"><enum>(70)</enum><text>Calendar Number 385: Lesley Murphy, of Nebraska, to be United States Attorney for the District of Nebraska for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf7ab6736fd2b4e9aa39ea7d235fb2b18"><enum>(71)</enum><text>Calendar Number 386: Ronald A. Parsons, Jr., of South Dakota, to be United States Attorney for the District of South Dakota for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id392c6b59373246778f1a90a82ba29da3"><enum>(72)</enum><text>Calendar Number 387: Kurt Wall, of Louisiana, to be United States Attorney for the Middle District of Louisiana for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddf9284bb875d4f8d87ca608df62d3da6"><enum>(73)</enum><text>Calendar Number 388: David Charles Waterman, of Iowa, to be United States Attorney for the Southern District of Iowa for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb56f0f5c7c074a309413058a3f75d4df"><enum>(74)</enum><text>Calendar Number 389: Daniel Rosen, of Florida, to be United States Attorney for the District of Minnesota for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id60d797de328f456daa26c169f6cc4513"><enum>(75)</enum><text>Calendar Number 391: Somers Farkas, of New York, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Malta.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1abd8a31e73b415b85a00e4693aa5dc3"><enum>(76)</enum><text>Calendar Number 392: Nicole McGraw, of Florida, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Croatia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id608f9b5c9f6241c0906a97f9c989b34b"><enum>(77)</enum><text>Calendar Number 393: Leandro Rizzuto, of Florida, to be Permanent Representative of the United States of America to the Organization of American States, with the rank of Ambassador.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida427ede992e04499bf689729c103041d"><enum>(78)</enum><text>Calendar Number 394: Herschel Walker, of Georgia, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Commonwealth of The Bahamas.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id73c50e699a91473c8a51d1dc2e5e62f5"><enum>(79)</enum><text>Calendar Number 395: Stacey Feinberg, of California, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Grand Duchy of Luxembourg.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5db4ed09ddac4aad8f484af82329b531"><enum>(80)</enum><text>Calendar Number 396: Kenneth Howery, of Texas, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Kingdom of Denmark.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida62bdf30094d49eea96103276f019036"><enum>(81)</enum><text>Calendar Number 397: Richard Buchan III, of Florida, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Kingdom of Morocco.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id854029ea0fc3482ba71ba0862a9119bb"><enum>(82)</enum><text>Calendar Number 398: Bill Bazzi, of Michigan, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Tunisia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id27fa4956e1ef4121b975884f19e87e93"><enum>(83)</enum><text>Calendar Number 399: Lynda Blanchard, of Alabama, to be U.S. Representative to the United Nations Agencies for Food and Agriculture, with the rank of Ambassador.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc2117e1479054d7fbbcbc64eb4e94533"><enum>(84)</enum><text>Calendar Number 400: Howard Brodie, of Florida, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Finland.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2d82076f8097421aa966515bd56305a4"><enum>(85)</enum><text>Calendar Number 401: Arthur Fisher, of North Carolina, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Austria.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id20f618e1ecd84afeb8a0a3f65a0222f5"><enum>(86)</enum><text>Calendar Number 402: Melinda Hildebrand, of Texas, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Costa Rica.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf3ad95bb6de24a38b76950720823fb66"><enum>(87)</enum><text>Calendar Number 403: Michel Issa, of Florida, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Lebanese Republic.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3464b4817584467ab2fd0bf6758d71be"><enum>(88)</enum><text>Calendar Number 404: Nicholas Merrick, of Texas, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Czech Republic.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idca38c2b61aa04e4fa1389d88861dc4e5"><enum>(89)</enum><text>Calendar Number 405: Roman Pipko, of Florida, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Estonia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4de6448bfadf4ef0bd9b6a0ac2d01779"><enum>(90)</enum><text>Calendar Number 406: Thomas Rose, of Florida, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Poland.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id64f83218722b401e83344b5756b15446"><enum>(91)</enum><text>Calendar Number 407: William White, of New York, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Kingdom of Belgium.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idef1f03c8715043808fb22d09b6f5e08d"><enum>(92)</enum><text>Calendar Number 408: John Giordano, of Pennsylvania, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Namibia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd9921ceb43db40a1854974dc219f092e"><enum>(93)</enum><text>Calendar Number 409: Anjani Sinha, of Florida, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Singapore.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd7e348bbb434442298cd6ea5f7fe2801"><enum>(94)</enum><text>Calendar Number 411: Sean O'Neill, of Virginia, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Kingdom of Thailand.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7a98cf55ca2840ff8494c979bee85822"><enum>(95)</enum><text>Calendar Number 412: Julie Stufft, of Ohio, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Kazakhstan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id771d57ae183749d1869c89a53325570a"><enum>(96)</enum><text>Calendar Number 413: Dan Negrea, of Connecticut, to be Representative of the United States of America on the Economic and Social Council of the United Nations, with the rank of Ambassador, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as an Alternate Representative of the United States of America to the Sessions of the General Assembly of the United Nations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc1cdbac9dab849abb1149de7cedc4edf"><enum>(97)</enum><text>Calendar Number 414: Sergio Gor, of Florida, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of India.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb4e7758cdd144f0286e0b803ee67cbf8"><enum>(98)</enum><text>Calendar Number 415: Stephanie Hallett, of Florida, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Kingdom of Bahrain.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf18d00ac3e214458895b43e5b1b29b74"><enum>(99)</enum><text>Calendar Number 416: James Holtsnider, of Iowa, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3bb6ea0546984f74a2d055eab14f73bb"><enum>(100)</enum><text>Calendar Number 417: Jacob Helberg, of Florida, to be an Under Secretary of State (Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4fe1a3a4d9964dda9b3eae15b569ea0c"><enum>(101)</enum><text>Calendar Number 418: Benjamin Black, of New York, to be Chief Executive Officer of the United States International Development Finance Corporation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf9f09cc2fc6449278d298e0d0e8c2637"><enum>(102)</enum><text>Calendar Number 419: Thomas DiNanno, of Florida, to be Under Secretary of State for Arms Control and International Security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id44a8de87320d4a2ab13344673b54f33d"><enum>(103)</enum><text>Calendar Number 420: Paul Kapur, of California, to be Assistant Secretary of State for South Asian Affairs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id31fa222386db43c7baecfbc450ab6c9b"><enum>(104)</enum><text>Calendar Number 423: Sarah Rogers, of New York, to be Under Secretary of State for Public Diplomacy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb2b23c6ae95f46f8824acbdc3e19c4a6"><enum>(105)</enum><text>Calendar Number 424: Michael DeSombre, of Illinois, to be an Assistant Secretary of State (East Asian and Pacific Affairs).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddcd80c2fccba4f4598a681c6bcf18ba8"><enum>(106)</enum><text>Calendar Number 426: Riley Barnes, of Texas, to be an Assistant Secretary of State (Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id568f44192b0b43f69e8ef2562d4988fa"><enum>(107)</enum><text>Calendar Number 427: Todd Wilcox, of Florida, to be an Assistant Secretary of State (Diplomatic Security).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b94ea24cefe4a7c90470846b7118780" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(108)</enum><text>Calendar Number 428: Neil Jacobs, of North Carolina, to be Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

