<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MUR25435-C47-S1-80X"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2050 IS: Advancing Student Services In Schools Today Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2050</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Social Security Act to provide for an increased Federal medical assistance percentage for State expenditures on certain behavioral health services furnished under the Medicaid program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HD36A1C3412024BE6BCA5440B8784C0B5"><section section-type="section-one" id="HEE82A8529D9145C8AD4336DC4E6A9918"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advancing Student Services In Schools Today Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ASSIST Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H211ACA289BCF4463B4F215C1B927A732"><enum>2.</enum><header>Increasing the applicable FMAP for State expenditures attributable to certain behavioral health services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1905 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HD62BA33D1E014471A9B12000DBC9B78D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>and (ii)</quote> and inserting <quote>(ii), and (kk)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0854AB9E4228428E8FB6A7DE3AA24FAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="idB2FDF3EA78B94F55AFFD091D0BC8D60A" act-name=""><subsection id="id6FFC83E3C2464DC5AD1F9B7080363047"> <enum>(kk)</enum> <header>Increased FMAP for medical assistance for services furnished by mental health and substance use disorder care providers in certain school-Based settings</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8e863f32930f44bb82088f863bf6eb74"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header> <text>Notwithstanding any preceding provision of this section, with respect to State expenditures for medical assistance consisting of services provided by a mental health and substance use disorder care provider (as defined in section 3 of the <short-title>Advancing Student Services In Schools Today Act</short-title>) and furnished at a school or at a school-based health center (as defined in section 399Z–1(a)(3) of the Public Health Service Act) on or after the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning on or after the date that is 12 months after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Federal medical assistance percentage otherwise determined under subsection (b) shall, subject to paragraph (2), be equal to 90 percent.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="id9660a172149442429ee791876d59fe41">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Application of higher match</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply in the case of State expenditures described in such paragraph if application of such paragraph would result in a lower Federal medical assistance percentage for such expenditures than would otherwise apply without application of such paragraph.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="idd30d1c55555b47a1a9b0a816e036d081">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <header>Exclusion of expenditures from territorial cap</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any payment made to a territory for expenditures for medical assistance described in paragraph (1) that are subject to the Federal medical assistance percentage specified under such paragraph shall not be taken into account for purposes of applying payment limits under subsections (f) and (g) of section 1108 to the extent that such payment exceeds the amount of the payment that would have been made to the territory for such expenditures without regard to this subsection.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H7BB841007072412B845B8C5F28C9F19C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Program to increase mental health and substance use disorder care providers in schools and school-based health centers</header><subsection commented="no" id="H68B8F1626F1F4132938CA4C8E403B161">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
 <text>Congress finds that the lack of access to mental health and substance use disorder care in schools and school-based health centers has a negative impact on the health of children in the United States, including children who are eligible for coverage under the Medicaid and Children's Health Insurance Program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc6721cdbe2d04657bac6ac102a1b1b00"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grant authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the <term>Secretary</term>), in consultation with the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services and the Secretary of Education, shall award grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to eligible entities to increase the number of mental health and substance use disorder care providers in schools and school-based health centers served by such entities.</text></subsection><subsection id="H25733F031E3E4BFB8FEECBCAE0C62126"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity seeking an award under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including a description of—</text><paragraph id="H2336774886EE431D938634CA0115CAB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the mental health and substance use disorder needs of the student population served by the eligible entity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1B456C7AF2843FBBF2E66705CD48855"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the student population served by the eligible entity, how the eligible entity will ensure that the mental health and substance use disorder care providers supported by the eligible entity, and the services administered by such providers, are culturally competent and linguistically appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H93843D892977413BB0F2A4813D529FFC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Restriction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds made available through an award under this section may be used for a threat assessment team.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0856BEA17F5845489EDC026DF35C3222"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting</header><paragraph id="H014582C82A1946F99E5DB5E89407D820"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligible entities receiving an award under this section shall submit an annual report to the Secretary accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require, including—</text><subparagraph id="HA0BBF12325F74CB49658C77043C99378"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of mental health and substance use disorder care providers working at the schools or school-based health centers served by the eligible entity, and the number of such providers supported through the award;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA107F9D549264ECEB16C509A968CB9C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the types of services provided by the mental health and substance use disorder care providers and the efficacy of such services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB4088421EFE24892AECC0C1F5ACB1615"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the practices used by the schools or school-based health centers served by the eligible entity to recruit and retain mental health and substance use disorder care providers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45E063BA66B44E6591470E7A4C105C48"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the rates of retention of mental health and substance use disorder care providers at the school or school-based health center.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H96884A4B80B8419994986F7DC4BCF969"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this section, and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the effectiveness of the awards under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF6B4FC2D5699474EB9A9170DE934D548"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H0CF337616E154AD7BE91BDEC2634BB5C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8226A5E8CDE54A7897E892405BDA2C17"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a local educational agency, as defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE65E273846A04A50B7FDA5FD8F444DF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an institution of higher education, as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2111A751C6624091B8F585E71CE3FDC9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a school operated by the Bureau of Indian Affairs; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB3F22900B6E43338DAB58905B0A8068"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a school-based health center, as defined in section 399Z–1(a)(3) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280h-5">42 U.S.C. 280h–5(a)(3)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD9A1105E6D46406F8A6EEEC65BF93F8A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mental health and substance use disorder care provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>mental health and substance use disorder care provider</term> means an individual who is licensed or credentialed to provide mental health and substance use disorder services, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H735431BC85AC4439B61246BCEF6C67AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a school counselor;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA1F870444C0A4BFD978BBBE0E24216A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a school psychologist or any other psychologist;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1B9AC70CFB954997BC024C96AFF385C6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a psychiatrist who specializes in child or adolescent psychiatry;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8542A93A9D8405CA029E5028245FAF6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a school social worker;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3461D73B5A9436D8BB3C9EC0ECDFCF4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a peer support specialist or peer recovery coach;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC1142EE59ED649DC87840F73257E5E48"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a licensed clinical social worker;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddeb6fd0630e446c28555b017c7f10bed"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an addiction medicine specialist; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id92b0b6687f4e4b78b2fdb1673a693609"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other providers, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

