<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H96D6D5557A3F4F2CB90284C445C9D3BF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4995 IH: Enduring Welcome Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4995</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250819">August 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To modify the responsibilities of the Coordinator for Afghan Relocation Efforts, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEE2E3EB6DBF946D083B64498C97B6EA7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE8AA33CC94D94DA89E833A44985D970D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Enduring Welcome Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFC3BD33FB62E4F94BADB67BB6B684C05"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7130221857A342349609B71867E97AB3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Enduring Welcome program is the safest, most secure legal immigration pathway to the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C15462BDB924851A20611DF0A0C5713"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The resettlement of Afghan allies in the Special Immigrant Visa (SIV) and the United States Refugee Admissions Program (USRAP) P1/P2 pipelines is critical to upholding United States credibility and incentivizing future support for United States servicemembers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD98B49BC57D4D43875BAB04B092E097"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Failing to reunite active-duty United States military personnel and veterans with their Afghan family members in the Afghan relocation pipeline is harmful to the United States servicemember community.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H754E7CE1170D4AF1B02D42C18099FECE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A review conducted by Department of Justice’s Office of Inspector General released on June 10, 2025, concluded that the process for vetting applicants for Afghan SIVs is rigorous and effective in protecting United States national security.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1ACFB01B9491481997D44346DD15D66B"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The permanent authorization of the Coordinator for Afghan Relocation Efforts (CARE) under section 7810 of the Servicemember Quality of Life Improvement and National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/159">Public Law 118–159</external-xref>) reflects a bipartisan commitment to fulfilling wartime promises and ensuring accountability in United States relocation policy.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H50695F2673794BB8BF64EE9D21FD25E1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Office of the Coordinator for Afghan Relocation Efforts</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7810 of the Servicemember Quality of Life Improvement and National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/159">Public Law 118–159</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H15BF9E08C8864B019FB1B47607BE4CE7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H335FBA671C11404680D47D416E385887"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">of coordinator</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H729A3D07F7394E48869D8F2B21651878"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="HC9C6417C823345F8A4C95917918F8640"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting before <quote>The Secretary</quote> the following: <quote>The Secretary shall establish an Office of the Coordinator for Afghan Relocation Efforts in the Department of State.</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H48E467D1C8694DD0BFF2C58FFE5A6CAA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting before <quote>who shall be responsible for</quote> the following: <quote>who shall be the head of the Office of the Coordinator for Afghan Relocation Efforts, and</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF3F5811059D0407899AD69D1E150F2CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c), (d), and (e) as subsections (d), (e), and (f), respectively; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCCE44A10001B48D1A59A53250907EE3C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0EBA1408E8874CDFA68126D1545E8D1D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HF6779347701F4BAB883F938A4522B035"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Coordinator shall be responsible for—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5F34D02BD565430499B8DA46F99B48B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supporting the voluntary departure of covered persons who request assistance departing Afghanistan;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H326DBE35DA39421293EC8EE4B916424C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>leading coordination of interagency efforts relating to vetting, security screening, and case processing of eligible Afghan allies in the Department of State, in coordination with the Department of Homeland Security and the Department of Defense;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1DA5E4D5343748A3A809B345648D656C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>facilitating relocation and resettlement logistics in coordination with resettlement support centers and United States-based resettlement agencies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H13C4367E28C5404AB2E6E32E0BB55A11"><enum>(4)</enum><text>addressing family reunification barriers, including cases involving United States active-duty servicemembers and veterans;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H02EDD795FD2140EDB54ED11C27BD474C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>coordinating integration support, including trauma recovery and medical care, with other Federal agencies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA773238034C40B4A4DFE0588B9541A7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>maintaining and analyzing a centralized, secure database of Afghan applicants, beneficiaries, and relocated individuals to inform operations and ensure transparency; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD9BBAC43B32F4B6BB545492D83CF3795"><enum>(7)</enum><text>providing timely information to Congress on the status of Afghan relocation efforts and progress made under this mandate.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="H6AF1E7FB692547FC9A7EC64473B360E8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Collection of information and database</header> <subsection id="H62EA3105688B4E26AFE2F9F6CD4AADDE" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Collection of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Coordinator shall collect information on Afghan applicants, beneficiaries, and relocated individuals to inform operations and ensure transparency, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H94F7F35474124AEE9CF3CA8282453BCD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of Afghan nationals pursuing admission to the United States as a special immigrant under section 602 of the Afghan Allies Protection Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> note), as a refugee under section 207 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref>) (whether as priority one or priority 2), or as a parolee under section 212(d)(5)(A) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(d)(5)(A)</external-xref>), disaggregated by whether they are in Afghanistan, the United States, or a third country;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H757BDD274AAA44EA8337FF6A7254C7CD" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of family reunification cases pending, approved, and completed;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H42C04C4D3173467FB59CED0913B3151E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the average time between application, vetting, relocation, and resettlement;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H18660366053247B4A54BB58603CF4D8B" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the number of individuals who have been denied or administratively closed out, and the reason for such actions;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB04839786F194BFF9C004D64FC2CBD21" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the number of active-duty United States military and veteran-linked cases involving family separation; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1EA5FEF8FE0543B7A848F19A650C2DE1" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary of State or Coordinator for Afghan Relocation Efforts may prescribe.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H22770AF825414F01A9C68E861495457A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Database</header> 
<paragraph id="HE695A27DDF9B4C8B956E5A5932564858"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State shall establish and maintain a secure, centralized database to maintain the information collected pursuant to subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H216D50FE92544C7FA507F7E566319A51"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The information in the database established pursuant to this subsection may be in classified form to the extent necessary but such information shall be usable for operational reporting, oversight, coordination across relevant Federal departments and agencies, and regular reporting to Congress.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H98DECC676113445BB29D8A52AFF655F1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is 30 days after the date on which the database required by this subsection is established, and every 90 days thereafter, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the status of each metric with respect to information that is being collected pursuant to subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC13A5EB4A54B46838E9DD2FFFDC3E31E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on and after the date specified in section 7(a), the Secretary of State shall continue to maintain this database required by this section unless the Secretary, with prior consultation with the appropriate congressional committees, provides notification to the appropriate congressional committees that shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0936255CD39C406CB909AA8FE5047E75"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of covered persons with pending relocation cases or appeals before the United States Government; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB34729B6D9984B9CA49670EE56F9E54D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the estimated population of eligible covered persons which remains to be resettled.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD37D3AECAA184A98829F4C64B4A3BDF6"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H8384EC0BBA124A09909AFC03A96A9E11"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H567173B4FF3949EEB0B0D0B7E6954FFB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H79734ADF585447C295EFE46042ED45DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4B1A5EA7C5A44F94BCF58F4968B91477"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordinator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Coordinator</term> means the Coordinator for Afghan Relocation Efforts appointed pursuant to section 3(a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H23A8889A71F94C24AB77DFBDCAF23878" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered person</header><text>The term <term>covered person</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1DF2B6FAF68940C6B5FFD2BC82B6909E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAC3ED2E364EF4843A187E0D92F569C3A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an immediate relative (as such term is described in section 201(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151</external-xref>)) with respect to whom a petition has been approved and all required documents have been received;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBF415756F3E64610889A29D4F6138319" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an alien who has been admitted to the United States as a lawful permanent resident;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H69B558CDBEA1439CA51B205BD3322DD3" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a spouse or unmarried child under the age of 21 of an alien described in subparagraph (C) with respect to whom a petition has been approved, all required documents have been received, and who has a current priority date as of the date on which the individual seeks assistance from the Coordinator;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF24852F5A65E4C8BBE94E219815C5C9F" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a principal applicant for special immigrant status under section 602 of the Afghan Allies Protection Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> note);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H580750729333432BB100815C3D83925D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a spouse or unmarried child under the age of 21 of an alien described in subparagraph (E) who has been issued a visa or with respect to whom the Chief of Mission has approved their application, and with respect to whom all documents have been received;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD9012CA56DCF4853A97516EE1AA0BEE0" commented="no">
                    <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an alien who has been approved to be admitted to the United States as a refugee or spouse or unmarried child under the age of 21 (as of August 14, 2021) of such an alien;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCCA216DE3A9C4C24866E45CA27044A1E" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a spouse or an unmarried child under the age of 21 of an alien admitted to the United States pursuant to the Operations Allies Welcome program (or any successor program); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCC751A4465684CF3A10425387340C02B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the primary caregiver of a surviving child described in section 602(b)(2)(C) of the Afghan Allies Protection Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> note), or a spouse or an unmarried child under the age of 21 of such a primary caregiver.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H479CEF1FF0E44E788EDD0BE6A93FF187" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Sunset</header> 
<subsection id="H3EA14FFE571D47A1B7B17727ED0E4F62" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in section 4(c), this Act and the authorities provided by this Act shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H22D751D427FF45FB93F1B9753CBF4D82" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (f) of section 7810 of the Servicemember Quality of Life Improvement and National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/159">Public Law 118–159</external-xref>), as redesignated by section 3, is amended by striking <quote>3</quote> and inserting <quote>5</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

