<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV25889-XRT-FF-59L">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1780 IS: Mexico Security Assistance Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 1780</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250515">May 15, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on
                    Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To provide for congressional oversight of security assistance to Mexico, and
            for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mexico Security Assistance Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id2c83de330be247f89283f2f7909b0440">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Strategy for United States security assistance to Mexico</header>
            <subsection id="id750c46735e7b4fb1b1d8b692c2348d76">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a report with a strategy for United States security assistance to Mexico.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id9312f0efba8c4c3eaac291b807274f54">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Strategy elements</header>
 <text>The strategy required under subsection (a) shall include the following elements:</text>
                <paragraph id="idca15adda8c034f2b91e656497c38123a">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>A detailed plan for how United States security assistance will—</text> <subparagraph id="id2aa587e8591b4f2a927e289e7858b98f"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>dismantle transnational criminal networks that traffic illicit drugs, including fentanyl, into the United States and profit from other criminal activities, including pervasive human trafficking and human smuggling;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id152f6722eb7d4728b74431fbebb88de7">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>increase the capacity of Mexico’s military and public security institutions to improve security at Mexico’s northern and southern borders and degrade transnational criminal organizations; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idec17adccba6d4c49b1724d004cb7f423">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>enhance the institutional capacity of civilian law enforcement, prosecutors, and courts to strengthen rule of law, redress public corruption, and combat impunity.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id01382b899b5c4427b8f67ff4b0b8c639">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>A detailed summary of activities to implement the plan described in paragraph (1), including a list of implementing government entities and nongovernmental organizations.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id6554f8ccd5db4d5ca2b25a49ba73e4b8">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>A detailed summary of priorities, milestones, and performance measures to monitor and evaluate results of the strategy.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="id5737909ded204f19b04568790bcbb56b">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Bilateral cooperation reporting</header>
 <text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include an overview of bilateral cooperation mechanisms and engagements between the United States Government and the Government of Mexico, such as diplomatic engagements, security assistance programs, technical assistance, and other forms of cooperation that advance the priorities described in subsection (b).</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85be50a3df9a45419e43dcb29c84e047">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Form</header>
 <text>The report and strategy required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id2d33358859f744f895641201f8c1eec1">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Briefing</header>
 <text>Not later than 1 year after the submission of the report and strategy required under subsection (a), and annually thereafter, the Secretary of State shall provide to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a briefing on the implementation of the strategy.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

