<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H884DABA5E9934702AAA82DB0B33880C4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1802 IH: Safeguard Pets, Animals, and Research Ethics Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1802</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250303">March 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001314">Mr. Bean of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the use of animals in federally funded research, promote the adoption of humane and scientifically advanced alternatives, and ensure the ethical rehoming of retired research animals, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAEAA3BBAC1074E80B49E973732513E7B" style="OLC"><section id="HA34A3D2C464B4B48BB8F9133C3ACAFA8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safeguard Pets, Animals, and Research Ethics Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SPARE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6450983549D44B0291C2A7F8617941C3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H87C2144D98F940DC9D89DB2C006DC0C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Tens of millions of animals are used annually in federally funded research, including dogs, cats, rabbits, primates, and other species.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96B8ABB3CE35489CB0320A4232A572FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Many of these animals cost thousands of tax dollars each, burdening taxpayers with billions of dollars annually in inefficient and unnecessary research costs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5259F80C64A46E4B066320FAE8CD800"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Modern non-animal research alternatives, such as human-cell-based models, artificial intelligence, and organ-on-chip technology, provide more reliable and ethical research methods.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CA1B613C3C94678A14891CAEFED445D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The continued use of animals in federally funded research contradicts existing Three Rs (Reduce, Refine, Replace) policy goals aimed at reducing reliance on animal models.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEB5592859A14F908605D59DB0D990EA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Many animals used in federally funded research are viable for adoption or sanctuary placement upon the cessation of experiments.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H73EC7EE14F884FED856C55B154AA2BDE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on certain research, testing, and experimentation that utilizes an animal</header><subsection id="H5B991C1A277C489D879208BDE353EBF5" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in this section, a Federal department, Federal agency, Federal contractor, subcontractor, or grantee may not authorize, obligate or expend funds for, or otherwise engage in research, testing, and experimentation that utilizes an animal.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC2952C81067242A9A4A0F778D13048C0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions and penalties</header><paragraph id="HB490FDEE15B1462EAD641892823262C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal contractor, subcontractor, or grantee that violates subsection (a) or subsection (f)(1) shall be subject to a civil penalty in an amount of not more than $250,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2A2F522D72D427FB651445DA29C76DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sanctions</header><subparagraph id="H7007F276AE714B31A4D2996505207719"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Federal departments and agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary of Agriculture or the Director of the National Institutes of Health determines that a Federal department or agency has violated subsection (a) or subsection (f)(1), such department or agency shall implement a plan, which may include a reporting requirement, prescribed by such Secretary or Director, as the case may be, to correct the violation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0537E35EB9644A8A9C05CA1632AEBF67"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Federal contractors, subcontractors, and grantees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if the Secretary of Agriculture or the Director of the National Institutes of Health determines, after reasonable notice and opportunity for a hearing, that a Federal contractor, subcontractor, or grantee has violated subsection (a) or subsection (f)(1), such contractor, subcontractor, or grantee may be prohibited from receiving, for a period of time specified by such Secretary or Director, as the case may be, a Federal grant for research, testing, and experimentation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H275AE3FE32684D4AA01901E51FACF709"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Delayed application</header><paragraph id="H9CD416B7CE484AC394663FD4196DA999"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eighteen months</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to research, testing, and experimentation that utilizes an animal and relates to cosmetic testing, toxicity testing, or basic psychological or behavioral experimenting, subsection (a) shall not apply until 18 months after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A4DFADEC7104D3C88844994D122FB27"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Three years</header><text>With respect to research, testing, and experimentation that utilizes an animal and relates to biomedical experimenting or drug testing, subsection (a) shall not apply until three years after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA11CEF6BFE91449E9C81B0B73A145763"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="H2234BF6C01944DD2BB668C75CE2E13F8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certain veterinary research or animals</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to research, testing, and experimentation that utilizes an animal and relates to any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HB508F2BCA61F4CB4A24437B24EBA4945"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Clinical veterinary research.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04EE61F629D7435FAEEFA4D893A8BFF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A physical exam, training program, or study relating to a military animal or service animal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAACE6EA4DE94DA9935397849022A109"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Congressional authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal department, Federal agency, Federal contractor, subcontractor, or grantee may authorize, obligate or expend funds for, or otherwise engage in research, testing, and experimentation that utilizes an animal if the following requirements are satisfied:</text><subparagraph id="HFB0443950AD7421B8F7A2DA4E358A6E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of such department, agency, contractor, subcontractor, or grantee submits to Congress an application that states the following:</text><clause id="H332D3CA898BC4C1EBA57571769E10556"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Such research, testing, and experimentation would relate to an infectious disease or national security.</text></clause><clause id="H024125687ACA4E2C99C4FCF6286FD84F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Such research, testing, and experimentation would utilize such animal sparingly.</text></clause><clause id="HF2FDF2E2FDFA448390674EC6D1F0F7DE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Such head has determined that an alternative does not exist for such research, testing, and experimentation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB80117042E64B7F8E2369712BD07DBD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>After Congress receives the application described in subparagraph (A), Congress enacts a joint resolution that authorizes such research, testing, and experimentation for a period of not more than one year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1681373D7F8947CDBD58E2C50BFDD06F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal Research Modernization Fund</header><paragraph id="H30202715F11D432DB2ECF4B87E97C828"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal Research Modernization Fund (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Fund</quote>) is established in the National Science Foundation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48EEEFC29CBC4453A1DDC4E8A54D356B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Director of the National Science Foundation, through the Fund, shall carry out the following:</text><subparagraph id="HE582B2EBC7BD4C64ADF28CA6EFA672D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establish a program to award grants on a competitive basis to transition research, testing, and experimentation that utilizes an animal to research, testing, and experimentation that does not utilize an animal, and not less than one grant under such program shall be awarded to a non-profit rescue or rehabilitation organization.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3752E98CF7D34CBEB51D50C79259FA13"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For Federal contractors engaging in research, testing, and experimentation that utilizes an animal, offer training to such contractors to transition such research, testing, and experimentation to research, testing, and experimentation that does not utilize an animal.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00B305DB866F4534AD7E6FAF8283D62B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establish a program to facilitate collaboration between entities to expedite any transition of research, testing, and experimentation that utilizes an animal to research, testing, and experimentation that does not utilize an animal.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75662404A70B46559053A621FF1F0E75"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establish a program to support the validation and standardization of research, testing, and experimentation that does not utilize an animal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDBDF22E6CBD54F08B084648362D22B17"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Animal release program</header><paragraph id="HD7D1AEEAD03E4076ADC54E1191DE9889"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any federally funded research facility that has utilized an animal for research, testing, and experimentation prohibited under this section shall carry out the following:</text><subparagraph id="H28450E8FF032482EA798C981DDC0571C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, establish a program to release each such animal to any of the following:</text><clause id="H05B37565F02A4173B20BBD872178AB34"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An animal rescue organization.</text></clause><clause id="H5E80CEF38DB14C5FB4BD2ACFFDB07DD1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An accredited sanctuary.</text></clause><clause id="HFE74769CD1A6424384A45DFA42C81A8A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A licensed animal shelter.</text></clause><clause id="H4901A0CD666F40FC83A6595A0AFD07F8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>An individual eligible to receive such animal.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0ABB7CBCF8DA499880236E114A1BADE4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program described in subparagraph (A), consult with an accredited sanctuary or a specialist in animal behavioral rehabilitation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D218E3278A04AF795E2770A809DD1B8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Before releasing such animal pursuant to such subparagraph, receive from a licensed veterinarian a certification that states such animal is suitable for release.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAAE7F91ABFC4709B36C11856EB7B9BE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Not later than 16 months after the date of the enactment of this section and quarterly thereafter, submit to the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service of the Department of Agriculture and the Office of Laboratory Animal Welfare of the National Institutes of Health information relating to the number of animals released pursuant to such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H41BBC6A85C2649C4A617DAFF14A9DE55"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public database</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 20 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Agriculture and the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall jointly develop, maintain not less than quarterly, and make publicly available a database on each animal released pursuant such program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF56664C4AD734641B06D4F9E5E06E36B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Audits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section and annually thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States, in consultation with the personnel of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service of the Department of Agriculture and the Office of Laboratory Animal Welfare of the National Institutes of Health, shall carry out the following:</text><paragraph id="H6B196ED519CA45CEA8F5CD9E4810CFD0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Audit each Federal department, Federal agency, Federal contractor, subcontractor, or grantee for compliance with this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B74ECAD4FCD4A90B7C4036B47E8E398"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Submit a report to Congress on the compliance of each such department, agency, contractor, subcontractor, or grantee with this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD1B0EB7BB6A6407F84350C3CA8A9AAAC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Congressional hearings</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this section and annually thereafter, each House of Congress shall hold a hearing on the annual report submitted under subsection (g).</text></subsection><subsection id="H9174F96CD7274CB4B9536C0AC1503665"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Conflict</header><text>If a conflict exists between the Animal Welfare Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2131">7 U.S.C. 2131 et seq.</external-xref>), or the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/301">21 U.S.C. 301 et seq.</external-xref>), and this section, this section shall apply.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0F082E6F06B545C182C207D85A305E9F"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HEC0C4E18333640EE873359D0D859B73F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Accredited sanctuary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>accredited sanctuary</term> means a facility or organization that satisfies the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="H70062E242E4D4D02AD39B79360059749"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Provides lifetime care and shelter to animals.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF837911DD2644B97A24AB4252D27A614"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Maintains animals in a protective environment without engaging in breeding, commercial trade, or for-profit public exhibition.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57F58F7DDBB64D61BDDFA4CFC0455578"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Possesses an accreditation by a nationally recognized accrediting body, such as the Global Federation of Animal Sanctuaries, or another entity designated by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7245D991B4A4B6D9E318F946B0755E2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Adheres to standards of animal care, including adequate housing, nutrition, and veterinary attention, verified through periodic reviews conducted as a condition of such accreditation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F48A656AA9B4C07A2D70407F5C6E5D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Animal</header><text>The term <term>animal</term> means a living or dead dog, cat, non-human primate, guinea pig, hamster, rabbit, or other warm-blooded animal that the Secretary of Agriculture designates as being used, or intended to be used, for research, testing, and experimentation, exhibition, or as a pet.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71F6B249A62445628053AFF4C407F501"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Animal rescue organization</header><text>The term <term>animal rescue organization</term> means an organization that satisfies the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="HB77C53EC80EF4B57861045B4D8BD20F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Is described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF63D1DF683AC4C9F892627891AE61200"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Is primarily dedicated to the rescue, rehabilitation, and placement of animals into adoptive homes or other suitable environments, including with respect to the following:</text><clause id="H19C810C3FD7645F6932C9E2FDF227BEA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Taking custody of such animals from research facilities, shelters, or other sources.</text></clause><clause id="HBE42C147EC1A4B348BFCEE71893FB9C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Providing necessary care, including veterinary treatment and socialization, to such animals.</text></clause><clause id="H9DB602DD07E0444EB77132C1B8FEAE4F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Facilitating the adoption or transfer of such animals to permanent placements.</text></clause><clause id="HC18ED703FA594A44A9A52961F0E474A9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Maintaining records of the intake, care, and disposition of such animals.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD51846DA7F884D03AB5AFBCC84233942"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Does not engage in the commercial sale or trade of animals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H227CFF35F80E4830AB368EC9588EC2F2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Clinical veterinary research</header><text>The term <term>clinical veterinary research</term> means research on a dog or cat with a naturally occurring disease or injury that is conducted—</text><subparagraph id="H437812AEBD9443BE81107CAA843A8252"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for the benefit of the dog or cat; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B988977F7BE437A86359E2E3487F146"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with the intention of studying the effect of a procedure, device, or treatment protocol.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1E3CEB112DB449CB5B8414D9493B3EF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Grantee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>grantee</term> means an entity that receives Federal research funds under a grant agreement with a Federal department or agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C6DB7C66DBF46CC955AF8E737C02526"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Licensed animal shelter</header><text>The term <term>licensed animal shelter</term> means a facility that satisfies the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="HE36D1CBCAB5B4A9FA09F6F165514F087"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Is operated by or under contract with a State or local government, a duly incorporated humane society, or an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59ABE0D669244A6D840004830E390A8B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Is licensed or registered under any applicable law to impound, harbor, or care for stray, abandoned, or surrendered animals, including animals released from research facilities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2BE53A9765141F398B704DA2ACFFCF9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Provides humane care and treatment to such animals.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4870F8AC10C41888D53D8DBB87D39EA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Facilitates the adoption or transfer of such animals to suitable placements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D78AB851F6D4D4DBE9A6B6748D94146"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Military animal</header><text>The term <term>military animal</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2583 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94ACC63B16A14DD8AFDAA655F668DCF8"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Research, testing, and experimentation</header><text>The term <term>research, testing, and experimentation</term> includes any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H36F6D86349584852B87292C957827070"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Basic research.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCCF15E5767D34E3F997FCFD4068F4646"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Behavioral research.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55CB8B3F41F541BD884FFCDCE6224BDD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Infectious disease research.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E1845C7995E40DB81AC65196CF9BB46"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Drug and device development and testing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89E4D6AD5D0346E98FEBA05D2A2BDA21"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Cosmetic development and testing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C3DDFA412DA4C5EA680E3574D5D7EA3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Chemical development and testing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED4B99035E61493D87AFC83C3E81BF23"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Biomedical training.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C6B461E6E044AF59B5EF69360D58ADE"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Service animal</header><text>The term <term>service animal</term> has the meaning given the term in section 37.3 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB41FDAE46CC247F3B9DDC5A61E201C40"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Subcontractor</header><text>The term <term>subcontractor</term> means an entity that performs work under a subcontract funded by a Federal research grant or another Federal contract.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

