<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H710F89DA86E349F1A954F14ED2382ECE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 955 IH: Health Out-of-Pocket Expense Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 955</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250204">February 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reform health provisions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H783F3CBF52444F628337EFD1F97C7DD8" style="OLC"><section id="H18877F6541AC47B4AF8C9F6021432FFE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Health Out-of-Pocket Expense Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HOPE Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H20A524CFBB134227B9D22590BA051A15"><enum>2.</enum><header>Hope Accounts</header><subsection id="H80D71F3E3F1D4DE7A70859F4F5DB35FB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Accounts established</header><paragraph id="HD1AE9065024B4887AB445E6637363BD2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part VIII of subchapter F of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H154BD8FB1230426ABD01329902BB1150" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H709350A6F1414ABBA870031FE8F45714"><enum>530A.</enum><header>HOPE Accounts</header><subsection id="H72FB048F2DF445DDB2E08105A9F59F65"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A HOPE Account shall be exempt from taxation under this subtitle. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, the Hope Account shall be subject to the taxes imposed by section 511 (relating to the imposition of tax on unrelated business income of charitable organizations).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD506F8E884D041A0994B10B7F5FDFA27"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions and special rules</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H8A2B26AD922A464FBDBAC20FBDE1C446"><enum>(1)</enum><header>HOPE Account</header><text>The term <term>HOPE Account</term> means a trust created or organized in the United States as a HOPE Account exclusively for the purpose of paying the qualified medical expenses of the account beneficiary, but only if the written governing instrument creating the trust meets the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="H8EDCC3B32DDC447CA8CBD8630BD09127"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except in the case of a rollover contribution described in subsection (d)(4) of this section, no contribution will be accepted—</text><clause id="H727117B9603E4F679B45996A9F0D6D17"><enum>(i)</enum><text>unless it is in cash, or</text></clause><clause id="HC633503AAFF844C4B3E66BE444DC6124"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to the extent such contribution, when added to previous contributions to the trust for the calendar year, exceeds the contribution limitations in subsection (c).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3B7C81DBD194376A08B442E4AC37BA0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The trustee is a bank (as defined in section 408(n)), an insurance company (as defined in section 816), or another person who demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the manner in which such person will administer the trust will be consistent with the requirements of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50BD2FA318C14A90A9A14DDF5FF1A6F5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>No part of the trust assets will be invested in life insurance contracts.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FECF8D1D5724F7992D2E084BA92DA81"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The assets of the trust will not be commingled with other property except in a common trust fund or common investment fund.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC0F9224EC814096BD8B7B479E41F1B4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The interest of an individual in the balance in the individual’s account is nonforfeitable.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H035640759DC24C688BBF377EB8D279FA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>No more than reasonable fees are paid in connection with the administration of the account.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DF8A64BCBCB4A8894253E530DA5A38B"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The trust includes procedures for the trustee to reasonably assure that distributions are limited to payment or reimbursement for qualified medical expenses incurred after the establishment of the trust. Procedures shall be considered reasonable that meet the substantiation requirements contained in Proposed Treasury Regulation section 1.125–6 (as in effect on January 1, 2025) or under any superseding guidance prescribed by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADBFE7CD380641BC8EC678E69948151C"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The trust follows all reporting requirements as may be prescribed by the Secretary with respect to distributions that are not substantiated as qualified medical expenses pursuant to this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94F04FBCF02C4D6784B03D1CE783A06A"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The trust follows any other guidance with respect to HOPE Accounts prescribed by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CFEED49D33A4DECBF7571B875450ED6" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (d)(2)(B), amounts held by the trust may not be distributable other than exclusively to pay the qualified medical expenses of the account beneficiary, spouse or dependents.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37E1800BCF3045118A5707BFC095D53E"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The trust reports all contributions on Form 5498–A, or such other form as is required by the Secretary. The trust annually must also—</text><clause id="H1AADAF51429B40E28BC044DDBCF84552"><enum>(i)</enum><text>request each account owner to provide the trust with the amount if any, the account owner contributed to an FSA for the year, and</text></clause><clause id="HCF5F8787827A4CEEBEC5A13C6C6B058A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>report such amount on Form 5498–A or such other form as is required by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC981BD5742784E3A92193B7CD7D2188B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible individual</header><subparagraph id="HA56BE71826E549A181123FADA8027C6F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>eligible individual</term> means, with respect to any month, any individual if for such month such individual meets the requirements of subparagraphs (B) and (C).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FF0FF4E0E074844AF6CCFBF3207E992"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Coverage requirement</header><text>An individual meets the requirements of this subparagraph for a month if such individual is covered under one of the following types of coverage as of the 1st day of such month:</text><clause id="HD26F331D8EC64EEE93231B0B66CAC2AC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Minimum essential coverage (as defined in section 5000A(f)).</text></clause><clause id="HB495D338E3F74D5CB9686AD48510ADA1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>With respect to members of federally recognized American Indian and Alaska Native Tribes and their descendants, the Indian Health Service.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34E4D24969034A77A9E8C0CB2DD77A1C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Other coverage</header><clause id="H52DA38A66A0D470D984C4ED141E0C382"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An individual meets the requirements of this subparagraph for a month if during such month no amounts are contributed by or on behalf of the individual to any of the following accounts of such individual:</text><subclause id="H7C3AA018AE0741AA857A8805507678C9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>A health flexible spending arrangement.</text></subclause><subclause id="H5177BAF745864D379B51406900966E9D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>A health savings account (as defined in section 223(d)).</text></subclause><subclause id="H55F7D05386714AB9B2DE2C9DDC131B29"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A health reimbursement arrangement which is treated as employer-provided coverage under an accident or health plan for purposes of section 106.</text></subclause><subclause id="H5E6626A4522744FDAB3FFEF5FDA4B2DF"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>An Archer MSA (as defined in section 220(d)).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H3F473D980BD74251AB29691CE0EF379B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception for certain disregarded coverage</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply in the case of an account described therein if for the month such account constitutes coverage described in section 223(c)(1)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEE358916A3C4DD08DFC17847414F1B8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified medical expenses</header><text>The term <term>qualified medical expenses</term> has the meaning given such term in section 223(d)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H33F704701A1E4BFFAC5A62B5F2B57DCC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Account beneficiary</header><text>The term <term>account beneficiary</term> means the individual on whose behalf the HOPE Account was established.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA66886B5C7D4EBA93AF589CD77B24B2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Account terminations</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (2) and (4) of section 408(e) shall apply to HOPE Accounts, and any amount treated as distributed under such rules shall be treated as not used to pay qualified medical expenses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EE536628F0D4E15AB55DE328D75AE4F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Certain rules to apply</header><text>Rules similar to the following rules shall apply for purposes of this section:</text><subparagraph id="HE27FDF35F630493F89E9848C1890A9B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 219(f)(3) (relating to time when contributions deemed made).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC3045170EA543C8B9821B90A95BB883"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Except as provided in section 106(h), section 219(f)(5) (relating to employer payments).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D6BBBC7F78444ACB446EDB2C1609DBA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 408(g) (relating to community property laws).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD06C845E2EB44DA6AB3C7AC06B3FF2F8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Section 408(h) (relating to custodial accounts).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02AF02D74DE74C8C9DB1C073B9983D08"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Section 223(f)(7) (relating to transfer of account incident of divorce).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42C843DB89C14787B96E1A74795F3DC3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Section 223(f)(8) (relating to treatment after death of account beneficiary).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8BBA7B5A872C459EBEA790BFBACB39FA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contribution limitations</header><paragraph id="H27DE34AB20074CA4ABCA5890C64E9FFB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The aggregate amount of contributions from all sources to all HOPE Accounts maintained for the benefit of an eligible individual for any taxable year shall not exceed the sum of the monthly limitations for months during such taxable year that the individual is an eligible individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H672D83A68BC94014850BE438CA25633B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Monthly limitation</header><text>The monthly limitation for any month is <fraction>1/12</fraction> of—</text><subparagraph id="HF61B4F621165459EAB3010731443296B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an eligible individual who has self-only coverage, or an eligible individual that is married filing separately or married filing jointly that has family coverage, $4,000, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H222102823ED04E4CBDDCE8679F55A572"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible individual who has family coverage and is head of household, $8,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H816232100CFE4BA4A14BD7B7DEB7FC46"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on third party contributions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A trust shall not be treated as a Hope Account under this section unless the aggregate of contributions on behalf of the individual from all employers of the individual and from any Medicaid program established and administered by a State or subdivision thereof, if approved by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under Section 1115 of the Social Security Act or Section 1332 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, will not be accepted in excess of 50 percent of the limit with respect to such individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40C77777DD8341F5A06DEE84F9CA8E1A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>No deduction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No deduction shall be allowed for a contribution made by an eligible individual to a HOPE Account maintained for the benefit of such individual for any taxable year. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91B3E0ACA8774DBFBEA16BC0545567A9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Exclusion from gross income limited</header><text>Any contribution under paragraph (c)(3) to the HOPE account of an individual whose adjusted gross income for the prior taxable year does not exceed $100,000 ($200,000 in the case of a married individual filing a joint return) shall be excluded from the individual’s adjusted gross income.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7249AE2BAD540CE9EAE537E62D6D537" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Coordination with other contributions</header><text>The limitation which would (but for this paragraph) apply under this subsection to an individual for any taxable year shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the sum of—</text><subparagraph id="H43778D54052C4DA191703279FAF9B0FA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the aggregate amount determined with respect to the individual for the taxable year under section 223(b)(4),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0E7BD4A561A46ADA057FA39A46E7D2D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the aggregate amount contributed by the individual to health savings accounts of the individual for such taxable year and not taken into account under subparagraph (A),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7340BE5847346C4A945961A09F12D87" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the aggregate amount contributed to a HOPE Account of such individual by the individual’s employer, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD762945F2FC449C1932F6F44D9EBEEB6" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the aggregate amount contributed to a HOPE Account of such individual for such taxable year by a program established and administered by a State or subdivision thereof with respect to converted cost-sharing reduction payments.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H02236B9DE4834FA28E88B039A7F16887"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Cost-of-living adjustment</header><text>In the case of any taxable year beginning in a calendar year after 2026, each dollar amount in paragraph (2) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text><subparagraph id="H893BC600E256465089C864F260D7F771"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBFE306F03D144D193D979C62A0B4652"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which such taxable year begins determined—</text><clause id="H7382AFBD208840AF88F4A8BFC2AA37D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by substituting <quote>calendar year 2025</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof, and</text></clause><clause id="H8EE68B35DB0242599EE670E9F0326CB9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by substituting <quote>March 31</quote> for <quote>August 31</quote> in section 1(f)(4). </text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">The Secretary shall publish the adjusted amounts under paragraph (2) for taxable years beginning in any calendar year no later than June 1 of the preceding calendar year. If any increase under this paragraph is not a multiple of $50, such increase shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $50.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC0B7A093876A45869F6F67BCC1E42AEA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Tax treatment of distributions</header><paragraph id="H82B8E7D566774B08A5815AC33BF0D24D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amounts used for qualified medical expenses</header><text>Any amount paid or distributed out of a HOPE Account which is used exclusively to pay qualified medical expenses of any account beneficiary shall not be includible in gross income.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D9AE597E8C84531B3A810C15FA28189"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distribution and taxation of amounts not used for qualified medical expenses</header><subparagraph id="H1DCF3FD61CC547C9B0805EA0C0D19266"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), no amount may be paid or distributed out of a HOPE Account which is not used exclusively to pay the qualified medical expenses of the account beneficiary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE502AF0F6D74E12B6D789A84537ABFB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception for certain distributions</header><text>An amount may be paid or distributed out of a HOPE Account which is not used exclusively to pay the qualified medical expenses of the account beneficiary if such distribution is reported to the Secretary pursuant to such regulations or other guidance the Secretary may prescribe, and the distribution is—</text><clause id="H493303E53704464A83DB0D0CF6D71895"><enum>(i)</enum><text>made to an account beneficiary (or to the estate of the account beneficiary) on or after the death of the individual, or</text></clause><clause id="H42FC7B5510F941BABB9C0A369717A61F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>attributable to the account beneficiary being disabled (within the meaning of section 72(m)(7)).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD24C4E17E1E04E8C98858512A5970E80"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Taxation of distributions not used for qualified medical expenses</header><clause id="H8CA31DC08D19452CB082BB47ABFA2385"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any amount paid or distributed out of a HOPE Account which is not used exclusively to pay qualified medical expenses of any account beneficiary shall be includible in gross income, except to the extent such distribution is allocable to amounts described in subparagraph (D)(iii).</text></clause><clause id="H5E6D9D5F0FE4444D97B90EDF0696ECCA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Additional tax</header><text>The tax imposed by this chapter on the account beneficiary for any taxable year in which there is a payment or distribution from a HOPE Account of such beneficiary which is includible in gross income under clause (i) shall be increased by 30 percent of the amount which is so includible.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0069279536F4E77B8F29238D3527E88"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Ordering of distributions</header><text>Any distributions out of a HOPE Account pursuant to subparagraph (B) shall be treated as made from amounts to the extent that the amount of such distribution, when added to all previous distributions from the HOPE Account, does not exceed the aggregate of such amount, and from such amounts pursuant to the following ordering rules:</text><clause id="HFFBB4D26C66B435694B45F5AAB70229E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>from earnings, if any, on such amounts described in clauses (ii) and (iii),</text></clause><clause id="HC72D81DDA7E24DE08C828B7057D062C9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>from contributions described in subsection (c)(3),</text></clause><clause id="HBF9B37D4AF4B4B0AA231AF282C9B23BE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>from contributions by an eligible individual to the HOPE Account, and</text></clause><clause id="H1ACAAB74D318413A820B201EE849D0E0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>from rollover contributions to the HOPE Account from another HOPE Account allocable to contributions by an eligible individual to such other HOPE Account, on a first-in, first-out basis.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9BC04D737DE44049B11F9521E84B2C4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Excess contributions returned before due date of return</header><subparagraph id="H3304131D8C724B799BDCDD238BE65CF9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If any excess contribution is contributed for a taxable year to any HOPE Account of an individual, paragraph (2) shall not apply to distributions from the HOPE Accounts of such individual (to the extent such distributions do not exceed the aggregate excess contributions to all such accounts of such individual for such year) if—</text><clause id="H7FFA2E3AA4914C5985F163AE9170EE31"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such distribution is received by the individual on or before the last day prescribed by law (including extensions of time) for filing such individual’s return for such taxable year, and</text></clause><clause id="H8B8BEA2C8ADF48869351E4B5A5ED11B2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such distribution is accompanied by the amount of net income attributable to such excess contribution.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">Any net income described in clause (ii) shall be included in the gross income of the individual for the taxable year in which it is received.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE1292A6940C4C6F8A343081FDA2D339"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Excess contribution</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <term>excess contribution</term> means any contribution (other than a rollover contribution described in paragraph (4)) which is neither excludable from gross income under section 106(h) nor allowable under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A87890922694A5888F4B49B241BA78D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rollover contribution</header><text>An amount is described in this paragraph as a rollover contribution if it meets the requirements of subparagraphs (A) and (B).</text><subparagraph id="H0C204A74ABF2486D8AE2C1F43FBD43B1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (2) shall not apply to any amount paid or distributed from a HOPE Account to the account beneficiary to the extent the amount received is paid into a HOPE Account for the benefit of such beneficiary, the beneficiary’s spouse or the beneficiary’s dependent not later than the 60th day after the day on which the beneficiary receives the payment or distribution.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE55437C8B90049AF9DD9094018D8C502"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>This paragraph shall not apply to any amount described in subparagraph (A) received by an individual from a HOPE Account if, at any time during the 1-year period ending on the day of such receipt, such individual received any other amount described in subparagraph (A) from a HOPE Account which was not includible in the individual’s gross income because of the application of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB371B51A9C914A079DA42578BD45BBBA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Dependent</header><text>The term dependent means any individual with respect to whom a deduction under section 151 is allowed to another taxpayer for a taxable year beginning in the calendar year in which such individual’s taxable year begins.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6F38C21EC5C42B68CD89D7D0FF4FCCC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Coordination with medical expense deduction</header><text>For purposes of determining the amount of the deduction under section 213, any payment or distribution out of a HOPE Account for qualified medical expenses shall not be treated as an expense paid for medical care.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE7D8848FBDE84D0F8C62083603D0D84C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>The Secretary shall require the trustee of a HOPE Account to make such reports regarding such account to the Secretary and to the account beneficiary with respect to contributions, distributions, the return of excess contributions, and such other matters as the Secretary determines appropriate. The trustee shall include in each such report an accounting of the amount contributed by the account beneficiary, and may, if necessary to determine such amount, request such information from the account beneficiary.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H1591E4444F0E4A778CF6A21DB3B87E5D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for part VIII of subchapter F of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6A927F9C7D6B404C8982960984A49011" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 530A. HOPE Accounts.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFCB8B828E71C401D83BA1A41A48A450D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Excess contributions</header><paragraph id="H8905CF8D286A4107A5CC840796AEBF31"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4973(a) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of paragraph (5), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (6) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by inserting after paragraph (6) (as so amended) the following new paragraph: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H749058FB5E4B441482E7A4D9950DB586" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HF30EF29170D24F4B933B79ED5BAC7D08"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A HOPE Account (as defined in section 530A(b)).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EFB4C73867E4FB09DE2407709975AEE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Excess contributions defined</header><text>Section 4973 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H070B18D0488E41C68E69471149E14517" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HA1A8A21A7E4B450DAFE33267A3ED0359"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Excess contributions to HOPE Account</header><paragraph id="H1711507D6E0F423DB46A9F5DE963DBBE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, in the case of HOPE Accounts (within the meaning of section 530A(b)), the term “excess contributions” means the sum of—</text><subparagraph id="H45A1F06848D94FA8BAA0D8D32729BCD1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The aggregate amount contributed for the taxable year to the accounts (other than a rollover contribution described in section 530A(d)(4)) which exceeds the contributions limits under section 530A(c), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H797A023247244833AADD937D17E1C77B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount determined under this subsection for the preceding taxable year, reduced by the sum of—</text><clause id="H3D0CD0D42655480BB79C185A27E3C48E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the distributions out of the accounts which were included in gross income under section 530A(d)(2)(C), and</text></clause><clause id="H6001E8DDE8324200813A5C5263190560"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the excess (if any) of—</text><subclause id="HFAB3819202F74F0A97B630D4FB77BDBB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the maximum amount of allowable contributions under 530A(c) for the taxable year, over</text></subclause><subclause id="H13EC6B82F15A45D79AD8F8D26771B9EB"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount contributed to the accounts for the taxable year.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7F55486B95F49E1A10AD32BC44D5FC6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Returned excess contributions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, any contribution which is distributed out of the HOPE Account in a distribution to which section 530A(d)(2)(C) applies shall be treated as an amount not contributed.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H31270672E0754B2584DA94F9A9B9D0B2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Employer contributions</header><paragraph id="HAFB5D99CD3EB4BE99BE13C9887E01057"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 106 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="H8EF076A37715401AAC5C4A9227011494" style="OLC"><subsection id="HB3FB73CEDBCC48D89AB09524E3F155D7"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Contributions to <enum-in-header>HOPE</enum-in-header> Accounts</header><paragraph id="H6489114F68EE495EAF7A6B27BAA9463E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an employee who is an eligible individual, amounts contributed by such employee’s employer to any HOPE account (as defined in section 530A(b)) of such employee shall be treated as employer-provided coverage for medical expenses under an accident or health plan to the extent such amounts do not exceed the limitations applicable to such individual for such taxable year under section 530A(c) (determined without regard to this subsection).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D6BF28A1CE94BE68D5633E9028F73F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply in the case of a taxpayer whose adjusted gross income for the taxable year exceeds $100,000 ($200,000 in the case of a joint return). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA28A135E8F7B482A9D1197577760EF78"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rules</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (2), (3), (4), and (5) of subsection (b) shall apply for purposes of this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CCD790D578A4AC5BC52D8EBA8F978C1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cross reference</header><text>For penalty on failure by employer to make comparable contributions to the health savings accounts of comparable employees, see section 4980G.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H49ADCB1B89C14AD89243D8B3A97F6CBB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information reporting for employees</header><text>Section 6051(a) is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (16), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (17) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by inserting after paragraph (17) (as so amended) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCC1051FA3115443088DDAD59C03E9409" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HABA445E51DF445ECA4282458ED0BFA10"><enum>(18)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount contributed to any HOPE Account (as defined in section 530A(b)) of such employee.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H380A2B38DBE843459215BDDCCACD41B0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conforming amendment relating to cafeteria plans</header><text>Section 125(f)(1) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>106(h),</quote> after <quote>106(b),</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE4FE1ED0743740D291F91A2FDC3913B8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Failure of employer To make comparable HOPE Account contributions</header><paragraph id="H09E7FB0952F045729262E92C55B516CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4980G(a) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>or HOPE Account</quote> after <quote>health savings account</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7AC5CD6C2B2A458DA737A7C0A4192F92"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><subparagraph id="H0145EAC140BB40AB8EA0D68C29373C33"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4980G(c) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and health savings accounts</quote> and inserting <quote>, health savings accounts, or HOPE Accounts</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2FCAF0E3A814080A7BB7AB915FD199C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 4980G(d) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>or HOPE Account</quote> after <quote>health savings account</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96576A116A354AD68D77428E094B1751"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The heading for section 4980G of such Code is amended by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">or HOPE Account</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">health savings account</header-in-text></quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD01E008D29441D8BAC83CC140F79248"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The table of sections for chapter 43 of such Code is amended by striking the item relating to section 4980G and inserting the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBE6E2543AFC440DAAAABB8D765BCC364" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 4980G. Failure of employer to make comparable health savings account or HOPE Account contributions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3603C0B674A0434CACEEB1FB6A618514"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application of prohibited transaction rules</header><paragraph id="H3F96314F03204057AF18994ED366EB23"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 4975(e)(1) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (F), by redesignating subparagraph (G) as subparagraph (H), and by inserting after subparagraph (F), as so amended, the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H56D2E47540754B4E80BFEDCF30FC2BA9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H73AC53A23E3E488ABEA908E6557F4E55"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a HOPE Account described in section 530A(b), or</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2FDC9A78FC2E45D2AA66101B1B9F46F4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Failure To report</header><text>Section 6693(a)(2) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (E), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (F) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by inserting after subparagraph (F) (as so amended) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2F2EBF3DB5E643BBBBB6AB93284DC8B8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HD580CA20411645C583D77C7B1B9A5022"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 530A(e) (relating to HOPE Accounts).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H2E19F006048D4CF2A567A699E4E0CD63"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

