<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR25244-L0R-G3-YC8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S978 IS: Homes for Every Local Protector, Educator, and Responder Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 978</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250312">March 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S439">Mrs. Moody</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S414">Mr. Ossoff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the National Housing Act to establish a mortgage insurance program for first responders, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Homes for Every Local Protector, Educator, and Responder Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HELPER Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="ida59f8c301af1434b8e3c7094334a4fda"><enum>2.</enum><header>FHA mortgage insurance program for mortgages for first responders</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 203 of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1709">12 U.S.C. 1709</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf930f468e2fd4d3484df508eb63b6a8c"><subsection id="id5bbc9d0f87e54990a7f4a7bad251e848"><enum>(z)</enum><header>FHA mortgage insurance program for mortgages for first responders</header><paragraph id="idb9bafdcc614b420b9f2d3bd31c533cb5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idac3717aabe3b4f5198b41445ab88298d"><enum>(A)</enum><header>First responder</header><text>The term <term>first responder</term> means an individual who is, as attested by the individual—</text><clause id="id64D5D21FE7CC4987AD20EF67F9F83DB1"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id9f3c693284f24ff9a0062dc32fe52c1d"><enum>(I)</enum><text>employed full-time by a law enforcement agency of the Federal Government, a State, a Tribal government, or a unit of general local government; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6fc6fce290ac43eb9e7358ddcb4fea90" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in carrying out such full-time employment, sworn to uphold, and make arrests for violations of, Federal, State, county, township, municipal, or Tribal laws, or authorized by law to supervise sentenced criminal offenders or individuals with pending criminal charges; </text></subclause></clause><clause id="id51608723bc024dd59bf76edbc04a36f0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employed full-time as a firefighter, paramedic, or emergency medical technician by a fire department or emergency medical services responder unit of the Federal Government, a State, a Tribal government, or a unit of general local government; or</text></clause><clause id="id28298EFABBA74E12B80DC8DDCF3DA691"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>employed as a full-time teacher by a State-accredited public school or private school that provides direct services to students in grades pre-kindergarten through 12. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id251c851f61034a22a63f85488362b9f0"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">First-time homebuyer</header><text>The term <term>first-time homebuyer</term> has the meaning given the term in section 104 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12704">42 U.S.C. 12704</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idad336d3049a143b9afd4175b1200a295"><enum>(C)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given the term in section 201.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide5dea9bfe8c046ed8ef27cb8f77b76dd"><enum>(D)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Tribal government</header><text>The term <term>Tribal government</term> means the recognized governing body of any Indian or Alaska Native tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, community, component band, or component reservation, individually identified (including parenthetically) in the list published most recently pursuant to section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5131">25 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3507364164e34e538bf03c3d333ea460"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Authority</header><text>The Secretary may, upon application by a mortgagee, insure any mortgage eligible for insurance under this subsection to an eligible mortgagor and, upon such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, make commitments for the insurance of such mortgages prior to the date of their execution or disbursement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id01552e99516b4e3e94a275dee2d1ea6f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mortgage terms; mortgage insurance premium</header><subparagraph id="ida72b9280abc24acfb93bac5d9ed9af97"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Terms</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida079f4269da54fa9b6e010788a5021f2"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>A mortgage insured under this subsection shall—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id74dcedc8c0974709b683ed202fa994d8"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be made to an eligible mortgagor;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb7c3d172b637429096fd9f67576ddbed"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">comply with the requirements established under paragraphs (1) through (7) of subsection (b); and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaab9e6bd57a24240b7fc26ddbd48bf49"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be used only to—</text><item id="id8a90dc8734284928973c7eb4ca40e124"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>purchase or repair a 1-family residence, including a 1-family dwelling unit in a condominium project, to serve as a principal residence of the mortgagor, as attested by the mortgagor; or</text></item><item id="id9f16d07463a84aac869ebab9b91ed85d"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>purchase a principal residence of the mortgagor, as attested by the mortgagor, which is—</text><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf25f03899fa848be896860baa907ea27"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a manufactured home to be permanently affixed to a lot that is owned by the mortgagor and titled as real property; or</text></subitem><subitem id="id751c69a4692d4e7a9a0f679e01cd4f84"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>a manufactured home and a lot to which the home will be permanently affixed that is titled as real property.</text></subitem></item></subclause></clause><clause id="id4ab7e733e1fd4c0fb57f29d8c9f121d0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>No down payment</header><text>Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary in the matter following subsection (b)(2)(B) with respect to first-time homebuyers—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id94ebca98b7cd42a5986cc94149eb3a2f"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary may insure any mortgage that involves an original principal obligation (including allowable charges and fees and the premium pursuant to subparagraph (B) of this paragraph) in an amount not to exceed 100 percent of the appraised value of the property involved; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0ab3c0f0b7a3490789e095e89200d944"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the mortgagor of a mortgage described in subclause (I) shall not be required to pay any amount, in cash or its equivalent, on account of the property.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf4201f73724e402a96129f0c4d825abe"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Mortgage insurance premium</header><clause id="id7a1b67646cf545bfb7f7fcdf09abc44d"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Up-front premium</header><text>The Secretary shall establish and collect an insurance premium in connection with mortgages insured under this subsection that is a percentage of the original insured principal obligation of the mortgage amount, which shall be collected at the time and in the manner provided under subsection (c)(2)(A), except that the premiums collected under this subparagraph—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc763bc63f8f5496aab83d704c314ffbb"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be in an amount that exceeds 3 percent of the amount of the original insured principal obligation of the mortgage; and </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id54e065cf54ff4e4c96edeb0285d8b02a"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be adjusted by the Secretary from time to time by increasing or decreasing such percentages as the Secretary considers necessary, based on the performance of mortgages insured under this subsection and market conditions.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id9939abb4d4574ce5b514b76802caf439"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Prohibition of monthly premiums</header><text>A mortgage insured under this subsection shall not be subject to a monthly insurance premium, including a premium under subsection (c)(2)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd26a3da9fb654c1dab75621ecd735c4d"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible mortgagors</header><text>The mortgagor for a mortgage insured under this subsection shall, at the time the mortgage is executed—</text><subparagraph id="iddc79b31122024a9a87a13bae535d8c90"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be a first-time homebuyer;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida7afe551e0f34d4d8489803517eb3a33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have completed a program of housing counseling provided through a housing counseling agency approved by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8d3a7576edce4448847ac0f99d1211bd"><enum>(C)</enum><text>as attested by the mortgagor—</text><clause id="ide4dc60efcb9d48c4b1e1f2e5af658f68"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be employed as a first responder;</text></clause><clause id="id6a5b9186126e4ad58e975e71df056e60"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have been—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide7b237de8fcb481f96cb09080f14786c"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employed as a first responder for not less than 4 of the 5 years preceding the date on which the mortgagor submitted an application to insure the mortgage under this section; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id785418b1c26c4775ab1aefc8db3a7f37"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">released from employment as a first responder due to an occupation-connected disability resulting from such duty or employment;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idde07bbc6f4634f7b9e9785a2ac1fe9da"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>be in good standing as a first responder and not on probation or under investigation for conduct that, if determined to have occurred, is grounds for termination of employment; </text></clause><clause id="id124e41cef2ce4419a51744e1fb071566"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in good faith intend to continue as a first responder for not less than 1 year following the date of closing on the mortgage; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf8b1322e261f47caa73fae2ff8ab1692"><enum>(v)</enum><text>have previously never been the mortgagor under a mortgage insured under this subsection;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6c4a45c4acfe498fad8b3c5aa5df6ce7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>meet such requirements as the Secretary shall establish to ensure that insurance of the mortgage represents an acceptable risk to the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id807337e67bb04db08ba1a69f9ca87542"><enum>(E)</enum><text>meet such underwriting requirements as the Secretary shall establish to meet actuarial objectives identified by the Secretary, which may include avoiding a positive subsidy rate or complying with the capital ratio requirement under section 205(f)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1f1d4369c544462d9d686b1353db9afb"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out the program under this subsection—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e33b293ab414eccaf6c152a19d7c18c"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$660,000 for fiscal year 2026, to remain available until expended; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e5c589a250c41ccaabcf1090a619937"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$160,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2032, to remain available until expended.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide2a083c7fc9342c589e7c0041ba69547"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reauthorization required</header><text>The authority to enter into new commitments to insure mortgages under this subsection shall expire on the date that is 5 years after the date on which the Secretary first makes available insurance for mortgages under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

