<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA5B819D8A2534194B53D14A19E1D9D89" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2478 IH: Financial Exploitation Prevention Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2478</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Steil</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000600">Ms. Perez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Investment Company Act of 1940 to postpone the date of payment or satisfaction upon redemption of certain securities in the case of the financial exploitation of specified adults, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6C55E2F06AAC4D278834F24C9BE09071" style="OLC"><section id="H19E49A78C9B84F179198681419EDE75C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Financial Exploitation Prevention Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H62667983A724418F8B11DB8340D80620"><enum>2.</enum><header>Redemption of certain securities postponed</header><subsection id="HED0AA21B5CE14162837EE7A4862CC44C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 22 of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-22">15 U.S.C. 80a–22</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H49885D59393942248ADFC21AC185B6F8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H9A3A7C01235349628BE8A126D865D0F2"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Requirements with respect to non-Institutional direct at-Fund accounts</header><paragraph id="H7E174FBC467B4E3491B90349A89025EE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Election</header><subparagraph id="HF176192852D1453DAB008D2BFD10E7F9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A registered open-end investment company and a transfer agent described under paragraph (2) may elect to comply with the requirements under paragraph (2) and subsection (i) by notifying the Commission of such election.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE46BDD9BFCC042C383C5B4028F1EDEF1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect of election</header><text>Paragraph (2) and subsection (i) shall only apply to a registered open-end investment company and a transfer agent that have made the election under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H79B14C26790E4AADAD05F0BF95270A78"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In the case of a customer who is a holder of a non-institutional account held directly with a registered open-end investment company and serviced by a transfer agent (a <quote>direct-at-fund account</quote>), the company and transfer agent shall—</text><subparagraph id="HC440010820264E66AB6527E0BAA29C02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>request from such customer the name and contact information of at least one individual who—</text><clause id="H9D23BCE6491A43569954FD3A47CA83BB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is at the time of such request an adult; and</text></clause><clause id="HD5C4079C4C32401488125980395756B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may be contacted with respect to such account;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6A4E29577D34EC38B60CA88965962FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>document and retain the information received pursuant to subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50A8FA4A7EF54C9B8BA754EC26F452B0"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disclose to such customer in writing (including through electronic delivery) that such company or transfer agent may contact an individual specified pursuant to subparagraph (A) with respect to the account of such customer to—</text><clause id="H4DC2F7903ADB48E1B33E729B2A823004"><enum>(i)</enum><text>address possible financial exploitation of such customer;</text></clause><clause id="H22E79605940A47C7B4D164FD6877217E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>confirm the contact information or health status of the customer; or</text></clause><clause id="H33B102F263514AD092AD442E26FB17F0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>identify any legal guardian, executor, trustee, or holder of a power of attorney of the customer.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H012043F132A84F7EBC44BA6CCC59864B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Redemption of certain securities postponed</header><paragraph id="H7B3AF25C5BE74229BBD92394508DD082"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (e), a registered open-end investment company or a transfer agent acting on behalf of such company may postpone the date of payment or satisfaction upon redemption of any redeemable security in accordance with its terms for more than seven days after the tender of such security to such company or its agent designated for that purpose for redemption if such company or agent reasonably believes that—</text><subparagraph id="H8CC3C3D7E8BA4A41B7CCA666460369D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the redemption is requested by a security holder who is a specified adult; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8231BACABF3E4983B6DD14B81BFDD3AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>financial exploitation has occurred, is occurring, or has been attempted with respect to such redemption.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D0466DB1FD442968E9B24E3A5E58456"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><subparagraph id="HBA92D714BA8D477CAF69C2F7583DBF41"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C), a registered open-end investment company or a transfer agent acting on behalf of such company may postpone the date of payment or satisfaction upon redemption of a redeemable security under paragraph (1) for a period of not more than 15 business days.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AC3861E360244BA901E752A16D51D9F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Extension upon determination of exploitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The period described in subparagraph (A) may be extended by an additional 10 business days if the registered open-end investment company or a transfer agent acting on behalf of such company—</text><clause id="H0BDF6ADE750748F991C05341FCFCB603"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reasonably believes that—</text><subclause id="H5A345B66569F4BA892C160DC153CC47C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the redemption is requested by a security holder who is a specified adult; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H436F4278A0564E13BE5F14124BFBE687"><enum>(II)</enum><text>financial exploitation has occurred, is occurring, or has been attempted with respect to such redemption;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H9D387B4352C14913BA7B1DACAF0E573B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subject to subparagraph (D), not later than 2 days after making a determination under clause (i), notifies the individuals specified by such security holder under subsection (h)(2)(A) in writing (including through electronic delivery) of the extension of the period described in subparagraph (A) under this subparagraph and the reason for such extension;</text></clause><clause id="HF8547910A4EB4F59BCF233781CECA5AF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>initiates an internal review of the facts and circumstances relating to the determination under clause (i);</text></clause><clause id="H8BC9C7241FAC4B5DAF2F23532DA7A258"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>holds amounts related to the delayed payment or satisfaction upon redemption of the redeemable security in a demand deposit account; and</text></clause><clause id="H4578CA45EF26473F912379275567E1EF"><enum>(v)</enum><text>documents and retains records related to carrying out clause (iv) and includes such records in the first required account statement of the security holder provided after the date on which the determination is made under clause (i). </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EFE13C059F94B1DA5E7A1B36AF178D0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Extension by government</header><text>A State regulator, administrative agency of competent jurisdiction, or court of competent jurisdiction may extend the period described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9433F1AE3C34FB7A3B2BF7891F0BE4A"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Notification</header><clause id="HF7E73F3E48BE432EBE47F0D935966FA6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subparagraph (B)(ii) shall not apply if a registered open-end investment company or transfer agent acting on behalf of such company reasonably believes that an individual required to be notified under such subparagraph is, has been, or will subject the security holder who identified such individual under subsection (h)(2)(A) to financial exploitation.</text></clause><clause id="HC3B049A4F619413BAF3E648F681FBC24"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reasonable efforts</header><text>An open-end investment company or transfer agent acting on behalf of such company shall be considered in compliance with subparagraph (B)(ii) if such company or transfer agent makes a reasonable effort to contact the individuals specified by a security holder under subsection (h)(2)(A).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CB9F5919E974776B909BBF0D699EE82"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Internal procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An open-end investment company or transfer agent acting on behalf of such company shall establish procedures to carry out the requirements under this subsection, including procedures—</text><clause id="H4731D25893C242029AB724F2A9BFD31A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">related to the identification and reporting of matters related to the financial exploitation of specified adults;</text></clause><clause id="H4D97F45745F340C4A5E34011DBE3E998"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to determine whether to release or reinvest delayed redemption proceeds, taking into account the facts and circumstances of each case, should the internal review under subparagraph (B)(iii) support the reasonable belief described in subparagraph (B)(i); </text></clause><clause id="HF35C4A5EE3494D079B80E02137F214E4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>identifying each employee of the company or transfer agent with authority to establish, extend, or terminate a period described in paragraph (1) or subparagraph (A);</text></clause><clause id="HF9A116C685A9427D867A0AD54509A420"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the case of a transfer agent, that are reasonably designed to ensure that the employees of such transfer agent comply with this subsection; and</text></clause><clause id="HD025C02BF2E24043A552556C42FA8C50"><enum>(v)</enum><text>in the case of an open-end investment company, establishing periodic reporting requirements under which a transfer agent acting on behalf of such company shall notify such company of—</text><subclause id="H2651578303114D2793ED7B820BD8DB9B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>each extension under subparagraph (B) authorized by such transfer agent;</text></subclause><subclause id="H594AAAE8C7F245C4B6C09B500DB16C5A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>each finding by the transfer agent under subparagraph (B)(i);</text></subclause><subclause id="H9660EA685C8C47F889DF83FB27D28407"><enum>(III)</enum><text>each notification under subparagraph (B)(ii) carried out by such transfer agent; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H3E680055E13947FB8408C0F333C9B552"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the results of each internal review initiated by the transfer agent under subparagraph (B)(iii). </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H465DFA4B5D094ADE942FF3D2655A6CF8"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Information included in certain statements</header><text>An open-end investment company shall include in each prospectus or statement of additional information a notification that the company or transfer agent acting on behalf of such company may postpone redemption of certain securities under this subsection. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6C55307C8D24DBE9E4BBFDC1E776797"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Record retention</header><text>An open-end investment company or transfer agent acting on behalf of such company shall—</text><clause id="H0AE44806E5384C9982DE1B0362A54EA2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>document and retain records of—</text><subclause id="H205B3D08672D44E9A4B16C30300681CE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>each postponement of redemption under subparagraph (A), (B), and (C);</text></subclause><subclause id="HBC3E6B1DB4584A50BF7D63E2E073ED20"><enum>(II)</enum><text>each finding under subparagraph (B)(i);</text></subclause><subclause id="H8A53646FBDA6477A876F23861C18627F"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the name and position of each employee described in subparagraph (E)(iii);</text></subclause><subclause id="H4FA5FEDC594A4A75BAE2B407E7FC632A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>each notification carried out under subparagraph (B)(ii); and</text></subclause><subclause id="HCA91A5478524472CAF47A6487D9F9F90"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the results of each internal review initiated under subparagraph (B)(iii); and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H1AF4376E19134BCB9185D578D77EA1C2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>make such records available to the Commission at the request of the Commission.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B8C1CAB435D4E50B5915682C8347F64"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Specified adult defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>specified adult</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H32DCA1E8035B4EDB8F421BBE939F84AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual age 65 or older; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54012E2DEF2E4B69A04FB3D6FB1E9FA6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individual age 18 or older who a registered open-end investment company or a transfer agent acting on behalf of such company reasonably believes has a mental or physical impairment that renders the individual unable to protect the individual’s own interests.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H25549D784809415BB02C6EF03215C9C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><paragraph id="H526FF78BC5774CB59AC2B8E58B15EB6F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Securities and Exchange Commission, in consultation with the entities specified in paragraph (2), shall submit to Congress a report that includes recommendations regarding the regulatory and legislative changes necessary to address the financial exploitation of security holders who are specified adults (as defined in subsection (i)(3) of section 22 of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-22">15 U.S.C. 80a–22</external-xref>), as added by this section).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD3736F06E3C4521AD7857CE81FB9C35"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The entities specified in this paragraph are as follows:</text><subparagraph id="H0FA53AE722454F57A48D7C446C86E11F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commodity Futures Trading Commission.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H003F45F201F0410196CFC8D38ED12D87"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CC9E80A2A0F4B3F931F3D8CF8C88E1D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Financial Industry Regulatory Authority.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD0104C89F464E8B962E35D0C0C57E16" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The North American Securities Administrators Association.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9379B2AD2A71443B91EA161343B6F4CB"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD81A58B206AD4FE698429615498AB402"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller of the Currency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE89D1DCF954F471E8484C1AEED4311A7"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

