<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG25466-K96-3P-8PH"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1492 IS: Deploying American Blockchains Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1492</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S434">Mr. Moreno</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Commerce support the leadership of the United States with respect to the deployment, use, application, and competitiveness of blockchain technology, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="HA428EDEA6E6C44DA921356D20F13807E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Deploying American Blockchains Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD88559B9AA0C4E8CBF0D77B006F31D11"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idfcfa85b2f9e844b5bd680fd7a8e5f84e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advisory committee</header><text>The term <term>Advisory Committee</term> means the National Blockchain Deployment Advisory Committee established pursuant to section 603(c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27552CC78D92478CA3B78E9A374B4BFD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology</header><text>The term <term>blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology</term> means a distributed digital database where data is—</text><subparagraph id="H68B4DE0F2C894460A7D788DAD112DD0A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shared across a network of computers to create a ledger of verified information among network participants;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FD78BC52C624BDC99FA5B924A67ADCF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>linked using cryptography to maintain the integrity of the ledger and to execute other functions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H400101A011D64500884948F0816317E6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>distributed among network participants in an automated fashion to concurrently update network participants on the state of the ledger and other functions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B7E32364F8543789949A2AD176E4904"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered nongovernmental representative</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered nongovernmental representative</term> means a representative as specified in the second sentence of section 135(b)(1) of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2155">19 U.S.C. 2155(b)(1)</external-xref>), except that such term does not include a representative of a non-Federal government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAC434FCD4AE48DDA0A82C1139A29B98"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8E4083E294F4B6B8334ED4496AE23EC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, each commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD40BEC9A185480E9106E2BB3D94D50D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Token</header><text>The term <term>token</term> means a transferable, digital representation of information recorded on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9073BF06C0CB4DDC9B9060227E80869D"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Tokenization</header><text>The term <term>tokenization</term> means the process of creating a token.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H79D6E241B8964D01899DC43ACCE3BAFD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Department of commerce leadership on blockchain</header><subsection id="H03B702FFBBEC4F6387EFA2E6F29A5EFC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Function of Secretary</header><text>The Secretary shall serve as a principal advisor to the President for policy pertaining to the deployment, use, application, and competitiveness of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8226E1DF6E344A16868C10CE22D1460E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>The Secretary shall support the leadership of the United States with respect to the deployment, use, application, and competitiveness of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization by organizing the Advisory Committee—</text><paragraph id="HB7621EBE87294921A5F4771363C7E7C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to examine and to provide recommendations on issues and risks relating to the deployment, use, application, and competitiveness of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization, including the issues of decentralized identity, cybersecurity, key storage and security systems, artificial intelligence, fraud reduction, regulatory compliance, e-commerce, health care applications, and supply chain resiliency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E9DA1CBFEEE42E2BF0AE5AE99336BA0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to support and to promote the improvement and security of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H252FD0E0B5154F86AAC84D96EA76A7F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to help to promote the leadership of the United States with respect to the deployment, use, application, and competitiveness of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H218673444C2C4B8E9A53D0688D0B3958"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to promote the national security of the United States with respect to blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H833958EB65DB44B498D5268695227CD8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to support engagement with the public to develop a compendium of proposals for practices as part of the work described in subsection (d);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E71A761C9A14076BA8416F5BB91AF84"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to consider policies to encourage coordination among Federal agencies with respect to the deployment of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DC0B396A6164B19A193C84DEAE3CFC8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to examine—</text><subparagraph id="HE34237D7A4984D499544D86CF5903E4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how Federal agencies can benefit from utilizing blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECEB15B73B0F4EE6A8B7A8A0CB954EC9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the current use by Federal agencies of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6FD29409D964580921361F3B1DF306B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the current and future preparedness and ability of Federal agencies to adopt blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5F33789BF504A62AABC8027303478DC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>additional security measures Federal agencies may need to take—</text><clause id="H59DE0174027D4C73BCF2AC988BA96156"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to securely use blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization, including to support the security of critical infrastructure; and</text></clause><clause id="HB17945B9C4E6429BB16C1602BDB26C05"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to enhance the resiliency of Federal systems against cyber threats to blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3A1DD7810E9424EAE1CBE4081B52F80"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to support coordination of the activities of the Federal Government relating to the security of blockchain technology and other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H50EC53467D8045909C8A1AB2E4E26E2D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Establishment of national blockchain deployment advisory committee</header><paragraph id="H55F6B3547E3B4F42821D22A376F15178"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4565ffc1fed7456ab80a114102db01c2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall, in consultation with the heads of relevant Federal agencies, establish an advisory committee to support the adoption of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida8e090df37f94927b1cb66739632bb7f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The advisory committee established pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall be known as the <quote>National Blockchain Deployment Advisory Committee</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1FAA56A742348F9AA384DFE2E67ED51"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership composition</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall consist of members appointed by the Secretary, which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H4ABBEFA2B85240B98EC410EC6E18B371"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F7238BC26734A989A5ED431B68DEA31"><enum>(B)</enum><text>representatives of Federal agencies (as determined necessary by the Secretary); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BD5EF3F816E4395B80F36738C17FEDA"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">covered nongovernmental representatives with expertise related to blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology (as determined necessary by the Secretary), which may include—</text><clause id="HBF1B40F5AB9141CA9D8435195BF61607"><enum>(i)</enum><text>blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology infrastructure operators, suppliers, service providers, and vendors;</text></clause><clause id="H2A43DFD03D2149B3B9443CC1DA6F1433"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>application developers building on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology;</text></clause><clause id="HA8CD60451C9A4897B87C76B035F481AB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>developers and organizations supporting the advancement and deployment of public blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology;</text></clause><clause id="H8818597B9ED2492A942D08976F21864B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>subject matter experts representing industrial sectors that can benefit from blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology;</text></clause><clause id="HA5994DADBC6C49CD8C79128D5B4679FD"><enum>(v)</enum><text>small, medium, and large businesses;</text></clause><clause id="H502BCD0CEE134BEAAFC5A1FFC9D1BFF5"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>think tanks and academia;</text></clause><clause id="H4C5BA01681B64B198669DA270D404548"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>nonprofit organizations and consumer groups;</text></clause><clause id="H80F2E2CD50BC4279A906E62DDE9BB0CE"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>cybersecurity experts;</text></clause><clause id="H0F58506D3CEB4A769DD09F5594D68D4F"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>rural stakeholders;</text></clause><clause id="H31622CFCCDED43B0ACC65CE54378FDAF"><enum>(x)</enum><text>covered nongovernmental representatives; and</text></clause><clause id="H74CC2EC0E42944F7A16712096FD02DCC"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>artists and the content creator community.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7F7CFD347E942B39925226D6BED5396"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination of advisory committee</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall terminate on the date that is 7 years after the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD337AA2A296D46079B3DDA02E3D47075"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text>The Secretary shall, on an ongoing basis, facilitate and support the development of a compendium of identified or recommended guidelines or best practices for the deployment of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization that—</text><paragraph id="H4C7B35513A6D494BA3F1F89472FB53F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support the deployment of technologies needed to advance the capabilities of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CF00DCED65E49A58EE8AE3F8D6271F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support the interoperability of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FD7F671C989460A89857256399030BE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support operations, including hashing and key storage and security systems, that form the foundation of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B27F14AB40C4246ABB806253A1B6727"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reduce cybersecurity risks that may compromise blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88374CFD629D402FBA86F0BFC8C04BC3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>quantify the value and potential cost savings associated with adoption of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization, including through comparative analyses of competing and existing technologies within specific industry applications.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H31D54804057B4370BDDAA4D255481138"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HFA0283D9A65D48F1B2732D620CB42D40"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consult closely and regularly with stakeholders, including private sector individuals and entities, and incorporate industry expertise;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0D4D20531684710B3D5B4FF8C4D89E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>collaborate with private sector stakeholders to identify prioritized, flexible, repeatable, performance-based, and cost-effective approaches to the deployment of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6D60DB704FD45E89810D0C741E58745"><enum>(3)</enum><text>make public research and information pertaining to the use of, and marketplace for, blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H226ACF142EF245488028AB0511A7AEFE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>develop standardized terminology for, and promote common understanding of, blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF1B487E3CFE4235A9C87AD1BB7A2BAE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>align the recommendations of the compendium described in subsection (d) with the goal of facilitating the ease of use of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H872BCA87595C4459836663A9F8D2ACE3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>support open-source infrastructure, data management, and authentication activities with respect to blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97BBCFE6912F484796FD8A54C81E1862"><enum>(7)</enum><text>consider the needs and interests of both the private and public sector, including small businesses and Federal, State, and local governments.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC56F379E2FB14A808FD10F27E2B7643D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed—</text><paragraph id="HF64A0696E58B471CADAE30F772ED8825"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to require a private entity to share information with the Secretary;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE8A0B3D6516470F8837740CF49A1761"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to require a private entity to request assistance from the Secretary;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B37A275A5F74402B0CB7E3576A4F987"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to require a private entity to implement any measure or recommendation suggested by the Secretary in response to a request by the private entity; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD264C26E05494488A2D0C58A41B59A76"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to require the adoption of the best practices described in subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H67FBE758523B4275AAAE231F70B54B35"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In implementing this section, the Secretary may, as appropriate, consult with the heads of relevant Federal agencies.</text></subsection></section><section id="H4631E76B3E804263B7B7F0970FE8FC3B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><subsection id="H0636772D2FB146369F504D51D1C3B669"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Interim reports</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall make public on the website of the Department of Commerce and submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="H002C78739C1E4372AD20899EDC98E4B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the activities of the Secretary under this title during the preceding year;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD0FB47D138B417EBA82F345289BC86D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any recommendations by the Secretary for additional legislation to strengthen the competitiveness of the United States with respect to blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H526F27C2FA02469AA5BE2549590D5CEE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of any emerging risks and long-term trends with respect to blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6751D23312B44C108869A47DA90B63E9" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months before the termination of the Advisory Committee pursuant to section 603(c)(3), the Secretary shall make available to the public on the website of the Department of Commerce and submit to the President, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a final report containing the findings, conclusions, and recommendations of the Advisory Committee.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

