<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H1B7677B9EC31440CB73D8195C0FECD25" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 152 : Federal Disaster Assistance Coordination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>H. R. 152</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250114">January 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Disaster Recovery Reform Act of 2018 to develop a study regarding streamlining and consolidating information collection and preliminary damage assessments, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H81951443DB3C4ECFBDE52AC0B2B2E9DE" style="OLC"><pagebreak></pagebreak><section id="H808233407B3F4450A707C7E80D44479E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Disaster Assistance Coordination Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H53CCBC0422144D6CB0AD7E9789AC7E29"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study to streamline and consolidate information collection and preliminary damage assessments</header><subsection id="H9482AB16142141F1A68C89A97381A0BA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1223 of the Disaster Recovery Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/254">Public Law 115–254</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57FA3416364B476AAE52690CBF416708" style="OLC"><section id="H185BC926462843BB81EF1EAEC1773D13"><enum>1223.</enum><header>Study to streamline and consolidate information collection and preliminary damage assessments</header><subsection id="H225392BAA4774FC08569617F01B7AEA0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Information collection</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator, in coordination with the Small Business Administration, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the Disaster Assistance Working Group of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, and other appropriate agencies, shall—</text><paragraph id="H409909B7C169414A99B0F7FBA565EE76"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a study and develop a plan, consistent with law, under which the collection of information from disaster assistance applicants and grantees will be modified, streamlined, expedited, efficient, flexible, consolidated, and simplified to be less burdensome, duplicative, and time consuming for applicants and grantees; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2233694F8074257833F9DCEEE908751"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop a plan for the regular collection and reporting of information on Federal disaster assistance awarded, including the establishment and maintenance of a website for presenting the information to the public.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5F42B17D9654318B851568E88BE6F08"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preliminary damage assessments</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator, in consultation with the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, shall convene a working group on a regular basis with the Secretary of Labor, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, the Secretary of Transportation, the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Economic Development, and other appropriate agencies as the Administrator considers necessary, to—</text><paragraph id="HD9546E0B6AD84C169F02428CD2134D32"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify and describe the potential areas of duplication or fragmentation in preliminary damage assessments after disaster declarations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48F764B674A943769552CCAD91E989AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determine the applicability of having one Federal agency make the assessments for all agencies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36C951D6537C466685AC62651BC9926A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify potential emerging technologies, such as unmanned aircraft systems, consistent with the requirements established in the FEMA Accountability, Modernization and Transparency Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> note), to expedite the administration of preliminary damage assessments.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H101CBEF024F14244A222241F3862829A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Comprehensive report</header><text>The Administrator shall submit one comprehensive report that comprises the plans developed under subsections (a)(1) and (a)(2) and a report of the findings of the working group convened under subsection (b), which may include recommendations, to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2943A5257C5A4C2A8D3DD775B45B4907"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The comprehensive report developed under subsection (c) shall be made available to the public and posted on the website of the Federal Emergency Management Agency—</text><paragraph id="H218D001DB6AC4B87B6CB8AECD62AF06A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in pre-compressed, easily downloadable versions that are made available in all appropriate formats; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF71690124FD48D1B4EDCD077EDA5746"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in machine-readable format, if applicable.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFFD368743060415D84260256638A48BB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sources of information</header><text>In preparing the comprehensive report, any publication, database, or web-based resource, and any information compiled by any government agency, nongovernmental organization, or other entity that is made available may be used.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8E3C807292F9421F8F5997461C5BF8A8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 180 days after submission of the comprehensive report, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, or a designee, and a member of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, or a designee, shall brief, upon request, the appropriate congressional committees on the findings and any recommendations made in the comprehensive report.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H89D827339F1B45ABB61F20FF28810CFA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The item relating to section 1223 in the table of contents of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/254">Public Law 115–254</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC5ACC7F9CED4A7BA700BEA4762D81FF" style="OLC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1223. Study to streamline and consolidate information collection and preliminary damage assessments.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250113" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives January 13, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

