<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV25B80-JMH-5T-C83">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2125 IS: Prying Into Chinese Tyrants' Unreported Riches, Earnings, and Secrets Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2125</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250618">June 18, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> (for himself and
                    <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>) introduced the following
                bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SLIN00">Select Committee on Intelligence</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To require a report on the wealth of the leadership of the Chinese Communist
            Party, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prying Into Chinese Tyrants' Unreported Riches, Earnings, and Secrets Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PICTURES Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa6a2f4255fc4650ab9021cda4a8ef92">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Findings</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="ided0965a8da3b4cdeb1b1e5c31fa21605"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>The Chinese Communist Party (CCP) operates as an opaque, authoritarian regime in which political power is concentrated in the hands of a relatively small group of senior officials.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id7645bb4c707d490cbc5c1dcf9aaf2308">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>The leadership of the CCP, including full members of the Central Committee and the Central Committee’s Politburo (also known as the Political Bureau) and Politburo Standing Committee, exert significant control over economic, military, and political affairs both within the People's Republic of China and externally.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id0ac493d820bb4fd1b6192ef34da5d81c">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>Numerous credible reports and investigations have revealed that senior CCP officials and their families have amassed substantial wealth, often hidden through opaque financial structures, foreign holdings, and proxies.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idb60115e7658b499dab7f88fa974c7993">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>A report issued by the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI) in March 2025 provided an important initial assessment of the financial assets of CCP leaders. A subsequent report, incorporating photographic evidence of CCP leaders’ wealth and corruption, could build upon that work to further expose the hypocrisy and duplicity of the Chinese Communist Party.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id932f8b41b8334b6a99428ee8534c9ede">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>Understanding the financial interests, personal assets, and overseas holdings of CCP leaders is essential to informing United States foreign policy, national security, and economic security decision-making.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida44ae06924e94befbe7d530a35a2d2c9">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Sense of Congress</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4200b438d43c448d9e041cb93819b631"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effectiveness and credibility of intelligence reporting on sensitive subjects, including the wealth of senior CCP officials, depends upon the full cooperation of all relevant components of the United States intelligence community; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6dadfb2c95174a34960a6cde8e73c89e">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all related nonpublic information, including classified intelligence, financial data, and foreign partner reporting, must be made available within the United States intelligence community to support such assessments to the fullest extent possible consistent with the protection of sources and methods.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb2ba68f311544eeca3b7c4d87435d87b">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>Report on the wealth of the leadership of the Chinese Communist Party</header>
            <subsection id="id4884c2c81aaa4d82bd6fb69a77aa5027">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not later than 180 days following the appointment of a new Central Committee within the CCP, the Director of National Intelligence shall post on a publicly available website of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence and submit to the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives a report on the wealth of the leadership of the Chinese Communist Party.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id1ced7c39a39a4cb5b4b19617bae739d1">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Elements</header>
 <text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include the following elements:</text>
                <paragraph id="ide4b71a7baa1640278f1052e035ae1aaa">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>A detailed assessment of the personal wealth, financial holdings, and business interests of full Central Committee members and the head of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection, including all immediate family members of such foreign persons, prioritizing the following individuals:</text>
                    <subparagraph id="idca0fff31d19e46f689956dd828a43271">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>The General Secretary of the Chinese Communist Party.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idca23faca9d8c4e12b7a95a8a16aed90e"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>Members of the Politburo Standing Committee.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idaaae275553a441c88895cc8b52ab3472">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>Members of the full Politburo.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="ida559a7e9477f46c7b0bd7912f2ceec70"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>Provincial-level Party Secretaries.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id198e9b46fdb44c04b15076902d16ff48">
                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>Members of the Central Military Commission.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id4bd76bad04754d67ac44a51538de464f"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>Documentation and, as available, photographic evidence of physical and financial assets owned or controlled directly or indirectly by such officials and their immediate family members, including, at a minimum—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="idffb05f6b5d004172b1ad6d2ba1a14843">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>real estate holdings inside and outside the People's Republic of China, including the Special Administrative Regions of Hong Kong and Macau;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id6f0b92612ce3489bae447e4825ea77ac">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>high-value personal assets, such as yachts, luxury vehicles, private aircraft; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idacdb70ccf4704fcbba61c3ed83a09f30">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>business holdings, investments, and financial accounts held in foreign jurisdictions.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id9da5da3dc5f04e148308e509dadf5276">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>Identification of financial proxies, business associates, or other entities used to obscure the ownership of such wealth and assets, including those referenced in ODNI’s March 20, 2025, report as a baseline.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id550bb0754f3f43109e54946e7ce64a5a">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>An assessment by the Director of National Intelligence regarding the level of cooperation and responsiveness of each relevant component of the intelligence community in providing information, analysis, and support for the preparation of the report, including whether any component failed to fully cooperate or provide requested nonpublic information.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idefb8d9fa812349bd9d987b2020724ad8">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>Nonpublic information related to the wealth of the leadership of the Chinese Communist Party, to the extent possible consistent with the protection of intelligence sources and methods, including information derived from classified sources, foreign partner reporting, financial intelligence, human sources, or other intelligence community holdings.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida2821dab8608473bba0d5fea4f9d5147">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Form</header>
 <text>The report posted and submitted under subsection (a) shall be in unclassified form, but the version submitted to Congress may include a classified annex as necessary.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="idb2c39a1bcbfa400dbd2e9efb914cfc95">
            <enum>5.</enum>
            <header>Intelligence community defined</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>intelligence community</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</external-xref>).</text>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

