<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELT25556-8T5-J8-NCJ">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1902 IS: Energy Threat Analysis Program Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>S. 1902</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20250522">May 22, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title>To require the Secretary of Energy to establish an energy threat analysis program, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HFEFDBCF45A0342C5B05797B64D50B2B1">
<section id="ide7ff5901ebe94aca9149e6ac7441eb6d" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Energy Threat Analysis Program Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ETAP Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf9430e405d9143c783d4ed81aac4966f"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id606bc13474bf4391a3f235bc53bcea46"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <quote>Department</quote> means the Department of Energy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddd4f837c67e64fb480c321df9b3fd298"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <quote>Program</quote> means the energy threat analysis program established under section 3.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5830fb3c1b5b434ea6a19da398dede5d"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="idaefb74af94504c1d9b113dfef6511b8a"><enum>3.</enum><header>Energy Threat Analysis Program</header> <subsection id="idc387d4b2648347379c36e7944a9f114b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As part of the program developed under section 40125(c) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18724">42 U.S.C. 18724(c)</external-xref>), the Secretary shall establish an energy threat analysis program—</text>
<paragraph id="idb18d75a6792540e4b5eee78ac2502356"><enum>(1)</enum><text>under which the Office of Cybersecurity, Energy Security, and Emergency Response, in consultation with the Office of Intelligence and Counterintelligence, may establish, for activities of the program to advance public-private operational collaboration—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id84f8d96d23e34cab8194e5706771b2bf"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an Energy Threat Analysis Center as a physical location; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide70fb357bedf46989f9b03264f90140b"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other additional facilities, as necessary;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id9bab9af77d774698b08870cb36800931"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to enhance situational awareness of threats to the security of the energy sector;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="ida4f8419a8d084dbd81a691157c705e68"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to analyze threats against the security of the energy sector;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idc619facb27ff44eab19a6f581a7a7372"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to identify relevant security threat mitigation measures for energy systems;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id0b2d27fbdc564631aedca7baa66518e1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to support relevant response and restoration activities for the energy sector under existing constructs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="ide126b5b609b34601a762c5fb10dbd2f1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to inform research and development activities in support of the security of critical energy systems, technologies, and components;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="ida1c30c2142f14d06b3ec50f96b23c281"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to conduct other security and resilience efforts identified by the Secretary;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id25246d861bfe48cc9af922edb5efc604"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to enhance and periodically test the emergency response capabilities of the Department;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id2db3d62d450644b8b5ef538bd8010137"> <enum>(9)</enum> <text>to expand cooperation of the Department with the intelligence community for energy sector-related threat collection and analysis;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id33b958a7514c43f781e396b190b305ed"><enum>(10)</enum><text>to enhance the tools of the Department and the Electricity Information Sharing and Analysis Center for monitoring the status of the energy sector; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="ida10c46e80590460ba0e0d80a43a742f3"><enum>(11)</enum><text>to expand industry participation in the Electricity Information Sharing and Analysis Center.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="id4782c0dd72b04336b0e0b86eed38aeeb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Program shall be—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e8c02769c9240c79b5d456d82361f54"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">directed by the Secretary;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2c732036b872436e8327c89dea240ac4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">managed by the Office of Cybersecurity, Energy Security, and Emergency Response; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd16658e2d5f04e4bb512c0bec51ba2c7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supported by the Office of Intelligence and Counterintelligence.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="id79b295fb96bc4a0fa623135e07c61a3c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The functions of the Program shall include—</text>
<paragraph id="idebb4ffc0c67c41a8a7f73b26194d6216"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supporting public-private operational collaboration for the government and industry—</text> <subparagraph id="id3028B01588E64708B0A30800AD2A16EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to develop actionable operational information relating to threats to the security of the energy sector; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id921CE0F0BB4C4242A5471BF20FA116A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to develop and offer meaningful threat mitigation advice and actions to enhance—</text> <clause id="id1EA056B768F140CEB2703A98BB60E49E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the defense of, and response to security threats to, the energy sector; and</text></clause>
<clause id="id49ACB1C4C7754253ABCAC95422E00680"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the resilience of the United States energy sector;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id2a17cab9af4049cdb10d6c95600f116e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enabling collaboration in the production and exchange of information on threat activity among government and industry to address energy security and resilience and shared energy sector security threats relating to national security, public health, safety, and the economy;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id26a63a91a9e343baafedc90246ad65e0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improving detailed understanding of national security risks associated with the energy sector that are or could be exploited by adversaries, including nation-states;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id068e44ec451a48d08157dc062cdf5b6e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>achieving a deeper understanding of the tactics, capabilities, and activities of threat actors that have the potential to impact systemic risks to the energy sector; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idaac4e17be5a44f3994706a615a8974de"><enum>(5)</enum><text>facilitating increased collaboration between government and industry, including the sharing of information regarding actual acute threat activity, including incidents, in a secure setting, physical and virtual, to facilitate the energy security and resilience of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="id679ca62c44ee4233b9d270949b486e47"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination and integration</header><text>In carrying out the responsibilities of the Program, the Program shall—</text>
<paragraph id="id08878cbb80224d6e907547234c701fb0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>align priorities of and enable support from—</text> <subparagraph id="id8ddcab9a6b554c72895ea7d55db3d827"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Department of Homeland Security, including the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="idfe1893e408f44194abd797a6037625ad"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of Defense, including United States Cyber Command, the National Security Agency, and the Army Interagency Training and Education Center of the National Guard Bureau;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id28a530a3dfe5480e92142681daaa79f6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Department of Justice, including the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="ida7dcd445bf9943769ddc342364163bde"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Office of the Director of National Intelligence; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id33ea13528c8c4fd6b8b754f990e5a3e7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>other Federal agencies and departments, as determined by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idaadeb3adc1f9417ea53a4b07f89eddab"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that the processes used by the Program are performed in collaboration with the activities of the Department of Homeland Security and the Department of Defense relating to cybersecurity, including—</text> <subparagraph id="id007538684b2b441ebf89e9cdd355885c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Joint Cyber Defense Collaborative of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id25c243fa162143bea41a47dd3647ada4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Cybersecurity Collaboration Center and Enduring Security Framework of the National Security Agency;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id35900702616441cda3dac56408b8038d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>regularly consult with appropriate representatives of non-Federal entities, such as—</text>
<subparagraph id="id5f5f925e5dc64dda9af1382c6fae3dd2"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>State, local, federally recognized Tribal, and territorial governments;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id42b742d0f9c44edb8900448b01a09f92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information sharing and analysis organizations, including information sharing and analysis centers such as the Electricity Information Sharing and Analysis Center; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id1ede89d24df34f48a22b9963ba955a73"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other appropriate representatives or entities, including private entities, such as manufacturers and vendors, that contribute to the energy sector, as determined by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="idd690e0b026904112995574c89c0d5ef3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>leverage the existing capabilities and services of advanced technology providers, including—</text>
<subparagraph id="id709ecde2476d4b92afd2b2e659cebe06"><enum>(A)</enum><text>National Laboratories with relevant capabilities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idf3015d8f2d5f4ecc8c4da58410daada9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>commercial threat intelligence production and cyber incident response entities; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id2b89ff2dd2d64902846f771c85a54986"><enum>(C)</enum><text>energy infrastructure vendors and integrators; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="idf5a9cf4aa5554078ae08ee8cf96ce885"><enum>(5)</enum><text>as appropriate, protect information submitted to and shared by the Program consistent with applicable laws, regulations, policies, and procedures.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="id26911cc1f0b74fa996301d556ba38964"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No right or benefit</header>
<paragraph id="id7a6a660149734fe38f1464a7550d9814"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The provision of assistance or information to governmental or private entities under this section shall be at the sole and unreviewable discretion of the Secretary.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="iddc62fdc7bd914048ab39df1583417576"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certain assistance or information</header><text>The provision of certain assistance or information to a governmental or private entity pursuant to this section shall not create a right or benefit, substantive or procedural, for any other governmental or private entity to similar assistance or information.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="id9a977872451d406486acf1516092f124"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Entities of concern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No entity of concern (as defined in section 10114(a) of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18912">42 U.S.C. 18912(a)</external-xref>)) shall participate in any manner in carrying out the functions of the Program.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida6f0673808c04bd2baf5fa56ecb08657"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Program shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="idaf017bf4f2324adba58ead5e767bc92c"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Nonapplicability of FACA</header><text>The Program shall be exempt from complying with the requirements of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (including regulations).</text></subsection> <subsection id="idad7e8453ec4644728edea973412fe4b8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Exemption from disclosure</header><text>Information shared by or with the Federal Government or a State, Tribal, or local government under this Act shall be—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf7b8289851de40c6b5bb6a345ed6ada2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">deemed to be voluntarily shared information;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id39315de7468d473597b2380badeb7451"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">exempt from disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code, or any provision of any State, Tribal, or local freedom of information law, open government law, open meetings law, open records law, sunshine law, or similar law requiring the disclosure of information or records; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc8c46ebc75c546e38708092fc6177674"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">withheld from the public, without discretion, under section 552(b)(3) of title 5, United States Code, or any provision of any State, Tribal, or local law requiring the nondisclosure of sensitive information or records.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="idddcc322623744d819b0b689cb84fac67"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit to Congress an annual report that describes, for the year covered by the report—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3ffb40f72e2f44b1b4406f19c6b39a8c"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the achievements of the Program; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d628f196a8049dda90aa6d9bf0ac3bc"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">areas for improvement with respect to the activities and operations of the Program.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided95a2ffd6ee4c0e96a92de7d6f2d77f"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $50,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2025 through 2029.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

