<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR25800-6VJ-MS-K47"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2565 IS: District of Columbia Sister City Integrity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2565</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250731">July 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit the District of Columbia government from entering into Sister City relationships with jurisdictions located in foreign adversary countries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H422B392D00B14C67BB382D36B0084667"><section section-type="section-one" id="ided397364977d4121a147ddf776f4fb48"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>District of Columbia Sister City Integrity Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H2695FD15743F403BA7EE5C756AA6ED9E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibiting <quote>Sister City</quote> relationships between District of Columbia and foreign adversaries</header><subsection id="HCA04D9A952C143078EF0B8654F6BDDF6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>foreign adversary country</term> has the meaning given the term <term>covered nation</term> in section 4872(f)(2) of title 10, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="H21F0E3CCB59D440ABABE3DFBEBCA9A28"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>The District of Columbia government may not enter into any Sister City relationship with a jurisdiction located in a foreign adversary country.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4E55E186EECD45FD86DEB941AF327350"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment of existing relationships</header><text>If a Sister City relationship between the District of Columbia and a jurisdiction located in a foreign adversary country is in effect on the date of enactment of this Act, the District of Columbia shall terminate the relationship not later than the earlier of—</text><paragraph id="HBF9E3A685188430FA38243A7CA483602"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date provided under the terms of the relationship; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48C151BB688B41DFA7B627838BDC90B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H317A6DF1B81B4ADA90EC6B20D15B1736"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Loss of certain funds</header><text>The District of Columbia may not use any Federal funds to provide liaison and outreach services to the diplomatic and international communities unless the District certifies to the President that the District is in compliance with this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

