<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9B28F7B793DA4F1EB6F014325BB38B0D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3429 IH: US-Japan-ROK Trilateral Cooperation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3429</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250515">May 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish an inter-parliamentary dialogue to facilitate closer
      cooperation between the United States, Japan, and the Republic of Korea on shared interests
      and values.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H89AF317D5B6B4515BDA32992A44008DF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H14953537B0B64161834385E233DABA3A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>US-Japan-ROK Trilateral Cooperation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H9398322A2D1A4FCFB882449ACB4DCAB5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H8BE6A8FB79E04EAB9D321ACF0FFD730F"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>the United States should continue to strengthen trilateral cooperation between the United States, Japan, and the Republic of Korea (in this Act referred to as the <quote>ROK</quote>) to enhance and implement a shared vision to meet regional challenges and to promote a free, open, inclusive, resilient, and healthy Indo-Pacific region;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7BFFA43CABF947A69EE6D3868E8F3A44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the historic Camp David summit on August 18, 2023, marked a new era of trilateral partnership between the United States, Japan, and the ROK, reaffirming their commitment to align collective efforts for regional security and prosperity;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H844F9AC96EA64A6BA397E198497B86D3"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>the Spirit of Camp David, as outlined in the joint statement, should guide future trilateral cooperation, emphasizing shared values, strategic alignment, and commitment to regional peace and stability;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H57F93ED9842B4E569D486D7CF7CBDB12">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>the United States, Japan, and the ROK should enhance Trilateral Maritime Security Cooperation to promote stability and freedom of navigation in the Indo-Pacific region;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1C947CEC658341F695C125AB0484F4DE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the United States, Japan, and the ROK should collaborate on countering foreign information manipulation and interference to protect democratic institutions and promote accurate information sharing;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCCE3A40C27614365B2876D52658250C5"> <enum>(6)</enum> <text>President Biden’s decision to elevate the US-Japan-ROK trilateral partnership to the leaders level was critical to bolstering cooperation, and all three countries should work to ensure that the Trilateral Leaders’ Summit continues to take place regularly;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD1EF3399AEF400ABB0F7EE847F6EB08">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>the ambitious framework for ongoing cooperation laid out by the three leaders at the historic Camp David summit on August 18, 2023, should continue and be strengthened; and</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2DCCF1CB087F43DF88029F19B4B15327">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
 <text>the formation of a regular US-Japan-ROK Inter-Parliamentary Dialogue will—</text> <subparagraph id="HDCC636802D6C44FD9AE2DF8031A96BAF"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>sustain and deepen engagement between senior officials of the three countries on a full spectrum of issues; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H2E6EE45B9C0E4D4B97008EB6B22CE49E">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>be modeled on the successful and long-standing bilateral inter-parliamentary groups between the United States and other allied nations.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph></section> 
<section id="HEB33633EFFA64DA7BCE52686069E0E46">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Establishment of US-Japan-ROK Inter-Parliamentary Dialogue</header>
      <subsection id="H0C24E2B6845041058901A4D544427580">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in consultation with Congress, shall seek to enter into negotiations with the Governments of Japan and the ROK with the goal of reaching a written agreement to establish a US-Japan-ROK Inter-Parliamentary Dialogue to facilitate closer cooperation on shared interests and values.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H4FA1FBB83CD24FBF8D29DFF2488D48D4">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>United States Group</header>
        <paragraph id="H7FC137321D9C458AB7F75C9CC60E3C87">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
 <text>At such time as the governments of the United States, Japan, and ROK enter into a written agreement described in subsection (a) to establish a US-Japan-ROK Inter-Parliamentary Dialogue, there shall be established a United States Group, which shall represent the United States at the US-Japan-ROK Inter-Parliamentary Dialogue.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB3434F2514224B159446526E4F636F14">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Membership</header>
          <subparagraph id="H9755520CD75B415090A72D36A725FCFD">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
 <text>The United States Group shall be comprised of not more than 8 Members of Congress.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H53909B7D6BC141AEBDDB2469A7004B76">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Appointment</header>
 <text>Of the Members of Congress appointed to the United States Group under subparagraph (A)—</text>
            <clause id="H12532C03A0E94C17B46964BE8189EA81">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>two shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, from among Members of the House, not fewer than one of whom shall be a member of the Committee on Foreign Affairs;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HB43FC4691CE44091AB14EB0F6F43B0B4">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>two shall be appointed by the House Minority Leader, from among Members of the House, not fewer than one of whom shall be a member of the Committee on Foreign Affairs;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H242E98FE8097452D82EE502ADEF63346">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>two shall be appointed by the Senate Majority Leader, from among Members of the Senate, not fewer than one of whom shall be a member of the Committee on Foreign Relations; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H8CB7C7EC7065465082E8CBE67ED91513">
              <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>two shall be appointed by the Senate Minority Leader, from among Members of the Senate, not fewer than one of whom shall be a member of the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC9D235C640AD4C198634361A40B96692">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <header>Term</header>
 <text>Appointments to the United States Group shall be for the duration of two years.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7CED550D39D64A66A284CECB092AF32E">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Meetings</header>
          <subparagraph id="H184D9B86D6BE4F6AA1E970BB23045E0E">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
 <text>The United States Group shall seek to meet not less frequently than annually with representatives and appropriate staff of the legislatures of Japan and the ROK, and representatives and appropriate staff of any other country invited by mutual agreement of the three countries.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H20776BD323844924BEEF65F09E55289A">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Limitation</header>
 <text>A meeting described in subparagraph (A) may be held—</text> <clause id="HC8C590A0E7274CE7B4D334B5E17DED0C"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>in the United States;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H33220EA79C7B491A8E654C677DB0F389">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>in another country during periods when Congress is not in session; or</text> </clause> <clause id="H26E317FC1ABD403E8B906A9F8AED3969"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <text>virtually.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H42AB18421EDA4D029675CD5C3940DE47">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Chairperson and Vice Chairperson</header>
          <subparagraph id="HF36641A972AF46A481D8D48BC459193C">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>Rotation</header>
 <text>The positions of Chairperson and Vice Chairperson of the United States Group shall alternate between the House and Senate delegations every two years, coinciding with each new Congress.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H80F7845059224733AA4138FD87CE7C42">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>House delegation</header>
            <clause id="HA38EFFD25F6D4E739FD8C9F79C68F2A8">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>In Congresses with an odd number, the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall designate the Chairperson of the United States Group from among members of the House delegation who are also members of the Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HB8D8CA57D6924CD481F9CED26893899A">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>In Congresses with an even number, the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall designate the Vice Chairperson of the United States Group from among members of the House delegation who are also members of the Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H0155013848184C79B5CD73D4E5372DD4">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <header>Senate delegation</header>
            <clause id="H6A9C5FFC33994DDC853D2E9D33840D73">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>In Congresses with an even number, the President Pro Tempore of the Senate shall designate the Chairperson of the United States Group from among members of the Senate delegation who are also members of the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HF2671D9E52294614A0CC4902237097D5">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>In Congresses with an odd number, the President Pro Tempore of the Senate shall designate the Vice Chairperson of the United States Group from among members of the Senate delegation who are also members of the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H00376AEECE5949CFA94B0622B382758D">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <header>Term</header>
 <text>The Chairperson and Vice Chairperson shall serve for the duration one each Congress.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H564AECED325A46C78404E44A333BD1C8">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <header>Private sources</header>
 <text>The United States Group may accept gifts or donations of services or property, subject to the review and approval, as appropriate, of the Committee on Ethics of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Ethics of the Senate.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HEA5A07FBDF6B40509AE90E5BBE6991B7">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <header>Certification of expenditures</header>
 <text>The certificate of the chairperson of the delegation from the House of Representatives or the delegation of the Senate of the United States Group shall be final and conclusive upon the accounting officers in the auditing of the accounts of the United States Group.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H34B19A8355FA427AA8F701237A92C0A3">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <header>Annual report</header>
 <text>The United States Group shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report for each fiscal year for which an appropriation is made for the United States Group, which shall include its expenditures under such appropriation and a description thereof.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

