<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-PAT25471-KJ9-KL-670">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2661 IS: To allow for the use of risk-based inspections for in-service breakout tanks.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2661</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250801">August 1, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</sponsor> introduced the following bill;
                which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and
                Transportation</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To allow for the use of risk-based inspections for in-service breakout
            tanks.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Risk-based inspections for in-service breakout tanks</header>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id02ed4f0bf5fc4391a5fe430c6e54687f">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, an owner or operator of a pipeline facility (as defined in section 60101 of title 49, United States Code) may use risk-based inspections to comply with the relevant inspection requirements imposed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/601">chapter 601</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, for in-service breakout tanks, including any relevant requirements established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/4/195">chapter 195</external-xref> of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id04d1e456ffd34737b8daaea5c4012e26">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Rulemaking</header>
 <text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation, acting through the Administrator of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration, shall revise section 195.432 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, to allow for risk-based inspections of in-service breakout tanks in accordance with subsection (a).</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

