<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-CAN25645-H2N-XR-K8G"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 304 ATS: Commemorating the 75th anniversary of the outbreak of the Korean War and reaffirming the critical importance of maintaining military readiness in defense of the United States and its allies.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 304</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250625" legis-day="20250624">June 25 (legislative day, June 24), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commemorating the 75th anniversary of the outbreak of the Korean War and reaffirming the critical importance of maintaining military readiness in defense of the United States and its allies.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas June 25, 2025, marks the 75th anniversary of the outbreak of the brutal three-year conflict known as the Korean War, which began when the armed forces of North Korea launched a full-scale invasion of the Republic of Korea;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States, under resolutions of the United Nations Security Council, responded to that unprovoked aggression and mobilized more than 1,700,000 United States soldiers, sailors, airmen, and marines, and led a unified United Nations Command to fight in defense of freedom and security on the Korean Peninsula;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 103,000 Americans were wounded, and 36,574 Americans made the ultimate sacrifice, giving their lives defending the security of the Republic of Korea, while more than 7,500 remain unaccounted for;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Korean War has long been referred to as the “Forgotten War,” which fails to recognize the significance of this noble chapter in American history, as well as the sacrifice and valor of American service members;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the defense of the Republic of Korea by United States and allied forces allowed for the development of the modern Republic of Korea into a robust market economy, a vibrant democracy, a strong ally of the United States, and a bedrock contributor to regional stability and the global community;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Republic of Korea endured immense hardship during the war, suffering 137,899 soldiers killed, 450,742 injured, and more than 30,000 missing or captured, in addition to almost 1,000,000 civilian casualties, yet demonstrated extraordinary resilience and resolve in the face of destruction and invasion;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States-Republic of Korea alliance, formed with the signing of the Mutual Defense Treaty Between the United States and the Republic of Korea on October 1, 1953, is a mutual commitment to the other’s defense, in accordance with constitutional processes, in the event of an armed attack in the Pacific area on either of the parties;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the hard-learned lessons of the Korean War underscore the ongoing need for strategic, operational, and tactical readiness across all branches of the military in an increasingly dangerous global environment; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the words engraved on the Korean War Veterans Memorial—<quote>Freedom is not free</quote>—remain a solemn reminder of the cost of liberty and the importance of military preparedness: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idd1fbd0f60446455185e72776dbcfc35d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commemorates the 75th anniversary of the outbreak of the Korean War and honors the bravery, sacrifice, and service of the United States Armed Forces and allies who fought to defend the people of the Republic of Korea from being conquered by the communists of North Korea, the People's Republic of China, and the Soviet Union;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3052045cd5d94f728cc6f8630e0cd0fe"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the Republic of Korea as a vital treaty ally and linchpin of peace, security, trade, and democratic values for Northeast Asia and the Indo-Pacific region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id51469d517e7b496cbe2a4e4ece41b730"><enum>(3)</enum><text>acknowledges the enduring legacy of the Korean War in shaping United States defense policy and alliances in the Indo-Pacific region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7bcefa6569e049eaac04eb27cf1bafb4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reaffirms the commitment of the United States to maintaining a strong, modern, and fully prepared military force capable of deterring aggression and defending national security interests;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id66ec1af33cf44ca5852dc4f72e4b65dd"><enum>(5)</enum><text>urges continued investment in training, equipment, and support for members of the United States Armed Forces to ensure military readiness across all domains, including land, sea, air, space, and cyber; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id349501e756cc4b9da3299807e677d0dd"><enum>(6)</enum><text>calls upon all people of the United States to remember the Korean War not as the <quote>Forgotten War,</quote> but as the <quote>Noble War,</quote> an endeavor that preserved freedom for millions and exemplified the courage, sacrifice, and resilience of the United States Armed Forces.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

