<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA3CC889B4DBA4513991D75F2D841D17D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1105 IH: Disaster Resiliency and Coverage Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1105</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250206">February 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001123">Mr. Cisneros</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000136">Mr. Vasquez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to require the President to establish an individual household disaster mitigation program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0E25A6AB5A8E4B0984E35E0CC3904215" style="OLC"><section id="H0DD45AA61109484AAC030A06956C4829" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Disaster Resiliency and Coverage Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD8AA13090D834089AC26E786D8A9196D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Individual household disaster mitigation program</header><subsection id="HC2A63301C1D9446DB87242224D78B1AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title II of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5131">42 U.S.C. 5131 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3683D991417E4E009A737F49B0CE3BF5" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HC2046B15A25E45EABC959215E8ADC6D2"><enum>207.</enum><header>Individual household disaster mitigation program</header><subsection id="HFE32A09C8AD543A9B82C72387BA7A9A4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall establish a program to provide grants to States and Indian tribal governments for qualifying pre-disaster mitigation activities on individual residential households that are at risk of being damaged by a major disaster.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE62D5394488146B6A242CF566D9AA1A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of eligible disaster areas</header><text>In carrying out the program under this section, the President shall—</text><paragraph id="HB7B9E8A0CD3F45368D696004213A595D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish eligible disaster areas, in consultation with States, that the President determines to be at risk of a natural hazard, including—</text><subparagraph id="H25C4425CE6A4417A81F97EC41C6917A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the type, likelihood, and severity of each potential natural hazard affecting each such risk area; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1383BE56E253460281DF1DE4B0F0DEF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by taking into account previously declared major disasters impacting such areas; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F97D2D96C274018AC7D16D2645BFE64"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide technical assistance to the States or Indian tribal governments in developing the plan described in subsection (c) and administering grants provided for individual households under the program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37BCECDBCD9C4192BE84061B601FF469"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less frequently than every 5 years, review and update the eligible disaster areas that the President determines to be at risk of a natural disaster, including a description of the type and severity of each potential natural disaster affecting each such risk area; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F23B13CDF894257A8FF28DEACEF180B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with relevant governmental and nongovernmental experts in order to ensure that such determinations are made using current scientific standards and tools available in establishing, reviewing, and updating the eligible disaster areas that the President determines to be at risk of a natural disaster.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H58704EA1E2114E63AFF3B4573AD9B737"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Plan for eligible activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for a grant under this section, a State or Indian tribal government shall submit to the President a plan that includes—</text><paragraph id="HF105E1B805954506B9E76CED3000249F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each disaster risk area established by the President under subsection (b) in which the State or Indian tribal government proposes to provide funds under the program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0755DBB9FFC243A5A609C095E4D434AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the availability and affordability of homeowner insurance coverage in each such risk area, including a breakdown of coverage offered by—</text><subparagraph id="H5CB87C1AB69A4E1DB4F930FCA3024EDC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">private insurance companies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28A4A7DAFD5041CEA19E8E1FCC6C4D36"><enum>(B)</enum><text>State residual markets; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D92EFFFCF5046ECB1FC751DF832BF9F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>State and Federal insurance programs;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A3BCE287FB947D387679BBB6CC4C789"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of factors that may be adversely impacting insurance availability and affordability;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35293DAFBEB04BB3BE89F9B5CBDB7F0B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a list of each qualifying mitigation activity that is eligible for funds in each such risk area;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H266D110EE7344251B4C2158FF1FA59E7"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the criteria by which a State or Indian tribal government will evaluate applicants, which shall include consideration of the household income of the applicant and whether the residence is located in a Community Disaster Resilience Zone; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FAE02A3A652436EA1304D4CBCDBC60D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a financial plan that includes maximum amounts available to a household for each qualifying mitigation activity.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H868EF85BDF8C4DD3829B74111EA0E383"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing the program under this section, the President, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency and the Director of the Federal Insurance Office, shall consult with the chief insurance regulators from the 50 States, the District of Columbia, and the territories of the United States, insurance industry stakeholders, including insurers, reinsurers, agents, brokers, and insurance-funded research organizations, and consumer and environmental stakeholders to determine what qualifying mitigation activities are likely to incentivize the availability and purchase of residential property insurance and other financial risk transfer mechanisms in eligible disaster areas.</text></subsection><subsection id="H076FDC1785134A5880EB6597BB027158"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitations</header><paragraph id="H8FEEE740CF6D4FD08188F45EFBF209EE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>High-risk areas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds provided under this section may only be used in eligible disaster areas that the State or Indian tribal government determines are at a high risk of experiencing a major disaster for the major disaster that presents such a risk.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F4A25A4E38A42AD81B60842EF94A55B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation based on adjusted gross income</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual shall not be eligible to receive a grant under this section if the adjusted gross income of such individual exceeds $250,000 ($500,000 in the case of a joint tax return) for the taxable year ending in the calendar year immediately preceding the calendar year with respect to which a grant application is filed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE35A596E7CBB4010A8D79BAC3B07392C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definition of adjusted gross income</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>adjusted gross income</term> has the meaning given such term in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/62">section 62(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4D41A9327EC74594A5D4C41D858AE144" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Multi-Tiered mitigation standards</header><paragraph id="H0573216128084E4B844C1E146C183E32" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, shall establish mitigation standards for individual households that carry out each type of qualifying mitigation activity eligible for funds under the program, which may include a multi-tiered standard. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H916660200BBF4A448AF76DF8AB8CB534" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>In establishing the mitigation standards under paragraph (1), the President, acting through the Administrator—</text><subparagraph id="HFD4052A2CC7D4EC38DF91785120C891D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall consider any standards established by—</text><clause id="H4901E7875CCA4F2CB49ED06085E5B2BD" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Insurance Institute for Business and Home Safety;</text></clause><clause id="H5233B3DAA413470EAE23A6A431249006"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the chief insurance regulators from the 50 states, the District of Columbia, and the territories of the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="H7B951A41B55C4BEA8E96A85BC7986E02" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other standard-issuing entity determined appropriate; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H526BE2DF455F4C638016B75063607C9D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may—</text><clause id="H61784D3E64E04B8FA08BB511752EAB7D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>adopt a standard considered under subparagraph (A); or</text></clause><clause id="HDDB19AD0297B4A6483B76551679C2F90" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establish alternative standards.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC10CAA4CDC434F2EB15295DEF6B24F9C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Guidance to insurance providers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for a grant under the program under this section, a State or Indian tribal government shall establish, and make available to the public, guidance to insurance providers and consumers that includes suggested incentives for households that carry out disaster mitigation activities under the program, including—</text><paragraph id="H6C679A33B98E4AC69E698F8551B81FFF" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the mitigation standards established under subsection (f);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25E738BE3F3347F4A1B6CD2C62DDB948"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increased consumer coverage choice; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93AF6B401E0F4FD2A4D74CAB99073DEB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">actuarially supported favorable pricing benefits such as discounts, rebates, or premium credits.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H987E43D6FB914D00A3E4319D24EA7FB6"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Maximum amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or Indian tribal government may not provide more than an amount of $10,000, not to exceed the actual cost of mitigation activities, to any individual household under the program. Such amount shall be increased yearly to reflect any increase in the Consumer Price Index. </text></subsection><subsection id="H6F85F7C2651043DB88CA2B4A93788A98"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definition of qualifying mitigation activity</header><text>In this section, the term <term>qualifying mitigation activity</term> means an activity relating to a housing unit—</text><paragraph id="H367B1D1BBC074103A827E9BF8111E67B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for property to—</text><subparagraph id="H2052DFCE184C43518B8EB4B1ACDA4432"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improve the strength of a roof deck attachment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F2FB3AEAD794A77BACD77DC6CCD7CBB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>create a secondary water barrier to prevent water intrusion or mitigate against potential water intrusion from wind-driven rain;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5E4990A6F98476CBF295D1045E702D7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improve the durability, impact resistance (not less than class 3 or 4 rating), or fire resistance (not less than class A rating) of a roof covering;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2A7B7E60EC94658AFC9F259E245BD9C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>brace gable-end walls;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7ADB2365A38340CFA19ABB84CDE25A5B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>reinforce the connection between a roof and supporting wall;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88D32BD91C2648FE9A44B3BC897293B8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>protect openings from penetration by wind-borne debris;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E2F4F48407646578D0D019E7AD40B81"><enum>(G)</enum><text>protect exterior doors and garages from natural hazards;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9464259887104624B7F65938F0E3FAA6"><enum>(H)</enum><text>complete measures contained in the publication of the Federal Emergency Management Agency entitled <quote>Wind Retrofit Guide for Residential Buildings</quote> (P–804);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H149ADCA1AAF24B74A9FACDFC75C30B32"><enum>(I)</enum><text>elevate the qualified dwelling unit, as well as utilities, machinery, or equipment, above the base flood elevation or other applicable minimum elevation requirement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H025A79E469DA4B22A3F13505F57498F9"><enum>(J)</enum><text>seal walls in the basement of the qualified dwelling unit using waterproofing compounds; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07318DC013C04497BE40D2447CE613F8"><enum>(K)</enum><text>protect propane tanks or other external fuel sources;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA61B73C9F9C140F482D62387ACB6B317"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to install—</text><subparagraph id="H08532DE4AD0F4E5D9F4F669E4C7FA865"><enum>(A)</enum><text>check valves to prevent flood water from backing up into drains;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD95D3D91F9284A61B6176296F1C5EED8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>flood vents, breakaway walls or open lattice for homes located in V zones;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC7F865B8452492F875D338696454F88"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a stormwater drainage system or improve an existing system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H258AA4DE7D5A4129BF7D0D9CA8DE2C66"><enum>(D)</enum><text>natural or nature-based features for flood control, including living shorelines;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3109AC926134063B7131D4ABA30F1D3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>roof coverings, sheathing, flashing, roof and attic vents, eaves, or gutters that conform to ignition-resistant construction standards;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE55B726491841948539B9918882CA88"><enum>(F)</enum><text>wall components for wall assemblies that conform to ignition-resistant construction standards;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3138889BD844D1193C111FB05516969" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a wall-to-foundation anchor or connector, or a shear transfer anchor or connector;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABE871DBFE9944A2B14E8C938FC4B51B" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>wood structural panel sheathing for strengthening cripple walls;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2081511FCDEC4A6E99F1ED5FD3D2B73E" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>anchorage of the masonry chimney to the framing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02C3201258F64B58AED240D53FACF798" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><text>prefabricated lateral resisting systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CE3F6AB578F49E98506F81226B7F506" commented="no"><enum>(K)</enum><text>a standby generator system consisting of a standby generator and an automatic transfer switch;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF76DA35DC84C42C490506DF3B3D759BD" commented="no"><enum>(L)</enum><text>a storm shelter that meets the design and construction standards established by the International Code Council and the National Storm Shelter Association (ICC–500), or a safe room that satisfies the criteria contained in—</text><clause id="HCC773721F5FE417E9CC5B5FB3A4B8B93" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the publication of the Federal Emergency Management Agency entitled <quote>Safe Rooms for Tornadoes and Hurricanes</quote> (P–361); or</text></clause><clause id="H2B03513971894EE8B82D08ECE6D681AC" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the publication of the Federal Emergency Management Agency entitled <quote>Taking Shelter from the Storm</quote> (P–320);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64AA4B616D614660A94849ED04C43D40" commented="no"><enum>(M)</enum><text>a lightning protection system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CB92DAADC86473CB33674A293AD9D89" commented="no"><enum>(N)</enum><text>exterior walls, doors, windows, or other exterior dwelling unit elements that conform to ignition-resistant construction standards;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H828D5C1651354C378DBC8269CC91E4E7" commented="no"><enum>(O)</enum><text>exterior deck or fence components that conform to ignition-resistant construction standards;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D0CE4A665F640E0BE015EA28F23AD95"><enum>(P)</enum><text>structure-specific water hydration systems, including fire mitigation systems such as interior sprinkler systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF485227917A54F518646CF375B2FD1AD"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>flood openings for fully enclosed areas below the lowest floor of the dwelling unit;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44164B4B7D284C4DA3E6329EA8090FD8"><enum>(R)</enum><text>lateral bracing for wall elements, foundation elements, and garage doors or other large openings to resist seismic loads; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9FF0BDB41004408BB24E5DB85B86507"><enum>(S)</enum><text>automatic shutoff valves for water and gas lines;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H99FDD91DB5BF42CFBE3C766027B01EE4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for services or equipment to—</text><subparagraph id="HEDB7770EFA5E444FBAB879FF84D09A6B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>create buffers around the qualified dwelling unit through the removal or reduction of flammable vegetation, including vertical clearance of tree branches;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0E811D85F0C49B884BCB95F175951D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>create buffers around the dwelling unit through—</text><clause id="H9785BD47F72446A2A655771AAF00DA00"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the removal of exterior deck or fence components or ignition-prone landscape features; or</text></clause><clause id="HF85C525FA03F4B0AA274470DDF91C60A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>replacement of the components or features described in clause (i) with components or features that conform to ignition-resistant construction standards;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9027B8CCE6924A5B870B8B916C54270E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>perform fire maintenance procedures identified by the Federal Emergency Management Agency or the United States Forest Service, including fuel management techniques such as creating fuel and fire breaks; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H579F5E40A5A449A9A1D4E4FC4E9BCEDB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>replace flammable vegetation with less flammable species;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H03D128D57D4543E4A45DE8634851EC8E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>for property relating to satisfying the standards required for receipt of a FORTIFIED designation from the Insurance Institute for Business and Home Safety, provided that the qualified dwelling unit receives such designation following installation of such property;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCCED1848FC544F28123040E697F240F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for property relating to satisfying the standards required for receipt of a Wildfire Prepared Homes designation from the Insurance Institute for Business and Home Safety, provided that the qualified dwelling unit receives such designation following installation of such property; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H195003FC33FE43B1880EC084538361A1"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for any other hazard mitigation activity identified by the President, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency and the hazard mitigation advisory committee established in subsection (k), for mitigation of a natural hazard.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC82BE7CBDE27471BB364D720C40A2B9F"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Hazard mitigation advisory committee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall establish a hazard mitigation advisory committee that shall—</text><paragraph id="H0A0A021432F241A0B8703BA28AE202F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consist of 50 representatives, including representatives from—</text><subparagraph id="H7E569B56CAAF477BB5256B646230B981"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the State Insurance Commissioners;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C76079241F642C2994C1E8D03CD62A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>private insurance companies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H089932F16A4C41E192D8D5CD699ECE1A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>private reinsurance companies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01242BDC998F4FBBB99745E3980683F2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>insurance broker companies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2E706B9BFBE4F4DB1FED19791A3D6E1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>insurance-funded research organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13EC0F2449E34E498FC3FB49F74761B7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>consumer advocate organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF15DFC032DAF401BAF856281DE2C9326"><enum>(G)</enum><text>State, local, and tribal firefighting agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06AF81BD6C5E4016B8FDA66EDD3346E3"><enum>(H)</enum><text>State-sponsored insurance plans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BCC170A04CF426D833ECB768714792C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>realtor associations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB75E12E34BA54150871CDDE68AADBDB7"><enum>(J)</enum><text>home builder associations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE22E1E67215D41289A6E7B6E416A3286"><enum>(K)</enum><text>State, local, and tribal emergency responders;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DCE8A9E6F654C448D621CCBFC236606"><enum>(L)</enum><text>State and tribal emergency managers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FBCAF7809FE4EFE9660A6F7EA0A0616"><enum>(M)</enum><text>State and tribal hazard mitigation officers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9296A344B94435BAEDB9585DEBA63F4"><enum>(N)</enum><text>relevant academic experts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37B022DD8B264A0586CA2F38DEABC72A"><enum>(O)</enum><text>building code associations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09D3583CB9774F8B911F419F79706006"><enum>(P)</enum><text>agricultural groups; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2527C7D125E44334B394DC82537B6719"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>environmental organizations; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD5398637E44478E9C530A1302F84BF1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advise the President on developments in emerging hazard mitigation research and testing and recommend additions to the qualified hazard mitigation activities eligible under this program, including reviewing the effectiveness of hazard mitigation systems, products, and designations submitted to the advisory committee by private or nongovernmental companies or organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDB4562115DCB42089DE10AAB376B0775"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall—</text><paragraph id="H6A1B76652698433E919DC9050D8B03A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require a State or any other entity to base the assessment of the status of the availability of homeowner insurance coverage required under subsection (c)(2) on data not already collected by that entity absent this requirement; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H32851EB4F5854052B0FA12B883C2CE8F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be construed to preempt the State regulation of the business of insurance or require, by the Federal Government or any State government, any insurance provider to alter the underwriting, pricing, and distribution of insurance.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HF1EBC1D6F9A74123822C5229CD143AA5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tax treatment of individual household disaster mitigation program</header><paragraph id="H9EBFA2633CB848B0B5C3CF1F97EBED1F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/139">Section 139</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating subsection (h) as subsection (i) and by inserting after subsection (g) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6E8F37AA4D75445E91205A9C4F22D1D7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H8EE997C04D8D472DA2EA15E9F255B646"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Individual household disaster mitigation program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Gross income shall not include amounts received under section 207 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H236E8DFB27FB443A86394A99F57041CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by this subsection shall apply to amounts received after the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H792543360906476183AF6FD35BF6A717" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exclusion of amounts received from State-based catastrophe loss mitigation programs</header><subsection id="HDEBA344EF04B43608DCE24CF5081D8EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/139">Section 139</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by the preceding provisions of this Act, is amended by redesignating subsection (i) as subsection (j) and by inserting after subsection (h) the following new subsection: </text><quoted-block id="H4B268975AB78452898D924C1CCE26BBC" style="OLC"><subsection id="H08288E76ABFA43C79E0995B68E0ECCB0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>State-Based catastrophe loss mitigation programs</header><paragraph id="HAAFA5DDA62794FD1A019A123649FDBA6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Gross income shall not include any amount received by an individual as a qualified catastrophe loss mitigation payment under a program established or administered by a State, or a political subdivision or instrumentality thereof, for the purpose of making such payments.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H70743360042F43B1A3DFDEB6AD7ABD4C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified catastrophe loss mitigation payment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>qualified catastrophe loss mitigation payment</term> means any amount which is received by an individual to make improvements to such individual’s residence for the sole purpose of hazard mitigation with respect to such residence.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H0091105F42D94A8C8A42D597699B9DE6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No increase in basis</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of subsection (g)(3) shall apply in the case of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H6B821AE785534CB186C44C5B1CC8386F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="HABAB19544AA745989AD387971F10C8E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 139(d) is amended by striking <quote>and qualified</quote> and inserting <quote>, qualified catastrophe mitigation payments, and qualified</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF73AFF0421A2464DABF713BA9FA38511"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 139(i) (as redesignated by subsection (a)) is amended by striking <quote>or qualified</quote> and inserting <quote>, qualified catastrophe mitigation payment, or qualified</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3235D9B2462246189DBEA50ED2A3C15A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section><section id="H0F5004FE1F954B92B68693698FA300F5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Exclusion from gross income of certain emergency agricultural assistance</header><subsection id="H42EC974A45D04BE8B6ADB5EF9BCEF061"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/139">Section 139</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by the preceding provisions of this Act, is amended by redesignating subsection (j) as subsection (k) and by inserting after subsection (i) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBA53079F42AE434ABC71CEE359747E96" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HE1D3AD33AE1E45FEA5B1F68D360F4513"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Certain agricultural assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>qualified disaster relief payment</term> shall include any assistance received under any of the following:</text><paragraph id="H43652D0F43E7449BB8394E65AFEFA5F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance received under the Wildfires and Hurricanes Indemnity Program Plus under subpart O of part 760 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0E540E9E77B4B2F815E50B3D3E13BED"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance received under section 1501 of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/9081">7 U.S.C. 9081</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5191976018994C24B5C6E3C6B19B0CA2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Noninsured crop assistance under section 196 of the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7333">7 U.S.C. 7333</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB5B99C5198347F8B762D74EF645BE20"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance under a food assistance program under part 9 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF097697E479C49D59DB49FEA6D977949"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance under title IV of the Agricultural Credit Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2201">16 U.S.C. 2201 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H238D820EA9E64C1685EC414D3E2C0CD2"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance under the Quality Loss Assistance Program.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HD20E966C2EB94E69A0490421B4B931B9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section><section id="H6401846C2C6E4A9A9CC67B9CBAAF2144"><enum>5.</enum><header>Credit for disaster mitigation expenditures</header><subsection id="H0C5BD364748F46BD93341969E406C385"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart B of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 27 the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H45CBDCE972E74C838E2E4A8DA18A2145" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H81B7D96077C241D99CEFF4C47B6378C3"><enum>28.</enum><header>Disaster mitigation expenditures</header><subsection id="HB18E8B32C2F24413BC5B399737C01C50"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year an amount equal to 30 percent of the expenditures paid for qualifying mitigation activities paid or incurred by the taxpayer during such taxable year with respect to real property owned or leased by the taxpayer.</text></subsection><subsection id="H701D23FE12F44644AD95AA43DFA0712C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified disaster mitigation activities</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="HA5B66DABD4A148239F4B9E8EE8256339"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualifying mitigation activity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualifying mitigation activity</term> has the meaning given such term in section 207(j) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F45232C781744DFA853189A3E1C4C4E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of reimbursements</header><text>Any amount originally paid or incurred by the taxpayer which is reimbursed by a State under a qualified State disaster mitigation program shall be treated as paid by such State (and not by such taxpayer).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCDB592ED06014976911664057692C23F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application with other credits</header><paragraph id="H1396FDCD958144BD95A41CC33787E820"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Business credit treated as part of general business credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">So much of the credit which would be allowed under subsection (a) for any taxable year (determined without regard to this subsection) that is attributable to expenditures made in the ordinary course of the taxpayer’s trade or business (or, in the case of expenditures made by a State, would have been expenditures made in the ordinary course of the taxpayer’s trade or business if made by the taxpayer) shall be treated as a credit listed in section 38(b) for taxable year (and not allowed under subsection (a)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6278865FF2FD4816B7A4277389F60BEB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Personal credit</header><text>For purposes of this title, the credit allowed under subsection (a) for any taxable year (determined after application of paragraph (1)) shall be treated as a credit allowable under subpart A for such taxable year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB17A90130EEB49CDB84D647C72709D3C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reduction of credit percentage where taxpayer expenditures less than 30 percent</header><paragraph id="HDD645CC11ED54A19B75D5ED745987BAA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the expenditure percentage with respect to any item of expenditure described under subsection (a) is less than 30 percent, subsection (a) shall be applied by substituting <quote>the expenditure percentage</quote> for <quote>30 percent</quote> with respect to such item of expenditure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H816194EEAA2747B180A82E41D421EF17"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Expenditure percentage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>expenditure percentage</term> means, with respect to any item of expenditure described under subsection (a) any portion of which is paid or incurred by a State, the ratio (expressed as a percentage) of—</text><subparagraph id="H6A55EEF77DDE414DA120FF2474CCFAA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the taxpayer’s expenditure for such item, divided by</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H325F390D4CEF4AB1883F11449B4B74BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the sum of the taxpayer’s and such State’s expenditures for such item.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC75F90EA3B52425AACFD654E452BF03D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Special rules</header><paragraph id="H2D4E081B412942E0867E511C8A367FE0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Treatment of expenditures related to marketable timber</header><text>An expenditure shall not be taken into account for purposes of this section (whether made by the taxpayer or a State) if such expenditure is properly allocable to timber which is sold or exchanged by the taxpayer. The preceding sentence shall not apply to the extent that such amount exceeds the gain on such sale or exchange.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3AC431160F74653B509B44A4E8E4C88"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Basis reduction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subtitle, if the basis of any property would (but for this paragraph) be determined by taking into account any expenditure described under subsection (a), the basis of such property shall be reduced by the amount of the credit allowed under subsection (a) with respect to such expenditure (determined without regard to subsection (c)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA132E29C70D448C6B23C765C26B729EB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text>The amount of any deduction or other credit allowable under this chapter for any expenditure for which a credit is allowable under subsection (a) shall be reduced by the amount of credit allowed under such subsection for such expenditure (determined without regard to subsection (c)).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H28F5FD9623434AA7A2D5938F19DD4332"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="HE6D2450230A14883BE2E3259B137C79F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 38(b) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (40), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (41) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H62C905D41F7C4154860CD5D8C7F5A08F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HCB54A7622A9C4AC08543FC95DDA5E77F"><enum>(42)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the portion of the disaster mitigation expenditures credit to which section 28(c)(1) applies.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2A01922ED5C4A348BF065B69AD61420"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 1016(a) of such Code is amended by redesignating paragraphs (35) through (38) as paragraphs (36) through (39), respectively, and by inserting after paragraph (34) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9CB34C59037D4EC28CA391EBEABFEB31" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H37A526D5BDEC41A3AF36E885EF141177"><enum>(35)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent provided in section 28(e)(2),</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HE88324B6711C48F8882006603CCE0926"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for subpart B of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 27 the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF5689F3114C14AF5989CBFEE3455D573" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H45CBDCE972E74C838E2E4A8DA18A2145" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H81B7D96077C241D99CEFF4C47B6378C3" level="section">Sec. 28. Qualified disaster mitigation expenditures.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4AB9E292DA60479780BBDD18ECB6EEE7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to expenditures paid or incurred after the date of the enactment of this Act, in taxable years ending after such date.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

