<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE0ACE39587FE449B946A68001C24411F" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 468 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the week of June 1 through June 7, 2025, as “National Trailer Safety Week” in the United States, and supporting the goals and ideals of National Trailer Safety Week to educate American motorists about the importance of proper towing techniques and maintenance.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 468</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250603">June 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000067">Mr. Yakym</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the week of June 1 through June 7, 2025, as <quote>National Trailer Safety Week</quote> in the United States, and supporting the goals and ideals of National Trailer Safety Week to educate American motorists about the importance of proper towing techniques and maintenance.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas <quote>National Trailer Safety Week</quote> was launched to raise awareness about the need for increased education on trailer safety to further reduce injuries and fatalities on the road;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas educating end-users is crucial to utilize the connections that dealers and manufacturers have with consumers in order to raise awareness of proper towing techniques and maintenance;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas national trailer growth remains high, with 964,000 new light- and medium-duty trailers registered in 2024; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the National Association of Trailer Manufacturer’s Trailer Safety Week reaches hundreds of thousands of individuals each year, and is the first nationwide traffic safety initiative aimed at addressing safe towing practices for light- and medium-duty trailers: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H30E1FE94115146BB9133306B694165DD"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HD8B15B9D25B34957BC5ED037ADD25A68"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HCFC673068852481995D0D98C83D12109"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National Trailer Safety Week</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7900F70C10A4464A8EFCA7764ECBDDAC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses strong support for—</text> <subparagraph id="HC05D904C616845349A500DA99C064C75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the goals and ideals of National Trailer Safety Week;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3B6FCA4E5D3F4110ADDC21E77A263A3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>efforts to increase awareness of the importance of being committed to trailer safety;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEDEA69624DEC4E0FADF21DEF93A8DEE3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>educating end-users about proper trailer maintenance and usage;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7EC815BC922842E89F4AC81443C551B6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>creating a stronger partnership and alliance between stakeholders of the industry, including suppliers, trailer dealers, and manufacturers, and end-users; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H106F185B90D04B31915F4E3486CF2B5D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>encouraging the people of the United States to participate in National Trailer Safety Week events and activities, and educate themselves and others on the importance of regularly inspecting, maintaining, and operating light- and medium-duty trailers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

