<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HD7231FC5611544A8858353A17F39AFEA" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 195 RH: Of inquiry requesting the President of the United States to furnish certain information to the House of Representatives relating to the operations of the Social Security Administration after January 20, 2025, including information on the Department of Government Efficiency’s access to the Social Security Administration and to information in the possession of such Administration.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
<calendar display="yes">House Calendar No. 11</calendar>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 195</legis-num>
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–29]</associated-doc>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250321">March 21, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor></action-desc>
</action>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250321">March 21, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported adversely, referred to the House Calendar, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">Of inquiry requesting the President of the United States to furnish certain information to the House of Representatives relating to the operations of the Social Security Administration after January 20, 2025, including information on the Department of Government Efficiency’s access to the Social Security Administration and to information in the possession of such Administration.</official-title>
</form>
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="HB8714929EA0C4929BEDA4023014661B8"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H8214F06E79FC4216A5EA2FAD5648741F"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the President of the United States is requested to furnish the House of Representatives, not later than 14 days after the date of adoption of this resolution, copies of any document, record, audio recording, memorandum, call log, correspondence (electronic or otherwise), audit trails and audit logs, written agreements, or other communication in his possession, or any portion of any document, record, audio recording, memorandum, call log, correspondence (electronic or otherwise), or other communication, that refers or relates to the following:</text> <paragraph id="H52B1149A64914B618ECA78F0705B5ECB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Access to, or usage of, the Social Security Administration’s information technology systems (including systems used by the Administration to issue and record social security account numbers, record wages and earnings from self-employment, determine eligibility for benefits, pay benefits, or to allow the public to access information or services from the Administration) by the Department of Government Efficiency (hereafter referred to as <quote>DOGE</quote>), Elon Musk, any member of his team, or any individual coordinating with the DOGE.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H528199F2B7EF4964B36517DFCAD41C74"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Visits to Social Security Administration offices by the DOGE, Elon Musk, or any member of his team.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FD18D42D7AD419DB7A72EB96B9907BF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Alignment and compliance by the Social Security Administration with Executive Orders 14148, 14151, 14160, 14168, 14170, and 14171 of January 20, 2025, Executive Order 14173 of January 21, 2025, Executive Order 14192 of January 31, 2025, and Executive Orders 14217 and 14219 of February 19, 2025.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H29DDEDC9AB284D12BEE227BA1B93CF16"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The number of calls per day to the national toll-free telephone number maintained by the Social Security Administration for inquiries by the public, for days after January 20, 2025, through the date of enactment of this resolution.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20072BC6A781462EA234D843590DDBFB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The number of calls per day and visitors per day to Social Security Administration field offices and card centers, for days after January 20, 2025, through the date of enactment of this resolution.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD48D201262234FAB8CB8C1A65AC729A1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The closure or consolidation of offices of the Social Security Administration, including field offices, card centers, and hearing offices, occurring in 2025.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H69B9184232C44B8C9AC362B6AB3F40EF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Reduction in staff at the Social Security Administration, including at field offices, hearing offices, teleservice centers, processing centers, work support units, and other offices, occurring in 2025.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body>
<endorsement display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20250321">March 21, 2025</action-date> 
<action-desc>Reported adversely, referred to the House Calendar, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</resolution> 


