<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H473E1A3E45BB4014BA9B98FE8B72F7CD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5440 IH: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish a tax credit for small businesses to provide diaper changing stations in restrooms.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5440</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250917">September 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001230">Mr. Mackenzie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish a tax credit for small businesses to provide diaper changing stations in restrooms.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H74519CB3AE6A44EFB42A1E3584B05810" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC5EEB8F8A4B043C984DCCA2ECFBFE45B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Diaper changing station restroom credit</header> 
<subsection id="H8D28DA2544914A4C99DF3E711ABC94A6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D95C1AA143F4412B21BE5D114259431" style="OLC"> <section id="H73CE94BDF063421294F401AC240F8C11"><enum>45BB.</enum><header>Diaper changing station restroom credit</header> <subsection id="H922BC02E5981460D835C946C01CE320F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 38, in the case of an eligible small business which meets the family bathroom requirement of subsection (e) with respect to a business location of such business, the diaper changing station restroom credit determined under this section for the taxable year is an amount equal to 70 percent of the qualified diaper changing station restroom expenses paid or incurred by the taxpayer during such taxable year with respect to such business location.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5A0F3D8AE9B34715B244CD3DE3BDD051"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header> 
<paragraph id="H7C0B8AD40E4B464BAE6654AC855AD14A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The credit determined under subsection (a) with respect to any business location of the taxpayer for any taxable year shall not exceed the excess (if any) of—</text> <subparagraph id="HB394D294951541D49157C0FE5A1548FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$10,000, over</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2ACF128AAF8E40D18155062735FA24A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the aggregate credits determined und subsection (a) with respect to such business location for the 3 preceding taxable years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F4C9643DD4B48A984EDB7EE7DFFE552"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Business location</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H299113E7478F4FEC9F6834CFB1B8405B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <quote>business location</quote> means each building from which the taxpayer conducts a trade or business (other than the trade or business of being an employee).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H30EFDE10187F4E3696D4775F53850995"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Separate trades or businesses in separate portions of a building</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a taxpayer that conducts separate trades or businesses from different portions of a building, each such portion shall be treated as a separate business location for purposes of this section if the taxpayer meets the requirements of subsection (e) applied by taking into account only such portion of such building.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4C321156C37B435C9BD18F74534FA484"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified diaper changing station restroom expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H7895476ACBFF43BFBC99834269B97E0C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>qualified diaper changing station restroom expenses</quote> means, with respect to any business location, amounts paid or incurred by the taxpayer for—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H302332BA76014BEE883F969FB9BC1EE7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any diaper changing station (which may be accessed free of charge) located in any restroom at such business location (including labor costs and other expenses associated with installation of such station),</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7867F05FAB6F41B0A955C93D5A4913BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any diaper dispenser (which may impose a charge and which may dispense hygiene products in addition to diapers) located in any restroom at such business location (including labor costs and other expenses associated with installation of such dispenser), and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H76987C4A12224B52A16ECBBAB972B62D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">installation of one or more restrooms which meet the requirements of subsection (e) (or renovation or expansion of one or more existing restrooms into restrooms which meet such requirements).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2A60C801C33E479F83C6CE3178D2E777"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible small business</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="H300F2B0262F0424DBFC29D65B54CC2F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>eligible small business</quote> means any taxpayer for any taxable year if—</text> <subparagraph id="H48C619189F7740B5925BE756D430E92B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the business gross receipts of such taxpayer for such taxable year do not exceed $5,000,000, or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H506CF2D75C714BA9BBD52958D3B4C98C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such taxpayer employs less than 100 full-time equivalent employees for such taxable year (as determined under section 45R(d)(2)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A869767A3D34519ABDF6142B7EB2990"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Business gross receipts</header><text>The term <quote>business gross receipts</quote> means gross receipts received in the course of any trade or business (other than the trade or business of being an employee).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3881C7676DAA4C93916CB20B31F4DACA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Aggregation rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, all persons treated as a single employer under subsection (a) or (b) of section 52, or subsection (n) or (o) of section 414, shall be treated as one person.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0C113412734C4A14BB255B4833D3C869"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Family bathroom requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements of this subsection are met with respect to any business location if both men and women have access at such location to at least 1 public restroom that is equipped with a diaper changing station (which may be accessed free of charge) and a diaper dispenser (which may impose a charge).</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0E336F8B90894E6097512F609FF2D512"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text>In the case of any qualified diaper changing station restroom expenses with respect to which credit is allowed under subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="H34C4C797C7904A95AAEFD7585E76D4E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>no deduction or credit shall be allowed for, or by reason of, any such expense to the extent of the amount of such credit, and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4B4124C0070749BB9F1154D1DEA4C499"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the basis of any property shall be reduced by the amount of such credit to the extent that such expenses were taken into account in determining such basis.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HFD8F670097C14D05BAAF2F6148AC95C1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit made part of general business credit</header><text>Subsection (b) of section 38 of such Code is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (40), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (41) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA740A40516B64A849F34709776B12605" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H634E6C0C29214134A369D7D9323AC58A"><enum>(42)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an eligible small business (as defined in section 45BB), the diaper changing station restroom credit determined under section 45BB.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H46A2A892B1144B9996255668073E8A6D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H529B4D2F7DD840F6B0DEA636E1BFF235" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H2D95C1AA143F4412B21BE5D114259431" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="H73CE94BDF063421294F401AC240F8C11" level="section">Sec. 45BB. Diaper changing station restroom credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD1D2C95083DA4C408F881583307A4528" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

