<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-CAN25364-5RR-RS-165"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1740 IS: Pacific Partnership Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1740</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250513">May 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</sponsor> (for herself and
                    <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill;
                which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To bolster United States engagement with the Pacific Islands region, and for
 other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HBFE77E0713554D2480269D786B96BD33"><section section-type="section-one" id="HE24F30F11B14449495EF0FA7278CB300"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pacific Partnership Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3A42AFE3DA244EB989C33F1BF8029CE5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress as follows:</text><paragraph id="HEB9BF18EAE404B379E3AC401DD679D63"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States has longstanding and enduring cultural, historic, economic, strategic, and people-to-people connections with the Pacific Islands, based on shared values, cultural histories, common interests, and a commitment to fostering mutual understanding and cooperation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86D110B3798A4855A3E72E53BD9C6242"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Successive United States administrations have recognized the critical importance of the Pacific Islands, to the world in high-level strategic documents, including the—</text><subparagraph id="H0D25BB8AE44343B08905D4EB2485FC8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>2015 National Security Strategy, which first declared the rebalance to Asia and the Pacific, affirmed the United States as a Pacific nation, and paved the way for subsequent United States engagement with the Pacific Islands;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDEEE77F15164028B54909CF32D3D5F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>2017 National Security Strategy, which includes a commitment to <quote>shore up fragile partner states in the Pacific Islands region to reduce their vulnerability to economic fluctuations and natural disasters</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFD154871B044C72913E8C87BFF84E51"><enum>(C)</enum><text>2019 Indo-Pacific Strategy Report, which identified the Pacific Islands as <quote>critical to United States strategy because of our shared values, interests, and commitments</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA548362293E0480AB89E49E2F0CBBB25"><enum>(D)</enum><text>2022 Indo-Pacific Strategy Report, which recognized the need to engage further with the Pacific Islands on shared security goals; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC620E3791EE432A9145CBF939FD54B7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>2022 Strategy for Pacific Partnership, which outlined goals and methods for deepening the United States partnerships with Pacific Island nations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C356A1EB7FB4FCDB41C303C7228D4F5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The United States Government should further develop, expand, and support a comprehensive and multifaceted United States policy for the Pacific Islands that—</text><subparagraph id="H58FC7D407D184B9B942215D6D4A6E6A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promotes peace, security, and prosperity for all countries that respects the sovereignty and political independence of all nations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B65739E08264389A38B6857E57684A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preserves the Pacific Ocean as a corridor for international maritime economic opportunities and growth and promotes sustainable development;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB5BEAC58D1D4D2D8F5370FD5818F92A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>supports regional efforts to address shared challenges, including by strengthening resilience to natural disasters and stewardship of natural resources; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CD123BFAE9043B6B723F4C758A1F3FA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>strengthens democratic governance and the rule of law, and promotes internationally recognized human rights and the preservation of the region’s cultural heritages.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H32B07A32DF9746F6A73847BD845C267F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The United States should collaborate closely with existing regional multilateral institutions and frameworks, such as the Pacific Islands Forum and the Pacific Community.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC04952F4F2443F6BAC845A2B2039196"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States should work closely with United States allies and partners with existing relationships and interests in the Pacific Islands, such as Australia, Japan, South Korea, New Zealand, and Taiwan, and regional institutions like the Pacific Islands Forum.</text></paragraph></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H572F49450A3845A697F7B292359CF1DA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Strategy for Pacific Partnership</header><subsection id="H2BD5820D78014A9C93F4C7A65C64C1E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2026, and again not later than January 1, 2030, the President, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall develop and submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy entitled the <quote>Strategy for Pacific Partnership</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Strategy</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H936A396257244A13B536517B40C0E9E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The Strategy shall include each of the following:</text><paragraph id="H617283C70AB14E07988FAE4ADF1E6768"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of overarching goals for United States engagement in the Pacific Islands region, including United States diplomatic posts, defense posture, and economic engagement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2454415A5C3E4D6B87F59E364A93E92B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of threats and pressures to the Pacific Islands region including those caused by factors such as—</text><subparagraph id="H4D648A9F3AAE439C9A0C4F9E1076C20C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>natural disasters;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED3AF5BB33D248D0BF0B54E0638E3159"><enum>(B)</enum><text>illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD83B416B7891417BAAA6DFB0591857CD"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">non-United States military presence and activity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H316D8C0F17B943A7A76ECFFBFE80D8CC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>developmental challenges;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H869ECF05075C465BAF94FEABFFCF9D39"><enum>(E)</enum><text>economic coercion and corruption; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08079008191F4D89BBE922D6556C50C7"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other factors assessed to be causing a direct risk to the United States national interests in the Pacific Islands.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7ACE213ED4A346B080FBF75AA6EAAD65"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A plan to address the threats assessed pursuant to paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEA55DDD009B43EDB25890A17826E08D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan for the resources necessary for the United States to meet its goals in the Pacific Islands region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D7F29A269384DD98FEB5C79CC865DF0"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mechanisms, including existing forums, for coordinating and cooperating on shared goals among the following, as appropriate:</text><subparagraph id="H62C0BC9237344794BF0EA01850D7DFD5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the governments of Pacific Island countries;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89D4FAB31CB14A34BDBB98E3864A7BFE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regional partners in the Pacific Islands region, including multilateral forums and organizations, such as the Pacific Islands Forum;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB585E6933E234EC8A3BF920B65F23624"><enum>(C)</enum><text>civil society in the Pacific Islands; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29578F7597324B449C22E4EC7B641DFD"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States subnational governments in the Pacific.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD2296E9713B14F70B281395E8A7985D0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing the Strategy, the President should consult, as appropriate, with—</text><paragraph id="HB0FAB9925AD44E9AAB46CE52B3E42F1D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>relevant United States governmental agencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D35D8CB3CCB4C57B8FEBC9C8CC42193"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regional organizations, such as the Pacific Islands Forum, the Pacific Islands Development Program, the Pacific Community, the Forum Fisheries Agency, and the Secretariat of the Pacific Regional Environment Programme;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD72A4282DF648388402316CF6495F24"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the governments of the countries in the Pacific Islands;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA74A5CBA15A47A3B5467FCE077DC344"><enum>(4)</enum><text>civil society stakeholders;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H941E4EFB6DA7428DB4BA434C775B4BDF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>United States allies and partners; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16A8468B3BD5469E8290C4557077B461"><enum>(6)</enum><text>United States Pacific territories and States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H7436CB96751542019074A909D50851B6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Extension of diplomatic immunities to the Pacific Islands Forum</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The provisions of the International Organizations Immunities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/288">22 U.S.C. 288 et seq.</external-xref>) may be extended to the Pacific Islands Forum in the same manner, to the same extent, and subject to the same conditions as such provisions may be extended to a public international organization in which the United States participates pursuant to any treaty or under the authority of any Act of Congress authorizing such participation or making an appropriation for such participation.</text></section><section id="H844F585180A449CF84451AC50E2EF582"><enum>5.</enum><header>Allies and partners in the Pacific Islands region</header><subsection id="HBC399E7E7F2C4DDD84AA852E2A7A5179"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President, in consultation with the Secretary of State, and the relevant heads of other Federal departments and agencies, should consult and coordinate with allies and partners in the Pacific Islands region, including Australia, Japan, New Zealand, Taiwan, and regional institutions, such as the Pacific Islands Forum, the Pacific Islands Development Program, the Pacific Community and Secretariat for the Pacific Regional Environment Programme, with respect to programs to provide assistance to the Pacific Islands, including for purposes of—</text><paragraph id="HD0C8A2B0200E46ACBD51E1DBDDFAEE09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>deconflicting programming;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12551CCCB0F146EA94804C97FC161E2E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensuring that any programming does not adversely affect the absorptive capacity of the Pacific Islands;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEDF21AC857C465AAD9D4079920CEE81"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensuring complementary programs benefit the Pacific Islands to the maximum extent practicable; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H330FB6EF5DB845FAB0CBDB1BFB3E2D9C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ensuring that programming aligns with regional development goals to promote a shared vision for the future of the Pacific Islands.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1968C45BE3E04310B7BC36510CA9B48B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Formal consultative process</header><text>The President should establish a formal consultative process with such regional allies and partners to coordinate with respect to such programs and future-years programming.</text></subsection></section><section id="H632AE6ACC19F45CD9AEEA86CE47E8D22"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reporting</header><subsection id="H9D9EF1073FA0461789E0242B267C8A82"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Updates of certain reports</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2ea577cdef6943709e5ebd21e296a07b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the heads of other Federal departments and agencies as appropriate, shall annually update the reports listed in paragraph (2) to include within the scope of such reports a regional discussion of transnational crime affecting the Pacific Islands.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68B8A1798E204B6FB2DDC20F82B3BA69"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports listed</header><text>The reports listed in this paragraph are the following:</text><subparagraph id="H22E16858431846F1800A0ADD562F2C35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The International Narcotics Control Strategy report required by section 489 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2291h">22 U.S.C. 2291h</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AE10F97B436411D909DCF668A672AA8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Improving International Fisheries Management report required by section 607 of title VI of the Fisheries Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826h">16 U.S.C. 1826h</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE65971C59084D03901623102CB66224"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Trafficking in Persons report submitted under section 110 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7107">22 U.S.C. 7107</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9a4aad6d4c1449e9a5d24379b171c2d6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Modification to report on Indo-Pacific region</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5595(c) of the James M. Inhofe National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/263">Public Law 117–263</external-xref>; 136 Stat. 3393) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07ea04889e0c46f3b082941473d0b384"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (1) and redesignating paragraph (2) as paragraph (1);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6a48974c50514cca90d631c2a5a4a260"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>the 2022 Indo-Pacific Strategy, or successor documents,</quote> and inserting <quote>any relevant guidance documents</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4491ac46ae554c75a0855bdae262078d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1), as so redesignated, the following:</text><quoted-block id="id59121612CF3140508A1DF8DBC24084EA" style="OLC" act-name=""><paragraph id="id11640D6D95AD48ACAD386206902DA927"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Implementing any relevant guidance documents that set forth the United States Government strategy toward the Pacific Islands region.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H889FF5B0864342B2AD97F7874116FF04"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HDF402B4956324A95B9EF8F93B86E107C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idad72636832a64ce9a184e997470c8349"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AC4D947AB694D10BE559476069E2477"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6A49F931C53E455DB0106031D80E656A" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pacific Islands; Pacific islands
 region</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Pacific Islands</term> and <term>Pacific Islands region</term> mean the nations, territories, and other jurisdictions in the Pacific Ocean within the broad groupings of Melanesia, Micronesia, and Polynesia.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


