<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H65BD4445F9CB4A3BACA146AB0BA6532F" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 182 IH: Expressing support for the designation of March 3, 2025, as “National Triple-Negative Breast Cancer Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 182</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250303">March 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of March 3, 2025, as <quote>National Triple-Negative Breast Cancer Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas triple-negative breast cancer was recognized as a distinct type of cancer in 2006;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas triple-negative breast cancer disproportionately affects young women, Black and Hispanic women, and those with BRCA gene mutations;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas triple-negative breast cancers are estrogen receptor-negative, progesterone receptor-negative, and HER2-negative, making them distinct from other breast cancers;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas 10 to 15 percent of all breast cancer diagnoses are designated as triple-negative;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas triple-negative breast cancer can be more aggressive and more likely to spread and recur;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas triple-negative breast cancer accounts for around 25 percent of all deaths from breast cancer in the United States; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas March 3, 2025, would be an appropriate date to designate as <quote>National Triple-Negative Breast Cancer Day</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H6477B9556CC646AAA9ADFC8CE60E6DC3"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HE4B3F540FFED4407BBF8759C946163CA"><text>That the House of Representatives supports the designation of <quote>National Triple-Negative Breast Cancer Day</quote> to create awareness of the devastating effect of these cancers on families in the United States and the need for strong action to eradicate triple-negative breast cancer.</text></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

