<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG25416-5RT-T6-MH6"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1331 IS: Quantum National Security Coordination and Competition Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1331</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Defense to establish or designate an office in the Department of Defense to serve as the lead for all quantum efforts of the Department, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id6c4e59554f734f3c9d56a7d3e4944641" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Quantum National Security Coordination and Competition Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id37da0c9cd0e644e4aafb41163c35b1fa"><enum>2.</enum><header>National security quantum coordination and competition</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida79509a4198347249fe38127f2654d7d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Office of Quantum Capabilities and Competition</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70944bcf75674c66b0fcab656991d5f8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall establish or designate an office in the Department of Defense to serve as the lead for all quantum efforts of the Department relating to the following:</text><subparagraph id="id4cb25106c53c4d4bafc3c060513ee2d8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Quantum technology research, including quantum sensing, quantum computing, and quantum communications.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb64f4af5035348ea80a7739d0a384db9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Quantum technology development, including quantum sensing, quantum computing, and quantum communications.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6d293bc7a68d4dbc83ce1b9ca22e807b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Quantum technology application, including quantum sensing, quantum computing, and quantum communications.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id786dc89f53804cd68467073f03c18883"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Quantum technology policy, including quantum sensing, quantum computing, and quantum communications.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6d34806d25ca44e8b44abbaa070fa8b2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Such other quantum related efforts as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id116fdffb643b4a2ebc08fb7d5f8cc1e8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The office established or designated pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be known as the <quote>Department of Defense Office of Quantum Capabilities and Competition</quote> (in this section the <quote>Office</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide0db216d179e45eb9ada482955a499f3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Primary mission</header><text>The primary mission of the Office shall be coordinating, leading, and directing quantum technology efforts of the Department in order—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9ed9f17dcd7a4aedac13c69489518011"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to advance Department research efforts in quantum technology;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc01fdec67884449d9797a0e5494a9a4b"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop quantum technology expertise that enables advancements in United States national security capabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2aa5f9b22fe34d198d5ad6af6b803517"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to aggressively pursue a national competitive advantage in quantum technology, vis-à-vis other countries; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd0e7edf1ce484b4289a582f7e9370291"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop quantum technologies that can be utilized for real-world application by the Department of Defense or other United States national security entities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49627b13053c4b1d845b3dd2483fc62e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination with other quantum efforts</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4c16df1337ef439abe7fc8100e808d64"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall, acting through the Office, regularly coordinate with the heads of other Federal departments and agencies that work on quantum science, quantum technology, or quantum research.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f150fe0bc2d47039743b0b218717f8f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Quantum Coordination Office for National Security</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id66e14bd6359a494584a69113b42a40ff"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall establish within the Office a subcomponent to liaise with, share expertise with, and whenever feasible, coordinate and, if necessary, deconflict efforts with other relevant U.S. government entities pursuing efforts on quantum science, quantum technology, or quantum research.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd20e1809c76b440fb2e561233dd10a28"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The subcomponent established pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall be known as the <quote>Quantum Coordination Office for National Security</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide529853461c7441aa5c47a97538f1d0d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Triennial reports</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbd1b4cdbcd134d0a8d6d3e688e695187"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than once every three years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on national security quantum capabilities and competition.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id24e26ca60eae4374b4270e80613245ef"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents generally</header><text>Each report submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall cover the following:</text><subparagraph id="ide6862c14dea344a4ade3c3bfc6baf2c0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The state of current quantum efforts within the Department of Defense, including specific sections on quantum sensing, quantum computing, and quantum communications.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8f5db7b03dfc48e6b6c5a71ed0870ea5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The state of current quantum efforts of adversarial and competitor countries, including specific sections on quantum sensing, quantum computing, and quantum communications.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idac08fb62fe034edcbb2c094dde1f8a74"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The state of current quantum efforts of any other countries with advanced capabilities in quantum technology and quantum science, including specific sections on quantum sensing, quantum computing, and quantum communications.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id988ce31faa9e4057a41257e9c82002c6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A comparison of the capabilities of the United States and those of adversarial and competitor countries, as well as any other countries with advanced capabilities in quantum technology and quantum science.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc1e9cebad2d847e9a48c8f4c6cbad21b"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An assessment of capabilities of the United States compared to those of China, Russia, and Iran, combined with an assessment of how such countries (in addition to any other countries the Secretary considers relevant) may utilize quantum technology in a conflict against the United States or allies and partners of the United States, including via hybrid warfare.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id22bdeb3d9e0c40489455b99e25e52132"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A realistic pathway forward, both short term (3 years) and long term (10 years and beyond), for the United States to compete with and outpace other countries in quantum technology and quantum science in regard to national security.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id093c178e6f504a7ea1867fffb69cc4b0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents of initial report</header><text>In addition to the matter covered by paragraph (2), the first report submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include an annex on quantum communication efforts that covers the following:</text><subparagraph id="id1bfc70932c3f4dc598e550fba28761ad"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The current state of United States national security quantum communications technology and capabilities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9b188ec15f944c6e96a5722c5a39c925"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A comparison of the national security quantum communications technology and capabilities of the United States compared to that of China, Russia, Iran, and such other countries as the Secretary considers relevant.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaebf96369e07490aa9ab9f09a7588ad3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An immediate (2 years) and long-term (10 years and beyond) plan—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idddf9bc35a8f14658885f2b41b23ccd88"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to close any gaps that may exist between national security quantum communications technology and capabilities of the United States and those of China, Russia, Iran, and such other countries as the Secretary considers relevant; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7aba9ed7de284b4498db27145d317d1d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to outpace the quantum communications technology and capabilities for China, Russia, Iran, and such other countries as the Secretary considers relevant.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddd789cc1a8d940ab929ff37d7879f688"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be submitted in classified form.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id347b319c1bf34debb3e5b2557e79850e"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5ae5b16872fc4774885a201eb83e1ffb"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services, the Select Committee on Intelligence, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc44d8da379c740349a6f34aefcab7902"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85ef0d9e51eb4b9b83cffae9fc282a73"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Protection of national security</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out this section in accordance with all applicable provisions of law and policies relating to classified information and national security.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id25fbd73bdf7b4eaab416ab1809adc11d"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require any action that is not consistent with a provision of law or policy that was in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

