<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3CBBA0379A3C4F159EBAA6CDD9EFF538" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5622 IH: National Gun Violence Research Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5622</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250930">September 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for a coordinated national research program to examine the nature, causes, consequences, and prevention of violence and unintended injury and death relating to gun ownership, use, and trafficking, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB8DB32B5A1F84069AE43AF219A910588" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2B5291C9F09A4C678AAB12D6F6BAB506" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Gun Violence Research Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6E39B2446B004C38A91C2AAE4AD4717A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE55B84F40A6C461A9761CFE840FEB8E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the last 50 years, more individuals in the United States have died from gunshots than in all wars in which the United States was a combatant, combined.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDAE9ED081A4844CCAC099A814284B97A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The rate of gun violence deaths in the United States is more than 11 times that of other high-income nations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB0A2C51CA04D4E13AB8A091630320F8C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Guns accounted for 79 percent of homicides and 55 percent of suicides in 2023, totaling over 45,000 deaths in the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H49EADFF5733844A3A53B2EA6D4B45846"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Gun violence disproportionately affects communities of color. In 2022, Black Americans were 12 times as likely as White Americans to be killed by gun violence while Hispanic and Latino Americans were twice as likely to be killed.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H941CB7A8144A46A98344BDA065717BDB"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provisions in appropriations Acts dating back to 1996 have had a chilling effect on Federal funding for research on gun violence across the Federal Government and, as a result, research on gun violence is significantly underfunded relative to other leading causes of death.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6A7E7DA96A8944E7947953562D1D3B49"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Research examining the nature, causes, consequences, and prevention of gun-related violence, suicide, and unintentional injury and death does not constitute advocacy in support of, or opposition to, gun control policies or regulations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H42532D65E86445C89D1B16306DC94CB4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>More research and high-quality data relating to gun violence are needed to inform the development of effective strategies to reduce the incidence of gun-related injury and death.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H31CC8B1ABAA043789C88552F9EAF6377"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HD092CC841C384D8F90941391AEFA3255"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H39F8958DD9974AD5815BCE9052F976B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC20BB0793D0C41D99B65EC49712C2762"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>Program</term> means the National Gun Violence Research Program established under section 5.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HFA5A6C67726B43D39018488307D2E0DE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Research and data restrictions repeal</header> <subsection id="H2557DF905F8A4368A78E7845025ACE12"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Gun trace data</header> <paragraph id="H558153196D3E4795ADD9A0D41C30D133"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The matter under the heading <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives—Salaries and Expenses</quote> in title II of division B of the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/923">18 U.S.C. 923</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/55">Public Law 112–55</external-xref>; 125 Stat. 609–610) is amended by striking the 6th proviso.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HECED0143FDF14B5BBC84218F34227F8D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The 6th proviso under the heading <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives—Salaries and Expenses</quote> in title II of division B of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/923">18 U.S.C. 923</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/117">Public Law 111–117</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 3128–3129) is amended by striking <quote>beginning in fiscal year 2010 and thereafter</quote> and inserting <quote>in fiscal year 2010</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H289D161408E4456D9108502A38D112CD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The 6th proviso under the heading <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives—Salaries and Expenses</quote> in title II of division B of the Omnibus Appropriations Act, 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/923">18 U.S.C. 923</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/8">Public Law 111–8</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 574–576) is amended by striking <quote>beginning in fiscal year 2009 and thereafter</quote> and inserting <quote>in fiscal year 2009</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H70F3712210FF4B2E844646EACDE985A8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The 6th proviso under the heading <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives—Salaries and Expenses</quote> in title II of division B of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/923">18 U.S.C. 923</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/161">Public Law 110–161</external-xref>; 121 Stat. 1903–1904) is amended by striking <quote>beginning in fiscal year 2008 and thereafter</quote> and inserting <quote>in fiscal year 2008</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C12352831E9450889F507137C225A0A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The 6th proviso under the heading <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives—Salaries and Expenses</quote> in title I of the Science, State, Justice, Commerce, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/923">18 U.S.C. 923</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/108">Public Law 109–108</external-xref>; 119 Stat. 2295–2296) is amended by striking <quote>with respect to any fiscal year</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8A9DA70D6FB141BFAED805A4569D1931"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The 6th proviso under the heading in title I of division B of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/923">18 U.S.C. 923</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/447">Public Law 108–447</external-xref>; 118 Stat. 2859–2860) is amended by striking <quote>with respect to any fiscal year</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HF3451B87CD904FB09E2755C24AB59886"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Department of Health and Human Services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, funds made available to the Department of Health and Human Services, including the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the National Institutes of Health, may be used to conduct or support research with respect to gun violence.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HA42820D8623F40AB82D27C8E3B7E43C4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Research program</header> 
<subsection id="HA0154C339CD548CC9EF5E191169279A1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President, acting through the Director, shall develop and implement a program to improve public health and safety through research on gun violence, to be known as the <quote>National Gun Violence Research Program</quote>, through activities carried out in collaboration with covered agencies that—</text> <paragraph id="H28E8903F4F8845AF82229A66993E22CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support gun violence research;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8947AFA1643843C394654067C08943C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>accelerate the translation of gun violence research into effective policy interventions to reduce the incidence of injury and death related to guns;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF67B66392A494113BC7B3E4CB2F5F4B3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>expand the number of researchers and students in the field of gun violence research; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBD757FC28AC84074A7BBC1CDBA645AA7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>improve interagency planning and coordination of Federal Government activities relating to gun violence research.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5592B7F6C1CC49F1AC912E3434E14516"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program activities</header><text>A covered agency, in carrying out activities described in subsection (a) under the Program, shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEE5177EC162B4864851BFC0CE454CB01"><enum>(1)</enum><text>award grants to individual investigators and interdisciplinary teams of investigators for projects related to gun violence research;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7824BE814F7040E59C28E3C9A2E2F135"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support projects funded under joint solicitations by a collaboration of not fewer than two covered agencies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEFB3CD40CF704CD99696D7F7EC7D4302"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish interdisciplinary research centers that are organized to investigate basic research questions and inform policy decisions relating to gun violence;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FCE976A29904AA6B7100E0AFA2767EB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide for the education and training of undergraduate students, graduate students, and postdoctoral scholars in gun violence research; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8EDE7A032B2F4CEE9C447F60DFC35169"><enum>(5)</enum><text>promote the development of voluntary consensus gun safety technical standards.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H082005C6701F4F979C11AFBAD108A8AB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Interagency working group</header> <paragraph id="H9FB9BD5C5BCE4D8CA251CB3634F2E995"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President, acting through the National Science and Technology Council, shall establish or maintain an interagency working group on gun violence research.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H62CA6F71B2C041BEB4286A4D4C8FB834"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The working group established or maintained under paragraph (1) shall be chaired by the Director and include representatives from each covered agency.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H87B6B15288ED4B38B083904A116933CA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Working Group shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0390B03A1CF84F02BFDD16E0C70DFC90"><enum>(A)</enum><text>oversee the planning, management, and coordination of the Program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD63A21F4792E42B5A814B37DA7B70879"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide for coordination among covered agencies of Federal gun violence research and other activities undertaken pursuant to the Program;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC8B4AB5612544295BAA0D29F6F1F251D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establish and periodically update goals and priorities for the Program; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6E29D6F9906F4427922795C268418067"><enum>(D)</enum><text>develop, not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act, and update every 5 years, a strategic plan to guide the activities of the Program to meet the goals and priorities established under subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCBDCEDA9B345424FA9B33055EA718302"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Advisory committee</header> 
<paragraph id="H8F446B5A76014D2B87A81408D471D1D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President, acting through the Director, shall establish or maintain an advisory committee on gun violence research.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77396956EF8043E3AAAEB4514ED2F552"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Composition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The advisory committee established or maintained under paragraph (1) shall be composed of not fewer than 12 members, including, to the greatest extent practicable, representatives of research institutions, institutions of higher education, health care and social services providers, local government agencies, law enforcement, community-based organizations, and relevant nonprofit organizations who are qualified to provide advice on the Program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3AC4778415F14C41B60E7F0AF1E891A5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The advisory committee established or maintained under paragraph (1) shall assess—</text> <subparagraph id="H4F063330D8EB4F989AA91B7A0731733A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the management, coordination, implementation, and activities of the Program;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H69359A0A1409407F868BADBE33B25FD5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the balance of activities and funding across the Program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4910DE457AB840AABA887F6BAA9A8CEE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether the Program priorities and goals developed by the interagency working group established under subsection (c) are helping to improve public health and safety; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H927FD8C0CDB9446D94D3CBB6F486FC7D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the need to revise the Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB6EF7985168C45799DDBAA9A1B463762"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Covered agency defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered agency</term> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9357689D3A1D400D9A72742445F5FA24"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the National Science Foundation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0206C6AE69A04A48BB6975B21EE3F15F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the National Institute for Standards and Technology;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF0738B311A114C3D98707C7089475E2F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H350810EEACFE419197F2F7FE494F1B75"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the National Institutes of Health;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H045994A3B5FE4A7795A3DF0F8B0948FF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the National Institute of Justice; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B36845D8F27465FB8EDF7DE831159D1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>such other Federal agency as determined appropriate by the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF1253A459ACC41118F9885F7ADCA40AF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Director to carry out this section $200,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H154D8DAF951B4610A244C08EC074B758"><enum>6.</enum><header>Agency activities</header> <subsection id="HB18A97E36CBA41C084A2A247E675C8F0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National Science Foundation</header> <paragraph id="HCAFFC92FC9784AFABC62F53B523DB170"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Research</header> <text>The Director of the National Science Foundation shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to institutions of higher education or nonprofit organizations (or consortia of such institutions)—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H548CAE7213A7454C9611D113FDEC7EA2">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>to support multidisciplinary research to better understand the nature, causes, and consequences of gun violence, including violence, suicide, unintended injury, and death involving guns;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H684FB4E54BDA4A8D9FEA5F36F9B0955F">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to examine the effects of gun policy interventions on—</text>
                        <clause id="H91D7989185674487BAC038F8F7923B3C">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rates of suicide, homicide, and unintended injury and death;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HF671F7B93B53476F86220AE36D0E2539">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>individuals’ ability to use guns for self-defense, hunting, and recreation; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H9781BBF0DE4A4E079065297B5D414ECA">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>the gun industry; and</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H17077AB1F3F340ECA1DF425A264F0F45"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to educate and train researchers in the field of violence, including gun violence, research.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83F021A79F6543F9887590D87748CDBA" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National Center for Violence Research</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Science Foundation shall award grants on a competitive basis to institutions of higher education or nonprofit organizations (or consortia of such institutions) to establish one or more centers to conduct multidisciplinary research and education activities in support of the goals and priorities of the Program. Such grants shall be known as <quote>National Center for Violence Research Grants</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7DCC15138AF84F47AC16A2E95A91FBCB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H029DD6AF49874B4D867F96614485E7BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National Institute of Standards and Technology</header> 
<paragraph id="HC6B112E69BFC4ACD95182802863A7A72"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Voluntary consensus standards</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, shall establish a program to promote the development of voluntary consensus gun safety technical standards. Such program shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HD2E01E96343C4C2D9F8875C667264FD5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>outreach, coordination, and technical support to relevant industry and nonindustry stakeholders and standards development organizations to assist such entities in the development of voluntary consensus gun safety technical standards;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H426D5DC483B449F38008E47FE1F599A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the conduct of research to support efforts to develop and improve such standards and conformity assessment; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H27B40518CE29493295D3250907C46498"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the development of such standard reference material as the Director determines is necessary to further the development of such standards.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBD61958A5CB84948831E3D395C0B3EE2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on regulation</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed as conferring upon the Secretary of Commerce any authority to establish or enforce mandatory gun safety standards.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H01B0A95025BD421790D5C7E1C150C01B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H047FB9F9FE934E33BE49AAB9E543C81D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Department of Health and Human Services</header> 
<paragraph id="HEFC6979D15D64ED08A96AA4462166A95"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and other scientific agencies within the Department of Health and Human Services, shall award grants on a competitive basis to conduct or support research into the nature, causes, consequences, and prevention of gun violence.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E46008B7BF64F5FB9F1599A71D1981A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out this subsection $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4C649E39DEEC44FFBCA855AC760C8886"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Department of Justice</header> 
<paragraph id="H2FE538EB231B4EA0A007AD6AE30407BA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Research</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General, acting through the Director of the National Institute of Justice, shall conduct or sponsor research into the nature, causes, consequences, and prevention of gun violence.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H54EFF7B4E11E46F1844D1FFBDF29BF19"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Trace data</header> <subparagraph id="H8F46C711B77D4C4B8C35BA4AACE59653"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, in collaboration with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall develop consensus protocols for granting researchers access to gun trace data that abide by standard principles for ethical research.</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD87BECCB034240669E574CAD0F78F09E">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <header>Data sharing</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, shall commence sharing with researchers according to the protocols developed under subparagraph (A), the contents of the Firearms Trace System database and information required to be kept by licensees pursuant to section 923(g) of title 18, United States Code, or required to be reported pursuant to paragraphs (3) and (7) of such section 923(g).</text>
                    </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D8DC96AFD4F498986E118CC26BB6333"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

