<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HED0109934B35432486FFA3D6873E6560" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4823 IH: Promoting Free and Fair Elections Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4823</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250729">July 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit agencies of the government from soliciting or entering into agreements with nongovernmental organizations to conduct voter registration or voter mobilization activities on the property or website of the agency or from using Federal funds to carry out activities directed under Executive Order 14019, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9E3F3EC43D344AB3A840795B45C6409A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8253428E13B84F888EC6F162607B17E4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Free and Fair Elections Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD3C4030BA6DC44FC8B5564CC5DB41350"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal agency involvement in voter registration activities</header> <subsection id="H493146E4EB8A4C4D8C12B6D0AF857841"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Clarification of Federal agency involvement in voter registration activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 14019 (86 Fed. Reg. 13623; relating to promoting access to voting) or any substantially similar executive order shall have no force or effect to the extent that it is inconsistent with section 7 of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20506">52 U.S.C. 20506</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H82ED71808F38409FB8F460BCBE9D1A23"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibiting promotion of voter registration by agencies</header> 
<paragraph id="HEC6B3EE1E96C4947B6EF220093DD2AAF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agreements with nongovernmental organizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available for the salaries and expenses of an agency may be used to solicit or enter into an agreement with a nongovernmental organization to conduct voter registration or voter mobilization activities, including registering voters or providing any person with voter registration materials, absentee or vote-by-mail ballot applications, voting instructions, or candidate-related information, on the property or website of the agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC205DBCEEA724D4BAEE150A4A8A6DDF9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities under Executive Order 14019</header> <subparagraph id="H7E33634BB49240B8AC789BECFA070A7D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Delay in implementation</header> <clause id="H131C209227A741D0B040FC55EB179A4E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Delay</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in clause (ii), none of the funds made available for the salaries and expenses of an agency may be used to implement activities directed under Executive Order 14019 (86 Fed. Reg. 13623) or any substantially similar executive order until—</text> 
<subclause id="H75087C03D90941DFBAF042B438C60B38"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of an agency that is required to submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees under subparagraph (B)(i), 180 days after the agency submits the report; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC77DC3391E1A4FE19E3B26E9BC29C94F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of an agency that is required to submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees under subparagraph (B)(ii), the date on which the agency submits the report.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H77001FFCB3E4436C9411ECDB8521B8D4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply to any activity described in section 7(c) of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20506">52 U.S.C. 20506(c)</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDE52EE6D21914C95A1C79410FE3169A5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the head of each agency shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees—</text> 
<clause id="HCCA027E74A4B46BAB927B7D5FDC6642E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a copy of the strategic plan of the agency for promoting voter registration and voter participation under section 3(b) of Executive Order 14019 (86 Fed. Reg. 13623) that the agency developed or submitted to the Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy; or</text></clause> <clause id="HA03AEBA93EA04BCD920F75C7959B6A1C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the agency did not develop or submit a plan described in clause (i) to the Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy, a certification signed by the head of the agency that the agency did not develop or submit such a plan.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC6374B45CCC4D60903DA74E4ED050B6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2)(B), this section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2025 and each succeeding fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H45D94A0BB52E4FF29467EDB6857FA181"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional report on voter registration and mobilization</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the head of each agency shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing the activities carried out by the agency pursuant to sections 3 and 4 of Executive Order 14019 (86 Fed. Reg. 13623).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE8D773799AFC43F398624DCBEC8AEF85">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Prohibiting voter registration and mobilization in Federal work-Study
          programs</header>
 <text>Section 443(b)(1) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087-53">20 U.S.C. 1087–53(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
        <paragraph id="H9DF6D4223B0B4222A555875CEF51DD52">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>and</quote>;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H94DAFF32DC7C430F8A531892A3565C80"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>by redesignating subparagraph (D) as subparagraph (E); and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H98FF29496F134A71A89DEA61B8C50D20">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5137B83E181847A1804BD6E15A76D209"> <subparagraph id="H1C5D9772DE844E34B7FA4B14B3EBB9BA"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>does not involve registering or mobilizing voters on or off the campus of the institution; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H2B9980A20AC04EDEB7358C5F8036F4E3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H7A03DA9FD4634DE1AC662DCE8EC9E910"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3502(1) of title 44, United States Code, except that for purposes of subsection (c)(2) such term does not include an independent regulatory agency as defined in section 3502(5) of title 44, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H13F33485A4CA4FD987D6DA5A95134DF6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HC88DE021EA184E20A44ED4C8ACD0AF99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC7D12CF8B15D43D4B8430FA1567243A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H91D994661BA34BA28478580ED58ADC85"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9C43DF4D2E7B4729902313323DE14600"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

