<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ERN25289-C29-26-3MW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1658 IS: Sensible Adoption For Every Home Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1658</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250507">May 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit entities receiving Federal assistance that are involved in adoption or foster care placements from delaying or denying placements under certain conditions.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H6BA8263125184F3FACEA7916430BE07F"><section section-type="section-one" id="HFE956EDF1220474988EE3D177C77992C"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sensible Adoption For Every Home Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAFE Home Act</short-title></quote> .</text></section><section id="H0DE06F39C912404399E6FBCFAF8CF54C"><enum>2.</enum><header>State plan requirement under the Federal foster care and adoption assistance program</header><subsection id="HD8011208623C4149A3BEC261A5A9465F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 471(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/671">42 U.S.C. 671(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H281FA7D3044B4613BA511BC6678690BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (36);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A28335CAE45456C86FABB306DFCEFE0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (37) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H83FDF9D1BAC642EF9E8D0AE14CF611F8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC2A7EDFCD2345B79AF5AD819B655B04"><paragraph id="H5FA4285A2B4D48859EF88F2556199823"><enum>(38)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA3E6AB84067A4C9F969C2CA212296A78"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prohibits any entity that receives Federal assistance and is involved in adoption or foster care placements from delaying or denying the placement of a minor child for adoption or into foster care, or otherwise discriminating in making a placement decision with a prospective or actual adoptive or foster parent, for any of the following reasons:</text><clause id="HF86FBECE37264F34B72E1A85D00B89DD" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The parent raises, cares for, and addresses a child in a manner consistent with the child’s sex.</text></clause><clause id="H98CAC93E8C574CEFB9AA497F70F3F33E" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The parent declines to consent to a child receiving any medical, surgical, pharmacological, or psychological treatment or other medical or mental health service for the purpose of attempting to alter the appearance of, or to validate a child’s perception of, the child’s sex, if the appearance or perception is inconsistent with the child’s sex.</text></clause><clause id="H1B29A7426DB242E6BBA9DB48762B2699" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The parent declines to consent to an amendment or alteration to a child’s birth certificate, passport, driver’s license, school records, or other government-issued identification document, if the amendment or alteration is inconsistent with the child’s sex; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CD36664D36B46AE8D2C440085928803" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for purposes of this paragraph, defines—</text><clause id="H639CBED9DCBC4019AAC3FC496AE3F9F9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the term <quote>sex</quote> as biological sex, either male or female;</text></clause><clause id="HA2D3E621A40A47069DF0E1FD0BD20579"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the term <quote>female</quote> as an individual who has, had, will have, or but for a developmental or genetic anomaly or historical accident would have, a reproductive system that at some point produces, transports, and utilizes eggs for fertilization; and</text></clause><clause id="HB5EF47F25EBF41629DF7794FCC1D8AE8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>male</quote> as an individual who has, had, will have, or but for a developmental or genetic anomaly or historical accident would have, a reproductive system that at some point produces, transports, and utilizes sperm for fertilization.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6FF464EF0FFF4F8AA777105922CBA46A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><paragraph id="H77B31665D8664BDC83DCACBD15DA7212"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendment made by this Act shall take effect on the 1st day of the 1st fiscal quarter beginning on or after the date of the enactment of this Act, and shall apply to payments under part E of title IV of the Social Security Act for calendar quarters beginning on or after such date.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70F43DDF932F44BFB76711E17DB51700"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Delay permitted if state legislation required</header><text>If the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines that State legislation (other than legislation appropriating funds) is required in order for a State plan developed pursuant to part E of title IV of the Social Security Act to meet the additional requirements imposed by the amendments made by this Act, the plan shall not be regarded as failing to meet any of the additional requirements before the 1st day of the 1st calendar quarter beginning after the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act. For purposes of the preceding sentence, if the State has a 2-year legislative session, each year of the session is deemed to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

