<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC2BB44AB15EC4916972F9038EE396A4C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5026 IH: Accelerated Logistics and Coordination for Arresting, Transporting, and Removing Aliens Zones Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5026</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250822">August 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000597">Ms. Lee of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Appropriations</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish in the Department of Homeland Security a grant program to reimburse States the costs incurred by such States relating to the detention of migrants at detention facilities in such States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6AEB2AB309AD4E2E9792B0AF72BE0367" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3D61FE013FD749C89536115126D0BA2D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Accelerated Logistics and Coordination for Arresting, Transporting, and Removing Aliens Zones Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ALCATRAZ Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HB2E67DD5AD1B4655B7835F2928C9B7E5"><enum>2.</enum><header>DHS grant program relating to detention of migrants</header> 
<subsection id="H9DA0EB9AF7514839BB54DF2F7E1D38A3" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Department of Homeland Security a grant program, to be known as the <quote>Detention and Logistics Program</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>), to reimburse States and local governments the costs incurred, on and after January 20, 2025, by such States or local governments, as the case may be, relating to the detention of migrants at detention facilities in such States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H710C4B4F5FD245569F3661444E879D8D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible for reimbursement under the Program, a State or local government, as the case may be, shall submit to the Secretary of Homeland Security an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H106E6728B10746C5AA1565C1772121FE" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall transfer the unobligated balances of all amounts made available as of the date of the enactment of this Act to the <quote>Shelter and Services Program</quote> administered by the Federal Emergency Management Agency to, and merge such balances with, appropriate accounts of the Department of Homeland Security to carry out the Program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H522522B172484A1BAFFC89B0EFEE6ECB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report that includes the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H4D74B7F503254755A7D742ABBFD1CCFC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A plan for—</text> <subparagraph id="H707B9009B8004493BC98C3A30F6695DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coordinating with States to rapidly construct new migrant detention facilities; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9745FC9B62A04D33AC4C337FDCE4250F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifying Federal or State properties that might be used for such construction.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD956BFE5EEEB490CB582235F2687000C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The identification of underutilized, wasteful, or redundant accounts the funding of which could be better utilized by the Detention and Logistics Program of the Department of Homeland Security.</text> </paragraph> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

