<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3F6F7B68A60345AE9A33017A791D2C64" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1815 IH: VA Home Loan Program Reform Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1815</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250303">March 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to take certain actions in the case of a default on a home loan guaranteed by the Secretary, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC079C3AE9C064EEE941B852B1E4187F1" style="OLC"><section id="HD4389A0E9D1044E2BC9F5C3E6963914C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>VA Home Loan Program Reform Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFC70F33AE4CE4F0291F79A9817742D0A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authority of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to take certain actions in the case of a default on a home loan guaranteed by the Secretary</header><subsection id="HEDE02439D1E14C68A09EFAD8AFA01412"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3732 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF39D5B87E1014D6B812393E8222F2FD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA8C410CEC16B43E999E7B130D6F095D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>obligation</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>loan</quote>; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H096EEC264BAF49219A3EDABA1BC958F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H29956EE043F74F74A1527332A034AE5A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC83B6BB153A4B7EB5CEF59333A0B328"><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H95D3474B73D247F09E6E873B95911649" indent="up2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may, under terms and conditions as determined by the Secretary—</text><clause id="H9AA5AC59461A43BCA342DD3BF23AC1FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>pay the holder of a loan guaranteed under this chapter an amount necessary to avoid the foreclosure of such loan;</text></clause><clause id="H1E1ACA7C844243D0B4D0F6ED94C01C64"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>require the holder of the loan and the veteran obligated on the loan to execute all documents necessary to ensure the Secretary obtains a secured interest in the property covered by the loan; and</text></clause><clause id="H7EDD74FA30C646E1A1C57B79BB52A05B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>require the holder of the loan to take any actions necessary to carry out this paragraph, including preparing, executing, transmitting, receiving, and recording documents, and requiring the holder of the loan to place the loan in forbearance.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="HF1EA36B21A094366A4D51B5CE2412D27"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>obligation</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>housing loan</quote>; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC183B910FEAD4A89A1122E081DCCF903"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H49F9EC219C994DF5BB062A453D1683B8"><subparagraph id="HB66659DD1ADC482B8F15D9F1D337B356" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1F3519BE44FF492DB3BE0F5D991DC024"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Any decision by the Secretary under this paragraph is final and is not subject to judicial review.</text></clause><clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF297C3E1EE944AB697397081B4D5AEB1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 511 of this title, any decision under this paragraph shall not be treated as a decision under a law that affects the provision of benefits.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC1FEC3DF4C38496C865358AD75E5AD77" indent="up2"><enum>(D)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HACC74403F90543A6881B4BEC531EE768"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may establish standards for processing payments under this paragraph based on a certification by a holder of a loan guaranteed under this chapter that the holder has complied with all applicable requirements established by the Secretary.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48B1DBF318134411A41F2008025EC02B" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out, on a random-sampling basis, post-payment audits to ensure compliance with all requirements described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H52BD20D75ECC4C44831808A53D1568AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>obligation</quote> and inserting <quote>loan</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0A50AC1B72094F7C9943C2715BFF0840"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)(10)(B)(i), by striking <quote>forebearance</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>forbearance</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H80F5859249D0476DB3DD92384E326633"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C3797FB91E74EA7B2DFB4DB034D26EF"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0741F49ED15A4A408BAD7CDE7AE6F662"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall prescribe loss mitigation procedures, including a mandatory sequence in which the holder of a loan guaranteed under this chapter shall offer loss mitigation options (including an option to enter into a partial claim agreement under the <short-title>VA Home Loan Program Reform Act</short-title>) to a veteran, to help prevent the foreclosure of such loan. The Secretary may not purchase an entire such loan until the veteran has completed such sequence.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF64C513ABA7B47B5B0E9D914A4B80BB8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relationship to other powers of Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3720 of such title is amended—</text><paragraph id="H5883F1B82BE54A97AF454638B49CCC9F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>Notwithstanding</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in subsection (h), notwithstanding</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D403814F380496D89D84F664A648303"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (f) through (h) as subsections (e) through (g), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H974A854397E543BF9D88855ADFCACDD7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection (h):</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H7A05402FC8F24FA2AD1B97BE3E485259" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H8030B4487B074D1BB862DF426B32038A"><enum>(h)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not take any action under paragraph (2),(3),(4), or (5) of subsection (a) with respect to a loan guaranteed under this chapter before the completion of the sequence of mitigation options offered to the veteran to whom the loan is made under section 3732(d) of this title.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3D86EDED3CFA4CAC93B0A10C350F2458" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Partial Claim Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="H48EEE2BCA6E8421FB7CEDBAF4D4A5D6D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out a program, to be known as the <quote>Partial Claim Program</quote>, under which the Secretary may make a partial claim, described in subsection (b), with respect to a loan—</text><paragraph id="HF2277BABE72E4631BAC11D7BCE856A35"><enum>(1)</enum><text>guaranteed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/37">chapter 37</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF8526CD332641EC8D4C3BC60601DED1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>regarding the primary residence of the borrower; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2460F6A06F3C4D83AC393AF3D1B532AD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the Secretary determines is in default or at imminent risk of default.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC8F39FA89CCE4324B7AF79590D62EC74"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Partial claim described</header><text>A partial claim described in this subsection is the purchase by the Secretary of a portion of indebtedness under the guaranteed loan, under which—</text><paragraph id="HBA7ACC07D53C4E9DBD9196030F9DC14F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the borrower of the guaranteed loan enters into an agreement under subsection (c);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB95CAD582B924542B906FA492C95FE96"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary pays the holder of the guaranteed loan the amount of indebtedness, subject to subsection (d), that the Secretary determines necessary to help prevent or resolve a default; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2110D24A94E4484D858108808A9DB9C9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Secretary receives a secured interest in the property, subordinate to the first lien guaranteed loan, serving as collateral for the guaranteed loan.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4D05CEBFD601405990DA7BC4E2BCE147" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Agreement between borrower and Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agreement under this subsection is an agreement by the borrower of the guaranteed loan to repay the Secretary the amount determined under subsection (b)(2) at the end of the period of such guaranteed loan, subject to the following annual interest:</text><paragraph id="HE915CADB889A479CBE22A3123B1F9635"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If the borrower agrees to make monthly payments beginning not later than three years after the date on which the Secretary makes the payment under subsection (b)(2), 0 percent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B1302B924B94A1BB8074DE24AFD40E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If the borrower does not agree to a repayment plan under paragraph (1), or fails to comply with such a repayment plan, 0.5 percent.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H51C26771C4FC4E79A175E32ABAF2537B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administration of partial claim</header><paragraph id="HF387AF3EDDEC4331B29885FE72379F85"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amount of claim</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of a partial claim under this section with respect to a loan guaranteed under such chapter may not exceed 20 percent of the unpaid principal balance of the guaranteed loan on the date on which the partial claim is made.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9777A67AF1344F698A91E6FC5E62CC5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>One partial claim per loan</header><text>The Secretary may make only one partial claim per loan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8888C79617B4D8E8E84F7277471F7B6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Not an advance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not structure a partial claim as an advance on a new loan guaranteed under such chapter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H813C4021A8B644429CBD177C62DA9F4E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Application of claim</header><text>A holder of a loan guaranteed under such chapter who receives a partial claim under this section with respect to such loan shall apply the payment first to arrearages, if any, on the guaranteed loan, which may include any additional costs (such as taxes, insurance premiums, or homeowner’s dues) the Secretary determines necessary to prevent or resolve a default.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61B055ACFEFD46A7AF35787E873585A9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Authority to contract</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may enter into a contract with an entity for service of a partial claim under this section. Such entity shall provide quarterly statements to the borrower.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8F8042D43A62421CBDECC6214950A293"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Requirements of loan holder</header><paragraph id="H0F4DAB7DC4B34F6D833B8F1E1C6BCADE" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment of claim</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may require the holder of a loan, regarding which the Secretary makes a partial claim under this section, to take any actions necessary to establish the partial claim, including preparing, executing, transmitting, receiving, and recording loan documents. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16799B54C4624F5AA27486926C5CB35D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensation of holder</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall compensate the holder of such a loan appropriately, as determined by the Secretary, for the services required of such holder under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H26FE17A40C884B3E9FC79801F4F46404" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exercise of powers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may exercise the authority of the Secretary under this subsection without regard to any other provision of law not enacted expressly in limitation of this section that would otherwise govern the expenditure of public funds. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3A937C4905B742D5B9A6E61CE533D707"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Default and foreclosure</header><paragraph id="HA98E57B2CF6A47A18322736255099D05" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Default</header><subparagraph id="H28CEE7435AB64FEB9B3209D7BA0C1001" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 3703(e) of title 38, United States Code, an individual who defaults under a partial claim made under this section shall be liable to the Secretary for any loss suffered by the Secretary resulting from such default, and such loss may be recovered in the same manner as any other debt due the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58BAC7C0D269444AABED551D50A35AF7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reduction of entitlement</header><text>In the event of default by an individual under a partial claim made under this section, the Secretary may reduce the aggregate amount of guaranty or insurance housing loan entitlement available to the individual under such chapter. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H616BB5BA6AAF4B0A80C2C67A1FCF2101"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreclosure</header><text>Notwithstanding section 2410(c) of title 28, United States Code, an action to foreclose a lien held by the United States arising under a partial claim made under this section shall follow foreclosure procedures in accordance with State or local law where the property involved is located.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H87EB678BD35849CF9DF498373AFB812D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Decisions by the Secretary</header><paragraph id="H2E7F466A08A641A689C1CD4953D536B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Sole discretion</header><text>Any partial claim under this section shall be made in the sole discretion of the Secretary and on terms and conditions acceptable to the Secretary that are consistent with this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D7D009E55EF4AD88E7CF87DF6CB4070" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final and conclusive</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any decision by the Secretary under this section is final and conclusive and is not subject to judicial review. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8FF1A9CA49840E781F0B9A4764FB102" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effect on provision of benefits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 511 of title 38, United States Code, any decision under this section shall not be treated as a decision under a law that affects the provision of benefits.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBEF524F5D1434C089549847C06095535"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Compliance</header><paragraph id="HA3F9E58E6B6B45E88318229BD3D30842" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Processing payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may establish standards for processing payments under this section based on a certification by a holder of a loan guaranteed under such chapter that the holder has complied with all applicable requirements established by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BE6876FFBEF4536B0B37208D016CF25" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Audits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out, on a random-sampling basis, post-payment audits to ensure compliance with all requirements described in paragraph (1). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0D8AAB5D1AB441B8A9C9AEC3E9644BA5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Guidance with respect to certain loans</header><paragraph id="HC5044916483C4447A38B1346A070EDDB" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a loan described in paragraph (2), the Secretary may—</text><subparagraph id="H2B7E12191B27435DA2196FF0E7E8AB1E" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">before prescribing regulations, issue administrative guidance regarding the making of a partial claim relating to such loan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9665BF6D26649518062EDA5AE4B7E4E" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish, through such guidance, additional requirements applicable to such a partial claim. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6841E5DCD7AD4D31996570FF907D074E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Loan described</header><text>A loan described in this paragraph is a loan that the Secretary determines was in default on the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC907DAFF47BA40B38007279E4EABE799"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary under subsections (a) and (d) of section 3732 of title 38, United States Code, as amended by section 2 of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H612345C3EA414F3BAE766D09288F5804" commented="no"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Secretary may not make a partial claim under this section after September 30, 2027.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE1A8BFC717DC4E238D3D726C6187C935"><enum>4.</enum><header>Strategy of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs regarding the effect of certain litigation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report on the strategy of the Secretary to ensure that a veteran who seeks to purchase a home with a loan guaranteed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/37">chapter 37</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is not at a disadvantage when attempting to secure representation by a real estate agent or broker. Such strategy may include amendments to section 36.4313 of title 38, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

