<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BUR25164-VC4-0N-SRM"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 S556 IS: Enhanced Iran Sanctions Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 556</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250212">February 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To impose sanctions with respect to persons engaged in logistical transactions and sanctions evasion relating to oil, gas, liquefied natural gas, and related petrochemical products from the Islamic Republic of Iran, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Enhanced Iran Sanctions Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0f66978093d64683943296fc88636034"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id260a49e187af430c870fe3966ca8f5e8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that, in accordance with the Iran Nuclear Weapons Capability and Terrorism Monitoring Act of 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8701">22 U.S.C. 8701</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/263">Public Law 117–263</external-xref>), the United States must— </text><subparagraph id="idbe0a6528d53440b58d813c32496a4103"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that the Islamic Republic of Iran does not acquire a nuclear weapons capability;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id431927b1bf1f4058910a3cabc7803158"><enum>(B)</enum><text>protect against aggression from the Islamic Republic of Iran manifested through its missiles and drone programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5080ddb5148b4c2188919f13767afe61"><enum>(C)</enum><text>counter regional and global terrorism of the Islamic Republic of Iran in a manner that minimizes the threat posed by state and non-state actors to the interests of the United States;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1e8f231bef1d4b6a8243b6111b5beb9b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to fully enforce sanctions against all persons involved in the international logistical chain that provide support to the energy sector of the Islamic Republic of Iran;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb3ebcf954c4d4cdd8cac0e37120b7172"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">through such sanctions, to deny the Islamic Republic of Iran the financial resources required—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9c7015ea51464205bf230c68331b862e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to fund and facilitate international terrorism;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb04a2dd8706c4260b4936912a841b171"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to finance the development of weapons of mass destruction; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0dae696fa4844dcdbc5ecea57cf8b2a1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to engage in destabilizing efforts abroad; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75fdfa937a6b4280b4e940d59d460dc8"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to repress the rights of Iranian citizens; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb3444a4f49d1404bbe4c1f160a47de2a"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to strengthen coherence among members of the international community in enforcing sanctions on the malign activity of the Islamic Republic of Iran.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34dbf66271f449749a1451e7855081b0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id3b8effb433324280a3c2be087a91ab6b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Admitted; alien</header><text>The terms <term>admitted</term> and <term>alien</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id218b5eeb6cdd45c49349acd587c4501a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idd02cb490818144d8b7d0e411723cb47d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3ff1f503854d4d999e69a2b81ae410e0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4fb2a93fe17e428baaed975e8484ae50"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means a person that is not a United States person, including the government of a foreign country.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0047992c1b764da38f4c4b34e9fac335"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Knowingly</header><text>The term <term>knowingly</term>, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person has actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id50fd78e6574b40668e6a1affab3a608c" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Property; interest in property</header><text>The terms <term>property</term> and <term>interest in property</term> have the meanings given the terms <quote>property</quote> and <quote>property interest</quote>, respectively, in section 576.312 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb0b70ea6a16a40a0bf6f3e1099bbf54e"><enum>(6)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id0717468733e647d7a2417c53bb21bd33"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual who is a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id222ea63e13ca4b0d9f45e5204fbce127"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbb49283a19b249bd8e437e83dd5ebd0d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any person in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id7a99d946eff540e4a12c01d2bb10782f"><enum>4.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Imposition of sanctions with respect to persons engaged in logistical transactions of oil, gas, liquefied natural gas, and petrochemical products from the Islamic Republic of Iran</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3b8fc951ff624184b9f699ef19e53d49"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On and after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any foreign person, including any bank or foreign financial institution, insurance provider, flagging registry, pipeline construction or operation facility for liquefied natural gas, that—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1a4684ba92594019a00f6ed17f2da89f"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the President determines knowingly engaged in, on or after such date of enactment, any transaction involved in, relating or incident to the processing, export, or sale of oil, condensates, gas, liquefied natural gas, or other petrochemical products in whole or in part from the Islamic Republic of Iran; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id088e7692c2f34651abd583d886b23d7d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is a subsidiary, successor, or alias of a foreign person described in paragraph (1); </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7c3106e910314b429570e8ea4816e3c0"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idfea8c3c57829487da8f515e1792ce1d0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">directly or indirectly owns or controls a 50 percent or greater interest in or is owned or controlled by a 50 percent or greater interest of a foreign person or foreign persons subject to sanctions pursuant to paragraph (1) or (2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id694d18f278b7467d94e44a821cb3f652" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">directly or indirectly conducts a significant transaction with, for, or on behalf of a foreign person described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of section 3(b) of the Stop Harboring Iranian Petroleum Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8572">22 U.S.C. 8572</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaf67ec2f83434243b233ec48ba6bb1c8"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the President determines is a corporate officer of a foreign person described paragraph (1), (2), or (3); or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75f0047ba71a439dbfc007c0b72b2d5f"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an immediate family member of a foreign person described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id438a590725ef4d50853ac0e8dbb696f0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="id35114af5c88f4ab38a429166b03c36a6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>The President shall, pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>), block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of a foreign person subject to sanctions pursuant to subsection (a)(1) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id63c87dd81fe6435dba5cdf845798e6ff"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aliens inadmissible for visas, admission, or parole</header><subparagraph id="id84b596761cba4976975ff699c0127398"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>In the case of an alien subject to sanctions pursuant to subsection (a), the alien is—</text><clause id="id30e0657f5e294b8c9f7dd23fa84db1d7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause><clause id="id52b63f766367462aa5797e1833089a28"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="id1e96924b2e3a4f5991e8bb3b2deb276c"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb789718a3f114046bcfe4ed42a478e86"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><clause id="id3e92f14d1d63419196afdac19ae491e3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The visa or other entry documentation of an alien described in subparagraph (A) shall be revoked, regardless of when such visa or other entry documentation was issued.</text></clause><clause id="id206e042500014f2da6b1891452a10d99"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Immediate effect</header><text>A revocation under clause (i) shall—</text><subclause id="id856a995407e34f1085f19ab02419095c"><enum>(I)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idb372f67cc36a43f6bcfda4422d281ae8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9ac0759238b14cb8a2e755c99e48bfb4" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="id4e2569f92c9c425485754c4335e6304d" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exception relating to importation of goods</header><subparagraph id="id489138d99a934f0f8e8deb499c00877b" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The requirement to impose sanctions under this section shall not include the authority or a requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6a142531e32142f3a137539c301866c1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Good defined</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>good</term> means any article, natural or manmade substance, material, supply, or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id91791182340a474484b19aa65b47a67e" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception to comply with international obligations and law enforcement activities</header><text>Sanctions under subsection (b)(2) shall not apply with respect to an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide140f2def3ee44e5a7a7ab7f97635c24"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id726a98146938471394415a143e427314"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to carry out or assist authorized law enforcement activity in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd043b496993444588adbcbb87dbe2dd0" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf56001bd995148668a941942d3ac23eb"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may, on a case-by-case basis for a period of not more than 180 days, waive the application of sanctions imposed with respect to a foreign person under this section if the President—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd1a5a6df225d4f008d61dc5e299aaf70"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the waiver is vital to the national interests of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a0c2a8270224a07b3c1918b7c39ab0c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submits with the certification required under subparagraph (A) a detailed justification explaining the reasons for the waiver.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7d6347a59c6a43178692824511bae431"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Renewal of waiver</header><text>The President may, on a case-by-case basis, renew a waiver issued under paragraph (1) for additional periods of not more than 180 days each up to a total of 2 years if the President—</text><subparagraph id="id6de64b7e71034fc79b22fc1d4f572c92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determines that the renewal of the waiver is vital to the national interests of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc7266d8bf73a41cb86e10fc055f14b9b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less than 15 days before the waiver expires, submits to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the renewal of the waiver that includes—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0df1ea34d1c94ef5adced6c0628c364a"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a justification for the renewal of the waiver; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id32f0b3220ac3428184e4a3f8e5b34063"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a detailed plan to phase out the need for any such waiver issued with respect to such foreign person.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7d33fbb749144ef680ffe0b2e3806ba1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination of waiver authority</header><text>The authority to issue a waiver under this subsection shall terminate on February 1, 2029.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id25ec3627dd904af59f8f2188c750809c" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation; penalties</header><paragraph id="idb8ca5bd42e5847e7b2b65a561867af1d" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0bc2f8dc0d464bd78538e15d2473b843" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of subsection (b)(1) or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out that subsection shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf6a9adc8b8b64d23bfe03b401aa7dcf3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Section 4(a)(3)(A) shall be construed to be consistent with Frequently Asked Questions 398 through 402, published by the Office of Foreign Assets Control on August 11, 2020, and August 13, 2014, or any successors to such frequently asked questions.</text></subsection></section><section id="id7bc999c9c28a4dd59a80aeff262d9f4e"><enum>5.</enum><header>Interagency Working Group on Iranian Sanctions</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf1ddd109732e4999b0eb5eef284bc0be"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall establish a working group to be known as the <quote>Interagency Working Group on Iranian Sanctions</quote> (referred to in this section as the <term>Working Group</term>). </text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcdd7dd2b2e5242c28ec59accca79138c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Working Group shall be composed one or more representatives from each of the following: </text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf1b4e19079a547e6af7d88513a0ee2e2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Department of State.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id195f8b95e6994375ac6839d37d3f6030"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Department of the Treasury.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ebb91afa6944f48a36bc6158167a7b5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Department of Justice.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id89a68e2cc8e0461caa4edff6ab3cd1c1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Such other Federal departments or agencies as the Secretary of State determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id141a8329f97f47fe8c774f05238388e1"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chair</header><text>The President shall designate a Chair of the Working Group.</text></subsection><subsection id="id0cf6e441e211424eada8f198e86c09ea"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Multilateral contact group</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida3e1d7ed357c412e8acd5e03f37b8f17"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Working Group shall endeavor to establish a multilateral contact group with like-minded nations to coordinate international efforts to enforce sanctions imposed with respect to the Islamic Republic of Iran.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91084e22104e497994c04bb930ef401b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The multilateral contact group shall—</text><subparagraph id="id468385900f374e96abf9424db552caf4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>share information on evolving sanctions frameworks to identify areas of difference or enforcement gaps; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6997d4b4e8dc48a7a5f519d9fe61a10b"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">share information on newly-designated entities, </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4c3adf79eaaf4d6b9df4f8d47329efa2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">raise awareness of new sanctions evasion practices; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id601df5ab71db4b3683c24be8e5e9a170"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate on new measures to curb Iranian malign activity, including uranium enrichment activities, ballistic missile production, and support for terrorism. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideda39d4786ee4bfe84351167edd27d04"><enum>6.</enum><header>Private sector reporting on persons engaged in sanctionable activities or sanctions evasion</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 36(b) of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2708">22 U.S.C. 2708(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd6a7a256da324089ae07111f94126192"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (13), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id305c6c348e7d41aca24c9f486957d43c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (14), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ba930e04dba42fc86bbc36fda067ade"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9595A3322D0F40149724446FC03E3D8E"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id66c5e4f73a374f4e92f04c5d9f2a72b6"><enum>(15)</enum><text>the identification a person described in section 4(a) of the <short-title>Enhanced Iran Sanctions Act of 2025</short-title> or any person that has attempted or is attempting to evade sanctions imposed under such Act with proceeds generated by the sale of intercepted oil, gas, liquefied natural gas, petrochemical products, or related products from the Islamic Republic of Iran.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

