<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6C936678A24940D88DB288DE97BD7C35" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2805 IH: Proper Leadership to Align Networks for Broadband Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2805</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information to develop a National Strategy to Close the Digital Divide, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7D3BCBB01A814CC486BBB1DFF866742B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H47CE722C140F4F86862D1242CFDCEFD0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Proper Leadership to Align Networks for Broadband Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PLAN for Broadband Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2F0F233370EC4406B97828B6564F2AB2"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Strategy to Close the Digital Divide</header> <subsection id="HB1AEC431FD674FE0A05F263A41EBF08B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary, in consultation with the heads of the covered agencies, shall develop and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a National Strategy to Close the Digital Divide to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8715D47F03CE44278B4AF474667CF02F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support better management of Federal broadband programs to deliver on the goal of providing high-speed, affordable broadband internet access service to all individuals in the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H44645C13A74E427688D60F50A04F7FE9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>synchronize interagency coordination among covered agencies for Federal broadband programs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDC3D174A6747432BA1F9AAB939FD66DC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>synchronize interagency coordination regarding the process for approving the grant of an easement, right of way, or lease to, in, over, or on a building or any other property owned by the Federal Government for the right to install, construct, modify, or maintain infrastructure with respect to broadband internet access service; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H727B032D837648CA82F618E530753AFE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reduce barriers, lower costs, and ease administrative burdens for State, local, and Tribal governments to participate in Federal broadband programs.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H47213B588BC646E9B452915CFEB2C558"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required contents</header><text>The Strategy shall—</text> <paragraph id="HF263104B726443B8B9CFA8E6BA85B730"><enum>(1)</enum><text>list all— </text> 
<subparagraph id="H75147A0083DD431B9A05F2DD78D150ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Federal broadband programs; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H454E52E261FE415B91FDEEBDF695AE68"><enum>(B)</enum><text>programs that exist at the State and local levels that are directly or indirectly intended to increase the deployment of, access to, the affordability of, or the adoption of broadband internet access service;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F8500CAF74D429E89BEF876D9C70174"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describe current, as of the date on which the Strategy is submitted, Federal efforts to coordinate Federal broadband programs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9CC224386BE74F248232B79FEC629787"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify gaps and limitations, including laws, that hinder, or may hinder, coordination across Federal broadband programs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H98BFF68C78E946EEB5FA19E0530A8DC0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establish clear roles and responsibilities for the heads of the covered agencies, as well as clear goals, objectives, and performance measures, for— </text> <subparagraph id="H1AC45442EE30454E9E665276C862B384"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the management of all Federal broadband programs; and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7F72581D138A4DABAF3E3AF983617EE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>interagency coordination efforts with respect to Federal broadband programs;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD069E5B846C44B9FBDB198981C825B26"><enum>(5)</enum><text>address the cost of the Strategy, the sources and types of resources and investments needed to carry out the Strategy, and where those resources and investments should be targeted based on balancing risk reductions with costs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H36E4BAA9B8AA4E24AAAB5C3CDE756315"><enum>(6)</enum><text>address factors that increase the costs and administrative burdens for State, local, and Tribal governments with respect to participation in Federal broadband programs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCAAD62266CBA481FA50F14F2542D3D19"><enum>(7)</enum><text>recommend incentives, legislative solutions, and administrative actions to help State, local, and Tribal governments more efficiently—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC1FBCFCB0EB44B7BAD40736622B50223"><enum>(A)</enum><text>distribute, and effectively administer, funding received from Federal broadband programs; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H811A09B593CF4814964D72B95454BA33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>resolve conflicts with respect to the funding described in subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA2F4EB48C48544648C513DA28B216C3C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>recommend incentives, legislative solutions, and administrative actions to— </text> <subparagraph id="H7C64C80DD04542EAB4DE82E27E5D9E43"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improve the coordination and management of Federal broadband programs; and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5A2F17DD15A84F92BFB57F816C69DC7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>eliminate duplication with respect to Federal broadband programs; </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDD8DABF8D781411EBF0E170D62296945"><enum>(9)</enum><text>describe current, as of the date on which the Strategy is submitted, efforts by covered agencies to streamline the process for granting access to an easement, right of way, or lease to, in, over, or on a building or any other property owned by the Federal Government for the right to install, construct, modify, or maintain infrastructure with respect to broadband internet access service; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0EA7841ACE7F48D1BACDC0899FC57FAC"><enum>(10)</enum><text>identify gaps and limitations with respect to allowing regional, interstate, or cross-border economic development organizations to participate in Federal broadband programs; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D4447C71D5F475BB9DD828251EF5E15"><enum>(11)</enum><text>address specific issues relating to closing the digital divide on Tribal lands. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H424E6D0CB1C2433CA289801C65989976"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public consultation</header><text>In developing the Strategy, the Assistant Secretary shall consult with—</text> <paragraph id="H99125FF9ECA0492EAA2841DE0DC56A6F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>groups that represent consumers or the interests of the public, including economically or socially disadvantaged individuals;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF5D971BB51CF4409AD5EA3FA61FD3D77"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject matter experts;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE5F678C469E47978278BFE921337243"><enum>(3)</enum><text>providers of broadband internet access service;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1097C2523C24082A8709BD334AA21DF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Tribal entities; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA69EC40007F446958DA4A823B0B80856"><enum>(5)</enum><text>State and local agencies and entities.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H1DCD5F24193543559912B2724FE25246"><enum>3.</enum><header>Implementation Plan</header> 
<subsection id="H85AA355762DC4E57AB8F766402FBCD73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date on which the Assistant Secretary submits the Strategy to the appropriate committees of Congress under section 2(a), the Assistant Secretary shall develop and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress an implementation plan for the Strategy.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9E9F774ECD14492EA0F20F7181D1195F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required contents</header><text>The Implementation Plan shall, at a minimum—</text> 
<paragraph id="H197D2FADBEE74C2C89C8B784E671AE83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide a plan for implementing the roles, responsibilities, goals, objectives, and performance measures for the management of Federal broadband programs and interagency coordination efforts identified in the Strategy;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE931758F587A468782C46FED0324C509"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide a plan for holding the covered agencies accountable for the roles, responsibilities, goals, objectives, and performance measures identified in the Strategy;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFA0D11C8FA694DF69E9FB055821442E5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>describe the roles and responsibilities of the covered agencies, and the interagency mechanisms, to coordinate the implementation of the Strategy;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA09810582388485BB0D139601E706D87"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide a plan for regular meetings among the heads of the covered agencies to coordinate the implementation of the Strategy and improve coordination among Federal broadband programs and for permitting processes for infrastructure with respect to broadband internet access service;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFA641CFDDA6F49A3A3FDCDB5D2B87C4B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide a plan for regular engagement with interested members of the public to evaluate Federal broadband programs, permitting processes for infrastructure with respect to broadband internet access service, and progress in implementing the Strategy;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4EF0B5B132AF408380C7B371748F5E8D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>with respect to the awarding of Federal funds or subsidies to support the deployment of broadband internet access service, provide a plan for the adoption of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB5D4B760D5DD40918878D61F67FF6C53"><enum>(A)</enum><text>common data sets regarding those awards, including a requirement that covered agencies use the maps created under title VIII of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/641">47 U.S.C. 641 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H09FA0A3F9F594AC987F30E86CB33AC83"><enum>(B)</enum><text>applications regarding those awards, as described in section 903(e) of the ACCESS BROADBAND Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1307">47 U.S.C. 1307(e)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5C8AFCCCA8B44B33BBB7AAECDFBFB361"><enum>(7)</enum><text>provide a plan to monitor and reduce waste, fraud, and abuse in Federal broadband programs, including wasteful spending resulting from fragmented, overlapping, and unnecessarily duplicative programs; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7EBA1CFEA1074514807B99495B77DF17"><enum>(8)</enum><text>require consistent obligation and expenditure reporting by covered agencies for Federal broadband programs, which shall be consistent with section 903(c)(2) of the ACCESS BROADBAND Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1307">47 U.S.C. 1307(c)(2)</external-xref>); </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1955FA57C7D2472E9361FE1DA02E5FD8"><enum>(9)</enum><text>provide a plan to increase awareness of, and participation and enrollment in, Federal broadband programs relating to the affordability and adoption of broadband internet access service; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B3960458C614A7A99E64405DF5254CE"><enum>(10)</enum><text>describe the administrative and legislative action that is necessary to carry out the Strategy.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB70DFACA352747D09676C6909170841E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public comment</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Assistant Secretary submits the Strategy to the appropriate committees of Congress under section 2(a), the Assistant Secretary shall seek public comment regarding the development and implementation of the Implementation Plan. </text></subsection></section> <section id="H6DFA746DACFB42AAB7882108FA21046B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Briefings and implementation</header> <subsection id="H477AEF8EE2FD4BA8A9415803760A84F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 21 days after the date on which the Assistant Secretary submits the Implementation Plan to the appropriate committees of Congress under section 3(a), the Assistant Secretary, and appropriate representatives from the covered agencies involved in the formulation of the Strategy, shall provide a briefing on the implementation of the Strategy to the appropriate committees of Congress.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA83D1BBF8B414306AA40BEECE96A8FA7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header> 
<paragraph id="HBF7099D49EBA483AA66A4F0EA88E5A77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H55928E231A7A41D0AD7AE7479751135E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>implement the Strategy in accordance with the terms of the Implementation Plan; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF4EF62C223884C39A88AD98A1EE7937D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 90 days after the date on which the Assistant Secretary begins to implement the Strategy, and not less frequently than once every 90 days thereafter until the date on which the Implementation Plan is fully implemented, brief the appropriate committees of Congress on the progress in implementing the Implementation Plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6906EDD42062412690B9A85D42E5CE33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to affect the authority or jurisdiction of the Federal Communications Commission or confer upon the Assistant Secretary or any executive agency the power to direct the actions of the Federal Communications Commission, either directly or indirectly. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H31D3CAE0F5F747E99B1C8594695D1DD7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Government Accountability Office study and report</header> 
<subsection id="H56AD4B9DF8DC4A13A5BD84D2E45F35F4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study that shall— </text> <paragraph id="H4D34480E090E4A2F8A62F490627288A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examine the efficacy of the Strategy and the Implementation Plan in closing the digital divide; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H89D77B66B77D43E3BB9A8DB74960A61E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make recommendations regarding how to improve the Strategy and the Implementation Plan.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0412717D3FAD43988FBC0F3B20D3E558"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Assistant Secretary submits the Implementation Plan to the appropriate committees of Congress under section 3(a), the Comptroller General shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the results of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H1472855AC12841A58C9129798B561478"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H0067EA32718E476098F103F01FAAB0AC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3C44E5C9C46343609E99CC45925293A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0D6A0951B6C14060881F9F9E2F5C94DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H193EC3AE46214FC89FDED8FA20127579"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Assistant Secretary</quote> means the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H95AF2CECB49B4FE3B7828D4597531FC5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered agencies</header><text>The term <term>covered agencies</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFD4C1D35C7F14DD69CB8A70DD1D0264B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal Communications Commission;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF8E69E93263148B9A36A71F8A215B166"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of Agriculture;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H75CBED59098A4C7BA5EB55E390DB38E0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the National Telecommunications and Information Administration;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H722A7F61CA4641719580E60BC741904E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Department of Health and Human Services;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4EB79BAEC4DD46E68FC293C5D0DF8BB8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Appalachian Regional Commission;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H625983C7D7A44C09A54634C051F83B51"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Delta Regional Authority;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB0DEBCCD43194D92B4CC866055A10E8F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Economic Development Administration;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB365B1D61C3E464FAE8977099F1B5D39"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Department of Education;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0AD4641090C14EFBA1D51D63291D2B13"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Department of the Treasury;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H45DBFE99231D408A8D6EC6FB673E6229"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the Department of Transportation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H768F7052310C43B4BF7FB74FE4FDF0C6"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the Institute of Museum and Library Services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H73731277EC9A4B91827F65902AB5A1A5"><enum>(L)</enum><text>the Northern Border Regional Commission; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H67032858338E4C81A571019B2FFAD531"><enum>(M)</enum><text>the Department of Housing and Urban Development; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5D9AF27B9B5B46DB85BC5E4329D5426E"><enum>(N)</enum><text>the Department of the Interior. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF74BAA3DFA1242F783E75BDD31B2DC9C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal broadband program</header><text>The term <term>Federal broadband program</term> means any program administered by a covered agency that is directly or indirectly intended to increase the deployment of, access to, the affordability of, or the adoption of broadband internet access service.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD5853E9A3B6548C7B36FE718D847FFBE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Implementation plan</header><text>The term <term>Implementation Plan</term> means the implementation plan developed under section 3(a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6AABE522CD52444AA2C58557F8DC3123"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>State</quote> means each State of the United States, the District of Columbia, and each commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2D47C1EC8B142B2949F0DC84DD8BB6A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Strategy</header><text>The term <term>Strategy</term> means the National Strategy to Close the Digital Divide developed under section 2(a).</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

