<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25973-2XC-3T-K7X"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 392 ATS: Expressing support for the designation of November 16, 2025, as “National Warrior Call Day” and recognizing the importance of connecting members of the Armed Forces and veterans in the United States to support structures necessary to transition from the battlefield, especially peer-to-peer connection.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 392</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250916">September 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S414">Mr. Ossoff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of November 16, 2025, as <quote>National Warrior Call Day</quote> and recognizing the importance of connecting members of the Armed Forces and veterans in the United States to support structures necessary to transition from the battlefield, especially peer-to-peer connection.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas establishing an annual <quote>National Warrior Call Day</quote> will draw attention to the members of the Armed Forces and veterans in the United States whose connection to one another is key to supporting<italic></italic> those members and veterans who may be dangerously disconnected from family, friends, and support systems;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the number of suicides of members of the Armed Forces was 523 in 2023, 363 of whom were on active duty;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2023, the overall rate of suicide deaths per 100,000 members of the Armed Forces reached 25.6;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2022, there were 6,407 suicide deaths among veterans, a slight increase from 6,404 suicide deaths in 2021; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the rate of suicide among veterans, not adjusted for sex or age, in 2022 was 34.7 per 100,000;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, after adjusting for sex and age, the rate of veteran suicide in 2022 was nearly 10.5 percent more than the rate of suicide in non-veteran adults;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Department of Veterans Affairs found in its 2024 National Veteran Suicide Prevention Annual Report that in 2022, <quote>Suicide was the 2nd-leading cause of death for Veterans under age 45-years-old.</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many of the veterans who die by suicide have had no known contact with the Department of Veterans Affairs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a myriad of factors leads to increased isolation and disconnection, further exacerbating mental and physical ailments such as post-traumatic stress disorder, traumatic brain injury, anxiety, and depression;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas invisible wounds linked to an underlying and undiagnosed traumatic brain injury can present as or exacerbate a mental health condition, a problem that can be addressed through appropriate medical treatment; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas additional research is needed to establish traumatic brain injury as a root cause of invisible wounds and suicide by members of the Armed Forces and veterans; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas November 16, 2025, would be an appropriate day to designate as <quote>National Warrior Call Day</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idb5bf90d32534435dbdeae2fe28a7e60d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of November 16, 2025, as <quote>National Warrior Call Day</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcd12e64c9bc1450997f5d4112021c674"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages all individuals in the United States, especially members of the Armed Forces serving on active duty and veterans, to call a warrior, have an honest conversation, and connect them with support, understanding that making a warrior call could reduce isolation and potentially save a life; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id18cfd80a89b94fb29154a290fd54e2a1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>implores all individuals in the United States to recommit themselves to engaging with members of the Armed Forces and veterans through <quote>National Warrior Call Day</quote> and other constructive efforts that result in solutions and treatment for the invisible scars that can afflict veterans and members of the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

