<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H82B1AD24B96A4292A9C7DB90EAD3DBBA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2527 IH: Early Detection of Vision Impairments for Children Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2527</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250331">March 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to improve children&#8217;s vision and eye health through grants to States, territories, and Tribal organizations, and the provision of technical assistance to support those efforts.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H407FBF4BD390449F9B7F5960EA4BDB26" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE51B1C2679B74DD98526E8C5A4ADB9BE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Early Detection of Vision Impairments for Children Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFB797CB81CDC4785A5EB53346A379A9D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statewide early vision detection and intervention programs and systems related to children’s vision and eye health</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part Q of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280h">42 U.S.C. 280h et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F22C4D7030E466D98CF3A0AA60254F2"> 
<section id="H730E662CF2EC4472BD28109FCD5F3988"><enum>399Z–3.</enum><header>Statewide early vision detection and intervention programs and systems related to children’s vision and eye health</header> 
<subsection id="H33FCCBF4788540B0A2D256725FB616BE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants or cooperative agreements</header> 
<paragraph id="H930FE0953A314AE6A79A9B1F68D50566"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall make awards of grants or cooperative agreements to eligible entities to develop and implement statewide early detection and intervention programs and systems related to children’s vision and eye health.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC1CA27B596E4BE7B3D06CD317662339"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant or cooperative agreement under paragraph (1), an entity shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8A37952BF281449EBF7D9B30E1FA5597"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be a State, territory, Indian Tribe or Tribal organization, or Urban Indian organization, including a State or community department of children and families, health, or public health, or a State educational agency; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA5C3A4513B47454A86F9327346A3335D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5D5D086E947949D1B4D24C7F1034E7B6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of awards</header><text>Amounts provided under a grant or cooperative agreement under paragraph (1) shall be used for three or more of the following activities:</text> <subparagraph id="H696ECA306C514EB99EDCD54F96F225B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Implementing early detection practices (such as vision screening) and intervention initiatives for the purpose of identifying vision concerns in children as they engage in the medical, home, public educational, or early learning setting, promoting referrals to eye care, and promoting the use of evidence-based and age-appropriate standards guided by nationally recognized and uniform guidelines.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H032B375E85774A1F8804536BED13DF18"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing an integrated approach to State-level data collection and management to advance State-based performance improvement systems and uniform children’s vision and eye health guidelines across relevant and appropriate State-level jurisdictions.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H927FE8DAC4AC403891189A0F6AD65773"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Identifying strategies to improve eye health outcomes, expand access to care, and reduce health disparities for the detection, diagnosis, and treatment of ocular disease and eye conditions in children who experience barriers to eye care from rural and underserved populations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H45F186B0F9574D6392E50D1FFC4F28B6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Raising awareness by providing the public, including families, guardians (permanent, legal, or temporary), family or community caregivers, and early learning settings with children’s vision and eye health information that is accurate, accessible, culturally and linguistically competent, comprehensive, up-to-date, and evidence-based or evidence-informed.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H56535AC9EF7441F8B3096B4274E9180A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Establishing a coordinated public health system for vision care and eye health, including early detection, referral to eye care, diagnosis and intervention, and follow-up for children.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB0F7D1C6DD16452C90BAF065AFB344A5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Providing referrals to wrap-around vision services, as necessary, for a future of independent living.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H10C9A2E7E9074C58B62095A857134A5E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Collaboration with necessary community and State partners</header><text>In carrying out activities under this subsection, the recipient of a grant or cooperative agreement shall consult with necessary community and State partners, including State agencies responsible for the administration of title V of Social Security Act (the Maternal and Child Health Block Grant Program), title XIX of such Act (the Medicaid Early Periodic Screening, Diagnosis, and Treatment Program), title XXI of such Act (the State Children’s Health Insurance Program), and parts B and C of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, the Indian Health Service, and consumer groups for the purposes of program and policy development, collaboration, and improvement. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3D1137BA1F1D4C70B2DD5A600198E20A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Evaluation and report</header> 
<subparagraph id="H6A9099B6B7D34B09A92238100B9BC063"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An entity that receives a grant or cooperative agreement under this subsection shall annually submit to the Secretary a report that describes the activities carried out under the grant or agreement, including a description of the period of performance covered under the report, the scope of activities carried out during such period, the outcomes of such activities, and a demonstration of whether funding recipients have met project goals for the designated time period outlined in the initial application under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H57835681D52C460889B39FF694FF001B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability of reports</header><text>The Secretary shall make available to the general public the annual reports under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFA3AC86F3F94425AA2A57D499AB91F98"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header> 
<paragraph id="H6FC0076309384B4B820793CBFF8D3284"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide eligible entities under subsection (a) with technical support in the development, implementation, and enhancement of activities described in such subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC74F9D32BC394EC098D126B6B08FCE32"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall award grants or cooperative agreements to provide technical assistance to eligible entities to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H75A02A43D213452CA2C43AF200576FC7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop, maintain, and improve data collection systems related to children’s vision screening, evaluation, diagnosis, and intervention services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF0784C6B4F8548589BB9DCCB7A9FD58C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disseminate information for stakeholders, including States and local governments, Indian Tribes, Tribal organizations, Urban Indian organizations, public health departments, and nonprofit organizations, to launch effective strategies and interventions in preventing and treating childhood vision disorders;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H453BBB5FE3E546928BFF467BE772E3FD"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct applied research related to early vision screening and intervention programs and outcomes;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBB26047D0678413DAED49161E9BF8600"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure quality monitoring of vision screening, evaluation, and intervention programs and systems; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB49E741B9366415CA6553C5A5377FDCA"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist eligible entities in coordinating on best practices and maintaining national goals related to vision and eye health.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBE9086473C5649E792603AF1EAB1F10D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Evaluation</header> <subparagraph id="H4EEB0297E9E54EE1B29CBE238650343B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this section, the recipient of a grant or cooperative agreement under this subsection shall evaluate the activities conducted with funds received under this section and submit a report to the Secretary on the outcomes, costs, and program effectiveness of such activities.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H89B9DE1A77434A28B65A1AFBB72085AC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A report under subparagraph (A) shall be in such form and contain such information as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H37985E9644DB414E890407467FB5596C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon determination by the Secretary that a report under subparagraph (A) meets the requirements of this paragraph, the recipient shall submit the report to Congress.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3D3987C946964F67B42BEA0A5A48FB3D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant or cooperative agreement under this subsection, an entity shall be a public or nonprofit private organization or institution, with expertise, or demonstrated proficiency, in developing systems-based approaches to children’s vision and eye health for the purpose of providing technical assistance in relation to one or more of the activities described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5C83976E263B446298DB3EB126FD6FA3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination and consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall coordinate and consult with the Health Resources and Services Administration, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, the Administration for Communities and Families, the Indian Health Service, and the Department of Education on recommendations for policy development at the Federal, State, and Tribal levels with the private sector, including consumer, medical, and other health and education child serving not-for-profit organizations with respect to early detection and intervention programs and systems.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCA9C9F3A97944F02BD575F8D51AD1367"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H178FDD3A4BFD4FBAA2BCC88BFE5AB34D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given to the term <term>Indian tribe</term> in section 102 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDEB56561D53946ACA867E99C0A040114" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State educational agency</header><text>The term <term>State educational agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65A121C86E064BD2984145F8AD0EE8A2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Tribal organization</header><text>The term <term>Tribal organization</term> has the meaning given such term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB1326DD35AF543068E32CC48072DB7C2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Urban Indian organization</header><text>The term <term>Urban Indian organization</term> has the meaning given such term in section 4 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7621435A27E3435FA5939509F85D9A9B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB14461F030DE4DBAA6F3954A47BB4E37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to carry out this section, other than subsection (a)(5), $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE07AEC0D66C45F3A6B1D0AD1AE63110"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to carry out subsection (a)(5), $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

