<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB266AE0025214E328B4CCBC60FE06759" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3985 IH: Helping Student Parents Succeed Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3985</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish notification requirements for policies and information concerning expectant and parenting students, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA9EA8F5CBC8041C2B8A0A45FD93DD609" style="OLC"><section id="HF5AC07F47F3E4119AFC791C682A8B630" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Helping Student Parents Succeed Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2E84E711314F4DB3AE5DD7A3D380333D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expectant and parenting students policies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 485 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (20 <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1092">18 U.S.C. 1092</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A8012293DEB4959A734A5D4CC548714" style="OLC"><subsection id="HEEF9CD0FB62B42E8A8812DAE7D9FFE22"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Expectant and parenting students policies</header><paragraph id="HDFBC2B2961954458B0E5B9D73F120C4A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each institution of higher education participating in any program under this title shall develop and make available (including on the institution’s website)—</text><subparagraph id="HCB90F05319C84589893BDA2FBAA7A242"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a statement of policy concerning expectant and parenting students, including the policy of the institution regarding a leave of absence related to pregnancy (and related medical conditions), and a leave of absence related to the birth or adoption of a child, which shall include any option (including time requirements) for making up missed work for taking such a leave of absence; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B47456E4EA1475E9A65EEBFF4E3F230"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all information relating to available resources available at, or provided by, such institution for expectant and parenting students—</text><clause id="HE91B3B9E22084ACD829CE71E877A1DBB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in manner that does not favor one particular such resource over any other such resource; and</text></clause><clause id="H66C1E968BBA049FEBEF8B8588CA6ABF9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that includes the information listed in paragraph (2).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1C93E3C1CB64343B73477AC656DF670"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum information</header><text>An institution of higher education shall, pursuant to paragraph (1), make available the following information:</text><subparagraph id="H28AFD12224A8475BA7E4322594016452"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Information regarding lactation accommodations available to students.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63FD1FC0B9954D25AAE1D91372493904"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the process for requesting accommodations, and the type of accommodations available to expectant and parenting students, including—</text><clause id="H06A1C76BD7D74B14B2B1C0DED83C07E1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>information on accommodations for pregnancy-related medical conditions; and</text></clause><clause id="H1D0F9BD3C7C9490F900BCD9F8F081010"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>information on accommodations for students who have parental responsibilities.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E4F7A20CAB546ACBDC74F1AB865C8B2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Information regarding financial aid eligibility for expectant and parenting students, including—</text><clause id="H155BA941CB7F41FE872045ACAD69A499"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the availability of dependent care allowances for a parenting student for the purposes of determining the student’s cost of attendance;</text></clause><clause id="H0D8D819A2983496AA67618535DBCA983"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the ability to change dependency status, including during an award year, following the birth of a child;</text></clause><clause id="H643BE98EB5554A69B7D4F6EDBF0C2CB3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the availability of and eligibility requirements for any emergency financial aid programs provided by the institution; and</text></clause><clause id="H51EA3DE6D4C04D9B8595A6E63BCC96C4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an explanation of the effect that a leave of absence may have on a student’s demonstration of satisfactory academic progress, including for the purposes of eligibility to participate in financial aid programs under this title.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90D76D85F7274B86A733B07967C269F9"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information on available student support services, programs, and community resources, such as academic advising, child care (including child care subsidy and assistance programs), housing (including housing subsidies and utility assistance programs), food (including food assistance programs), public benefits, health care, health insurance, mental health, transportation benefits, mentoring, and other services available for expectant and parenting students, both on-campus and in the community, and under local, State, and Federal law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12442971E7034F06AB0A6EDE263A1876"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Information regarding the availability of on-campus housing that permits students to live with dependents.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC523B2370AAA45E6B03ED8958A2B5102"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Information on the rights and protections that are guaranteed to expectant and parenting students under applicable Federal and State laws.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACFB94CDBD3648E8B6A7BF0CAC48BA43"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution’s procedures for addressing complaints under title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>), including procedures for reporting complaints under such title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB3A5E53CB82479C8046781D5CF00E79"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution’s procedures for addressing complaints alleging discrimination based on a pregnancy-related disability under section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/701">29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.</external-xref>) or the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>), including procedures for reporting complaints under such laws.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B3CDDD111F349459DA9344DDCE1C211"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The contact information for the institution’s Office of Accessibility, the institution’s title IX coordinator, and any other relevant staff members who serve as a point of contact for, or offer services available to, expectant and parenting students.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

