<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA25487-JPL-7V-LR2">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 263 IS: Condemning the violent antisemitic attack in Boulder, Colorado, and expressing support for the survivors and their families.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>III</distribution-code>
        <congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. RES. 263</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action display="yes">
            <action-date date="20250604">June 4, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution;
                which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the
                    Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
        <official-title display="yes">Condemning the violent antisemitic attack in Boulder,
            Colorado, and expressing support for the survivors and their families.</official-title>
    </form>
    <preamble>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, on June 1, 2025, a violent attack occurred at a peaceful march in Boulder, Colorado, organized by Run for Their Lives;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas Run for Their Lives is an organization that facilitates run and walk events calling for the release of all hostages Hamas kidnapped during the group’s October 7, 2023, terrorist attack and continues to hold in Gaza, over 600 days later;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the attack was carried out with a makeshift flamethrower and Molotov cocktails and injured men and women, including a Holocaust survivor, several of whom suffered serious burns and trauma while peacefully exercising their First Amendment rights;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas authorities are investigating the antisemitic attack as an act of terrorism and a Federal hate crime;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas this attack occurred amid a disturbing national surge in antisemitic incidents, with reported antisemitic activity in Colorado rising 40 percent in 2024 and reaching the highest level nationally in nearly 50 years, according to the Anti-Defamation League;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas Jewish communities across the United States have experienced an increase in threats and intimidation in recent months, including fatal shootings, arson, and harassment at synagogues and on college campuses;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas antisemitic violence threatens lives and violates the core values of the United States;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas Federal, State, and local officials, along with community leaders, have condemned the attack, reaffirming a shared commitment to ensuring the safety of Jewish Americans and all communities targeted by hate;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas law enforcement officials, including the Boulder Police Department and the Federal Bureau of Investigation, responded swiftly and continue to investigate the incident to bring the perpetrator to justice;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the Boulder- and Denver-based chapters of the Run for Their Lives plan to continue walking each Sunday, despite the terror attack against members of the Boulder chapter, to show solidarity and to continue calling for the release of the hostages in Gaza; and</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas elected officials and community leaders in Boulder have called on residents to unite in support of the survivors and to reject antisemitism and extremism in all forms: Now, therefore, be it</text>
        </whereas>
    </preamble>
    <resolution-body>
        <section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section">
 <text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="idc131b72580ba48fc84b8c3e711a9b0b8"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>condemns the antisemitic attack that occurred on June 1, 2025, in Boulder, Colorado;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id8dea7ede429e4cd28ef66bd80a7c1a7e">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>expresses solidarity with the survivors and their families;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id3262c1634c884cc990110c30ec3bf366"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>recognizes the resilience of the Boulder community and commends their continued efforts to promote peace, safety, and inclusion;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idb50143f4591b42b3a5002ff1521add31">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>calls for continued vigilance and Federal resources to counter rising antisemitism, investigate hate crimes, and support targeted communities;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08db5489455742d1bd2e32cb2fa34033">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">stands with the Jewish community, for freedom of speech and religion and against fear; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ida1590a6a156f4f07b39ab3542bb8d65e">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>affirms that hate and violence have no place in the United States and that all people, regardless of faith or belief, deserve to live free from fear and persecution.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
    </resolution-body>
</resolution>

