<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H7D72AF1840814840A28FD5CE87911956">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4648 IH: Access to Fertility Treatment and Care Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4648</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To require health insurance plans to provide coverage for fertility treatment, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HC2206AE8A77F49FFAA1989A3FA658C9C">
<section id="HE3DBA788924543949B7C64A060B7755F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Access to Fertility Treatment and Care Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3B54087C2AF246BE877DB1E5AC22083D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Standards relating to benefits for fertility treatment</header> <subsection id="HD9CCF66A21B2483690818B19E28988EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBECCBC1A827946E4A3E012F47F3F58BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>PHSA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part D of title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-111">42 U.S.C. 300gg–111 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1781EE88C2D8435E882058B3CB322E91">
<section id="HC5782148C4E54768A1E32E3275E8D8BA"><enum>2799A–11.</enum><header>Standards relating to benefits for fertility treatment</header>
<subsection id="H064A557B992342F0B40AC5257CD443F0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage shall provide coverage for fertility treatment, if such plan or coverage provides coverage for obstetrical services.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H141B632D042C47C589DF18128F61B005"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>fertility treatment</term> includes the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H1606CFD8BD944391ACA912FD149A12F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Preservation of human oocytes, sperm, or embryos.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED68E602F5984D2DA5A10F5A9C2ED067"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Artificial insemination, including intravaginal insemination, intracervical insemination, and intrauterine insemination.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9DF213E8960D4DB4AFCFB7AF484CBD78"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assisted reproductive technology, including in vitro fertilization and other treatments or procedures in which reproductive genetic material, such as oocytes, sperm, and embryos, are handled, when clinically appropriate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBBD65F05A07D45EA9F47EB97EF84CE4C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Genetic testing of embryos.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H788C274DBA974FBF8D5C622291D8AFA5"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Medications prescribed or obtained over-the-counter, as indicated for fertility.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10F7052BC3DD4439BAE5F7F27E5F0294"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Gamete donation.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0CDF193AB1B942B4A04C2F5EABC3A30E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Such other information, referrals, treatments, procedures, medications, laboratory testing, technologies, and services relating to fertility as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H97E735AC04884FFD923977BC2AA3308E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Required coverage</header><text>A group health plan and a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage that includes coverage for obstetrical services shall provide coverage for fertility treatment determined appropriate by the health care provider, regardless of whether the participant, beneficiary, or enrollee receiving such treatment has been diagnosed with infertility as defined by the American Society for Reproductive Medicine, if the treatment is performed at, or prescribed by, a medical facility that is in compliance with relevant standards set by an appropriate Federal agency.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H87C22C5F0D1945589DFB51AB715C8B9E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Cost-sharing, including deductibles and coinsurance, or other limitations for fertility treatment may not be imposed with respect to the services required to be covered under subsection (c) to the extent that such cost-sharing exceeds the cost-sharing applied to other medical services under the group health plan or health insurance coverage or such other limitations are different from limitations imposed with respect to such medical services, except where such limitation is more favorable with respect to fertility treatment. The Secretary shall promulgate interim final regulations to carry out this subsection, notwithstanding the notice and comment requirements of section 553 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0C8DC70CDCB54EC6B5639ED7EFF8D445"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><text>A group health plan and a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage may not—</text>
<paragraph id="H508E3E82E47A41C48BD720E066E964F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide incentives (monetary or otherwise) to a participant, beneficiary, or enrollee to encourage such participant, beneficiary, or enrollee not to seek or obtain fertility treatment to which such participant, beneficiary, or enrollee is entitled under this section or to providers to induce such providers not to provide medically appropriate fertility treatments to participants, beneficiaries, or enrollees;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H607BB15B8B7E4E438D70C46BD9A63F27"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibit a provider from discussing with a participant, beneficiary, or enrollee fertility treatment relating to this section;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE2B3B8936F654806AFB8DD0639416E84"><enum>(3)</enum><text>penalize or otherwise reduce or limit the reimbursement of a provider because such provider provided fertility treatment to a qualified participant, beneficiary, or enrollee in accordance with this section; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB2CFB52CC3A49BEAE99DEAC661FE23C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>on the ground prohibited under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972, the Age Discrimination Act of 1975, section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, or section 1557 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, exclude any individual from coverage in accordance with this section, or discriminate against any individual with respect to such coverage.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H0C4C798D5EB44D52931C51B4615EB560"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require a participant, beneficiary, or enrollee to undergo fertility treatment.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8BEA451AE2144E3BA751F910713FF02B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>A group health plan and a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage shall provide notice to each participant, beneficiary, and enrollee under such plan or coverage regarding the coverage required by this section in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary. Such notice shall be in writing and prominently positioned in any literature or correspondence made available or distributed by the plan or issuer and shall be transmitted—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA33EF32EF99D4F47A2C4EBBC12B7EE7E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than the earlier of—</text> <subparagraph id="H0DB9CBA57CFB408294C69896C3C28F6A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the first standard mailing made by the plan or issuer to the participant, beneficiary, or enrollee following the effective date of such regulations;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6B66BD5414B54ED1B83F697D26C37BE6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as part of any yearly informational packet sent to the participant, beneficiary, or enrollee; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC303FAB16D094A878F2699E6F470E980"><enum>(C)</enum><text>January 1, 2027;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4589244BBEF74935BD0EB86FAB315CE9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a participant, beneficiary, or enrollee not enrolled in the plan or coverage on the date of transmission under paragraph (1), upon initial enrollment of such participant, beneficiary, or enrollee; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCBE20BBB26A34B0A8EFBA89B9D1BC2C6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>on an annual basis after the transmission under paragraph (1) or (2).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H5B8B57E82B504108B55B752FE4598F5C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Level and type of reimbursements</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent a group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage from negotiating the level and type of reimbursement with a provider for care provided in accordance with this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3538A8D95D2E4389990A6F7EDB0AB8CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>ERISA</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5A5670A9AF5342E386E29D7F16EAD472"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Subpart B of part 7 of subtitle B of title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1185">29 U.S.C. 1185 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8566F77C0110432384D9089E978ECD04">
<section id="H7A6FC800319349EB958331240FC6B540"><enum>726.</enum><header>Standards relating to benefits for fertility treatment</header>
<subsection id="H7B08BD7F5304435D9F8C674C4448FC1C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage shall provide coverage for fertility treatment, if such plan or coverage provides coverage for obstetrical services.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H13B04C211EDB4AB59DA29E0D07232AA7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>fertility treatment</term> includes the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HBDB146A74C7C481CAC3FE7B63D14C9CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Preservation of human oocytes, sperm, or embryos.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6BBDF0B13C094C93A240B3BEE2EE4C90"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Artificial insemination, including intravaginal insemination, intracervical insemination, and intrauterine insemination.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4BB03FC91BE4932B73D6D1B6846F18C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assisted reproductive technology, including in vitro fertilization and other treatments or procedures in which reproductive genetic material, such as oocytes, sperm, and embryos, are handled, when clinically appropriate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5B62B43EF8854C9FAD30847C88BEB8DC"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Genetic testing of embryos.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D9EF9CB3F5749CE9478342CCCC35BE0"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Medications prescribed or obtained over-the-counter, as indicated for fertility.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02623FC1EA904FB1B925A98C0F8F8413"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Gamete donation.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H29E6025045164E90A878FAA18240D8E0" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Such other information, referrals, treatments, procedures, medications, laboratory testing, technologies, and services relating to fertility as the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H618822BB20BA42E393500AC9DC2FA6BA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Required coverage</header><text>A group health plan and a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage that includes coverage for obstetrical services shall provide coverage for fertility treatment determined appropriate by the health care provider, regardless of whether the participant or beneficiary receiving such treatment has been diagnosed with infertility as defined by the American Society for Reproductive Medicine, if the treatment is performed at, or prescribed by, a medical facility that is in compliance with relevant standards set by an appropriate Federal agency.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HB204B2E31E024647B31A5B492AFBEC88"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Cost-sharing, including deductibles and coinsurance, or other limitations for fertility treatment may not be imposed with respect to the services required to be covered under subsection (c) to the extent that such cost-sharing exceeds the cost-sharing applied to other medical services under the group health plan or health insurance coverage or such other limitations are different from limitations imposed with respect to such medical services, except where such limitation is more favorable with respect to fertility treatment. The Secretary shall promulgate interim final regulations to carry out this subsection, notwithstanding the notice and comment requirements of section 553 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H584728DED1004E30B3C4F6CEFFE4F492"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><text>A group health plan and a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage may not—</text>
<paragraph id="H770EE01403B04264A90A7CDF82F98B23"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide incentives (monetary or otherwise) to a participant or beneficiary to encourage such participant or beneficiary not to seek or obtain fertility treatment to which such participant or beneficiary is entitled under this section or to providers to induce such providers not to provide medically appropriate fertility treatments to participants or beneficiaries;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2903FF63083843869539AA430F6B5537"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibit a provider from discussing with a participant or beneficiary fertility treatment relating to this section;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBEFE1858E96F41AD853271248ABBADE2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>penalize or otherwise reduce or limit the reimbursement of a provider because such provider provided fertility treatment to a qualified participant or beneficiary in accordance with this section; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H224DFED831BD4F86B40BDEE425EAC629"><enum>(4)</enum><text>on the ground prohibited under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>), title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>), the Age Discrimination Act of 1975 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6101">42 U.S.C. 6101 et seq.</external-xref>), section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>), or section 1557 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18116">42 U.S.C. 18116</external-xref>), exclude any individual from coverage in accordance with this section, or discriminate against any individual with respect to such coverage.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H0B1E8F3DA2544183BEB645B1405B7935"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require a participant or beneficiary to undergo fertility treatment.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB5CAE1AC974F41C8869F2B889D29B610"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>A group health plan and a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage shall provide notice to each participant and beneficiary under such plan or coverage regarding the coverage required by this section in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary. Such notice shall be in writing and prominently positioned in any literature or correspondence made available or distributed by the plan or issuer and shall be transmitted—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1A3E71FDDC2B4EE6B58DFE49D13230A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than the earlier of—</text> <subparagraph id="HC16E7F092742472884F0949BF6550BCC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the first standard mailing made by the plan or issuer to the participant or beneficiary following the effective date of such regulations;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1835C50B07C64383B46F9C40CBB95147"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as part of any yearly informational packet sent to the participant or beneficiary; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2B0D42290DF4625BB8C7D9E09ABFFF0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>January 1, 2027;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13C15FC29E334ABA948F735D364A7329"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a participant or beneficiary not enrolled in the plan or coverage on the date of transmission under paragraph (1), upon initial enrollment of such participant or beneficiary; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H434D48CEB7334AE9AB802CBEE518A1B8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>on an annual basis after the transmission under paragraph (1) or (2).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H5815C672851541A7B8EDFCCB5E66A643"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Level and type of reimbursements</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent a group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage from negotiating the level and type of reimbursement with a provider for care provided in accordance with this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0AEB30E4B52A4C5FB89A6C2B5F1F6EF5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1001">29 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 725 the following new item:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0DDF5E9DFA64C429C4F432D47E8B451">
<toc>
<toc-entry level="section" bold="off">Sec. 726. Standards relating to benefits for fertility treatment.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F5A74C4935C4C36942E558BD3C90ADA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>IRC</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E9B9604192B4AD5BC4FD9C97E6C71D0"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/100">chapter 100</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F0AE04435A7427C8E916284AF4E377C"> <section id="H0D3B40B501ED471081142493729877FB"><enum>9826.</enum><header>Standards relating to benefits for fertility treatment</header> <subsection id="H6F8AB5CCFAEB45D0B8AA8AB9F03FFE84"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A group health plan shall provide coverage for fertility treatment, if such plan provides coverage for obstetrical services.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H4D4B2F691A2F45F99CB0F01AD40FE4D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>fertility treatment</term> includes the following:</text> <paragraph id="H49FEE57756784E77AB6443E825BF4417"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Preservation of human oocytes, sperm, or embryos.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H95FB4537B1B4402DB8A964B3687E3A1D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Artificial insemination, including intravaginal insemination, intracervical insemination, and intrauterine insemination.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E74DB2C16014745A2CFA938E0802783"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assisted reproductive technology, including in vitro fertilization and other treatments or procedures in which reproductive genetic material, such as oocytes, sperm, and embryos, are handled, when clinically appropriate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48C9166ECEFC49678C2142A0D313070F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Genetic testing of embryos.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A072D320EB34E5292EB628046E094A2"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Medications prescribed or obtained over-the-counter, as indicated for fertility.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB5A4E130FEC4DB9ADC085E4D44FF3D0"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Gamete donation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A851AA745A044EF80BECC9A6C22F743" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Such other information, referrals, treatments, procedures, medications, laboratory testing, technologies, and services relating to fertility as the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H72929E8E66F540CB971539D265420823"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Required coverage</header><text>A group health plan that includes coverage for obstetrical services shall provide coverage for fertility treatment determined appropriate by the health care provider, regardless of whether the participant or beneficiary receiving such treatment has been diagnosed with infertility as defined by the American Society for Reproductive Medicine, if the treatment is performed at, or prescribed by, a medical facility that is in compliance with relevant standards set by an appropriate Federal agency.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H40ED84C0AD204209A03654C327BDB5C2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Cost-sharing, including deductibles and coinsurance, or other limitations for fertility treatment may not be imposed with respect to the services required to be covered under subsection (c) to the extent that such cost-sharing exceeds the cost-sharing applied to other medical services under the group health plan or health insurance coverage or such other limitations are different from limitations imposed with respect to such medical services, except where such limitation is more favorable with respect to fertility treatment. The Secretary shall promulgate interim final regulations to carry out this subsection, notwithstanding the notice and comment requirements of section 553 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H9CBC0978E6A144D9B9366413EA02067B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><text>A group health plan may not—</text> <paragraph id="H906D38CB45184B8E824757A90245C9FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide incentives (monetary or otherwise) to a participant or beneficiary to encourage such participant or beneficiary not to seek or obtain fertility treatment to which such participant or beneficiary is entitled under this section or to providers to induce such providers not to provide medically appropriate fertility treatments to participants or beneficiaries;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCBD85CA22A554EB4BB73B598F8129228"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibit a provider from discussing with a participant or beneficiary fertility treatment relating to this section;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H238E7EF29F134DEA93B5093A0AE54D31"><enum>(3)</enum><text>penalize or otherwise reduce or limit the reimbursement of a provider because such provider provided fertility treatment to a qualified participant or beneficiary in accordance with this section; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57DAB76901F9456DB2E5F86161298E8B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>on the ground prohibited under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>), title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>), the Age Discrimination Act of 1975 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6101">42 U.S.C. 6101 et seq.</external-xref>), section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>), or section 1557 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18116">42 U.S.C. 18116</external-xref>), exclude any individual from coverage in accordance with this section, or discriminate against any individual with respect to such coverage.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFCF6499715C94E8D94E4CED224DE9681"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require a participant or beneficiary to undergo fertility treatment.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HF9195E0FF25148E0A716C466C0C9B18F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>A group health plan shall provide notice to each participant and beneficiary under such plan regarding the coverage required by this section in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary. Such notice shall be in writing and prominently positioned in any literature or correspondence made available or distributed by the plan and shall be transmitted—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA3A12D6C5D6421E8F29F90F2A20E25E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than the earlier of—</text>
<subparagraph id="H3C9A24ABCC3745218DC3C810C5CB9F15"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the first standard mailing made by the plan to the participant or beneficiary following the effective date of such regulations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H02870CD5B3A14DE2A80DDA0634ADBBA3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as part of any yearly informational packet sent to the participant or beneficiary; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDD651E5A5A194E07923C7DC6F5B5CEF6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>January 1, 2027;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5139B444FA4C4D39BD2F84D5DF8E2E72"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a participant or beneficiary not enrolled in the plan on the date of transmission under paragraph (1), upon initial enrollment of such participant or beneficiary; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6E23F454E96E4CBAB0B21DB8229446D1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>on an annual basis after the transmission under paragraph (1) or (2).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H60232E8DE4DD41B5BF194DCBDB60574F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Level and type of reimbursements</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent a group health plan from negotiating the level and type of reimbursement with a provider for care provided in accordance with this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H827444A69FD8427EBBF94385528D8AF0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/100">chapter 100</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H76BC2418FBF3426B91959BBE60E624C8"> <toc> <toc-entry level="section" bold="off">Sec. 9826. Standards relating to benefits for fertility treatment.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD7CDABBF414142B7BD95853AD4568EA2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE528614DFD54425B9830DA56ABF765F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>PHSA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2724(c) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-23">42 U.S.C. 300gg–23(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 2704</quote> and inserting <quote>sections 2704 and 2799A–11</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H578535F5B9D74F1F9341D72AE38A066D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>ERISA</header><text>Section 731(c) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1191">29 U.S.C. 1191(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 711</quote> and inserting <quote>sections 711 and 726</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H01B8A4D500DA4BA6BEADA2E24AD75979"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective dates</header> <paragraph id="H42EC61B8B1384F9684A81C6B78594D83"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) shall apply for plan years beginning on or after the date that is 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD249C04F72A943B6B505EA4335B1040D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Collective bargaining exception</header>
<subparagraph id="H232C884F2C4E468E958F66DED9E12B6C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a group health plan maintained pursuant to one or more collective bargaining agreements between employee representatives and one or more employers ratified before the date of enactment of this Act, the amendments made by subsection (a) shall not apply to plan years beginning before the later of—</text> <clause id="H7E4F2B293F7F4BE291C0EBFF337D6275"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date on which the last collective bargaining agreements relating to the plan terminates (determined without regard to any extension thereof agreed to after the date of enactment of this Act), or</text></clause>
<clause id="HFF6FBB76541849A2A4D09FF623EBAB6B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date occurring 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAB3B8E83E7AC4CD29F2F230E9A2D2B83"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), any plan amendment made pursuant to a collective bargaining agreement relating to the plan which amends the plan solely to conform to any requirement added by subsection (a) shall not be treated as a termination of such collective bargaining agreement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H003B695AF10C4BF5B197EE6F14F153F7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal Employees Health Benefits Program</header>
<subsection id="H559C7832D9094DAF82701CDB6DA56EDA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 8902 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9ECE8C2328646CF9B91037C7AB9E117"> <subsection id="H3B953EF2F0174D4981F691EE948CF9DD"><enum>(q)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H241C33A4F0F64657ABD862D92AA8A4C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <term>fertility treatment</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2799A–11(b) of the Public Health Service Act.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph indent="up1" id="H583AF3CAAC7641F690D3FD06E14D061E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A contract under this chapter shall provide, in a manner consistent with section 2799A–11 of the Public Health Service Act, coverage for fertility treatment, if that contract covers obstetrical benefits.</text></paragraph> <paragraph indent="up1" id="H9223AE9929BB47B6AC73C88E0EFFC011"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Coverage for fertility treatment under a health benefits plan described in section 8903 or 8903a may not be subject to any copayment or deductible greater than the copayment or deductible, respectively, applicable to obstetrical benefits under the plan.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph indent="up1" id="H0EA25BB288F04B52AB2CD360F476D737"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Subsection (m)(1) shall not, with respect to a contract under this chapter, prevent the inclusion of any terms that, under paragraph (2) of this subsection, are required by reason of section 2799A–11 of the Public Health Service Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE9CE94F2AE84810BE2DDFA826484681"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H876A0444B95F4926B17AEF252064FB91"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any contract entered into or renewed for a contract year beginning on or after the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC18E81945EBA4A37A8BA2C7108B21185" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any health benefits plan offered under a contract described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H021360E3CA314D0AB9F0572662648AA3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Benefits for fertility treatment under the TRICARE program</header>
<subsection id="HBA6EB6C3C8874F388158108B57D20D59"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/55">Chapter 55</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H159950017F57463FAE318491C97631A1"> <section id="H3259444D21EE4E649822C382DCAA9DC5"><enum>1110c.</enum><header>Obstetrical and fertility benefits</header> <subsection id="H43959B5943074979A7225FB4FDF1BBB7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any health care plan under this chapter shall provide, in a manner consistent with section 2799A–11 of the Public Health Service Act, coverage for fertility treatment, if such plan covers obstetrical benefits.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HEB4601E475A84B6EB961715A73743362"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Copayment</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall establish cost-sharing requirements for the coverage of fertility treatment that are consistent with the cost-sharing requirements applicable to health plans and health insurance coverage under section 2799A–11(d) of the Public Health Service Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5D41D86E589249D99E5C4D340FE379C5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe any regulations necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H77C0D348409A45EB88D358BA4D34449B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the term <term>fertility treatment</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2799A–11(b) of the Public Health Service Act.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H8E83FAE3EC1F4A92A0587868A919E4B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 55 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H57F3777685064DD89958567B77898233">
<toc>
<toc-entry idref="H3259444D21EE4E649822C382DCAA9DC5" level="section">1110c. Obstetrical and fertility benefits.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section>
<section id="H8780E2DFC68D481DB7B1A5A8FD1EF53E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Fertility treatment for veterans and spouses or partners of veterans</header>
<subsection id="H4436E543311D4F46946F2CCE091E235B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H69E8FFB7D25E4AC2A9FB01A911CCB7FF"> <section id="H2A1E58D7E85A4B2FB6D262A70566F82E"><enum>1720M.</enum><header>Fertility treatment for veterans and spouses or partners of veterans</header> <subsection id="H5D580E9A7184418C971C8BBF7FA27E80"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall furnish fertility treatment services to a veteran or a spouse or partner of a veteran if the veteran, and the spouse or partner of the veteran, as applicable, apply jointly for such fertility treatment through a process prescribed by the Secretary for purposes of this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HDA1190A2EB694B568A21256A58161D56"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the term <term>fertility treatment</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2799A–11(b) of the Public Health Service Act.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H1402EC4545AB40EDBE3EC7B513490C1F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 17 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1720L the following new item:</text>
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H1F307D46FD0845C185624D666CD63DA2">
<toc>
<toc-entry idref="H2A1E58D7E85A4B2FB6D262A70566F82E" level="section">1720M. Fertility treatment for veterans and spouses or partners of veterans.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HBD2039C9DCA0484BB3C212AC9E904AA6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall prescribe regulations to carry out section 1720M of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H8A5AFF19AEA543F4ADC9FCBB9AB4FAAD"><enum>6.</enum><header>Requirement for State Medicaid plans to provide medical assistance for fertility treatment</header> <subsection id="H9A8B01916CAA412499CD0EF701F46572"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1905 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HD2B7B999E297425C832A15E31373FFD0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)(4)(C), by inserting <quote>(which shall include fertility treatment provided in accordance with subsection (kk))</quote> after <quote>family planning services and supplies</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C7EDCEFD9B34B889AB131C810B89008"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E8A9B7D2450466882B61B9DD366B963">
<subsection id="H8776285CD29B43948EB5EDC246BC3549"><enum>(kk)</enum><header>Requirements for coverage of fertility treatment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a)(4)(C), a State shall ensure that the medical assistance provided under the State plan (or waiver of such plan) for fertility treatment complies with the requirements of section 2799A–11(b) of the Public Health Service Act in the same manner as such requirements and limitations apply to health insurance coverage offered by a group health plan or health insurance issuer.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2BF7CCD7DC31429CB48D79F4831C56A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text>Section 1903(a)(5) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(a)(5)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>described in section 1905(a)(4)(C)</quote> after <quote>family planning services and supplies</quote>.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H36A40461788143818A6C472EF43E51AC"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective date</header>
<paragraph id="HF42D6071BE384256B9DE70595BD1C273"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall take effect on October 1, 2026.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BCADA9A619042619DB7BECEDCBE818F" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Delay permitted if State legislation required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a State plan approved under title XIX of the Social Security Act which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation (other than legislation appropriating funds) in order for the plan to meet the additional requirement imposed by this section, the State plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such title solely on the basis of the failure of the plan to meet such additional requirement before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that ends after the 1-year period beginning with the date of the enactment of this section. For purposes of the preceding sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of the session is deemed to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H835E2E517F6E4E589F0A6BA9C9E34A51"><enum>7.</enum><header>Medicare coverage of fertility treatment</header>
<subsection id="H0E24769E956E41ACA839762BD5BB71FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coverage</header><text>Section 1861(s)(2) of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(s)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H775B0F66549F4007B33BD31EF85E1B05"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (JJ), by inserting <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF6BB1D201CB2498BA50078BBA357ADAD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3139EB0F42564604B0620C98D358762F" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H0C2B85B60EF84C7DA64B1B227155D494" indent="up1"><enum>(KK)</enum><text>fertility treatment (as defined in section 2799A–11(b) of the Public Health Service Act);</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H61B4A5ECC763428AB8798D5F1A5D1990"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payment and waiver of coinsurance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1833(a)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD9CDD72B69B44162AE78E17A5EDC56B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> before <quote>(HH)</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H392487B74FD049BF935DD2C7C2ED6CE3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, and (II) with respect to fertility treatment (as described in section 1861(s)(2)(KK)), the amount paid shall be equal to 100 percent of the lesser of the actual charge for the treatment or the amount determined under the payment basis determined under section 1848</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5C9D1277EE224FD2B5B56D377514F340"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver of application of deductible</header><text>The first sentence of section 1833(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HC656DEE6E0634ECC9AFB9A77071E94AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, and (13)</quote> and inserting <quote>(13)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9BD8C5AE79CF4BB2B6CD44D9E7597A63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>1861(n)..</quote> and inserting <quote>1861(n), and (14) such deductible shall not apply with respect to fertility treatment (as described in section 1861(s)(2)(KK)).</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H2D52B0A7593140FDA9BCF8CCEF5A7938"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Payment under physician fee schedule</header><text>Section 1848(j)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(j)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(2)(KK),</quote> after <quote>risk assessment),</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9EE277E328874BC2A155B0069EA8AE14"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conforming amendment regarding coverage</header><text>Section 1862(a)(1)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(a)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC13E7535FE9940A29FAAC3B11667CFAC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>or additional</quote> and inserting <quote>, additional</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C09C5B4686645708393350E2F7716E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>, or fertility treatment (as described in section 1861(s)(2)(KK))</quote> after <quote>1861(ddd)(1))</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE71CCF9814DE46C8B27DAFAA32AFCD13" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to services furnished on or after January 1, 2026.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill>

