<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELT25819-5YM-7F-NVJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2409 IS: Processing Revival and Intrastate Meat Exemption Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2409</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Federal Meat Inspection Act to exempt from inspection the slaughter of animals and the preparation of carcasses conducted at a custom slaughter facility, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H2BAC1B8972034E88AB04C52317E6202C"><section section-type="section-one" id="H10D3337404D541F1A13CC09791BB978E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Processing Revival and Intrastate Meat Exemption Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PRIME Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE06719516CE942209E6DB58EDDCDB424"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exemption for slaughter and preparation occurring at custom slaughter facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 23 of the Federal Meat Inspection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/623">21 U.S.C. 623</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H2AFE09761BB341478DBF3C3717357306"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b), (c), and (d) as subsections (c), (d), and (e), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEAF4F3245FA4D17B4160EC98FF32D61"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H69B0C72FBDEC4597B31FBDE5B503E038"><subsection id="H63CE5BC886C746E383A2608FEA5E6CD8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemption for slaughter and preparation occurring at custom slaughter facilities</header><paragraph id="id7D79AF6E415B4834B9BC7EA71CF810D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition of State</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>State</term> means any State or territory.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id40EEE9CA26DD469A9061A2AC7BEAF8E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>The provisions of this title requiring inspection of the slaughter of animals and the preparation of the carcasses, parts thereof, meat, and meat food products at establishments conducting those operations for commerce shall not apply to the slaughtering by any person of animals at a custom slaughter facility and the preparation at that custom slaughter facility and transportation in commerce of the carcasses, parts thereof, meat, and meat food products of those animals if—</text><subparagraph id="H9ADE11032F594F3AA0BD5924A6C21F0A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the slaughtering and preparation carried out at the custom slaughter facility is carried out in accordance with the law of the State in which the custom slaughter facility is located; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20592B9BF2314DA0BB42FAC56B9298D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the animals are slaughtered and the carcasses, parts thereof, meat, and meat food products of the animals are prepared exclusively for distribution to—</text><clause id="H0B40BB27481A48E6AC262709CE585B0D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>household consumers within the State in which the custom slaughter facility is located; or</text></clause><clause id="H97AD3D3F3A9942F584DA92D345730E6A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>restaurants, hotels, boarding houses, grocery stores, or other establishments located in the State in which the custom slaughter facility is located that—</text><subclause id="HE5A358DFD0FF46F885D326F9B2ACE78C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are involved in the preparation of meals served directly to consumers; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HBD06BE01C1A94FD3AE6E969AA0A5DF87"><enum>(II)</enum><text>offer meat and meat food products for sale directly to consumers in the State.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H122F362D218A4D58B7742B61C865F5EA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c) (as so redesignated), in the second sentence, by striking <quote>paragraph (b)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HAFE6488006224CAD86ED2D0E9390E7CA"><enum>3.</enum><header>No preemption of State law</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in an amendment made by section 2 preempts any State law relating to—</text><paragraph id="idEF1E87536D7144BAA0A0510CFA45BD4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the slaughter of animals or the preparation of carcasses, parts thereof, meat, and meat food products at a custom slaughter facility; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7B9A9E8426FE484DB1763897A9AAF267"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the sale of meat or meat food products.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

