<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA4CA954368B741DDB7B0E1D19EB0F02A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1607 IH: Heirs Empowerment and Inheritance Rights Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1607</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250226">February 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To assist applicants for community development block grant recovery assistance not having traditionally accepted forms of documentation of ownership of property to prove such ownership, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6C654F1B6F13456C8BD19DE973B5F054" style="OLC"><section id="H3401962CDF8340F2AC5849B339E0CE88" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Heirs Empowerment and Inheritance Rights Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HEIR Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HCA03A93320A24C9CB570E12722BD506D"><enum>2.</enum><header>CDBG-Disaster Recovery and CDBG-Mitigation programs</header><subsection id="H08E44A3C695941188B52708329A3094E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Documentation of property ownership</header><paragraph id="H32876B44F6424DDB85726DA06ADD4585"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall amend the regulations at part 570 of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations, to ensure that in providing assistance for the Community Development Block Grant program for Disaster Recovery (CDBG–DR) and the Community Development Block Grant program for Mitigation (CDBG–MIT), in connection with a Presidentially declared disaster, in a case in which a homeowner is required to demonstrate ownership of a property heir property owners and any other owners not having traditionally accepted forms of documentation of ownership of property are provided resources and options for proving ownership for purposes of receiving assistance under such Disaster Recovery and Mitigation programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0528E01242A042D3B879E75F48A4F13C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Acceptable Documentation</header><text>Acceptable documentation for purposes paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H4023C535739146988C3645A5C5AD29AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a signed affidavit of ownership form developed pursuant to subsection (b); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4074CC4312C54009BE7297211D6C3825"><enum>(B)</enum><text>letters from local public or private schools, Federal or State benefit providers, and social service organizations, including community assistance programs and nonprofit organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB364F34C2F654DEA9AE1A31F6E166D3E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>heir property</term> means residential property for which title passed by operation of law through intestacy and is held by two or more heirs as tenants in common.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D3451FDED1D464B8BD3260DC1BEC3F3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Affidavit of ownership</header><paragraph id="HAFE194CC444A4C71A6F32326D940B31F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Development and use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall amend the regulations at part 570 of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations, to provide for the use of a standardized affidavit of ownership form, to be developed by the Secretary, by grantees of the Community Development Block Grant program for Disaster Recovery (CDBG–DR) and the Community Development Block Grant program for Mitigation (CDBG–MIT) in coordination with appropriate authorities of the applicable jurisdiction. Each grantee shall ensure that, at the time of application for housing repair and reconstruction assistance or mitigation assistance under such programs—</text><subparagraph id="H7491C6E10232434CB7CF4D9A293413F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each applicant is informed of the existence of the affidavit of ownership and provided a copy at the time of application; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF202267EB8744DD787CF1E6A07DE11BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">copies of the form in English, Spanish, and any other locally predominant languages of the Presidentially-declared disaster area are accessible to the applicant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H79A9C49B7EDF452B86F92790F0A75285"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>A grantee may not require that the signed affidavit of ownership form of an applicant be notarized.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA01ECFC43239406C845CBA78A91FEDCE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>An affidavit of ownership form shall be exempt from any public comment periods or publication notices under part 570 of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

