<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4E6242BA7566440A83CBA2F957884C78" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 286 IH: Of inquiry requesting the President to transmit certain documents relating to the dangerous, unaccountable use of AI by the United States DOGE Service to jeopardize the private information and essential services of the American people.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 286</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250401">April 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Of inquiry requesting the President to transmit certain documents relating to the dangerous, unaccountable use of AI by the United States DOGE Service to jeopardize the private information and essential services of the American people.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H1A38FC91D113434A897F8C983CB24EA3"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H363CF3EB93AF4F669AED85AA3C270C13"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the President is requested to transmit, to the extent that such documents are in the possession of the President, to the House of Representatives, not later than 14 days after the adoption of this resolution, in a complete and unredacted form, a copy of any document, record, report, memorandum, correspondence, or other communication that refers or relates to the following:</text><paragraph id="HCF8A69F0B84743408D01EF1A7F9EEEB4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any artificial intelligence (AI) technology newly deployed or used at a Federal agency, by or at the direction of Elon Musk or an individual associated with the United States DOGE Service or DOGE, from January 20, 2025, to present, including any associated System of Records Notice, Privacy Impact Assessment, or Authorization to Operate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6A9CB59F8BA49CD88F4DD5DECD9428E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Federal data and sources of Federal data fed into such AI technology, including any reference as to whether such data contains the sensitive, personally identifiable information of American citizens.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61E0EA17D12A42EC9A6717B4F93B5BAE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>All individuals involved in both the policy decisions and technical planning associated with the feeding of sensitive Federal data to AI technology from January 20, 2025, to present, including—</text><subparagraph id="HA63193F4F6D4454A9800BBB57E6ACE85"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">individuals involved in plans to use AI technology to cut payments—</text><clause id="HED73B74A6AC9471FB19DDF6154DCD09A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to Americans; or</text></clause><clause id="HF30DB878C2F54B449AECA9B158379370"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>associated with programs for Americans; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H695282AD5A36429094F6F3DBCC6552DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>individuals involved in plans to collect and feed government contract data through AI software, including any concerns raised or steps taken to mitigate Elon Musk’s related conflicts of interest.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H908BED7CCA0942E695953C6DA60E9636" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any concerns raised by Federal workers that such actions by the Trump Administration violated the Privacy Act and the security of Americans’ private information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65BFF6F5B2F0418F8ACCD04DFA70851F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any concerns raised by Federal workers that such actions by the Trump Administration violated the Advancing American AI Act by failing to publicly disclose current and planned AI use cases to ensure transparency for the American people.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BD031580D134BD79150CB267826CD6A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any lists of Federal expenditures, programs, or personnel identified by AI software for freezes or cuts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35537F669ED94E0FB6D9656302438BBC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any analyses undertaken by any individual to determine which of such AI-identified expenditures, programs, or personnel to freeze or cut.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H400ABAD80F8F43EBA3E331DF9853BEDA"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Any communication or correspondence regarding—</text><subparagraph id="H3427CA0887BE46539810CBE2E0FB4794"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the legality of such freezes or cuts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC05C259B00844C3B92951F031858A212"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the harms to the American people of such freezes or cuts; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF479C10360E43B8A7E2937FC1A06EB4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether employees of DOGE or their associates believe that legality or harm to the American people are important considerations in their actions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H78D1DDAF904845489F81CF24D3BD7E69"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All individuals who managed or accessed Federal data in the process of feeding it through AI technology, including whether such individuals were Federal workers at the time of their data management or access and, if so—</text><subparagraph id="H2A859D29FA224A7AA9DC54E27265BABC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>under what authority they were hired; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C6B9D28053E48DEBAFC0ED6BF825699"><enum>(B)</enum><text>what background investigation and clearance processes they underwent as part of the hiring process.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6794D23CDFCC4EBCA13951AB82FE59E5"><enum>(10)</enum><text>All records, logs, code, certificates, and configurations for all Federal IT assets, databases, or repositories accessed by employees of DOGE in training or deploying new AI software.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

