<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4FE39BAE040F4AE399843861DC05BD4E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1985 IH: Promoting Precision Agriculture Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1985</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250310">March 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enhance the participation of precision agriculture in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8F9468F8304840F082C74D4D980FDACF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD4104399F44D4AC494332342788DC3EA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Precision Agriculture Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H688D5570C25241F992C73AA1D3066EEF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7E0DB2195E95498B82B978EDC9222DF5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advanced wireless communications technology</header><text>The term <term>advanced wireless communications technology</term> means advanced technology that contributes to mobile (5G or beyond) networks, next-generation Wi-Fi networks, or other future networks using other technologies, regardless of whether the network is operating on an exclusive licensed, shared licensed, or unlicensed frequency band.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA3E981EA40B44A27A1040B5F31D4E569"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given the term in section 238(g) of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/232">Public Law 115–232</external-xref>; 10 U.S.C. note prec. 4061). </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC59D797DF5AD4C81BFFC07B8F48B73F3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign adversary</header><text>The term <term>foreign adversary</term> means any foreign government or foreign nongovernment person engaged in a long-term pattern or serious instances of conduct significantly adverse to the national security of the United States, or security and safety of United States persons.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D5BFF7F800249639A788A73C8290FC2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Precision agriculture</header><text>The term <term>precision agriculture</term> means managing, tracking, or reducing crop or livestock production inputs, including seed, feed, fertilizer, chemicals, water, time, and such other inputs as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, at a heightened level of spatial and temporal granularity to improve efficiencies, reduce waste, and maintain environmental quality.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5CCAA05369F44D1FA42B350A8E90E8B9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Precision agriculture equipment</header><text>The term <term>precision agriculture equipment</term> means any equipment or technology that directly contributes to a reduction in, or improved efficiency of, inputs used in crop or livestock production, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HCBD12A5277A545E0A5F8C54CEFA50DBE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>global positioning system-based or geospatial mapping;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBDF685EEBE9D49C19F984F5871336280"><enum>(B)</enum><text>satellite or aerial imagery;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H68B5B513410743C18959C3EB7A1FD6A5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>yield monitors;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5AA1831D6B2E4DACA40214374A7BFA38"><enum>(D)</enum><text>soil mapping;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H06F9F41D5ECB4AC5A9B8ED07A46E1215"><enum>(E)</enum><text>sensors for gathering data on crop, soil, and livestock conditions;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3A9EC49330B54783B2D6720513382D48"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Internet of Things and technology that relies on edge and cloud computing;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7165EC583EC64167B4136DDAA9FC62FB"><enum>(G)</enum><text>data management software and advanced analytics;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC4CEBD06DD7F4FD1A8A09DC63399636D"><enum>(H)</enum><text>network connectivity products and solutions, including public and private wireless networks;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3102BA79AF2C4D8EA8FFDCAC36D8607A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>global positioning system guidance, auto-steer systems, autonomous fleeting, and other machine-to-machine operations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3ABFE0B90EBC47208D2D47A799297403"><enum>(J)</enum><text>variable rate technology for applying inputs, such as section control; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCC98353F6C864AD0A931E328ADC2B40F"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other technology, as determined by the Secretary, that directly contributes to a reduction in, or improved efficiency of, the use of crop or livestock production inputs, which may include—</text> 
<clause id="HD4C3A8E865504D5A85217E04CAB57941"><enum>(i)</enum><text>seed;</text></clause> <clause id="HD9A1FD3935004FD3BCC4482BD7D3CAA9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>feed;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBDF09B1B86244BFD9ECED2E7066A8F9C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>fertilizer;</text></clause> <clause id="HC53B9887D7574BEB841B4B15B09A5591"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>soil amendments;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H940964C4477943DCA807140F33951786"><enum>(v)</enum><text>chemicals;</text></clause> <clause id="H327D892AA80A43EBB0E81DA585F514F4"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>water;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H30BC66053DDF482799870B9CE6860937"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>time;</text></clause> <clause id="HB80547A1880D498DBE9828A54EFD897B"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>fuel; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H42952B7716BE4A9DAFCE6E197810D625"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other inputs as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF059E1B7E4E04466B055A3FE898041A8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D1E118B332C4FF790086611B3DFC888"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Trusted</header><text>The term <term>trusted</term> means, with respect to a provider of advanced communications service or a supplier of communications equipment or service, that the Secretary has determined that the provider or supplier is not owned by, controlled by, or subject to the influence of, a foreign adversary.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A0C00EC80574CD4928AB4247FD82AAE" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Voluntary consensus standards development organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>voluntary consensus standards development organization</term> means an organization that develops standards in a process that meets the principles for the development of voluntary consensus standards (as defined in the document of the Office of Management and Budget entitled <quote>Federal Participation in the Development and Use of Voluntary Consensus Standards and in Conformity Assessment Activities</quote> (OMB Circular A–119)).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HBA4D301935D140E899EA62B1574A10D7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text> <paragraph id="HC9FA27DCAA784067B5D916A6369E764D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to enhance the participation of precision agriculture in the United States; and </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H63001C9398794B4C8E9FC0DD2B83844F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to promote United States leadership in voluntary consensus standards development organizations that set standards for precision agriculture.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HEACCC562825C40409E2C0328304983E3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Interconnectivity standards for precision agriculture</header> <subsection id="H6AF8DA8191BE44029FCCD5F22AE69728"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology and the Federal Communications Commission, shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6C36F200AC8249ECB3490DB9D766FA55"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop voluntary, consensus-based, private sector-led interconnectivity standards, guidelines, and best practices for precision agriculture that will promote economies of scale and ease the burden of the adoption of precision agriculture; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B6548C3FA7840AFB3081F30B0190829"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in carrying out paragraph (1)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE738B1C19C764ED29C1F5DF67555E077"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coordinate with relevant public and trusted private sector stakeholders and other relevant industry organizations, including voluntary consensus standards development organizations; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF199CBCE11304C5499866971982870BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consult with sector-specific agencies, other appropriate agencies, and State and local governments.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFCD298A24C2E4DE5A3227EBE41779EF0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The Secretary, in carrying out subsection (a), shall, in consultation with the Federal Communications Commission and the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, consider—</text> <paragraph id="H9D17026671FE4128A8E4A9106F0267DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the evolving demands of precision agriculture;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6387BE2EEE804702AB4EA941D5756182"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the connectivity needs of precision agriculture equipment;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E88BE38C8EB4B93975FAFBD1FF591BE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the cybersecurity challenges facing precision agriculture, including cybersecurity threats for agriculture producers and agriculture supply chains;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3632E6C19EDC4EC3B9F9E24F926D8D8D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the impact of advanced wireless communications technology on precision agriculture; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF58DF8C2BFE4AE294E60DBF090F2495"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the impact of artificial intelligence on precision agriculture.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB7E17B99F46B43EAA0D5904F6D236E34"><enum>5.</enum><header>GAO assessment of precision agriculture standards</header> 
<subsection id="HC1EC624FE0EB4B1B8435164944722B4C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the Secretary develops standards under section 4, and every 2 years thereafter for the following 8 years, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study that assesses those standards, including the extent to which those standards, as applicable—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D336A24CBF044CB92D9CCB895ABE28E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are voluntary;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73C22B61DD0D4E429F64299C84A2DF53"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">were developed in coordination with relevant industry organizations, including voluntary consensus standards development organizations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBFC93229945D4685B27D47D1940E4691"><enum>(3)</enum><text>have successfully encouraged the adoption of precision agriculture.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H15395A9688B74557B3A8DCE3324F14F6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report that summarizes the findings of each study conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

