<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3DC2BA018005418EB0499068EB3A688B" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 159 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the week of February 24 through February 28, 2025, as “Public Schools Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 159</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250224">February 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. S&#225;nchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. Garc&#237;a of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000489">Mr. Turner of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001237">Ms. McDonald Rivet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001231">Mr. Mannion</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the week of February 24 through February 28, 2025, as <quote>Public Schools Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas public education is the foundation of a 21st-century democracy;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Nation’s public schools are where students come to be educated as citizens of the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas each public school prepares the Nation’s young people to contribute to the society, economy, and citizenry of the country;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, according to 2021 data from the National Center for Education Statistics, an estimated 90 percent of children in the United States attend public schools;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas local, State, and Federal lawmakers should prioritize support for strengthening the Nation’s public schools and empower local education leaders to implement, manage, and lead school districts in partnership with educators, parents, and other local education stakeholders and learning communities;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas local, State, and Federal lawmakers should support such necessities as counseling, extracurricular activities, and mental health supports that are critical to help students engage in learning;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas inclusive and safe high-quality public schools are where children learn to think critically, problem solve, and build relationships;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas public schools should provide an environment where all students can succeed beginning in their earliest years, regardless of who they are or where they live;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas efforts should be supported to advance equity and excellence in public education and to implement continuous improvement and evidence-based practices;</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas every child has the right to an education that helps them reach their full potential and to attend schools that offer a high-quality educational experience;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas stable, equitable, predictable, and adequate funding for great public schools for every student in the United States is necessary to ensure that students have inviting classrooms and school libraries with up-to-date resources as well as well-prepared and supported educators;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas educators include teachers, paraprofessionals, and principals who provide a well-rounded and complete curriculum and create joy in learning;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Nation’s school buildings should have class sizes small enough to allow students to receive one-on-one attention and to access support services such as health care, nutrition, and after-school programs when needed;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas students, teachers, and professionals make the Nation’s public schools vital components of the community;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas parents and communities are working hard to improve educational outcomes for children across the country; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the week of February 24 through February 28, 2025, would be an appropriate period to designate as <quote>Public Schools Week</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HE1CE3F58CA244FC2AC5A65F5102BDF43"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H694EA91D5CB34417A48F557E229C7DEE"><text>That the House of Representatives supports the designation of <quote>Public Schools Week</quote>.</text></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

