<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0A01C207ACAC488897E2600190C34661" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5250 IH: To provide for the foreign assistance authority of the Department of State, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5250</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the foreign assistance authority of the Department of State, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2647B829D4DE4525B095302ABCE6188A" style="OLC"><title id="H3668444B7FB043C5AD825861FF6169C9"><enum>VI</enum><header>FOREIGN ASSISTANCE</header><section id="H5F35ECF015284F389E151958CE6D68BC" section-type="section-one"><enum>601.</enum><header>Under Secretary for Foreign Assistance</header><subsection id="HF1EA2B5228014AF59354908087908056"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There shall be in the Department an Under Secretary for Foreign Assistance who shall be responsible to the Secretary of State for matters pertaining to the creation and maintenance of allies and partners to United States interests abroad, and such other related duties as the Secretary may from time to time designate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2F3414A4667B4682A273F52BB39EDD81"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>In addition to the responsibilities described under subsection (a), the Under Secretary for Foreign Assistance shall maintain continuous observation and coordination of all matters pertaining to assistance to foreign allies and partners in the conduct of foreign policy, including, as appropriate—</text><paragraph id="HB5FDEAEEA3AF43B78D55A96ECAF4AD5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>providing the strategic policy direction for, and policy and programmatic oversight of, funds and bureaus within the Under Secretary’s assigned jurisdiction; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC4DEACC1A2841C8AF308C057F5B3288"><enum>(2)</enum><text>overseeing and reviewing all matters pertaining to human rights and humanitarian affairs, including matters relating to prisoners of war and members of the United States Armed Forces Missing in Action.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6D222352D4764DD98FD38F61C8C78FAA"><enum>602.</enum><header>Director of Foreign Assistance Oversight</header><subsection id="HF1FFDEBB9CAC48E68E041553338EB0B2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is authorized to be established in the Department a Director of United States Foreign Assistance Oversight, who shall be responsible to the Under Secretary for Foreign Assistance for matters pertaining to coordination and strategic oversight of all foreign assistance activities across the Department of State, and such other related duties as the Secretary may from time to time designate.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBC6A9BD672F34985BEF0DF74A508A06F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>In addition to the responsibilities described in subsection (a), the Director of United States Foreign Assistance Oversight shall coordinate and oversee the strategic direction, planning, and budgeting of foreign assistance programs in the conduct of foreign policy, including, as appropriate—</text><paragraph id="H9C44A4B0438247BBAD1BA9493A88EB60"><enum>(1)</enum><text>developing and implementing comprehensive foreign assistance strategies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96C9B0442C0D4F41846A1963570AE634"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinating interagency assistance planning;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E188D3892884CE0B00A41E66763C639"><enum>(3)</enum><text>providing senior-level leadership for the planning, operational management, and oversight of foreign aid programming across the United States Government;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H651F822D4510472C8FBB8117B17A9965"><enum>(4)</enum><text>improving strategic coordination of, and oversight over, all foreign assistance funding, focusing on efficacy and strategy; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7FC314883DC4D1B9558CA048A924EFD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>integrating foreign assistance strategies with the broader objectives of United States foreign policy, including security, diplomacy, and development coherence;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11193BA26E9D44C98B052D06E831646D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>supporting interagency collaboration on foreign assistance programs and policies of other agencies and entities, including the Millennium Challenge Corporation, the United States International Development Finance Corporation, United States Department of the Treasury, Trade and Development Agency, and Export-Import Bank;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AD5D6F75922433F9B1149CB7541DB42"><enum>(7)</enum><text>generating data-driven performance assessments and policy diagnostics for dissemination to Congress and the Executive Office of the President; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA660D3BB0C3046D5BD70C4B468C33AF5"><enum>(8)</enum><text>leading coordination and oversight of vetting of foreign recipients of assistance, to ensure compliance, accountability, and alignment with United States foreign assistance policies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1781092D996A408FA941DC5105381AAE"><enum>(9)</enum><text>such other related duties as the Under Secretary for Foreign Assistance may from time to time designate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2942410700024F67A64742DCEEF10FE2"><enum>603.</enum><header>Office of Foreign Assistance Oversight</header><subsection id="H8F5DD6B29178471DAD1B9B84DA9BF865"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of State shall establish an Office of Foreign Assistance Oversight, which shall perform such functions related to department-wide management of foreign assistance as the Under Secretary for Foreign Assistance may prescribe.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7E05E9BE34D54CDE86821D8F199C38D7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Head of office</header><text>The Director of Foreign Assistance Oversight shall be the head of the Office of Foreign Assistance Oversight.</text></subsection><subsection id="H090EE8B0B3D044CAA37AAA89475EDE94"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The Office of Foreign Assistance Oversight shall, as appropriate—</text><paragraph id="H923C1D8277024311B55FB276C3DD1A8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support the Director of Foreign Assistance Oversight in the development and implementation of comprehensive foreign assistance strategies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6449BE3F60E34391B4F909E0C02896EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinate interagency assistance planning and align bilateral cooperation frameworks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA20B6D7605046FABE159B7E4B28F236"><enum>(3)</enum><text>coordinate and allocate United States foreign assistance funding across thematic and regional areas;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E51C064F48E4CB5A52F2C78989F11F5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>continually improve strategic coordination of and oversight over all foreign assistance funding, focusing on efficacy and strategy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA93608B6178C4B2586C3E4A8C6965FC0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>generate data-driven performance assessments and policy diagnostics for dissemination to Congress and the Executive Office of the President;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F12B98908BC4EF8A8618F964913B1A5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>ensure monitoring, evaluation, and transparency of foreign assistance programs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H641B81AEC7D24C42892FBAE5B67EFFB8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>perform such other duties as the Director may from time to time designate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0B1807AF8DC44EE2AABD21321E3BE22F"><enum>604.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations for foreign assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Of the funds authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of State under section 141, the Under Secretary for Foreign Assistance shall receive the funds necessary to fulfill the Under Secretary’s responsibilities for fiscal years 2026 and 2027.</text></section><section id="HDDF80891B3C54122AB243B4045085C87"><enum>605.</enum><header>Classification in United States Code</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Office of Law Revision Counsel shall—</text><paragraph id="H151F0B8835F742CFB0E8C56F74DCBE3E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>utilize sections 160–190 of title 22, United States Code, to classify the sections of this title; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03D73EB2A226411398B81DFFEF3ADB15"><enum>(2)</enum><text>maintain the legislative history, under editorial notes, of repealed law which previously occupied the corresponding sections of United States Code.</text></paragraph></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

