<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-GAI25968-DCD-NX-J7H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2712 IS: America's Clean Future Fund Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2712</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250904">September 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> introduced the following bill;
                which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish a carbon fee to
 reduce greenhouse gas emissions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>America's Clean Future Fund Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id78be6f58e55044ffbafee520e9443c2e"><enum>2.</enum><header>Climate Change Finance Corporation</header><subsection id="id279e8fba24914f9d81300186faf9e56b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph id="id0fbf116506024af7a0a9f0a7ecf47d18"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the executive branch an independent agency, to be known as the <quote>Climate Change Finance Corporation</quote> (referred to in this section as the <quote>C2FC</quote>), which shall finance clean energy and climate change resiliency activities in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id355c0fde7ff749cf89ae571d40288302"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mission</header><text>The mission of the C2FC is to combat climate change by reducing the dependency of the United States on fossil fuels, reducing greenhouse gas emissions, and building resilience to the harmful impacts of climate change.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfac006bf168b47978b880411ac6fd273"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Activities</header><subparagraph id="id51d1a06adb9e407fa3743233da8fe34d"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The C2FC shall reduce the reliance of the United States on fossil fuels and mitigate the impacts of climate change by financing—</text><clause id="id3a54112e7b5e4392be34b5fb4037bef6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the deployment of low- and zero-emissions energy technologies and fuels;</text></clause><clause id="id3fb5ef2e71a94196bb13c12032017ab2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the construction of climate-resilient infrastructure;</text></clause><clause id="ide51b0ed86a90426f95a3586b11790d46"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>research, development, and commercialization of new climate-smart technologies and tools to facilitate industrial decarbonization;</text></clause><clause id="idd28dbbb172c64ad6b589161273cee8a6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>clean energy and climate projects identified as too high-risk for private capital investment; and</text></clause><clause id="idbe85573cfdcf4b4dbca0e34d4d220d23"><enum>(v)</enum><text>projects that encourage the infusion of private capital and the creation of new workforce opportunities in clean transportation, energy, and climate resiliency.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddf6e5cf927e84f678702fdd86b9df627"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In carrying out activities under subparagraph (A), the C2FC shall give priority to projects that benefit—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbf29f042483d4cb79d62a1e7cdbfece3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">communities disproportionately facing the harmful impacts of climate change;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc8b2bc1fe2bc4218b2d2d59d27ef5fae"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">communities that have been historically overburdened by industrial pollution from carbon-intensive industries; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1d69ee5596e3495da6bf2cadc13f069d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">communities that have historically relied on carbon-intensive industries for economic support.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id76de683a1ffb432e85fe2008e43330ea"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Emissions reduction goals</header><text>In carrying out activities under subparagraph (A), the goals of the C2FC shall be to achieve—</text><clause id="idd1d4e6c3c29e45009ea5207060cc09fc"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by 2030, a net reduction of greenhouse gas emissions by 45 percent, based on 2018 levels; and</text></clause><clause id="id87f36d6c46034c30a632494dd2396ab1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by 2050, a net reduction of greenhouse gas emissions by 100 percent, based on 2018 levels.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9158f6ecf3674a6896c5a36c073761f5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exercise of powers</header><text>Except as otherwise provided expressly by law, all Federal laws dealing with public or Federal contracts, property, works, officers, employees, budgets, or funds, including the provisions of chapters 5 and 7 of title 5, United States Code, shall apply to the exercise of the powers of the C2FC.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id93aa1df0ef93412c94a8192a4224235a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Board of directors</header><paragraph id="idd69ade5c54c44ea1b78743aed5b477c7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The management of the C2FC shall be vested in a Board of Directors (referred to in this section as the <quote>Board</quote>) consisting of 7 members, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf2dace1bb1a9437d8497e18d1e28335f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chairperson and vice chairperson</header><subparagraph id="id8ffa41cfdf604599865dcd859b7da47f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A Chairperson and Vice Chairperson of the Board shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, from among the individuals appointed to the Board under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcddd0c4f66714e80ab10b5ae9a437888"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Term</header><text>An individual—</text><clause id="id47d9bae7de454d16bf73b62493d78d49"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall serve as Chairperson or Vice Chairperson of the Board for a 3-year term; and</text></clause><clause id="id24abfb93705c4e9e8a3d8529094b7581"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may be renominated for the position until the term of that individual on the Board under paragraph (3)(C) expires.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idca14c5726f2c45ca9d4728dd48e6a187"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Board members</header><subparagraph id="idc3c2a5943e79426b9837f90b19e5567e"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Citizenship required</header><text>Each member of the Board shall be an individual who is a citizen of the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id63187768c1924e91998a848de2e4dac7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Representation</header><text>The members of the Board shall represent agricultural, educational, research, industrial, nongovernmental, labor, environmental justice, and commercial interests throughout the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id89c8ab31f8b345e79100caaf8dc0495a"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Term</header><clause id="idb3ccc45ced2e4faa9595fe6b965d75e4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, each member of the Board—</text><subclause id="idfaae8005022c4a7e8a2341245131a1b8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall be appointed for a term of 6 years; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id32d4cdaee7f34d1ab2c3b81cea23d5fc"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may be reappointed for 1 additional term.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idaefcb7b6683d446cbe6be0388f62d931"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Initial staggered terms</header><text>Of the members first appointed to the Board—</text><subclause id="id22e79716e0fb4a67abeab04227d54f78"><enum>(I)</enum><text>2 shall each be appointed for a term of 2 years;</text></subclause><subclause id="id19096969c2a6435d9ea1d42066059e55"><enum>(II)</enum><text>3 shall each be appointed for a term of 4 years; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id86b06265ee29402b8e4cb00670489550"><enum>(III)</enum><text>2 shall each be appointed for a term of 6 years.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id52ad83f1549c456d807082e1b553b765"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which all members of the Board are appointed under paragraph (1), the Board shall hold an initial meeting.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7eaadb1fd2904f75938b5af6fb06a8a1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Working groups</header><paragraph id="id6c182a3afedb4a359b160305456bc266"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board shall create, oversee, and incorporate feedback from the following working groups (each referred to in this section as a <quote>working group</quote>):</text><subparagraph id="id9b06428c4d1b4b4284aab0245c57102f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An environmental justice working group.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb816008188d74bbbb3f4a4eae744258f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A worker and community transition assistance working group.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id40befd9ad2e845e9a71247320cca9754"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A research and innovation working group.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9ee3caa8d6714f7c91f196c91b6c1f42"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Working group members</header><subparagraph id="idea879908a0d2417d8349d2147376fd09"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each working group shall—</text><clause id="id43179aeb64934677a2c9a32f581f3677"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be chaired by a Board member; and</text></clause><clause id="id76b9157742c846da9f460be3674b7fd6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>comprise not less than 10 and not more than 20 individuals, who shall be experts, members of directly impacted communities relating to the subject matter of the working group, and other relevant stakeholders.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id99e9feee73094a59875920e51323afc7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Diversity</header><text>Individuals on a working group shall, to the maximum extent practicable, represent—</text><clause id="id31333645100d42bf94d2b268ff3f9ded"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a diverse array of interests related to the subject matter of the working group; and</text></clause><clause id="id17140ac91c26430188e222b4f394deb1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>diverse geographical, racial, religious, gender, educational, age, disability, and socioeconomic backgrounds.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1e34b9b523474377a9de0e135f4bddaa"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>Each working group shall meet not less than 2 times per year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id01814a8783c94dedbfeffeb73f949f9f"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Community and stakeholder engagement</header><subparagraph id="ida3cf06e5ba204b01b93f0129b94e68f9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each working group shall create and engage in meaningful community and stakeholder involvement opportunities, including through regular public community engagement activities, for purposes of—</text><clause id="id98b2fe3c7044442dbd2d43209e0fb5c3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>maintaining up-to-date situational awareness about the needs of relevant communities and stakeholders;</text></clause><clause id="id5ea01b7caff44fa4b60953f8ca122b05"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>using the feedback obtained through those opportunities to inform the advice of the working group to the Board; and</text></clause><clause id="id94c3a64354994546bb68233dd2eede9b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>providing a mechanism for direct and substantial community feedback relating to the investment plan and the funding decisions of the C2FC.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2935c8795e644b4e9094ed82dffb367c"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public awareness</header><text>Each working group shall inform the public about C2FC investment by engaging in public awareness campaigns, which shall target relevant communities through comprehensive and accessible outreach methods suited for the relevant community.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbdd22952ee4743e9a4f68619d7ddcee7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Broad participation</header><text>In carrying out subparagraph (A), each working group shall, to the maximum extent practicable, maximize participation from a broad group of stakeholders, including by holding multiple meetings with significant advance notice, providing access to remote participation in those meetings, and holding meetings in multiple languages and at different times and locations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2caf3d2b3a3c403d8de5fe02d96b0eb6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Tasks</header><text>Each working group shall, as it relates to the subject matter of the working group—</text><subparagraph id="id1b45a3d7ce13432184e8aa649bb7e033"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advise and provide general input to the Board regarding loans and grants provided by the C2FC; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2852cb50121048828a72ac5295700f17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consult with, and based on the activities described in paragraph (4), provide recommendations to, the Board in the development of and updates to the investment plan of the C2FC.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6f615a15f521432bb5448039ae50804b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Investment plan</header><paragraph id="id6f3a2b0f73f44f28ba72b8f5449ed34b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board, in consultation with each working group described in subsection (c)(1), shall develop an investment plan (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>investment plan</quote>) for the C2FC in accordance with this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7bd84bce1c2b4fe0a0f656437018fc24"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the investment plan are—</text><subparagraph id="idc61810793f9f4c46b3e3b0cb285ace8e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to ensure that investments made by the C2FC—</text><clause id="id18c1ba0f67f042a38ae8c10084d18c3a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are equitable and reach the prioritized communities described in subsection (e)(2);</text></clause><clause id="ide24d7ac8cdea42449222dd8ddc4a10c3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are effective at progressing towards the goals described in subsection (a)(3)(C);</text></clause><clause id="ide8bf309851ec44df9ae85fb5ad460060"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>support the advancement of research in clean technologies and resilience; and</text></clause><clause id="id5103da1c369a47cbb3727e3c7fee57ae"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>are transparent to the prioritized communities described in subsection (e)(2); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id06c5a9c02dc04b0b906ab26d49181b38"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to provide methods and standards by which the Board and the working groups described in subsection (c)(1) shall choose projects in which to invest.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id130e5d4162db4ccfb493025f295e6ad6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Distribution of grant funds</header><text>The initial investment plan shall require that, of the total amount of grant funds provided under subsection (e)(3)(A) each year, not less than 40 percent shall be used to invest in and benefit communities described in subsection (e)(2)(A).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id288db460de3749b1a266fbb1406c0e97"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Investment plan updates</header><subparagraph id="id5fb48f0000d54cbebf1e18df113f1a01"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board, in consultation with each working group described in subsection (c)(1), shall update the investment plan not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 4 years thereafter, including by taking into account—</text><clause id="idb088c60665dd4c599be1f0c1501382dc"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the current needs of the prioritized communities described in subsection (e)(2);</text></clause><clause id="id7cbf8543e4c642c18c99c00d59847021"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the effectiveness of the previous investment plan in addressing the needs of those communities;</text></clause><clause id="idca16a2a680a4445aaa8b56ff5b1ced37"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the current state of relevant research and technology;</text></clause><clause id="id55286386d6c04128a5101117bf11a4da"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the resiliency needs of local communities;</text></clause><clause id="idc05b442d18e842f59c5a825eac5157af"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the goals described in subsection (a)(3)(C); and</text></clause><clause id="id4a9f66e18dcf4425bcd128449902ef88"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the 2 most recent program reviews conducted under subsection (f).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id02a808039f39441f980ea1fbf0f941a8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effectiveness</header><text>An investment plan shall remain in effect until the date on which the Board approves an updated investment plan.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc1b3a7f209b84bdcb892af626349dbc1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public input</header><text>In updating the investment plan, the Board and the working groups described in subsection (c)(1) shall—</text><clause id="ide58b4b5da8b042f29cc96b3d6626ac98"><enum>(i)</enum><text>engage stakeholders and the public in a public comment and feedback process; and</text></clause><clause id="id787d26ebd7494f8cb817a6b66bb03f31"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensure that the prioritized communities described in subsection (e)(2) have access to participate in that process.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id310e6587dfda4cfe9d2e4dae0f87c6ac"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Public updates</header><text>The Board shall make publicly available on a quarterly basis information relating to the expenditure of funds under the investment plan.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5813acdb2f8040e8a858e5a608f523e9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Investment tools</header><paragraph id="idbdcd566128714bd7951f0e7a529400d4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="id1686f6dfe38846ca87ac91654181dac9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Community of color</header><text>The term <term>community of color</term> means a geographically distinct area in which the population of any of the following categories of individuals is higher than the average population of that category for the State in which the community is located:</text><clause id="id0086f5fe17fb4499982fdd0d6fb9ed2c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Black.</text></clause><clause id="idbb262824908044b5bd5426171048b439"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>African American.</text></clause><clause id="id7fa8b4ab0fdb43e791f9893b86d9a735"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Asian.</text></clause><clause id="ided07a60cb7d54bbeb6aaf36315dd123a"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Pacific Islander.</text></clause><clause id="id98365ff3fe15464797c7736dd6687447"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Other non-White race.</text></clause><clause id="id4e014d7446054373a0584d98987d1857"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Hispanic.</text></clause><clause id="id389802d50a184e969375af2f3fff0615"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Latino.</text></clause><clause id="id8c691f71a41e4608bd5d7495804359ce"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Linguistically isolated.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5e410b8885644c479c7aee3033039713"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible borrower</header><text>The term <term>eligible borrower</term> means any person, including a business owner or project developer, that seeks a loan to carry out approved practices or projects described in subparagraph (A)(i) of paragraph (3) from an eligible lender that may receive a loan guarantee under that paragraph for that loan, according to criteria determined by the C2FC.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd2ed2f05ae264bd1b30e97d2e6a5c0cd"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><clause id="id7580471015ee43a483a29dc68df64393"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a State;</text></clause><clause id="idc7240176a1e949209c27a3efc3b9aab0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe;</text></clause><clause id="id3d3350ec246447d8bd5636e93a72d6cc"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a unit of local government; and</text></clause><clause id="id4559375329924d71aebe7adb641dfbf8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a research and development institution (including a National Laboratory).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb6837724a6804ae9ab927b8a8f0ce72b"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Eligible lender</header><text>The term <term>eligible lender</term> means—</text><clause id="idbf08d155176f4a1dad8666d26c5ecd72"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a Federal- or State-chartered bank;</text></clause><clause id="idff924d1e06bd4113a4c4b9151f5e84f0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a Federal- or State-chartered credit union;</text></clause><clause id="ida112fb598bd64bb18c30a5cd4280cbb9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an agricultural credit corporation;</text></clause><clause id="ide2a867fc00b24c54be0333501d192225"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a United States Green Bank Institution;</text></clause><clause id="id5f9f305e8c604bbcabbe242f8822ba73"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a community development financial institution (as defined in section 103 of the Community Development Banking and Financial Institutions Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4702">12 U.S.C. 4702</external-xref>));</text></clause><clause id="id320a7423e7064434bc8ec8f8669a182c"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a minority depository institution (as defined in section 308(b) of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1463">12 U.S.C. 1463</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/101/73">Public Law 101–73</external-xref>)); and</text></clause><clause id="id468b3d6cdb6d482c811968f32015d5fe"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>any other lender that the Board determines has a demonstrated ability to underwrite and service loans for the intended approved practice for which the loan will be used.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6d0580e17da049e49fc81f80822f2eb6"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Environmental justice community</header><text>The term <term>environmental justice community</term> means a community with significant representation of communities of color, low-income communities, or Tribal and indigenous communities that experiences, or is at risk of experiencing, higher or more adverse human health or environmental effects.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd93ecf1f89ae441d9f75061eaf4ee8d4"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0a991fe8bc9d45a2bf9f2c48412cb5cc"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Low-income community</header><text>The term <term>low-income community</term> means any census block group in which 30 percent or more of the population are individuals with an annual household income equal to, or less than, the greater of—</text><clause id="id37726c1f98d240bbbf7caacb45c54dac"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an amount equal to 80 percent of the median income of the area in which the household is located, as reported by the Department of Housing and Urban Development; and</text></clause><clause id="idc167cc8cc4934d7da75a0c1b7dbc02bc"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>200 percent of the Federal poverty line.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbcf9247068d54e628ee3a714d0e3b3c2"><enum>(H)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means—</text><clause id="id0c5c22324974435b8d527134f7fb1bc3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a State;</text></clause><clause id="id5832ac1596b14319a99f6adb404ed370"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the District of Columbia;</text></clause><clause id="idb5f0a5f65b6b409e89478b2b632ec2bf"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico; and</text></clause><clause id="id418d1581a48442298494bc956aa6ac4b"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any other territory or possession of the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf18e47aa3e26449a9e1ab5896b0c6946"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community prioritization</header><text>In providing financial investment and other assistance under paragraph (3), the C2FC shall give priority to, as determined by the C2FC—</text><subparagraph id="idc63b75a7dd0247eebaa920ff3b948c1d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>environmental justice communities, communities of color, indigenous communities, rural communities, and low-income communities that—</text><clause id="ide0c48228f365424a98a37b7fed39ea8b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>experience a disproportionate burden of the negative human health and environmental impacts of pollution or other environmental hazards, such as natural disasters; or</text></clause><clause id="id794416c0e17d4a4f84557a9d635b1fc3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may not have access to public information and opportunities for meaningful public participation relating to human health and environmental planning, regulations, and enforcement;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6fe462ef57fd4703b1f40ec3b3405c94"><enum>(B)</enum><text>deindustrialized communities or communities with significant local economic reliance on carbon-intensive industries;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide3f1738fe59a4e6083dc8a1a1fb155f0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>low-income communities at risk of impacts of natural disasters or sea level rise exacerbated by climate change;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id902ce2b5752c4ab2837e2912f25b7374"><enum>(D)</enum><text>public or nonprofit entities that serve dislocated workers, veterans, or individuals with a barrier to employment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd09c9543d9bd4f7ba7ded5355a88e395"><enum>(E)</enum><text>communities that have minimal or no investment in the approved practices and projects described in paragraph (3)(A)(i).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id00a04c90c3854feb8ebf4e36ecf563e9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grants, loan guarantees, and other investment tools</header><subparagraph id="idd7b4099fb0ed4b1b8da3f62d0e507eac"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The C2FC—</text><clause id="idf9158ffb28454144af0951aa543f73f3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall provide grants to eligible entities and loan guarantees to eligible lenders issuing loans to eligible borrowers for approved practices and projects relating to climate change mitigation and resilience measures, including—</text><subclause id="idceefc902d0164c719a5b12bde97459f6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>energy efficiency upgrades to infrastructure;</text></subclause><subclause id="id5a5795f6e6b44665bbd50f399490cc91"><enum>(II)</enum><text>electric, hydrogen, and clean transportation programs and deployment, including programs—</text><item id="id4998cc852209498285d8e0cdc792e898"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>to purchase personal vehicles, commercial vehicles, and public transportation fleets and school bus fleets;</text></item><item id="idf5ee90e1a4c849af92b933314674bd01"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to deploy electric vehicle charging and hydrogen fueling infrastructure; and</text></item><item id="id9a999bfe61b44fba995054aca448a980"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>to develop and deploy sustainable aviation fuels;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id604b9af00ef1446c845bcd8ed77ce25c"><enum>(III)</enum><text>clean energy and clean vehicle manufacturing research, demonstrations, and deployment, with a particular focus on projects relating to the commercialization of new technologies;</text></subclause><subclause id="ida67ebdb55c724f7c8dea6ba47d795c36"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>battery storage research, demonstrations, and deployment;</text></subclause><subclause id="idf0a92a38023b4e54ad90fd3467ddd568"><enum>(V)</enum><text>development or purchase of equipment for practices described in section 6;</text></subclause><subclause id="id94c4d49aece9420bba6237563b6c7e20"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>development and deployment of clean energy and clean technologies, with a focus on—</text><item id="id67ff0329e67c4f44be6baf9fbec10802"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>carbon capture, utilization, and sequestration, bioenergy with carbon capture and sequestration, and direct air capture;</text></item><item id="id30bfd28439894c7fb00c629ca8521cd3"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>energy storage and grid modernization;</text></item><item id="id93eba6d6eacc46e99b69819ff262864b"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>geothermal energy;</text></item><item id="idc1ff21ce1f784320b8bb71515e8378a4"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>commercial and residential solar;</text></item><item id="id49d0990c34c14e6bac6f87d1cf8fd536"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>wind energy; and</text></item><item id="idee41be1a944b4f72908ddeb18bc74d68"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>any other clean technology use or development, as determined by the Board;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id658e9f7c52cb4399bcc996e78d769bbf"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>measures that anticipate and prepare for climate change impacts, and reduce risks and enhance resilience to sea level rise, extreme weather events, heat island impacts, and other climate change impacts, as determined by the Board, including by—</text><item id="id65743d4e0cd44d34ab983e059004c0e9"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>building resilient energy, water, and transportation infrastructure;</text></item><item id="id0de2e7534e73413d9f03cd8ba751b35c"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>providing weatherization assistance for low-income households; and</text></item><item id="idde7daa1dd5b04464aa74c79a36ad7951"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>increasing the physical and economic resilience of the agriculture sector; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id38f311423dc64adc993b5c35d6bb5fc0"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>natural infrastructure research, demonstrations, and deployment; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idba1fa3e124c64704a294d87892cc6055"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may implement other investment tools and products approved by the Board, pursuant to subparagraph (C), to achieve the mission of the C2FC described in subsection (a)(2).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idccd8985c76cb4b3fafa8aa13ed424d93"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Loan guarantees</header><clause id="id40a0e6c6a3724e5985d375899f99fb3b"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In providing loan guarantees under subparagraph (A), the C2FC shall cooperate with eligible lenders through agreements to participate on a deferred (guaranteed) basis.</text></clause><clause id="idfc6ed8898d334fbfaee45462e0307022"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Level of participation in guaranteed loans</header><text>In providing a loan guarantee under subparagraph (A), the C2FC shall guarantee 75 percent of the balance of the financing outstanding at the time of disbursement of the loan.</text></clause><clause id="id34858b52ccdb47c58674078c6503e6d0"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Interest rates</header><text>Notwithstanding the provisions of the constitution of any State or the laws of any State limiting the rate or amount of interest that may be charged, taken, received, or reserved, the maximum legal rate of interest on any financing made on a deferred basis under this subsection shall not exceed a rate prescribed by the C2FC.</text></clause><clause id="idba0060b1109e4e32a9624a919408733f"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Guarantee fees</header><subclause id="id37ec29487cb24626b7dd46833cdda71c"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to each loan guaranteed under this subsection (other than a loan that is repayable in 1 year or less), the C2FC shall collect a guarantee fee, which shall be payable by the eligible lender, and may be charged to the eligible borrower in accordance with subclause (II).</text></subclause><subclause id="idb05ea4fd7de74191ae904f39041524af"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Borrower charges</header><text>A guarantee fee described in subclause (I) charged to an eligible borrower shall not—</text><item id="id31e4c5649a8041aa900fa9bb75330715"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>exceed 2 percent of the deferred participation share of a total loan amount that is equal to or less than $150,000;</text></item><item id="ida42c42898cbe4fc9af409d10c5a2dca1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>exceed 3 percent of the deferred participation share of a total loan amount that is greater than $150,000 but less than $700,000; or</text></item><item id="id57e0748ca8a7461d9631e6383416301d"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>exceed 3.5 percent of the deferred participation share of a total loan amount that is equal to or greater than $700,000.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6b44935cec8f48c0abc2ddf084a96d84"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Other investment tools and products</header><clause id="id3b732b69e3ea47359e311f662bb60c51"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board may, based on market needs, develop and implement any other investment tool or product necessary to achieve the mission of the C2FC described in subsection (a)(2) and the deployment of projects described in subparagraph (A)(i), including offering—</text><subclause id="id8a78698f83e8459a82643c2323cf61c3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>warehousing and aggregation credit facilities;</text></subclause><subclause id="id18fb8fda82c4469d929800b57b7b3a09"><enum>(II)</enum><text>zero interest loans;</text></subclause><subclause id="id65d02147f4f3458c86563c134f6badfa"><enum>(III)</enum><text>credit enhancements; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idd3ca5e4705ad4c43a8402c6bb58f1250"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>construction finance.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idbb40c88eecfc4d48b8b8c3238890e1ee"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>State and local green banks</header><text>The Board shall provide—</text><subclause id="id57ba3ddce7114e0aaced0678f952bf2d"><enum>(I)</enum><text>funds to United States Green Bank Institutions as necessary to finance projects that are best served by those entities; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id5dda5f66ea004c1d8bc2444e01b0c27f"><enum>(II)</enum><text>technical assistance as necessary to States and localities seeking to establish green banks.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id15a7a7a4cef24790bee1db85662b48cd" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Prohibited investments</header><text>The Board shall not issue loans, grants, or otherwise invest in any activities that directly or indirectly contradict the mission of the C2FC described in subsection (a)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc1a59edb4f5943f9a03748ae87e5cbac"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Wage rate requirements</header><subparagraph id="idd4d0fd5dd3734c9a8f3a276a75ae7752"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All laborers and mechanics employed by eligible entities and eligible borrowers on projects funded directly by or assisted in whole or in part by the activities of the C2FC under this section shall be paid at wages at rates not less than those prevailing on projects of a similar character in the locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Davis-Bacon Act</quote>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5fda431f477d4f42a030f63fb617f0c6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>With respect to the labor standards specified in subparagraph (A), the Secretary of Labor shall have the authority and functions set forth in Reorganization Plan No. 14 of 1950 (64 Stat. 1267; 5 U.S.C. App.) and section 3145 of title 40, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0b1a54e72eab49c1a6f7739706908a2b"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Buy america requirements</header><subparagraph id="id46205dcf6ec441d0955985ebab390cd3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All iron, steel, and manufactured goods used for projects under this section shall be produced in the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc4f0a608324e402086a29627a47990c2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Board may waive the requirement in subparagraph (A) if the Board finds that—</text><clause id="id6ade48f5c48544fd874254e84060546e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enforcing the requirement would be inconsistent with the public interest;</text></clause><clause id="idd4671760692b46099682e7ce14f00a5e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the iron, steel, and manufactured goods produced in the United States are not produced in a sufficient and reasonably available amount or are not of a satisfactory quality; or</text></clause><clause id="id7e59ca4fa50b46e79619b8c2f361119c"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>enforcing the requirement will increase the overall cost of the project by more than 25 percent.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idef89114bd22748ed97930c947d03c06b"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Program review and report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the Board shall—</text><paragraph id="id3a41b146417046b38963253826c88ca2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a review of the activities of the C2FC and identify projects and funding opportunities that were a part of the current investment plan; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0e6d162f8eb449f3bef1c28088d53ec9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to Congress and make publicly available a report that—</text><subparagraph id="id33dde83e17eb434fb76978a9ce403266"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describes the projects and funding opportunities that have been most successful in progressing towards the mission described in subsection (a)(2) during the time period covered by the report;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id304672a387df44f2bf5750b5a396a081"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes recommendations on the clean energy and resiliency projects that should be prioritized in forthcoming years to achieve that mission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddc9787dbf4b64eb4a1e39ac191ab7022"><enum>(C)</enum><text>quantifies the total amount and percentage of funding given to prioritized communities described in subsection (e)(2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id10fc4f1f930948b393db10e90258be44"><enum>(D)</enum><text>identifies barriers for disadvantaged groups to receive C2FC funding and provides recommendations to address those barriers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0f4f1dfaf4e94b6bba2d83282631a234"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Initial capitalization</header><text>There is appropriated to carry out this section (including for administrative costs of the C2FC), out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $7,500,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 and 2027, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section><section id="idF8C1AD8AA7A04D8F99095095ED5F1F68"><enum>3.</enum><header>Carbon fee</header><subsection id="id38EFA998D2BC4DDEBB83239C76CDCEF6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 38 of subtitle D of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subchapter:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8CC4C2CC7E2A48569D9A6C7AAE3348DD"><subchapter commented="no" id="HC4FE540D048C4D76BEF9B01545868BEE"><enum>E</enum><header>Carbon fee</header><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="HD8B5A440240C4815AC1E7255EBF14F3F">Sec. 4691. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 4692. Carbon fee.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 4693. Fee on noncovered fuel emissions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 4694. Refunds for carbon capture,
 sequestration, and utilization.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 4695. Border adjustments.</toc-entry></toc><section id="HD8B5A440240C4815AC1E7255EBF14F3F"><enum>4691.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this subchapter—</text><paragraph id="HB85238849DAE4410B5F0125B8E723C8C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA612C6179FA14642BF4AD62FD8215D9B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Carbon dioxide equivalent or
 CO<subscript>2</subscript>-e</header><text>The term <term>carbon dioxide equivalent</term> or <term>CO<subscript>2</subscript>-e</term> means the number of metric tons of carbon dioxide emissions with the same global warming potential over a 100-year period as one metric ton of another greenhouse gas.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id467364D2820B43E0A1778F8058160CE1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Carbon-Intensive product</header><text>The term <term>carbon-intensive product</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="idBF9C613D01094EA1A298E04B7089D167"><enum>(A)</enum><text>iron, steel, steel mill products (including pipe and tube), aluminum, cement, glass (including flat, container, and specialty glass and fiberglass), pulp, paper, chemicals, or industrial ceramics, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idD5B2C5C5191047DB9319BE62414B8830"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any manufactured product which the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of Energy, determines is energy-intensive and trade-exposed (with the exception of any covered fuel).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idE378A92F6CA741CFBD4A5B68A5E6E957"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>The term <term>covered entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idCD29244DB13D4F9F88A3511D7505E813"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of crude oil—</text><clause id="id4033B61121214F2091F577B8C40F1A85"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any operator of a United States refinery (as described in subsection (d)(1) of section 4611), and</text></clause><clause id="id80B1C7F42CCF4C36BD733B975AC54672"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any person entering such product into the United States for consumption, use, or warehousing (as described in subsection (d)(2) of such section),</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id495831F4DB3F40B6AFC35C8825656638"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of coal—</text><clause id="id8A083F4B968340F1BE0394F72BB0B5EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any producer subject to the tax under section 4121, and</text></clause><clause id="idDEC10AD0DB9A4D9EB834685423ACBF4C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any importer of coal into the United States,</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1F74836BFFEF4353AA03BB284DE9A39F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of natural gas—</text><clause id="idD7332B8A0C414E64B4DE685D846CAFBC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any entity which produces natural gas (as defined in section 613A(e)(2)) from a well located in the United States, and</text></clause><clause id="id9C9C09A9E2A04768B8E4CE5FD190397A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any importer of natural gas into the United States,</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idF101BEAE0FEC4E3DB1C8ADFCC4E1E722"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in the case of any noncovered fuel emissions, the entity which is the source of such emissions, provided that the total amount of carbon dioxide or methane emitted by such entity for the preceding year (as determined using the methodology required under section 4692(e)(4)) was not less than 25,000 metric tons, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA05D4D9590534B65B2BE6F6533CA6538"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any entity or class of entities which, as determined by the Secretary, is transporting, selling, or otherwise using a covered fuel in a manner which emits a greenhouse gas into the atmosphere and which has not been covered by the carbon fee, the fee on noncovered fuel emissions, or the carbon border fee adjustment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id28C98D7E72954192B00EE268A781982F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Covered fuel</header><text>The term <term>covered fuel</term> means crude oil, natural gas, coal, or any other product derived from crude oil, natural gas, or coal which shall be used so as to emit greenhouse gases to the atmosphere.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id86522FD986224EC1AF4A185DC5A55066"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Greenhouse gas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>greenhouse gas</term>—</text><subparagraph id="idAD859D2389E7493B88E3B9E59C8CB657"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the meaning given such term in section 901 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17321">42 U.S.C. 17321</external-xref>), as in effect on the date of the enactment of the <short-title>America's Clean Future Fund Act</short-title>, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCED54306FAC748609A1790DEC60915E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes any other gases identified by rule of the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1B1B9D9D75DB4757AFBB39796BC6917F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Greenhouse gas content</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>greenhouse gas content</term> means the amount of greenhouse gases, expressed in metric tons of CO<subscript>2</subscript>-e, which would be emitted to the atmosphere by the use of a covered fuel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id50030584A9894E8F87E100E0770E7CB7"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Noncovered fuel emission</header><text>The term <term>noncovered fuel emission</term> means any carbon dioxide or methane emitted as a result of the production, processing, transport, or use of any product or material within the energy or industrial sectors—</text><subparagraph id="id1FA8535D322943CEBE65880F85912FB8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>including any fugitive or process emissions associated with the production, processing, or transport of a covered fuel, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id94A8D2BABCC24D779D3D779D255E810F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>excluding any emissions from the combustion or use of a covered fuel.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id7B444A20BD0E427398F4BCE5EB245DAE"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Qualified carbon oxide</header><text>The term <term>qualified carbon oxide</term> has the meaning given the term in section 45Q(c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id26CA3A63393C4A559DAAABC9230E1D7B"><enum>(10)</enum><header>United States</header><text>The term <term>United States</term> shall be treated as including each possession of the United States (including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands).</text></paragraph></section><section id="idA5467AFDA562476E82183FA7DD1F1ECC"><enum>4692.</enum><header>Carbon fee</header><subsection commented="no" id="id4D08513DB0B34F79801BD85F3CBE04AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id6A8BE4891369484499ECDD9335FB90A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicable period</header><text>The term <term>applicable period</term> means, with respect to any determination made by the Secretary under subsection (e)(3) for any calendar year, the period—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id34BCC19B99C54FABAFBA0CB2AAAE6650"><enum>(A)</enum><text>beginning on January 1, 2027, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id766387DDF2264040829163A49A979200"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ending on December 31 of the preceding calendar year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id422D0005298D4A7D884F66A2C6A40EAA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cumulative emissions</header><text>The term <term>cumulative emissions</term> means an amount equal to the sum of any greenhouse gas emissions resulting from the use of covered fuels and any noncovered fuel emissions for all years during the applicable period.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id9AF43644C14142E080EAFB5C23548318"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cumulative emissions target</header><text>The term <term>cumulative emissions target</term> means an amount equal to the sum of the emissions targets for all years during the applicable period.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id7E369B6514304B9EA34727FB7234D178"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Emissions target</header><text>The term <term>emissions target</term> means the target for greenhouse gas emissions during a calendar year as determined under subsection (e)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id08D174C201CB4BDE89F12223B3BEFB8D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Carbon fee</header><text>During any calendar year that begins after December 31, 2026, there is imposed a carbon fee on any covered entity’s use, sale, or transfer of any covered fuel.</text></subsection><subsection id="idF81EAA3C30634443B788CD0A2CEFDEF5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amount of the carbon fee</header><text>The carbon fee imposed by this section is an amount equal to—</text><paragraph id="id0903734AE00B42E49C2B2411327C34DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the greenhouse gas content of the covered fuel, multiplied by</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD41C21A289684B07B7DD1D011229BD4E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the carbon fee rate, as determined under subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id313EBF68D5124980B8DE90D651AB05E9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Carbon fee rate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The carbon fee rate shall be determined in accordance with the following:</text><paragraph id="idDB342504A2AC4512A9B7A536032CF8DD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The carbon fee rate, with respect to any use, sale, or transfer during a calendar year, shall be—</text><subparagraph id="id090A9BBE61CB45BE8B7DB6C97A5115AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of calendar year 2027, $75, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id484EBD736EF9435486323ABDEA6D328E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), in the case of any calendar year after 2027, the amount equal to the sum of—</text><clause id="idC6FF17AAFD7848EC82D8EDE8FC89FDEB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount under subparagraph (A), plus—</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1e165837bb4c436ea58c90ddc0a64cec"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idfffcbf8cd5e041449009dd86c3cc0896"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of calendar year 2028, $10, and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id38a11e6f642344508c7118aecfeead01" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of any calendar year after 2028, the amount in effect under this clause for the preceding calendar year, plus $10.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idFD02B10046364A7D946D750634D046DF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><subparagraph id="id8D712F91E3A649D78D7CBECB61F46C6C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any calendar year after 2027, the amount determined under paragraph (1)(B) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text><clause id="idEA5E0FE037984EEA86249633499C5CCA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that dollar amount, multiplied by</text></clause><clause id="id8A28CA3AD6AD4AAEA02FFFD10D870F40"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for that calendar year, determined by substituting <quote>2026</quote> for <quote>2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEF3D2C25C5A3415999596621D3765BE5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>If any increase determined under subparagraph (A) is not a multiple of $1, such increase shall be rounded up to the next whole dollar amount.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idA6F1F521AADF4B03A45DE4FEF6D46869"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Adjustment of carbon fee rate</header><subparagraph id="idCBFDF7F667CD4DBBABF19860A4A84234"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Increase in rate following missed cumulative
 emissions target</header><text>In the case of any calendar year following a determination by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (e)(3) that the cumulative emissions for the preceding calendar year exceeded the cumulative emissions target for such year, paragraph (1)(B)(ii)(II) shall be applied—</text><clause id="idC841AFF5F3A64115BF14A852E734F97C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of calendar years 2029 through 2030, by substituting <quote>$15</quote> for <quote>$10</quote>,</text></clause><clause id="id201B57D27CD34FE8998A849C566FB194"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of calendar years 2031 through 2040, by substituting <quote>$20</quote> for <quote>$10</quote>, and</text></clause><clause id="idB89E681CF47347ACA4D73723CB64417C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of any calendar year beginning after 2040, by substituting <quote>$25</quote> for <quote>$10</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA2A269052FA74B0FABBD28F17DF5832B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Cessation of rate increase following achievement of
 cumulative emissions target</header><text>In the case of any year following a determination by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (e)(3) that—</text><clause id="id1E46817A4E5B47EBA50730D9915353E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the average annual emissions of greenhouse gases from covered entities over the preceding 3-year period are not more than 10 percent of the greenhouse gas emissions during the year 2018, and</text></clause><clause id="id60F566BEE4034A0EBCF94056038F1D8D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cumulative emissions did not exceed the cumulative emissions target,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">paragraph (1)(B)(ii)(II) shall be applied by
                                            substituting <quote>$0</quote> for
 <quote>$10</quote>.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id62B098C41B90406B91DD7FFFD0144360"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Methodology</header><text>With respect to any year, the annual greenhouse gas emissions and cumulative emissions described in subparagraph (A) or (B) shall be determined using the methodology required under subsection (e)(4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idC890382B1E9D4A309FF3FC16DDD011BD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Emissions targets</header><paragraph id="idF530EF36D4B24E0790FB1511D514E6C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="id3A73583EE52B4BDA9766780359C9E33D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reference year</header><text>For purposes of subsection (d), the emissions target for any year shall be the amount of greenhouse gas emissions that is equal to—</text><clause commented="no" id="idEFFEBEBC04B94B2B9015C7FD03F3BFDC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for calendar years 2027 and 2028, the applicable percentage of the total amount of greenhouse gas emissions from the use of any covered fuel during calendar year 2018, and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idE476BD6044E84DE89FD7DB50EDC03412"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for calendar year 2029 and each calendar year thereafter, the applicable percentage of the total amount of greenhouse gas emissions from the use of any covered fuel and noncovered fuel emissions during calendar year 2018.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id78681BA421484FF7ACA63A32B2AAAEBB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Methodology</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), with respect to determining the total amount of greenhouse gas emissions from the use of any covered fuel and noncovered fuel emissions during calendar year 2018, the Administrator shall use such methods as are determined appropriate, provided that such methods are, to the greatest extent practicable, comparable to the methods established under paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3184CF18293B404EBC9CB91939E9DFD4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><subparagraph id="idDB56E0C4F44D4C53837F6FD55A1DC36F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>2027 through 2035</header><text>In the case of calendar years 2027 through 2035, the applicable percentage shall be determined as follows:</text><table table-type="Leaderwork" table-template-name="Tax (No Calculation) 1 text, 1 num (9 chars) and extra long heads" align-to-level="section" frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0" line-rules="no-gen" rule-weights="0.0.0.0.0.0"><tgroup cols="2" rowsep="0"><colspec coldef="txt" colname="column1" min-data-value="55" colwidth="275pts"></colspec><colspec align="justify" coldef="fig" colname="column2" min-data-value="9" colwidth="50pts"></colspec><thead><row><entry align="left" morerows="0" namest="column1" colname="column1"><bold>Year</bold></entry><entry align="justify" morerows="0" namest="column2" colname="column2"><bold>Applicable percentage</bold></entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" colname="column1">2027</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">63 percent</entry></row><row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" colname="column1">2028</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">60 percent</entry></row><row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" colname="column1">2029</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">57 percent</entry></row><row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" colname="column1">2030</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">55 percent</entry></row><row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" colname="column1">2031</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">52 percent</entry></row><row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" colname="column1">2032</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">49 percent</entry></row><row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" colname="column1">2033</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">46 percent</entry></row><row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" colname="column1">2034</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">43 percent</entry></row><row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" colname="column1">2035</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">40 percent</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3EF1392D01C444839F4C9CDBC77917A2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>2036 through 2050</header><text>In the case of calendar years 2036 through 2050, the applicable percentage shall be equal to—</text><clause id="id5E6514DC4C4B4D0BB9D430B62408D587"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the applicable percentage for the preceding year, minus</text></clause><clause id="id05C0E3BD66BA420D884E185EE8ECBF7C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>2 percentage points.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB6A2952E076541E490A3013841212172"><enum>(C)</enum><header>After 2050</header><text>In the case of any calendar year beginning after 2050, the applicable percentage shall be equal to 10 percent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id79F1B41F269F4E799CF61977883BE545"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Emissions reporting and determinations</header><subparagraph id="id7F4621ED81A04B86A37A2E137DB84512"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Not later than September 30, 2027, and annually thereafter, the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary, shall make available to the public a report on—</text><clause id="id2C40B27891E24F0693FD7E69762002C3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the cumulative emissions with respect to the preceding calendar year, and</text></clause><clause id="id02BCFD40A4414EC0A4346872C989E447"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other relevant information, as determined appropriate by the Administrator.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC45B5EAE5ED24994AFBA3C4E7AD62638"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determinations</header><text>Not later than September 30, 2029, and annually thereafter, the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary and as part of the report described in subparagraph (A), shall determine whether cumulative emissions with respect to the preceding calendar year exceeded the cumulative emissions target with respect to such year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idECFCA858E4B340E693A483BBB7E84ED0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Emissions accounting methodology</header><subparagraph id="idA451C6E098044197A7B95816B42C833C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2027, the Administrator shall prescribe rules for greenhouse gas accounting for covered entities for purposes of this subchapter, which shall—</text><clause id="idEA9529B97CF44D24ABC6E39E5DDCEBCE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to the greatest extent practicable, employ existing data collection methodologies and greenhouse gas accounting practices, including such methodologies and practices developed by the National Laboratories (as defined in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>)),</text></clause><clause id="id3121DA5E10624B7D88FADBE8145DFBE1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensure that the method of accounting—</text><subclause id="id2C881392855B49A495BF2C191755DC30"><enum>(I)</enum><text>applies to—</text><item id="id227F493D7B804318BD6F54932BA04D14"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>all greenhouse gas emissions from covered fuels and all noncovered fuel emissions, and</text></item><item id="id480BBCAF44B443A1970AB3EFA6F3BCC2"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>all covered entities,</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id5A9D617AA9F94FDEA224C9C48CBBFBFC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>excludes—</text><item id="idC3BDDC3D5E5947DF9D5B50F163858BB9"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>any greenhouse gas emissions which are not described item (aa) of subclause (I), and</text></item><item id="id27D45C4007C741458BC25F76D5C0FB4D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>any entities which are not described in item (bb) of such subclause, and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="idE0F90EA926C349D7A1F5B291AE9B7F5B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>appropriately accounts for—</text><item id="idDDF8CA4EDB954A98BEEC341AD0461978"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>qualified carbon oxide which is captured and disposed or used in a manner described in section 4694, and</text></item><item id="id0D9A261AA5F040C8A202C6DFDD7244F6"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>nonemitting uses of covered fuels, as described in subsection (f),</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="idF3FC97FADB4D4BA78F5B96490CDA70A6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>subject to such penalties as are determined appropriate by the Administrator, require any covered entity to report, not later than April 1 of each calendar year—</text><subclause id="id0E583B07D6E34451A00BFE5B3E4382B0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the total greenhouse gas content of any covered fuels used, sold, or transferred by such covered entity during the preceding calendar year, and</text></subclause><subclause id="idCCEF59BD672345A0AFA30D5A3F27654E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the total noncovered fuel emissions of the covered entity during the preceding calendar year, and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id5DB1A827A6614860B09B90CE9C9F210B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>require any information reported pursuant to clause (iii) to be verified by a third-party entity that, subject to such process as is determined appropriate by the Administrator, has been certified by the Administrator with respect to the qualifications, independence, and reliability of such entity.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEF80A9DB6A444C399DD64450F311AABA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Greenhouse Gas Reporting Program</header><text>For purposes of establishing the rules described in subparagraph (A), the Administrator may elect to modify the activities of the Greenhouse Gas Reporting Program established under part 98 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on January 1, 2025, to satisfy the requirements described in clauses (i) through (iv) of such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id03D5A25CAFCD491ABE54D3C66DEA08AD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Revisions</header><text>With respect to any determination made by the Administrator as to the amount of greenhouse gas emissions for any calendar year (including calendar year 2018), any subsequent revision by the Administrator with respect to such amount shall apply for purposes of the fee imposed under subsection (b) for any calendar years beginning after such revision.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idCEAE4F3A7A104150BEC22D3EFF2E9D29"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Exemption and refund</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such rules as are necessary to ensure the carbon fee imposed by this section is not imposed with respect to any nonemitting use, or any sale or transfer for a nonemitting use, including rules providing for the refund of any carbon fee paid under this section with respect to any such use, sale, or transfer.</text></subsection><subsection id="idB6F1A1B17D204CD5872B2AC8A7108B79"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Administrative authority</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator, shall prescribe such regulations, and other guidance, to assess and collect the carbon fee imposed by this section, including—</text><paragraph id="id262A201C454B4F4B96AC01F4AF25EABA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the identification of covered entities that are liable for payment of a fee under this section or section 4693,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6D9800A8D8554A26B1407942EE589EBC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as may be necessary or convenient, rules for distinguishing between different types of covered entities,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA7EE2B2349024EE28F029EECABEBD1B2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>as may be necessary or convenient, rules for distinguishing between the greenhouse gas emissions of a covered entity and the greenhouse gas emissions that are attributed to the covered entity but not directly emitted by the covered entity,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9EBBDE782CB045C59473006AE28AAB96"><enum>(4)</enum><text>requirements for the quarterly payment of such fees, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3D19D447A1EB4E0189A63878B6C191EF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>rules to ensure that the carbon fee under this section, the fee on noncovered fuel emissions under section 4693, or the carbon border fee adjustment is not imposed on an emission from covered fuel or noncovered fuel emission more than once.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id9c8de87c573d4f0988054cffdc6639b3"><enum>4693.</enum><header>Fee on noncovered fuel emissions</header><subsection id="idA0CD3C324DD34468B0C543594DBF9802"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During any calendar year that begins after December 31, 2028, there is imposed a fee on a covered entity for any noncovered fuel emissions which occur during the calendar year.</text></subsection><subsection id="id9D3543A557C74583BCF032E84D6EBD4F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The fee to be paid under subsection (a) by the covered entity which is the source of the emissions described in that subsection shall be an amount equal to—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id4a4ec3bf0b334c95b1258b3b3e76225c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the total amount, in metric tons of CO<subscript>2</subscript>-e, of emitted greenhouse gases, multiplied by</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f7b809342974730a2aa41db452a711f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an amount equal to the carbon fee rate in effect under section 4692(d) for the calendar year of such emission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id510877FE4C2D41DFB3F154F852ABD70F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administrative authority</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator, shall prescribe such regulations, and other guidance, to assess and collect the carbon fee imposed by this section, including regulations describing the requirements for the quarterly payment of such fees.</text></subsection></section><section id="id9532A95899264A3AB794BCCB9BA15A35"><enum>4694.</enum><header>Refunds for carbon capture, sequestration, and
 utilization</header><subsection id="id9E840E7883CF4BBB891C8871E4B89F78"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="id89687FBE258242F58FD500CAC0EE437C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Capture, sequestration, and use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator and the Secretary of Energy, shall prescribe regulations for providing payments to any person which captures qualified carbon oxide which is—</text><subparagraph id="id6DE76CAA3DAD4405A689431E7BF4F817"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disposed of by such person in secure geological storage, as described in section 45Q(f)(2), or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id505425B6952C4A47897D1E8A2CAF3478"><enum>(B)</enum><text>used in a manner which has been approved by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5A2947370A5E4244B2F9048FA5EA81B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Election</header><text>If the person described in paragraph (1) makes an election under this paragraph in such time and manner as the Secretary may prescribe by regulations, the credit under this section—</text><subparagraph id="idA6709C8FCE8142709AAFDF4F8CF4F365"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be allowable to the person that owns the facility described in subsection (b)(1), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF88183151E4547469F7C4B8AE68BA6C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall not be allowable to the person described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1D9F36A9CB9F4D06BA6F2669A9BB156B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payments for carbon capture</header><paragraph id="id91D0FAA02BA242D594ADCF7F53BDCB55"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any facility for which carbon capture equipment has been placed in service, the Secretary shall make payments in the same manner as if such payment was a refund of an overpayment of the fee imposed by section 4692 or 4693.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idC3B0C418E8D544DF961BEDAC833F5F3B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount of payment</header><text>The payment determined under this subsection shall be an amount equal to—</text><subparagraph id="idFB6F229E1E534ECEBFBAEA8771A6061E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the metric tons of qualified carbon oxide captured and disposed of, used, or utilized in a manner consistent with subsection (a), multiplied by</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2AEE476DC68E4B968AFDB0A7C8E7CCEC"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id3FCF3328D60C48A99B3271AEC696EDA0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the carbon fee rate during the year in which the carbon fee was imposed by section 4692 on the covered fuel to which such carbon oxide relates, or</text></clause><clause indent="up1" id="id79FBCE121D3B4644BFBF34086EC16AD0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a direct air capture facility (as defined in section 45Q(e)(1)), the carbon fee rate during the year in which the qualified carbon oxide was captured and disposed of, used, or utilized.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5ED56DC81A92471F8A134B711E20BFB7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Approved uses of qualified carbon oxide</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd19c0038953d428bb9e11abd18f2dd06"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary, in consultation with Administrator and the Secretary of Energy, shall, through regulation or other public guidance, determine which uses of qualified carbon oxide are eligible for payments under this section, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="id613EE4DB48304CF9A971401C4492F73A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>utilization in a manner described in clause (i) or (ii) of section 45Q(f)(5)(A), or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id10CD70EBDFE8430CB56F59F0F1E426C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other use which ensures minimal leakage or escape of such carbon oxide.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3d0ba648822c4f54a5590d4550cf3152"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusion for enhanced oil or natural gas
 recovery</header><text>The sale or use of qualified carbon oxide as a tertiary injectant in a qualified enhanced oil or natural gas recovery project (as defined in section 45Q(e)(4)) shall not be eligible for payments under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id6B87165DFFDD49F68838077C63E4151B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>In the case of any facility which is owned by an entity that is determined to be—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id8A5B268F21DC4060BB53039D847A2543"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in violation of any applicable air or water quality regulations, or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id39313AB53F2742BD863DB01E52283C6A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to any environmental justice community (as defined in section 2(d)(1)(D) of the <short-title>America's Clean Future Fund Act</short-title>), creating health or environmental harm to such community,</text><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">such
                                        facility shall not be eligible for any payment under this
                                        section during the period of such
 violation.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="id372E9C3CA8D4416DACD1A2D07A535977"><enum>4695.</enum><header>Border adjustments</header><subsection commented="no" id="id66AC2BFEE68C4EC1881E6261DABB7DE7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The fees imposed by, and refunds allowed under, this section shall be referred to as ‘the carbon border fee adjustment’.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idF417673265CF47828EF3FE1AE3AABACD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exports</header><paragraph commented="no" id="idCB6735239B9F4087836E484A93DA42B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Carbon-intensive products</header><text>In the case of any carbon-intensive product which is exported from the United States, the Secretary shall pay to the person exporting such product a refund equal to the amount of the cost of such product attributable to any fees imposed under this subchapter related to the manufacturing of such product (as determined under regulations established by the Secretary).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idC8E70348CCB64614B09219E4CAD0A130"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered fuels</header><text>In the case of any covered fuel which is exported from the United States, the Secretary shall pay to the person exporting such fuel a refund equal to the amount of the cost of such fuel attributable to any fees imposed under this subchapter related to the use, sale, or transfer of such fuel.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7CBE6C2AD3BB4DA0BB98779FC8013F1A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Imports</header><paragraph commented="no" id="idBF3F257EF3A4465CAB0502E43B25F245"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Carbon-intensive products</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="id589AC26588A24A78992D407EBEECB0BF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Imposition of equivalency fee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any carbon-intensive product imported into the United States, there is imposed an equivalency fee on the person importing such product in an amount equal to the cost of such product that would be attributable to any fees imposed under this subchapter related to the manufacturing of such product if any inputs or processes used in manufacturing such product were subject to such fees (as determined under regulations established by the Secretary).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idBAE0C765DDDA4F12BD7472C38A4B24CC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reduction in fee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of the equivalency fee under subparagraph (A) shall be reduced by the amount, if any, of any fees imposed on the carbon-intensive product by the foreign nation or governmental units from which such product was imported.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id1BA8C93D6C3C4925B6A07E50481D354D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered fuels</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="id2E1085729E8647508513F4893F8242DB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any covered fuel imported into the United States, there is imposed an equivalency fee on the person importing such fuel in an amount equal to the amount of any fees that would be imposed under this subchapter related to the use, sale, or transfer of such fuel.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id4A20EA67B3C24C19A952BD39644ABFC5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reduction in fee</header><text>The amount of the fee under subparagraph (A) shall be reduced by the amount, if any, of any fees imposed on the covered fuel by the foreign nation or governmental units from which the fuel was imported.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id6C0004925C1E454B9DBED0FA9659F347"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Treatment of alternative policies as fees</header><text>Under regulations established by the Secretary, foreign policies that have substantially the same effect in reducing emissions of greenhouse gases as fees shall be treated as fees for purposes of subsections (b) and (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="idE18E8D7B028A4B3FBB00C4B237AF5EFD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><paragraph id="idD6AEC61BD5AC4B49A11D88886340EA96"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall consult with the Administrator, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of Energy in establishing rules and regulations implementing the purposes of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB4AF591961F94E46BC32CCD5CE58E8D7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treaties</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State, may adjust the applicable amounts of the refunds and equivalency fees under this section in a manner that is consistent with any obligations of the United States under an international agreement.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id6321F5EB47454EBB9B9E163E6E7F84B9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to periods beginning after December 31, 2026.</text></subsection></section><section id="H1677B678DCE34ED18F291A90CC8B7CDE"><enum>4.</enum><header>America's Clean Future Fund</header><subsection id="id60CE2FCC3F234ED28BE1250221911E23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/98">chapter 98</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9837EB05056546AC9681A49EB3E03B59"><section id="id0BE8FB5F183C4CC99F4BFD37B2E1C955"><enum>9512.</enum><header>America's Clean Future Fund</header><subsection id="H83E72B3CBB1247299B9BA6245DD9EA99"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment and funding</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the <quote>America's Clean Future Fund</quote> (referred to in this section as the <quote>Trust Fund</quote>), consisting of such amounts as are appropriated to the Trust Fund under subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="HE1B8E0D7FE744E5E8FA9B55A310AD43E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfers to America's Clean Future Fund</header><text>There is appropriated to the Trust Fund, out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, amounts equal to the fees received into the Treasury under sections 4692, 4693, and 4695, less—</text><paragraph id="id0F15BECCCDE04FF78497BAFF269043F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any amounts refunded or paid under sections 4692(d), 4694, and 4695(b), and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5D1DF9E37BED401C8A85E8C08B833D81"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each of the first 14 fiscal years beginning after September 30, 2027, an amount equal to the quotient of—</text><subparagraph id="idE814A9AB8068453D973BB333E62A22E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$100,000,000,000, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB3D531D470DD4EC39E81C6517FFBBC92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>14.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA7359FCB1434324BEBC0B75B6393E15"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expenditures</header><text>For each fiscal year, amounts in the Trust Fund shall be apportioned as follows:</text><paragraph id="idCC5267E2B10045039ACD2FD5A5D8F311"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Carbon fee rebate and agricultural decarbonization
 transition payments</header><subparagraph id="id6BB256BB83AC4F33AB900BBC454A20C4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Carbon fee rebate</header><text>For the purposes described in section 5 of the <short-title>America's Clean Future Fund Act</short-title> and any expenses necessary to administer such section—</text><clause id="id5045AF296AE44A32AAF121440071006F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for each of the first 10 fiscal years beginning after September 30, 2027, an amount equal to—</text><subclause id="idC41ED31B88AA4E42A25EC3FA3DE1B48E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>75 percent of those amounts, minus</text></subclause><subclause id="idD3B5F9B18BA44C86807112D5ED307964"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the amount determined under subparagraph (B) for such fiscal year, and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id4654141EBBC2453F81AD5FB9180BF4B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for any fiscal year beginning after the period described in clause (i), the applicable percentage of such amounts.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8CA48BE64CB144839CDFD357A04675BF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Agricultural decarbonization transition
 payments</header><text>For the purposes described in section 6 of the <short-title>America's Clean Future Fund Act</short-title>, for each of the first 10 fiscal years beginning after September 30, 2027, an amount equal to 7 percent of the amount determined annually under subparagraph (A)(i)(I).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id79EB7F59332F44B4AA76B0A2850B918F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(ii), the applicable percentage shall be equal to—</text><clause id="id271A063B332E4900A8D779BEE551D7BB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for the first fiscal year beginning after the period described in subparagraph (A)(i), 76 percent,</text></clause><clause id="id3A259267A4F04ACBB098C853D182AE24"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for each of the first 3 fiscal years subsequent to the period described in clause (i), the applicable percentage for the preceding fiscal year increased by 1 percentage point, and</text></clause><clause id="id82FF270C453949C3A2E5B81A3336C88C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for any fiscal year subsequent to the period described in clause (ii), 80 percent.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id743D48DA5DB242ED91F08B32A694A6D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Climate Change Finance Corporation</header><subparagraph id="id83EF1B20AEBC454AAD39F54147DC49F2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the purposes described in section 2 of the <short-title>America's Clean Future Fund Act</short-title> (including any expenses necessary to administer such section), the applicable percentage of such amounts.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3157868F848241299BA65F3D78E0E113"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the applicable percentage shall be equal to—</text><clause id="idF114ABA72F3F4115B5804DC350EB191C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for each of the first 10 fiscal years beginning after the period described in subsection (e) of such section, 15 percent,</text></clause><clause id="idDB67FBD289544705BE41695CEABBC916"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for each of the first 4 fiscal years subsequent to the period described in clause (i), the applicable percentage for the preceding fiscal year increased by 1 percentage point, and</text></clause><clause id="idE64A897847C54CCE818511CC04635A30"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for any fiscal year subsequent to the period described in clause (ii), 20 percent.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4D57906FF38542CCA7F40924BE2917C7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transition assistance for impacted communities</header><subparagraph id="id3BCA514124A34C619A128CB68A6F124A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the purposes described in section 7 of the <short-title>America's Clean Future Fund Act</short-title> (including any expenses necessary to administer such section), the applicable percentage of such amounts.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8943D693A2FB42198960235321EB7ABE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the applicable percentage shall be equal to—</text><clause id="idA192245D4DE24DAA9569362698FA5FB0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for each of the first 10 fiscal years beginning after September 30, 2027, 10 percent,</text></clause><clause id="idDEA30C8BF2704EA682DF2D96505DDD6B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for each of the first 4 fiscal years subsequent to the period described in clause (i), the applicable percentage for the preceding fiscal year reduced by 2 percentage points, and</text></clause><clause id="id971442B95CC447D08141614D098C2F41"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for any fiscal year subsequent to the period described in clause (ii), 0 percent.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id0067707F35414806B72AEF6064125FD9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/98">chapter 98</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE3596DCF66E948FB9E5508E100A25D19"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 9512. America's Clean Future
 Fund.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="id61A58744705A41588F48D9A9EC9906EF"><enum>5.</enum><header>America's Clean Future Fund Stimulus</header><subsection id="H168DC2714AF8491A8DDAFA361B35CBFF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Eligible individual</header><paragraph id="idBDD43579DC94413E8F87B42F0FA348AD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this section, the term <term>eligible individual</term> means, with respect to any quarter, any natural living person—</text><subparagraph id="idF018D46D0A0345C6A73E76CA43034C41"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who has a valid Social Security number or taxpayer identification number,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id24787DC9536848609255AA1798F84D4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who has attained 18 years of age, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC7A960C251CF4610B39792C13126E00E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whose principal place of abode is in the United States for more than one-half of the most recent taxable year for which a return has been filed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85E8C4881AD24735841B3032D7B795A9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Verification</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury, or the Secretary's delegate (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) may verify the eligibility of an individual to receive a carbon fee rebate payment under subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5716DAEA372E45C1AC8BE63B34D3472A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rebates</header><text>Subject to subsections (c)(2) and (k), from amounts in the America's Clean Future Fund established by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9512">section 9512(c)(1)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 that are available in any year, the Secretary shall, for each calendar quarter beginning after September 30, 2027, make carbon fee rebate payments to each eligible individual, to be known as <quote>America's Clean Future Fund Stimulus payments</quote> (referred to in this section as <quote>carbon fee rebate payments</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H36EEBE0525654B9191C93CED42809608"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Pro-Rata share</header><paragraph id="idE10A43AF7D854D0AA91CB6A6D232DA64"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to each quarter during any fiscal year beginning after September 30, 2027, the carbon fee rebate payment is 1 pro-rata share for each eligible individual of an amount equal to 25 percent of amounts apportioned under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9512">section 9512(c)(1)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for such fiscal year.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id2415C95CDB0048DEAD7226B9452973FA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial annual rebate payments</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="idD789A1A687154227867C7ECC4D2351EE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From amounts appropriated under subsection (j), the Secretary shall, for each of fiscal years 2026 and 2027, make carbon fee rebate payments to each eligible individual during the third quarter of each such fiscal year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idE6269369D67A4754A3C7C40EC930F675"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Pro-rata share</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the carbon fee rebate payment is 1 pro-rata share for each eligible individual of the amount appropriated under subsection (j) for the fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idF64B500B0E714DD08857D22A7C8E63A4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Estimate</header><text>For each fiscal year described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall, not later than the first day of such fiscal year, publicly announce an estimate of the amount of the carbon fee rebate payment for each quarter during such fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idCB76296A702641F1B0D3989E7DBF6380"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Phaseout</header><paragraph commented="no" id="idD3654D4145094B0B99010D251081A71F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id1CEA0E9951964726AEC82071C80A3632"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Modified adjusted gross income</header><text>The term <term>modified adjusted gross income</term> means adjusted gross income increased by any amount excluded from gross income under section 911, 931, or 933 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id511DEEB0A3B747EABC8E5A2CBC255D4F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Household member</header><text>The term <term>household member of the taxpayer</term> means the taxpayer, the taxpayer's spouse, and any dependent of the taxpayer.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id783CADD2FE904C9A82C0888E7951DEC6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Threshold amount</header><text>The term <term>threshold amount</term> means—</text><clause commented="no" id="id81F580247E1F423488918A1F3C3D871C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>$150,000 in the case of a taxpayer filing a joint return, and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idD32E836A26424CF0B2FF30753335087E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$75,000 in the case of a taxpayer not filing a joint return.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idFCD7FB3D97AD41579A8AA5509E47C0D1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Phaseout of payments</header><text>In the case of any taxpayer whose modified adjusted gross income for the most recent taxable year for which a return has been filed exceeds the threshold amount, the amount of the carbon fee rebate payment otherwise payable to any household member of the taxpayer under this section shall be reduced (but not below zero) by a dollar amount equal to 5 percent of such payment (as determined before application of this paragraph) for each $1,000 (or fraction thereof) by which the modified adjusted gross income of the taxpayer exceeds the threshold amount.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HDFA3F74B0629472298ADB876C57B247A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Fee treatment of payments</header><text>Amounts paid under this section shall not be includible in gross income for purposes of Federal income taxes.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD5358470EC4C4D5D9B043BCEAF5F416D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Federal programs and Federal assisted programs</header><text>The carbon fee rebate payment received by any eligible individual shall not be taken into account as income and shall not be taken into account as resources for purposes of determining the eligibility of such individual or any other individual for benefits or assistance, or the amount or extent of benefits or assistance, under any Federal program or under any State or local program financed in whole or in part with Federal funds.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2C8A71DC07BD4C4B9DB8CC15A99390B2"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Disclosure of return information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">Section 6103(l)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBEC00D11B4B94677B9A831560864367C"><paragraph id="H1E7BD83337E344E5A066D5DD73B1F349"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Disclosure of return information relating to carbon fee rebate
 payments</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2B9DF62E7A444408BDC566464F018C18"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Department of Treasury</header><text>Return information with respect to any taxpayer shall, without written request, be open to inspection by or disclosure to officers and employees of the Department of the Treasury whose official duties require such inspection or disclosure for purposes of administering section 5 of the <short-title>America's Clean Future Fund Act</short-title>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H04F24528B0024E47B9FF24FF14C2A711"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Restriction on disclosure</header><text>Information disclosed under this paragraph shall be disclosed only for purposes of, and to the extent necessary in, carrying out such section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id9D523E616BFD4213AEDA871BB42227DF"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations, and other guidance, as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section, including—</text><paragraph id="id43FCAE026A0E466799BE05AB50613E18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establishment of rules for eligible individuals who have not filed a recent tax return, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id24A7B55285C2421497C65ED6C639272B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in coordination with the Commissioner of Social Security, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and any relevant State agencies, establish methods to identify eligible individuals and provide carbon fee rebate payments to such individuals through appropriate means of distribution, including through the use of electronic benefit transfer cards.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id89AA69D4923F45D58126AC0326B2605C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Public awareness campaign</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct a public awareness campaign, in coordination with the Commissioner of Social Security, the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, and Indian Tribes (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>)), to provide information to the public regarding the availability of carbon fee rebate payments under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="id248351BB70FF43549F9AD203FECCEC65"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Initial appropriation</header><text>For purposes of subsection (c)(2), there is appropriated, out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to remain available until expended—</text><paragraph id="idFCB1467E40504515B90D19DB0A7F31C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2026, $37,500,000,000, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idBAA505A33153449EB20E7E21C6164BCA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2027, $37,500,000,000.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id01950046E23B488F88714F8ADC8B060A"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>This section shall not apply to any calendar quarter beginning after—</text><paragraph id="id4B284372879D4817AC4EDB0DF2A220A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a determination by the Secretary under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4692">section 4692(d)(3)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id703606EACD6C4C3AB52D30A5C49704AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any period of 8 consecutive calendar quarters for which the amount of carbon fee rebate payment (without application of subsection (d)) during each such quarter is less than $20.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idB587579ACB0E4436B1C71CED0D91E0B8"><enum>6.</enum><header>Agricultural decarbonization transition payments</header><subsection id="id67132355E9544709BB5D8DA10E0A358A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this section are—</text><paragraph id="idB3C13335BFAA4FB58646960A2C2865B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide transition assistance to eligible producers in the agricultural sector to prepare for and facilitate entry into greenhouse gas credit markets; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8F898AB9B4F44079BCD7E851DDCAABAF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide for the collection and reporting of data under subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idCE0E5900271C49A1B9F892416D5B1332"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id345F3BC215794F56A60564FC992B7EB8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible land</header><text>The term <term>eligible land</term> means land in the United States, including territories of the United States and Indian land (as defined in section 2601 of the Energy Policy Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/3501">25 U.S.C. 3501</external-xref>)), that has a cropping or livestock history during each of the 3 years preceding the date on which a payment is provided under the program with respect to the land, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id24FBB5A9D0FE4A128C65DB2FDC78E015"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible producer</header><text>The term <term>eligible producer</term> means an individual or legal entity that—</text><subparagraph id="idF268358E7AC148E583749E42D5DD4C0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is an owner, operator, or tenant of eligible land; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id30E2C13F187341539EABF4AD81041299"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has the ability to enter into an agreement with the Secretary to carry out qualifying actions described in subsection (c)(2) under the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idDBF07DDB134445D6849CEE04A21C973C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Greenhouse gas emissions reduction</header><text>The term <term>greenhouse gas emissions reduction</term> means the reduction in greenhouse gas emissions as a result of the adoption of qualifying actions described in subsection (c)(2), as compared to an historical baseline.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9EB35CF6456F4F2DB451F103561E4F2F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>program</term> means the program established under subsection (c)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idEF96DB49B35247A6B7B3826550A3877B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6fb0034b4e5b49efab2e5da16131c917"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Traditionally underserved</header><text>The term <term>traditionally underserved</term>, with respect to an eligible producer, means that the eligible producer—</text><subparagraph id="id1ae185dc67ec4f1481a187a3885a0df9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has been socially or economically disadvantaged by previous discriminatory laws or policies based on race, ethnicity, or disability;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf1549143b1d947048e13e71009d6f036"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is new to agriculture, as determined by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1d81cf7d508a4ec096f7d93d894b3fb1"><enum>(C)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idc916ed52c7cf4b1481586c19334bb3aa"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has served in the United States Armed Forces; and</text></clause><clause id="id31f412c2d3044ab1b03f9bef4313f36b" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idde3bef3579714ab89f17727f4b5820c3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has not operated an agriculture operation;</text></subclause><subclause id="id62bbcb2796fb4933a045d1be52cfb80f" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is new to agriculture, as determined by the Secretary; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id842d42a24e034576a1089d7cc128a9e5" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>first obtained veteran status during the previous 5-year period;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3dd6bf83dcde4364bdb947f8293c156a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is an owner, operator, or tenant of a limited resource agriculture operation; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id88a0d9204f88425986b37532ba0758af"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has a household income not greater than the national poverty level.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9985BC64BC154B1BAEAC0017C300E2F8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Establishment of program</header><paragraph id="idFCC2DDBC37DA4B93B30714BA8ABD5035"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program to provide payments to eligible producers that will assist with reducing greenhouse gas emissions through the adoption of qualifying actions described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idEEBCAEB18B07429D992F94056F090857"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifying actions</header><subparagraph id="id5D1E8B774AA24053B394C56A32C65A2D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall determine actions that qualify for payments under the program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbbe4da0ca2714213855e6e6ed70ee52f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be a qualifying action under subparagraph (A), an action shall be—</text><clause id="id6A50D884668E419DBC5F925FBDA20689"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a climate-smart practice, including—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida5883093579d464c8b288a76581ce1a6"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a practice determined by a land-grant college or university (as defined in section 1404 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3103">7 U.S.C. 3103</external-xref>)); or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1ef3ab3f698a401e86bd7117a9e0aae4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>climate-smart energy generation, fueling, or efficiency; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id7EBBAF931FA5481E9CD48AC95A19CD19"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>measurable, reportable, and verifiable for reducing greenhouse gas emissions, as determined by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida4b4ef5a47ec46668dbcf2f99c3f4393"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In determining the rate and duration of a payment under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consider—</text><subparagraph id="id7a7d6f6d8c484b6a8efa49fa9bf46041"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the degree of additionality of the greenhouse gas emissions reduction;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1dc11e02a45f419a871ebfeeead48fa7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether the recipient of the payment was an early adopter of 1 or more practices that reduce greenhouse gas emissions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5760eecbffdf4a058047f4634a646395"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the likelihood that the applicable qualifying action described in paragraph (2) would have been carried out absent the provision of the payment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8660c015bd0643568e5c4a2efb484e5d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the degree of transitionality or permanence of the greenhouse gas emissions reduction;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6ed365f33f724bac82682a9357b63e3b"><enum>(E)</enum><text>whether the applicable qualifying action described in paragraph (2) provides multiple environmental and health co-benefits in addition to reduced greenhouse gas emissions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5c389ab2b6ce40fa90f917abc610cf15"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the degree to which the recipient of the payment is a traditionally underserved eligible producer;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id139a5c6f0a824810bf8fe82e1e42304b"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the integration with and enhancement of payments and policies of similar Federal, State, or local programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7599a7ed573f4b89a623e0e44f80f5d8"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any payments received, or to be received, by the applicable eligible producer from a similar Federal, State, or local program for applicable qualifying actions described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id44AB15CF998149FE965870E469CB3E2C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Ineligibility</header><text>A person that is determined to be in violation of any applicable water or air quality regulation, including under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>) (including regulations), shall not be eligible for any payment under paragraph (1) during the period of the violation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3BD5C055EBA54C728B88A65CCE9D781E" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Effectiveness</header><text>The authority to provide payments under this subsection shall be effective for each of the first 10 fiscal years beginning after September 30, 2026.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="id6FBDB7FF34D94A3A983C56AB760F5A82"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Collection of data and reporting</header><paragraph id="id948b2293ffad40e3b6d63be7c1c8ccda"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Measurement system</header><text>The Secretary shall use an outcomes-based measurement system that uses the best available science and technology for cost-effective recordkeeping, modeling, and measurement of farm-level greenhouse gas emissions on eligible land enrolled in the program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2607b953fb0b4c2187f2abd131614bd0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inventory</header><subparagraph id="id66219e5827a241f6ba0ba8c814879441"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the purposes of providing payments under the program, the Secretary shall conduct a nationwide soil health and agricultural greenhouse gas emissions inventory that uses the best available science and data to establish baselines and expected average performance for soil carbon drawdown and storage and greenhouse gas emissions reduction by primary production type and production region.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbb78054629b04bc285815354e0203bfd"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Database</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><clause id="id4BE5F4D113264FD5A8A5AB43D733DECF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish an accessible and interoperable database for the inventory established under subparagraph (A) using the measurement system established under paragraph (1); and</text></clause><clause id="id3811FE23A60F4473AB7A31E79C762B98"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improve and update the database as new data is collected, but not less frequently than once every 2 years.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9451b61a69024caf8a9b968284e6b561"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Criteria</header><subparagraph id="id87D6498112ED45A0A757E28A24D86A0A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish criteria for payments under the program to inform policy and markets established to promote greenhouse gas emissions reductions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAA098477AF7A4CA7BECC7022E9242D27"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The criteria established under subparagraph (A) shall—</text><clause id="id051745ccbdd6473ab98f573da79d6663"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have a documented likelihood of providing long-term net greenhouse gas emissions reductions, according to the best available science;</text></clause><clause id="idea23cd5cead644978461dd03ad194e44"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be based in part on environmental impact modeling of the changes of shifting from baseline practices to new or improved practices; and</text></clause><clause id="id6698a05921664420a1ad5e65f771f37a"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prevent, to the maximum extent practicable, the degradation of other natural resource or environmental conditions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idC61AECF8672141A2A596E66195198595"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Measurement, reporting, monitoring, and verification services</header><subparagraph id="id534AB8F3840645879A6306E4B1B3919A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary—</text><clause id="id12A7D2416B7844CE9A69E8CEFA0C43D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall provide services described in subparagraph (B) to eligible producers participating in the program; and</text></clause><clause id="id30744585CA9C40029D1F271F78A5C91C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may approve and provide oversight of 1 or more third-party agents to provide services described in subparagraph (B) to eligible producers participating in the program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB80917EBF4C448BE907B043B3505CEE8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Services described</header><text>Services referred to in subparagraph (A) are determining the greenhouse gas emissions reduction by—</text><clause id="id7DEB974AC7534FBB873D160E610AB513"><enum>(i)</enum><text>measurement;</text></clause><clause id="id5275F46917844841A397AFB6BC437912"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reporting;</text></clause><clause id="id95109A75C2234B32AEB1E94D523C2845"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>monitoring; and</text></clause><clause id="idDC3499D6665045AA84F178FAC7A96041"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>verification.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAA89D00AC4ED41D8AC8B1B5EA3489B99"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Use of protocols</header><text>Services referred to in subparagraph (A) shall be provided using—</text><clause id="idD19A4C66F06B4F7382874F4718D4C349"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the measurement system described in paragraph (1); and</text></clause><clause id="id07909D9FAC7B4A27B294FC1C69A30B86"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the criteria described in paragraph (3).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFDE6802F97834AA1ADB0FCF827054C68"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Privacy and data security</header><clause id="idE0A365A3557A4A09BDA3DFAEA1EBB851"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish—</text><subclause id="id82C0EA88035641099DA3B635600791ED"><enum>(I)</enum><text>safeguards to protect the privacy of information that is submitted through or retained by a third-party agent approved under subparagraph (A), including employees and contractors of the third-party agent; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id458513E2822A4C1698505F2A520168BC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>such other rules and standards of data security as the Secretary determines to be appropriate to carry out this subsection.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idADFE2CFBD3F043CAAC3758C53D0FE13F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The Secretary shall establish penalties for any violations of privacy or confidentiality under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id74198A155207436DB9C88D3E59038DD9"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Disclosure of information</header><clause id="id3C9872EB22EB4ADABBF7CC85F7924CCA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Public disclosure</header><text>Information collected for purposes of services provided under subparagraph (A) may be disclosed to the public—</text><subclause id="id4038D014510841E7A529FCA13D74B132"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if the information is transformed into a statistical or aggregate form such that the information does not include any identifiable or personal information of individual producers; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id707F3795216349C48D574E82C5FC219C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in a form that may include identifiable or personal information of a producer only if that producer consents to the disclosure of the information.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id0532eef5a0ad4f108c7140cb573e805a"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Research, audit, and program improvement</header><text>Information collected for the purposes of services provided under subparagraph (A) may be disclosed for the purposes of providing technical assistance, including audit, research, or improvement of a program under this section, either in aggregate or in a form that includes identifiable or personal information of a producer, if the Secretary obtains adequate assurances that—</text><subclause id="ide5d89a4a634a4b69862648ac07d57aff"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the recipient shall ensure privacy safeguards of identifiable or personal information of a producer; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id9cccb67f5d404df68cf33dccc847551b"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the release of any data to the public will only occur only if the data has been transformed into a statistical or aggregate form.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idC62B149D9F45437ABC32C0B2779C2B0B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than July 1, 2026, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations to carry out this section, including—</text><paragraph id="id8E45A1E0D7F742FA976E63B34147F338"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the amount of a payment under subsection (c), which shall be based on—</text><subparagraph id="id95618122CEB84505A184C81B8C5DFFFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the quantity of CO<subscript>2</subscript>-e reduced; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBFEA7BE4E715430FA6A6BF50453A0BF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the considerations described in subsection (c)(3);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idDE95A487D8C84CEC80C0E27ADEACED06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a methodology that any third-party agents approved under subsection (d)(4)(A)(ii) shall use to provide the services under that subsection, including—</text><subparagraph id="id645B35B14356457183F48ADA71BD8950"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an accreditation process; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD06FB3840C2F4256876578985E8028B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a conflict of interest policy; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9B5B8A6D529F480EAC60160C9B5E64E4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provisions for the ownership and transportability of data, including historical data, generated by an eligible producer for the purpose of determining eligibility for payments under the program.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idB4C3B2018FA04C4D8B9C5D9EAB778133"><enum>7.</enum><header>Transition assistance for impacted communities</header><subsection id="id9D661E57E4644BE79B3C378B5353B4C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="idd040cbe360a1426fb0c574fa66e4ffc1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id369D479D558C431CB786DC73BCFAF060"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individual with a barrier to employment</header><text>The term <term>individual with a barrier to employment</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE9CE6440F0F247AEBDF126DA763FA118"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8BF3498ECC224E23983D7D66F09E2957"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Local board</header><text>The term <term>local board</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id74388AD7FD6F467FB83BA3EE34D16B36"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Recognized postsecondary credential</header><text>The term <term>recognized postsecondary credential</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idC9A51412810449FE97D01293031C9381"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Economic Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE6D38E2DFEE1403A8DB0D5D548B3BD22"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="ID1AA0C8024B5B488EA17F81A36FBC1821"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID792A8B98FE9C42679797E3F1D68FC25F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the District of Columbia;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID28D43A31F3264D79A65D4436F400AF2F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID4912258B462B4AAD8DC29F5610699D3D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other territory or possession of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id88A500BE0FC74EE88283AE3E812D7151"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State board</header><text>The term <term>State board</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id86719E8C34954FCBA2D94B6BCE4F90F4"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Supportive services</header><text>The term <term>supportive services</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4A72ADA90838412DB959AAF1AD844A91"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Labor, shall provide grants to eligible entities to assist in the transition to a low- or zero-greenhouse gas emitting economy.</text></subsection><subsection id="id22D04B1F04CE4ABAA7DD184F1CE593E7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>An entity eligible to receive a grant under this section is a labor organization, an institution of higher education, a unit of State or local government, an Indian Tribe, an economic development organization, a nonprofit organization, community-based organization, or intermediary, or a State board or local board that serves or is located in a community that—</text><paragraph id="id15BCDD1161694680959A8C1DED2F8C99"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as determined by the Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Labor, has been or will be impacted by economic changes in carbon-intensive industries, including in an energy community (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45">section 45(b)(11)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2EB4F19D74AD4D4395D8D703E6B5E0AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, has been or is at risk of being impacted by extreme weather events, sea level rise, and natural disasters related to climate change; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id19327BA901E74FBE96F1FA8EC5B8810C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>as determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, has been impacted by harmful residuals from a fossil fuel or carbon-intensive industry.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2FEFA13A754C4BB78559CD6F5FC98405"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant for—</text><paragraph id="idA7C2DCC169EF4D8888018FF62DA1645C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>economic and workforce development activities, such as—</text><subparagraph id="id1418068F33CE4AD49F5D8599DF9E607D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>job creation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8713543F9B4F4D078F2204E46006D2B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing reemployment and worker transition assistance, including registered apprenticeships, subsidized employment, job training, transitional jobs, and supportive services, with priority given to—</text><clause id="idF070890AAFCA4212864471A66DCBB762"><enum>(i)</enum><text>workers impacted by changes in carbon-intensive industries;</text></clause><clause id="idCEBD0697C0AA48B68EFD98209E642FB5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>individuals with a barrier to employment; and</text></clause><clause id="id9EF7F426FA664E0AA3D705B3A3DE2AC9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>programs that lead to a recognized postsecondary credential;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBEC75086A7BB458BBF4E63276AB32BD4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>local and regional investment, including commercial and industrial economic diversification;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAD6F8689B2ED44BD890CAD9B43975A14"><enum>(D)</enum><text>export promotion; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4BBD536FFAE449B78EB80FD783EBD4C1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>establishment of a monthly subsidy payment for workers who retire early due to economic changes in carbon-intensive industries;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id696B8D3161014723B4BC7867CF1CCE14"><enum>(2)</enum><text>climate change resiliency, such as—</text><subparagraph id="id683D65EBD30E4D5F86952FBFEA5C53B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>building electrical, communications, utility, transportation, and other infrastructure in flood-prone areas above flood zone levels;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id21D9ACABD50A415BBCFF5C6E5B2E96F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>building flood and stormproofing measures in flood-prone areas and erosion-prone areas;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id720503CFD0884DA090E8337C85722129"><enum>(C)</enum><text>increasing the resilience of a surface transportation infrastructure asset to withstand extreme weather events and climate change impacts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9764596BC8DA485E93FA4B9C4C2EA489"><enum>(D)</enum><text>improving stormwater infrastructure;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8FE2378914A54EC1A88C6E22A367F9F4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>increasing the resilience of agriculture to extreme weather;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC62E90337E13416AA813AC8797330338"><enum>(F)</enum><text>ecological restoration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id313B16E672BF48D4811FD83E202C6FB4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>increasing the resilience of forests to wildfires;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id85189778DE0042D686BA4A68DDCF9C2F"><enum>(H)</enum><text>increasing coastal resilience; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBAD76096BC8C4FB4A553A5E34A6F92E5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>implementing heat island cooling strategies;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idCF5E57791C184E6FB9D36AE84528FEE2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>environmental remediation and restoration projects of fossil fuel industry facilities that are abandoned or retired, or closed due to bankruptcy, and residuals from carbon-intensive industries, such as—</text><subparagraph id="id2003592F7C054E5BB1C682FE4511406B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coal ash and petroleum coke cleanup;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id490D0C5DCB624E32A575733BA404FC0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mine reclamation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE99E5EEF60E2466B9CF791A0FF17FFFD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reclamation and plugging of abandoned oil and natural gas wells on private and public land; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id883D296937904213B74BFA0561F5327D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>remediation of impaired waterways and drinking water resources; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idD6625B4567034A418218BF6E6BB8BF6C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>other activities as the Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Labor, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, determines to be appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7E82BDDB28E247D5BBB469D936D2291C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Requirements</header><paragraph id="idDDF647A65F204B15AB1160FBF6C1284A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Labor standards; nondiscrimination</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall use the funds in a manner consistent with sections 181 and 188 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3241">29 U.S.C. 3241</external-xref>, 3248).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4ca67e087c0c4cc7baa0457a1156860e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Wage rate requirements</header><subparagraph id="id7454ABC5CB20493CBCE30EEC60A2F601"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All laborers and mechanics employed by eligible entities to carry out projects and activities funded directly by or assisted in whole or in part by a grant under this section shall be paid at wages at rates not less than those prevailing on projects of a similar character in the locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Davis-Bacon Act</quote>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id777934fc3d7740b6a3d726e1960f4cf3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>With respect to the labor standards specified in subparagraph (A), the Secretary of Labor shall have the authority and functions set forth in Reorganization Plan No. 14 of 1950 (64 Stat. 1267; 5 U.S.C. App.) and section 3145 of title 40, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7c2ea5517e3048bdbbec14b7af87ffe5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Buy America requirements</header><subparagraph id="id4c471f9c22a64328b45d2fce22558b66"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All iron, steel, and manufactured goods used for projects and activities carried out with a grant under this section shall be produced in the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id17918b3ea59f492e97d1badb7745a89e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary may waive the requirement in subparagraph (A) if the Secretary finds that—</text><clause id="id8c7dcef0c8164a9fa908f3dcbfaba1d1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enforcing the requirement would be inconsistent with the public interest;</text></clause><clause id="id6d140ba87c4f428eb37f268d683fb0b9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the iron, steel, and manufactured goods produced in the United States are not produced in a sufficient and reasonably available amount or are not of a satisfactory quality; or</text></clause><clause id="id947b6ff4e4924e61b114d20d6916f868"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>enforcing the requirement will increase the overall cost of the project or activity by more than 25 percent.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id463E43951A2C469D92D49C1EE6F46B4D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section is encouraged to collaborate or partner with other eligible entities and impacted communities in planning and carrying out activities with that grant.</text></subsection><subsection id="id98C82CB5C6454BA0A290BC625CE6202B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date on which the Secretary establishes the grant program under this section, the Secretary and the Secretary of Labor shall submit to Congress a report on the effectiveness of the grant program, including—</text><paragraph id="id0B1AD8E9868D4D84B905EC4D707F6A36"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of individuals that have received reemployment or worker transition assistance under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id18608597797743519C2589365C93321D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of any job creation activities carried out with a grant under this section and the number of jobs created from those activities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2F613A4D44CA4D628A3BD92AAA7E1A0C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the percentage of individuals that have received reemployment or worker transition assistance under this section who are, during the second and fourth quarters after exiting the program—</text><subparagraph id="id8CC86F82F7EF4BAEA21E5E3C16E62B96"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in education or training activities; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id724D85CE23D84E1DA92087E7180C30D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>employed;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6EA0DEAC1B2847CDAF1ED2C25466A61A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the average wages of individuals that have received reemployment or worker transition assistance under this section during the second and fourth quarters after exit from the program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1AC3EECDA7B64F85A7833D02383AB900"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a description of any regional investment activities carried out with a grant under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id141DCA9D2CE14236B6FB25C8E9F34938"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a description of any export promotion activities carried out with a grant under this section, including—</text><subparagraph id="idA976B23E72E8467E88F19452E37DC74B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the products promoted; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC4D849D2A5BE4E1D8F92C3172F762F98"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an analysis of any increase in exports as a result of the promotion;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idE3EC067AC1204408B599F08FF36425AA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a description of any resilience activities carried out with a grant under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE57096F86BDE40479D2DCF3DF1E2F9F0"><enum>(8)</enum><text>a description of any cleanup activities from fossil fuel industry facilities or carbon-intensive industries carried out with a grant under this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB77A0B60E2184BF8A91E4C13CDB412FF"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the distribution of funding among geographic and socioeconomic groups, including urban and rural communities, low-income communities, communities of color, and Indian Tribes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0B447DD7EDB64C739350989DA14503D1"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Funding</header><paragraph id="id946E8AD7C52C4F77B12FB3B6E75BB248"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial funding</header><text>There is appropriated to the Secretary, out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $5,000,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 and 2027 to carry out this section, to remain available until expended.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id019B59B2778B4231987903A433231170"><enum>(2)</enum><header>America's Clean Future Fund</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out this section using amounts made available from the America's Clean Future Fund under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9512">section 9512</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added by section 4).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id19b4bf25776c47d3a27851727c494731"><enum>8.</enum><header>Study on carbon pricing</header><subsection id="id1827addd449b4bf4bb87b2655dc03c9c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2029, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (referred to in this section as the <quote>Administrator</quote>) shall seek to enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences under which the National Academy of Sciences shall carry out a study not less frequently than once every 5 years to evaluate the effectiveness of the fees established under sections 4692 and 4693 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 in achieving the following goals:</text><paragraph id="ide464dcb22e484d03918f4a8eb7af5977"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A net reduction of greenhouse gas emissions by 45 percent, based on 2018 levels, by 2030.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6e4e65455aa446869285c85ca67adfd3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A net reduction of greenhouse gas emissions by 100 percent, based on 2018 levels, by 2050.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id93b2b13d289141f1bb223460c62deb17"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In executing the agreement under subsection (a), the Administrator shall ensure that, in carrying out a study under that subsection, the National Academy of Sciences—</text><paragraph id="id422013aadc844438aeb2fece6e2267d5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>includes an evaluation of—</text><subparagraph id="idc0d2add87b8e47f680ba1436659f2d0e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>total annual greenhouse gas emissions by the United States, including greenhouse gas emissions not subject to the fees described in that subsection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id43afaf83b0d344d59f58d7e6175663f8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the historic trends in the total greenhouse gas emissions evaluated under subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9e6961ccc59e40dbb5186fc971195355"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the impacts of the fees established under sections 4692 and 4693 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 on changes in the levels of fossil fuel-related localized air pollutants in environmental justice communities (as defined in section 2(e)(1));</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idda64ec5b38724c0fbe6722e1ac4af82b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>analyzes the extent to which greenhouse gas emissions have been or would be reduced as a result of current and potential future policies, including—</text><subparagraph id="id0c516964035b43e8afc7a3bb646e225a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a projection of greenhouse gas emissions reductions that would result if the regulations of the Administrator were to be adjusted to impose stricter limits on greenhouse gas emissions than the goals described in that subsection, with a particular focus on greenhouse gas emissions not subject to the fees described in that subsection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id87e9bdb26bcc4c3682c27c99df470346"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the status of greenhouse gas emissions reductions that result from the fees established under sections 4692 and 4693 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0d838f9034e44cb9835dc41fdf742517"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a projection of greenhouse gas emissions reductions that would result if the fees established under those sections were annually increased—</text><clause id="id4a8f37d975f241849ad9d31e42d74a1a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at the current price path; and</text></clause><clause id="ida6c1689c00f34f5090732c2ddf20a316"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>above the current price path;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id68089f091c91467ea1ad711271e038b0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an analysis of greenhouse gas emissions reductions that result from the policies of States, units of local government, Tribal communities, and the private sector; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id651474ee0bcb475b8784e7341403afa9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the status and projections of decarbonization in other major economies; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide0d9df5fbbf24d7691e45307e7f698cd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>submits a report to the Administrator, Congress, and the Board of Directors of the Climate Change Finance Corporation describing the results of the study.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idb1d5b7a8c4ad48eabfd1a0833b0f39a3"><enum>9.</enum><header>Establishment of targets for carbon sequestration by land and water</header><subsection id="id7ddb8715ee114c24b9ed6786d81a045d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality, in consultation with the Secretaries of Agriculture, Commerce, and the Interior, the Chief of Engineers, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall—</text><paragraph id="id1454fea30fa04bfcb53bf412efff5955"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish a target for carbon sequestration that can reasonably be achieved through enhancing the ability of public and private land and water to function as natural carbon sinks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0c44839b4fe64dff9f11b9acf55b7b5e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop strategies for meeting that target; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb2ca155cb2f04bd9b9afd6723163b666"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop strategies to expand protections for ecosystems that sequester carbon and provide resiliency benefits, such as—</text><subparagraph id="ideebf95c83afc49a5973b939aa5cdb430"><enum>(A)</enum><text>flood protection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id85657f09244f4b6bb605e8f7acf4f658"><enum>(B)</enum><text>soil and beach retention;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id45240d5f066646479862aa1134b4a6e5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>erosion reduction;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8ac10b21806145d08aefb5f78e92cd9c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>biodiversity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb87e10b591194053a3e8e3710a761ea8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>water purification; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idded27b5d2de04135a45f184ec4a98acc"><enum>(F)</enum><text>nutrient cycling.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddb124effab8141b6b106a712b16a6443"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality shall submit to Congress a report describing—</text><paragraph id="ida6080d15f6ed49eda386cd17f873ee98"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the target and strategies described in paragraphs (1) through (3) of subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddfbeb70f5cbe4b3d9afd26065ee9f09b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any additional statutory authorities or authorized funding levels needed to successfully implement those strategies.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


