<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H53916876856E47FAA28CAFAD832F0A92" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>109 HR 1114 IH: L’Ouverture Economic Development Plan for Haiti Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1114</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250207">February 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the establishment of a Haitian American Enterprise Fund for Haiti, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFA2B5C940DD9433A829E9C0B502E379C" style="OLC"><section id="HB65BE9D9CC0142D8BEA606000DBD0091" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>L’Ouverture Economic Development Plan for Haiti Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE369E952E62E45E7920830C1F6EC34F7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HC9A69EB8F833425893EB7EF1ACFE91E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The General Secretariat of the Organization of the American States stated in 2022, <quote>The international community, international financial institutions, the multilateral system, and the international financial community of donor countries must make a decision: whether they want to industrialize Haiti sufficiently to ensure work for nine million Haitians, or whether it is economically more profitable to continue absorbing Haitian migrants and let host countries accommodate them as and how they can and in such economic conditions as they can offer.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76E55B153E4A462D919F40F65CA342F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Rather than building upon the ongoing lucrative trade relations with a newly independent Republic of Haiti in 1804, the United States decided to impose a trade embargo on the nascent state in 1806 because Haiti’s independence ended chattel slavery in its land and perceived it as a threat because it became the world’s first Black republic.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H992188E07C9F4703B51E4D4E73C9D46F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>After its independence, Haiti was made to pay an indemnity to France, its former colonial power, beginning in 1825, for breaking away from slavery, which amounts to at least $21,000,000,000 today, setting the stage for Haiti’s dire impoverishment today.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF392308407284A7C984C4FFD3B275EED"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Haiti’s independence from France in 1804 directly resulted in France selling the bulk of its possessions in mainland North America in what became the Louisiana Purchase, fueling the westward expansion of the young United States to the Pacific Ocean in what is today States such as Arkansas, Colorado, Iowa, Louisiana, Kansas, Montana, Missouri, and Nebraska.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD108E142E1244481A67136F2A024F347"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Despite a tortured relationship, Haiti has long been a reliable partner of the United States. For example, after the bombing of Pearl Harbor in 1941, Haiti was among the first nations to join the United States in World War II and contributed funds to the United States effort.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD00EF33E79AD4CECBC570C0034A48D16"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Haiti bears a strategic importance to the United States due to its location in the Western Hemisphere.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H23C836D7D9A24BAABC4FA104C19CE779"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Haitian Americans continue to make important contributions to the United States economy and have played a significant role in education, health care, literature, politics, art, and culture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE53CDDC2F905461DB071EF25BBFDD05A"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau of the Census estimates that the Haitian-American population is 1.2 million, which many believe may be severely undercounted, as persons of Haitian descent have been coming to the United States since prior to the founding of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB38B3446CF7D44BFB5A22F832003E953"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Haitian American population plays a vital role in Haiti’s development efforts, leveraging their resources, expertise, and networks to support education, technology, sustainable development, resilience, and prosperity in the country and could do much more in partnership with the United States Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8A284B62075469AAE4E32101D6CB18D"><enum>(10)</enum><text>According to the World Bank, the Haitian diaspora sent over $4,000,000,000 in remittances to Haiti in 2023, equaling more than one-fifth of the country’s gross domestic product with these remittances having a crucial role in Haiti’s economy, providing a steady source of income for families in Haiti, contributing to poverty reduction, amounting to more than the sum of yearly foreign assistance to the country.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17F7AC906F0D4CB1A0D9CA15F4738C4F"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Haiti has played a pivotal role in Afro-descendants’ struggle for American values such as freedom in America, the Caribbean, and African countries, including the Haitian American leaders such as W.E.B. DuBois, cofounder of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, who have contributed to the Civil Rights movement in the United States and across the world.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF688671DAC77492AB3F67B40D5495E8A"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Assisting Haiti with a well-processed development program leading to sustainable economic development that keeps Haitians at home is in the vital interest of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A814C3EAB984A609F2A666171CC0F84"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The United States should assist Haiti in establishing sustainable inclusive development to meet the needs of all of its people, instead of being drawn to the lure of debt-trap driven development promoted by the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15DDBEFCB8F04C39B3BC3958C4E4DC1B"><enum>(14)</enum><text>According to the United Nations Conference on Trade and Development, Haiti will need, at minimum, an estimate of $19,300,000,000 (in 2020/2021 dollars) to meet key development metrics including to—</text><subparagraph id="H2A369B57A95945548FBC28740CBAB8FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>achieve 7 percent annual GDP growth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB60E187A27324BDC95C1D2B7F9DCAA10"><enum>(B)</enum><text>eliminate extreme poverty;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F1480064BE34A58BD70BDBE15C64FCC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>double manufacturing growth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8F850FFCC04483BAD9B7B27CD40AA82"><enum>(D)</enum><text>improve health and well-being;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFC45A939CC648ECB90AAE2E449CBFF2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>improve quality primary and secondary formal education leading to relevant and effective learning outcomes; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F5D0F2BE17F4147B171981DA6371AB1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>protect environmental biodiversity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H7D28CD50EF7548668AB170FAFC43FE39"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are to promote and facilitate—</text><paragraph id="H0908C658E14C4B29983D46E4FB5C95A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>development of the Haitian private sector, particularly micro, small, and medium businesses, the agriculture, biodiversity, construction, energy, finance, manufacturing, and tourism industries, and U.S.-Haitian joint ventures, including the Haitian-American diaspora;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD29D2371F2424AA9B26FB1B0BE34CCF3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>policies and practices conducive to Haitian private sector development through equity investments, feasibility studies, grants, guarantees, insurance, loans, technical assistance, and training;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C35E4CD2EC242CE983A53618FA6EE19"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an economic environment conducive for an accountable, transparent, and sustained democratic system of governance in Haiti, inclusive for its people, in coordination with the Global Fragility Act of 2019 (section 501 of title V of division J of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/94">Public Law 116–94</external-xref>; Stat. 3060); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB0A7F919E8946A39FEB548C9392566C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>policies that engender conditions for an industrialized Haiti sufficient to ensure work at full employment levels meeting United Nations medium to high human development from human development index indicators for the people of Haiti, thereby reducing irregular migration flows from the country, a United States national security concern.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H6306C1BF6E794D07B5A3B1BCDB859D2C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Statements of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to support the sustainable rebuilding and development of Haiti in a manner that—</text><paragraph id="H24C3F12408004390BD0A6DC40457500E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes that the United States has longstanding historical, economic, and cultural ties to Haiti, with millions of Americans tracing their heritage to the country, and has a vested interest in Haiti’s stability and development;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BB7FE75E6524EBD87B45CBFD9CC3407"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes Haitian independence, self-reliance, and sovereignty;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7A0A68E2D4B4D219C36B0AC6F8C7A86"><enum>(3)</enum><text>acknowledges that it is in the United States national and regional security interest to assist a stable, democratic and prosperous Haiti that will consequently reduce irregular migration, regional crime, narcotics proliferation, and insecurity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB02A5C2340D4D5E93822A958E1FF7CF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports the restoration of democratic governance in Haiti through free, fair, and transparent elections as an essential condition for reestablishing lasting security, economic development, and the national interests of Haiti and the United States by—</text><subparagraph id="H56E0B99BD3BE42968B9138B89B571A85"><enum>(A)</enum><text>supporting the self-determination of the Haitian people and recognizing that the sovereign and national right of the citizens of Haiti must be exercised free of interference;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B370C17073247A38EC76A1CF03F8EAC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>acknowledging that any political transition must come from a Haitian-led solution; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04EB0062839645F6AF02108B5D4D4556"><enum>(C)</enum><text>opposing any efforts to destabilize the state of Haiti;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H75D36A9C46004DAE8CDB5BF97A6BA13B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supports democratic transition, the strengthening of institutions, good governance, and the rule of law in Haiti by—</text><subparagraph id="H2143D5ACF4E34D3AA2F4FF1E0A0F432F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assisting in strengthening Haiti’s institutions, judiciary system, governance structures and mechanisms to better respond to the needs of Haitians;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6118B0F07254A66A2447B8ADD09D934"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supporting anticorruption efforts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20233B30021D48EDA458A312E16C76C1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promoting press freedom;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDD2885C5F08445287A84879AF2037F4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>supporting the empowerment of Haitian civil society;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF48FC9B73FE8445EB6CBBBA18758FAA0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>improving transparency and the independence of the media;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A08E052D5884AF0B74E89E4ED843B32"><enum>(F)</enum><text>preventing favorable treatment or influence on behalf of any individual, entity, or party in the selection by the Haitian people of their future government; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98B64AA75BC64389A76C3DEB964200A6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>reducing violence against women and children and addressing human rights concerns, including through the enforcement of sanctions imposed in accordance with the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656">22 U.S.C. 2656</external-xref> note) on individuals implicated in human rights violations and corruption;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H629AE56EA29140AB981CC5CE63166648"><enum>(6)</enum><text>improves Haiti’s security by—</text><subparagraph id="HCF61104699444A3A84F42654067BE62C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>supporting the goals of the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability 10-Year Plan for Haiti report, a derivative of the Global Fragility Act of 2019;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37F933581FCF4564BD84BF64EA3422F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supporting continued funding of the Haitian National Police;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B89D1828C9B427A99B5038150E7FDB1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>supporting Haiti’s and international efforts to assist the Haitian National Police in combating internal insecurity, including gang violence;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H021AACAF4178457498D11D246537F0CD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>stemming the flow of illicit firearms trafficking from the United States to the Caribbean, including Haiti;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B45CE8684714D94B53783B2735A7DF7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>encouraging the development of civilian oversight of the Haitian National Police;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D5C881A9DB04504823E2E4A5B2770EB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>encouraging the Haitian National Police to respect human rights and uphold anti-corruption measures in its practices; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED6A4CDA889548A8B242E55454DC1D34"><enum>(G)</enum><text>encouraging a Disarmaments, Demobilization, and Reinsertion program to reduce criminality and protect the youth;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BCB6099AA624B9B98973FAB1812A568"><enum>(7)</enum><text>addresses humanitarian needs by providing appropriate forms of assistance, such as humanitarian assistance, to the people of Haiti by addressing urgent food security, health, and education needs as well as protecting women and children;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H54399CE2469F41DDA3D56410EB701201"><enum>(8)</enum><text>spurs economic development by—</text><subparagraph id="H3EF5A87201214278B093603451EF545E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>leveraging public and private source funding to address Haiti’s long term development goal and achieving United Nations Sustainable Development Goals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87C762108F4B40A0B0AEA33F71755B78"><enum>(B)</enum><text>helping, creating, and enabling an environment that facilitates trade and investment in Haiti;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE9FDE9030784ECF9FC575488BDE051E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assisting in building the resilient and supportive physical infrastructure sector required for a stable and prosperous country, including country-wide access to reliable electricity, passable roads, ports, railroads, water, sanitation and health programs and digital infrastructure;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FD093A742C64986A195EF01ED0DD0BC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>reducing poverty and building prosperity by providing capacity building support to promote entrepreneurship and support small and medium-sized enterprises, including participation of Haitian women and youth in governmental and nongovernmental institutions and in economic development and governance assistance programs funded by the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CDD17A967374125A00758C5ED70D6E3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>supporting trade preferences with Haiti, including the preferences created through the Haitian Hemispheric Opportunity Through Partnership Act of 2006 (title V of division D of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/432">Public Law 109–432</external-xref>; 120 Stat. 3181) and the Haiti Economic Lift Program Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2703">19 U.S.C. 2703 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB333EEAE680492FA90755544812DF3C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>assisting in building the long-term capacity of the Government of Haiti, civil society, local resource mobilization in Haiti, and the private sector to foster economic opportunities in Haiti; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F7025BA6C8546DA9BBCE676CF58CAF0"><enum>(G)</enum><text>fostering collaboration and activities between the Haitian diaspora in the United States, including dual citizens of Haiti and the United States, and the Government of Haiti, local resource mobilization in Haiti, and the business community in Haiti;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC02FE7033674DED93CF0BF5C8F8B782"><enum>(9)</enum><text>encourages other countries, along with bilateral and multilateral organizations, to provide similar assistance and to work cooperatively with such countries and organizations to coordinate such assistance; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE84837218157402F912822D2414B0004"><enum>(10)</enum><text>respects and helps restore the natural resources of Haiti and strengthens community-level resilience to environmental and weather-related impacts.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H8018DDF508ED4AA68369330C92BEC61E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Haitian American Enterprise Fund for Haiti</header><subsection id="H92B6152A0B1E40ACA192431C6FF1277C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may designate a private, nonprofit organization (as described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such code) as the Haitian American Enterprise Fund for Haiti (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Enterprise Fund</quote>), if the President—</text><paragraph id="HB47AD3EDCE1C481C86CD324F5A96D83C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determines that such organization has the ability to carry out the activities described in section 7; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01F66E40287A42668C701D7C0ACB6EC1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has consulted with the Speaker and the minority leader of the House of Representatives and the majority leader and the minority leader of the Senate regarding such designation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2484A616F322475CA4496A22C9F64D42"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Operation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the designation of the Enterprise Fund under subsection (a), the Chief Executive Officer of the United States International Development Finance Corporation shall operate such Fund.</text></subsection><subsection id="H44E0FCC4C75042EA9AF819D60745178A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief Executive Officer may consult and coordinate with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development regarding the Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCFC85048156F49CD9D76288A8A3D7E16"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Private character of Enterprise Fund</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to make—</text><paragraph id="H73BC425E84FB440EA792B095E74F8D94"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Enterprise Fund an agency or establishment of the United States Government; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28DCBBB09324458D97A1AE2E90928649"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the officers and employees of the Enterprise Fund or members of the Oversight Panel officers or employees of the United States for purposes of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HECE2A28A27A241A0AE261CEDE731023D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Oversight Panel</header><subsection id="H748CA226E02344CDB4CAAB02D4A4A239"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Enterprise Fund shall be monitored by a Board of Directors Oversight Panel (hereafter referred to as the <quote>Oversight Panel</quote>) composed of 9 members.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAB9D608A429547B1AA237C45D2300FD7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Composition</header><paragraph id="HA1DBC8A346634DB8A0FCB6F77A21B169"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointments by Chief Executive Officer</header><text>The Chief Executive Officer shall appoint to the Oversight Panel—</text><subparagraph id="H0224832EE3804E23A3D431B6C9A702D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>5 individuals who are not employed by the Federal Government and—</text><clause id="H6D6E793A321E4428A0D089A8AD6C4297"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are citizens of the United States; or</text></clause><clause id="HC7BD1D9E59FA4DC6A14F2DDCEBD70576"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are citizens of the Republic of Haiti who—</text><subclause id="H4B2EB551A5934BE1985B0A5350C13B23"><enum>(I)</enum><text>primarily reside in the United States; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H3453C177093D4094AC673B213A2008CC"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have demonstrated respect for democracy and a free-market economy; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E2865A3B67B41018E4620AC9745900F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>2 individuals who are citizens of Haiti who—</text><clause id="H1BF8C8D432D74CE4B76BC0A997DAE6FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are not citizens of the United States;</text></clause><clause id="H1048D782ECF04A3CB72F344665884BB3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have demonstrated respect for democracy and a free-market economy; and</text></clause><clause id="H15259DAC611046DD9FD298BEDE560784"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>have—</text><subclause id="HB8F57367F8A9416F9A1936617CA0C088" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>had a successful business career in private equity, banking, or finance in a developing economy; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H33F580FBECFB412A8D1A84EEF668D2C4" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>experience comparable to service on the board of directors of a fund that is similar to the Enterprise Fund and which earned a positive return on the amounts under the control of such fund.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7108F66F726B463EAC0DA419449765DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appointments by President</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall appoint to the Oversight Panel 2 individuals who are citizens of the United States, who—</text><subparagraph id="HF607BDC1AC6643FBADED2604037652FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>primarily reside in the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9A2CAFCC92B47BF8620284CD7BB9A84"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have demonstrated concern for and commitment to the economic development of Haiti.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD3D9C50CF6604E6986F5E784631EC376" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultations</header><text>The Chief Executive Officer and members of the Oversight Panel are encouraged to consult extensively with—</text><paragraph id="H891C028C57204599BE1C4074F7D6F410" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>representatives of similar enterprise funds established by the United States Government, in order to learn best practices relating to the start-up phase and ongoing business of an enterprise fund;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39178A50CBA64CF9BC439727CC2A47E3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">representatives of multilateral institutions, including the Inter-American Development Bank, the World Bank, and the International Monetary Fund, to coordinate support for infrastructure in Haiti; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD30D3CE9DB2348A9939697188109A4C2" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">leaders from the private sector, civil society, labor organizations, human rights groups, academia, and environmental organizations in the United States and Haiti. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDCCB773426394DC58BD148672C399C2C"><enum>7.</enum><header>Investments for certain programs and projects</header><subsection id="H578D39F84EA84CD7A4530AF7528BBCA7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements for investments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Enterprise Fund may only provide investments in programs and projects that—</text><paragraph id="HF715EB0EEA0148A09F29599129316787"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote development of the Haitian private sector, particularly with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="HB9BB4BBAD18F48FE9D50EF7B1E0DF8E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>micro, small, and medium businesses;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A594AF882BE44CB8232109FE11B2477"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the agriculture, biodiversity, construction, energy, finance, manufacturing, and tourism industries; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H627BEF12133A49E895E609ABAEFA1FE6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>joint ventures between the United States and Haiti or the Haitian-American diaspora, including joint ventures that empower women and youth;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H066ED559E6C64604B2D2018E9824D0A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>promote policies and practices that facilitate the development of the Haitian private sector through—</text><subparagraph id="H400E5D611FEA41E19184ADC1F73EF2E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>equity investments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4306FB522214BD0B113B30FA78B6B6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>feasibility studies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AE23992E2BF4504AE2151C95FCE2B00"><enum>(C)</enum><text>grants;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F103708ABFF4213B860C57E98358A05"><enum>(D)</enum><text>guarantees;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H940ACA97BF4049C88B389B0138C6DA18"><enum>(E)</enum><text>insurance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H183371D036164D37B5A34B939C06C132"><enum>(F)</enum><text>loans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H001DF12E0BA941EC94D924271F23F39E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>technical assistance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3786B8D2F144DF5BF786223CE1B7143"><enum>(H)</enum><text>training;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H78352C0651AF4F46AF5C5739A070943F" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>facilitate an economic environment conducive for an accountable, transparent, and sustained democratic system of governance in Haiti, aligned with the Global Fragility Strategy required in section 504(a) of the Global Fragility Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9803">22 U.S.C. 9803(a)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A08FAC69C7F44A883AD0814AC705585"><enum>(4)</enum><text>build the resilient physical infrastructure required for Haiti to be stable and prosperous, including—</text><subparagraph id="H77B5FA7A32CD434A85BA33EA098227BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>country-wide access to reliable electricity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25B79CA4D7A941639889E38F11434EFA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>electricity generation plants;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95C631107CEC44B09F86585C675102E5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>passable roads and bridges;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58FB7EFDEDB5436CAB9BAF7B8E4E376D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ports;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDBCCE540B3C44ACBA4B384C8D8CF158"><enum>(E)</enum><text>railroads;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD23A782A51564121BFB20A2B4C405558" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(F)</enum><text>hydrological dams;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC3A57271FEE4CB3BA20F7A54DCBB0AF"><enum>(G)</enum><text>agriculture canals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57BD26BC8E4541909AFBFEE72FE9CBBC"><enum>(H)</enum><text>storm water management systems; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DF36513AC974EBAAC96FB6D32267277"><enum>(I)</enum><text>water infrastructure; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30EF45341EFF42EA8EDADD3204C041E3"><enum>(J)</enum><text>sanitation and health programs and infrastructure; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H731879DB3FC6409889560596AEA91192"><enum>(5)</enum><text>create a report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H32A4164B0311486D8A05EDB1E0D200DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the cost to update the physical infrastructure described in paragraph (4) in Haiti to meet resilience standards; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF48F5B4AB74243E8978ED988022F5C75"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an analysis of completed physical infrastructure projects;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H643B2CFC6E044D8A97C7B4F82AD07333"><enum>(6)</enum><text>assist in leveraging public and private funding to address development needs in Haiti; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H199D776AB207453195CABB559CF7BDD2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>engender conditions for development and industrialization, create sustainable jobs, or reduce the root cause of irregular migrations in Haiti.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H080C4ACD4DD647F3B78CF33AA377CAC0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorized activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Enterprise Fund may make investments in and encourage—</text><paragraph id="HACF07C4BA4F94B82AE839610F6727284"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increased access to consumer credit in Haiti, including from consumer credit unions (also known as <quote>caisse populaires</quote>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2157FEF2C35A42A7984232E285CC75C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the establishment of local agriculture cooperatives in Haiti;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46070DE5BCBF4C1CAC680ABC0C06E6BD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the establishment of major electricity generation facilities and complementary regional and national electricity grids in Haiti;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7AD87C8A676A454A91879B01E7B87D10"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the establishment of working global manufacturing facilities, including facilities manufacturing—</text><subparagraph id="H51C27EB9BD3B4221BAF0D4376DD99878"><enum>(A)</enum><text>food;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD96A5C1EC5E4C4FB6529F21DF2B847C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>beverages;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB425794F43B40CDA816547A5FE7CD3C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>tobacco;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9601EA06372949D9A24E843AF2297207"><enum>(D)</enum><text>chemicals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45326A430E0242A784133856F984CF56"><enum>(E)</enum><text>pharmaceuticals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4D52088A6EB4FEB911ADB526AE13512"><enum>(F)</enum><text>electronics;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H726A13224AEF4B099A2B49482EC9B233"><enum>(G)</enum><text>optical products;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBAB945C70D474C07AD306DAD47920723"><enum>(H)</enum><text>textiles;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C8171AF3FE04E7DBF77315977B12B8E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>apparel; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AF3FFEF763D4CAFAF8E20F8D3EB2516"><enum>(J)</enum><text>leather;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H40F6C7AD22784C6DAD5BDA755CB8C56C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>projects providing modern information technology infrastructure required to deliver and monitor development services to economically vulnerable populations in Haiti; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCDCA9FFEACB4007A59541F06B44921E"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">projects providing management and technical capacity training and development to promote private sector development, including training on effective management and governance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5E8C82FF26E246B6AED699AAE90A6311"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Financial instruments for investment in Haiti</header><paragraph id="H036E10D92C2D412E8D8322BCB9D6BB19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Enterprise Fund shall, if practicable, establish financial instruments to enable individuals to invest in the Haitian private sector.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADD154AFE47F4DF4AC85124E6AF3015D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Preferred investments</header><text>If practicable, the financial instruments established under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H95A112A347AF45EFB1B3C7D5C7A60DF8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facilitate investment in projects that support development and humanitarian relief in Haiti; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1071F6A25604E4F8725C55F1A53D89D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>support Haitian businesses and employees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H99A4D604D60E4C8E97B18E046EAB14B3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Investment priority</header><text>In making investments under this section, the Enterprise Fund shall give priority to industries identified by the Government of Haiti as priorities for the economic recovery and growth of Haiti.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0249F7B3B70542BFA506E0907CFEA37F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Matters for consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Enterprise Fund shall take into account—</text><paragraph id="H8521C9BE544B4E6D83F1069D46AF3E9E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>internationally recognized human rights, including the rights of workers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A786E6F66C74379BA68264CA1217701"><enum>(2)</enum><text>environmental factors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA56583F19C1467A80345C0DD1E300D6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the effect of the activities of the Fund on the economy and labor market of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5122B17E1A6D49B38A4A6913BCA318E4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the likelihood that the activity receiving investments from the Enterprise Fund will be commercially viable.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1D2B5FCE6DD0498C8B1BB86B8A53E9C0"><enum>8.</enum><header>Administration of funds</header><subsection id="H56350CC0F066419081551CA9978703FF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Use of investment returns and payments</header><text>The Enterprise Fund may use returns on the investments of the Enterprise Fund and payments to the Enterprise Fund to provide the investments described in section 7, without transferring such returns or payments to the Treasury and without further appropriation by Congress.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0DD7C4C799B64C2C8F76D410FC774869"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ensuring ability To repay funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief Executive Officer shall provide investments in a manner that ensures that the Enterprise Fund will be able to repay the Treasury as required by section 11.</text></subsection><subsection id="H210727C03A7B4BA9837DEFC5465F9176"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of United States private venture capital</header><paragraph id="H85F0A2299582423C911CE6421E7D8E88" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Enterprise Fund may conduct public offerings or private placements for the purpose of soliciting and accepting United States venture capital, which may be used, separately or together with funds appropriated to the Enterprise Fund, for any lawful investment purpose that the Chief Executive Officer considers appropriate to carry out this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5F5FB4731314C4FBDC7BBB61F485A2C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No private investor oversight</header><text>Acceptance of private venture capital does not authorize private investors to have a role in the oversight of the Enterprise Fund.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDCEB9F523624FD792F31123C503BE55"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Distributions</header><text>Financial returns on Enterprise Fund investments that include private venture capital may be distributed, at such times and in such amounts as the Chief Executive Officer considers appropriate, to the investors of such capital.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCB9C090507F44650865EA521475FBD69"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitations</header><paragraph id="HC65FB28D5D30496FAC8A1C1F7D0836F3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payments to Enterprise Fund personnel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds of the Enterprise Fund shall inure to the benefit of any Oversight Panel member, officer, or employee of the Enterprise Fund, except as salary or reasonable compensation for services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9049F89D5BF84FBBBDDE868593CECE8F" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of Federal funds for grants</header><text>Not more than 20 percent of Federal funds made available to the Enterprise Fund may be used for investments in the form of grants. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94B9002BDFE2438DBA6C9E5B9E9F624E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of appropriated funds for costs and feasibility studies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not more than 15 percent, in total, of funds appropriated to the Enterprise Fund may be used for operating costs and feasibility studies to assess commercial viability of activities and projects funded by the Enterprise Fund.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H093AAD1C954F419F8CEE33C92EAADC02"><enum>9.</enum><header>Audits and recordkeeping</header><subsection id="H0F0D0790B08845DCAED5E930FBB24170"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Independent private audits</header><text>The Chief Executive Officer shall ensure that the Enterprise Fund is audited annually by an independent certified public accountant or independent licensed public accountant certified or licensed by a regulatory authority of a State or political subdivision of a State, in accordance with generally accepted auditing standards.</text></subsection><subsection id="H353795CC7C694778997BECDE16354E80"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Government Accountability Office audits</header><text>With respect to any year during which the Enterprise Fund is in possession of funds received from the United States Government, the Comptroller General of the United States shall audit the financial transactions of the Enterprise Fund to identify waste, fraud, or abuse, in accordance with such principles and procedures and under such rules and regulations as the Comptroller General may prescribe.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5327EBAF8704454EA6E54835E7B3F065"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recordkeeping requirements</header><text>The Chief Executive Officer shall ensure that—</text><paragraph id="H18674682FAD74A38BBE21B54C30994C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each recipient of funds provided by the Enterprise Fund under section 7 keeps—</text><subparagraph id="HD46A5A57ACC84A26959F3B9F565B8F17"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a separate account for such funds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80B0F5DFFAF74725B1C2421720D2BFD2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such records as may be reasonably necessary to fully disclose—</text><clause id="HF26A8242F3D54768A0DBD674AAF2E90E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of such funds;</text></clause><clause id="H1A0DC0C8D9F442628CFF04CA277D927D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the total amount of such funds received by such recipient;</text></clause><clause id="HF9ACF4927AEE4EAFB65843072AE1E1EF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the total cost of the project or activity for which the Enterprise Fund provided such funds; and</text></clause><clause id="HEC642D697243436EABE4FDA2D64FDC28"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the amount of the cost of the project or activity supplied by sources other than the Enterprise Fund; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H080EF9E137D24C24A48B4907982C4C0A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other records that will facilitate an effective audit; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C7A61A115E0453A97FA4EC6A72978BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Chief Executive Officer has access, for the purpose of audit and examination, to any record described in paragraph (1)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF3320BEF604F40C4831A96B3A712B1FE"><enum>10.</enum><header>Reports</header><subsection id="H1AEA06A2AD6E4BBF934D9E9702408B81"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public report on Enterprise Fund activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the establishment of the Enterprise Fund and annually thereafter until the Enterprise Fund terminates, the Chief Executive Officer shall make publicly available on the websites of the Enterprise Fund, the United States International Development Finance Corporation, and the United States Agency for International Development a report describing the funds provided by the Enterprise Fund for activities and projects described in section 7, with a written explanation of the commercial viability of each such activity and project.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB33F0065C69647819B971A80913FB0CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress on Enterprise Fund activities</header><paragraph id="H242A30F11F8B413DB785B872780C4ABD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the end of the fiscal year during which the Enterprise Fund is established and annually thereafter until the Enterprise Fund terminates, the Chief Executive Officer shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that—</text><subparagraph id="H5A30A32FF4AB4F9089D95C27D521FE14"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describes the successes, failures, expenses, activities, funding, and forecasted projections of the Enterprise Fund; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H603A28197DC14C739E3B3C74BC3EED31"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes the results of the audit required by section 9(a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE67B46BD2C3C4C40968C221432FD42EB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HF5238AD68D83444AA3C17E5D85C78B0E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Financial Services, and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5246322FEF0D4E0AA9A1C6810469845D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE324665F129C490890357C052D2A401D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on Oversight Panel duties</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter until the Enterprise Fund terminates, the Oversight Panel shall submit to Congress and the President a report on the implementation of the duties of the Oversight Panel during the preceding year, including a description of successes regarding implementation of the Enterprise Fund and challenges preventing the Enterprise Fund from meeting its full potential.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB7AF9AAB31C24A0B9E4E8E2E5964FA25"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report after failure To repay</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the last day of any year in which the repayment to the Treasury required by section 11 has not yet been completed, the Chief Executive Officer shall make publicly available a report that includes a comprehensive and detailed description of the operations, activities, financial condition, and accomplishments of the Enterprise Fund during such year.</text></subsection></section><section id="H856F50E815374EE194286F5AB68E6CDD"><enum>11.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than December 31, 2031—</text><paragraph id="HD01F2DA2E75A4A728CF99457D06E07B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Chief Executive Officer shall repay from the Enterprise Fund to the Treasury the full amount of funds the Enterprise Fund received from the United States Government; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H95B72F7B94174816A7AF67B9E78E0AF7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Enterprise Fund shall terminate.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5EA1A66B24EF4A80B612ACAF56605511" commented="no"><enum>12.</enum><header>Nonapplicability of other laws</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, executive branch agencies may conduct programs and activities and provide services in support of the activities of the Enterprise Fund.</text></section><section id="HAC888384E68D4349AA8070711A29E4C2"><enum>13.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $1,000,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031, which shall be authorized to remain available until expended or until the Enterprise Fund terminates, whichever occurs first.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

