<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-REI25055-W82-Y0-PFN"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 330 ATS: Designating June 23, 2025, as “Social Media Harms Victim Remembrance Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 330</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250721">July 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating June 23, 2025, as <quote>Social Media Harms Victim Remembrance Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the internet has revolutionized the ability to exchange information, improved the accessibility of education, reduced the costs of healthcare through telehealth, and stimulated the national economy by providing millions of jobs and trillions of dollars in gross product each year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas social media has become central to modern communication, bringing together people from across the globe;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas teenagers spend approximately 8 hours on screens per day, on average; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas over 90 percent of teenagers use social media;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 51 percent of teenagers spend nearly 5 hours on social media each day;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nearly half of teens report being online almost constantly;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas parents identify social media as the leading reason it is harder to be a teen today than in the past;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas social media presents significant risks, especially to adolescents, including the perpetuation and promotion of harmful and dangerous behaviors and connections;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas countless individuals and families have suffered harms, including death, because of experiences on social media platforms, including cyberbullying, harassment, exposure to sex trafficking, and exploitation;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas social media has been linked to an increase in illicit drug poisoning and overdose related deaths;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas social media use has been linked to self-harming behavior and suicidal ideation in youth;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas suicide has become one of the leading causes of death in children aged 15 to 19;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is vital to recognize and honor the experiences of those who have been harmed by social media, including the victims, survivors, and their families;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas commemorating Social Media Harms Victim Remembrance Day provides an opportunity to raise awareness about the detrimental effects of social media and to advocate for measures to effectively mitigate these harms; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas establishing a designated day of remembrance fosters empathy, solidarity, and support for those who have endured social media-related trauma and encourages efforts to promote digital well-being and online safety: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idc4c38fb27fdd4d5baf82943ca1591ee1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates June 23, 2025, as <quote>Social Media Harms Victim Remembrance Day</quote> to honor the individuals who have lost their lives and have suffered harm because of social media;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb96c474cfef147628f05692de1858b05"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reaffirms its commitment to protecting individuals from harm in digital spaces and promoting a culture of respect, empathy, and responsibility online by acknowledging the significance of Social Media Harms Victim Remembrance Day;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide6479b945fb241f8a5ecc0ae816fb11f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges individuals, communities, organizations, and social media platforms to observe Social Media Harms Victim Remembrance Day through activities such as remembrance ceremonies, educational events, and advocacy efforts aimed at raising awareness about social media harms and supporting victims and survivors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id98192998220b43d3b9f034ea3212f547"><enum>(4)</enum><text>calls upon relevant government agencies, nonprofit organizations, and stakeholders to collaborate in developing and implementing initiatives to address social media harms effectively, including enhancing digital literacy, promoting online safety measures, and supporting the rights of victims; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id76d993e315104fefb639907ee66d181d"><enum>(5)</enum><text>respectfully requests that the Secretary of the Senate transmit enrolled copies of this resolution to the President of the United States, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Chair of the Federal Trade Commission to promote awareness of Social Media Harms Victim Remembrance Day and encourage actions to prevent social media-related harm. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

