<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H84347EB41D0B443C8527AD5631A59C67" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2529 IH: Convenient Contraception Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2529</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250401">April 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act to require group health plans and health insurance issuers offering group or individual health insurance coverage to permit enrollees to obtain a 365-day supply of contraceptives.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6DB5D78992E942EDA332A844944D7581" style="OLC"><section id="H44F3A6660AFA4EFF929D4A09FD95EE90" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Shot title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Convenient Contraception Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HB3EC277966B845C9ABFD264B272725B1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring group health plans and group and individual health insurance coverage to permit an individual to obtain a 365-day supply of contraceptives</header><subsection id="H5C4D3010C68C4D539C2977E9F53A7AB9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><paragraph id="HB6637337EB654B59B9EEDDC8CF1A843B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 2713(a) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-13">42 U.S.C. 300gg–13(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end of the matter following paragraph (5), the following: <quote>To be in compliance with the requirement under paragraph (4), regardless of the guidelines described in such paragraph, the Secretary shall require a group health plan or health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage to permit an enrollee under such plan or coverage to obtain (including in a single fill or refill), at the option of such individual, the total day supply (not to exceed a 365-day supply) for a contraceptive for which coverage is otherwise required without the imposition of any cost-sharing requirements pursuant to such paragraph.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6985E62C575E4F7F82DC60AA43535051"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply with respect to plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2026.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H542840CA25E4458BA896027E03CDF3B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text>Beginning not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Labor, and the Secretary of the Treasury shall jointly conduct such outreach activities as are necessary to inform health care providers and individuals who are enrolled (and who are eligible to enroll) in group health plans and group and individual health insurance coverage (as such terms are defined in section 2791 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-91">42 U.S.C. 300gg–91</external-xref>)) of the benefit requirements applied pursuant to the amendment made by subsection (a)(1).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

