<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ERN25009-922-FX-NJJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S141 IS: Connected Maternal Online Monitoring Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 141</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250116">January 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To identify and address barriers to coverage of remote physiologic devices under State Medicaid programs to improve maternal and child health outcomes for pregnant and postpartum women.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Connected Maternal Online Monitoring Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Connected MOM Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idb9bcf1233beb4806b106c67d1cf74725"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Coverage of remote physiologic monitoring devices and impact on maternal and child health outcomes under Medicaid</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id45ed59586689422ab4fdf350152b9c29"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress a report containing information on authorities and State practices for covering remote physiological monitoring devices, including limitations and barriers to such coverage and the impact on maternal health outcomes, and to the extent appropriate, recommendations on how to address such limitations or barriers related to coverage of remote physiologic devices under State Medicaid programs, including, but not limited to, pulse oximeters, blood pressure cuffs, scales, and blood glucose monitors, with the goal of improving maternal and child health outcomes for pregnant and postpartum women enrolled in State Medicaid programs.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idec8c55611678436082346d06ae805ddd"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">State resources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the submission of the report required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall update resources for State Medicaid programs, such as State Medicaid telehealth toolkits, to be consistent with the recommendations provided in such report. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

