<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25E65-LFM-SJ-G79"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>101 S2868 IS: India Shrimp Tariff Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2868</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250918" legis-day="20250916">September 18 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To increase the rate of duty on shrimp originating from India, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>India Shrimp Tariff Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id5240ad8dac324391ad9c8b8fe86efe4e"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id0a9aefb435f44551910fd5fee779ed51"><enum>(1)</enum><header>GATT 1947; GATT 1994</header><text>The terms <term>GATT 1947</term> and <term>GATT 1994</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 2 of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/3501">19 U.S.C. 3501</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide4301a89171f4451999cc618bb606dbf"><enum>(2)</enum><header>HTS</header><text>The term <term>HTS</term> means the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4982afe72d874c20a5f384399cdabc78"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National Trade Estimate</header><text>The term <term>National Trade Estimate</term> means the report required to be submitted by the United States Trade Representative under section 181(b) of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2241">19 U.S.C. 2241(b)</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id00dc10e401844b75828fc2e2f67ce577"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Schedule of concessions</header><text>The term <term>Schedule of Concessions</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Schedule XX</term> in section 2 of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/3501">19 U.S.C. 3501</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id3ee07fa294dc450dbab08dee54dfe346"><enum>(5)</enum><header>World Trade Organization</header><text>The term <term>World Trade Organization</term> means the organization established pursuant to the WTO Agreement, as defined in section 2 of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/3501">19 U.S.C. 3501</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="ideea1a37f542b4cb189331c592a299529"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on the need to phase-in a duty increase for shrimp from India</header><subsection id="idec615e952d184c17bbdc1192080fbddc"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="id0408c986c34a4468adfa8068cb3a994f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States has a grand tradition of shrimp production, but domestic producers are forced to compete in a wide open market while exports from India are heavily subsidized and protected.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddc5a6fce9e45418493e93a2c1d857ac9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>According to the National Trade Estimate in 2023, <quote>India’s bound tariff rates on agricultural products are among the highest in the world, averaging 113.1 percent and ranging as high as 300.0 percent.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd13f9a4ce37b4402bfd699e475d77ab1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>India’s basic duty on shrimp is 30 percent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfa74ae093c4746f4a822cfee111f6d95"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The National Trade Estimate also records that since 2018, India has applied an additional 10 percent social welfare surcharge on imports, assessed on the value of its existing high duties, which includes shrimp.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide0519b982ce54cc091b3bcf1cda35f02"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Wild-caught and farm-raised shrimp from the United States now account for less than 10 percent of shrimp consumption in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc063dee5ae6944fc997ad1cdb3164cc9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Shrimp production overseas is able to undercut the costs of shrimp produced in the United States due to poor worker and environmental protections.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddd17a0e0ade3476a83bf60aa2d7c7ce8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Shrimp imports from India consist almost entirely of farm-raised aquaculture shrimp, as the importation of wild-caught shrimp from India remains prohibited due to the failure of Indian fisheries to meet the certification requirements under section 609(b)(2) of the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/101/162">Public Law 101–162</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1537">16 U.S.C. 1537</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f2fa6ae235b42ee91a41d3efdca0734"><enum>(8)</enum><text>According to Seafood Watch, <quote>India’s farmed shrimp industry has expanded rapidly since 2014 and faces challenges with disease outbreaks, health management, farm registration, and data availability.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id27fe5068e4a24b15b9ff1a6d0aa9efa4"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The United States has taken a lax approach to inspecting imported shrimp, with only 0.1 percent of shipments being inspected for unsafe drug residues. Despite that low inspection rate, every year, shipments of shrimp from India are refused due to testing by the Food and Drug Administration for banned antibiotics.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id068fd10c5817456d8887aec32981ef96"><enum>(10)</enum><text>During the 20-year period preceding the date of the enactment of this Act, shrimp producers in the United States have paid a tremendous cost to litigate trade remedy laws to defend against predatory pricing and illegal subsidies from Indian shrimp imports.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0638fee5696c412ca5b42433f8888b7f"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Dispute Settlement Body of the World Trade Organization has limited the effectiveness of trade remedy laws of the United States in relation to shrimp imports from India and as a result, tens of millions of dollars in antidumping duties go uncollected by U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idec02a96b924b4c7ca1d2c586bc3a43bc"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The United States rate of duty for warm-water shrimp, set under subheadings 0306.17, 1605.21, and 1605.29 of the HTS, is set to <quote>free</quote> in both the column 1 and column 2 rate of duty columns, meaning there is no duty owed for the entire world absent a trade remedy order.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id056892a752664f3c95ff554582d8cc3b"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The United States rate of duty for preserved or frozen shrimp, in a product containing fish meat or prepared meals, is 5 percent, but waived under the Generalized System of Preferences under title V of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2461">19 U.S.C. 2461 et seq.</external-xref>) and all relevant United States free trade agreements under the column 1 special rate of duty column of the HTS.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id34292cde576b44bbaffeffb59b696510"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Maintaining a 0 percent tariff on shrimp under both column 1 and column 2 of the HTS negates any benefits, including increased environmental and worker rights protections, stemming from preferential tariff programs or free trade agreements.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbbd47179868b48f684bf693e775bddbc"><enum>(15)</enum><text>India maintains a base customs duty for shrimp of 30 percent, before applying an additional 10 percent social welfare surcharge—special duty.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idec1cb3618959449b88fb5fc4d58d1ec9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that phasing in an increased duty for shrimp originating from India is prudent and necessary to safeguard sustainable harvesting of shrimp in the United States and from free trade agreement partners of the United States, and would enhance the trade and development goals of the tariff preference programs of the United States.</text></subsection></section><section id="idbb34d555395f4de39552c265aa19a040"><enum>4.</enum><header>Treatment of shrimp from India</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2cd0defa0f9940159c16043d55085627"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Phase-In of duty increase</header><paragraph id="id16CD642C544B45399D960172C7D74152"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Calendar year 2026</header><text>Effective on January 1, 2026, subheadings 0306.16.00, 0306.17.00, 0306.35, 0306.36, 0306.95, 1605.21, and 1605.29 of the HTS shall be applied and administered with respect to imports from India—</text><subparagraph id="idE9E243ED01014A5890B3B5066987A23C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the column 1 general rate of duty column, by substituting <quote>10%</quote> for the rate of duty otherwise applicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF6E2F2F0030144789B76096B4579C8DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the column 2 rate of duty column, by substituting <quote>25¢/kg</quote> for the rate of duty otherwise applicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7D03DB81FC874028B2E4251ABB7562A7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Calendar year 2027</header><text>Effective on January 1, 2027, subheadings 0306.16.00, 0306.17.00, 0306.35, 0306.36, 0306.95, 1605.21, and 1605.29 of the HTS shall be applied and administered with respect to imports from India—</text><subparagraph id="id5D62998F7C7C40889F93FDB964E3C83F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the column 1 general rate of duty column, by substituting <quote>20%</quote> for the rate of duty otherwise applicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id37A31B66BD194A1F8B3C88610E38AD2A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the column 2 rate of duty column, by substituting <quote>50¢/kg</quote> for the rate of duty otherwise applicable. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idA2C8FA7F1C5446B8AD992656C1B8F09A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Calendar year 2028 and thereafter</header><text>Effective on January 1, 2028, subheadings 0306.16.00, 0306.17.00, 0306.35, 0306.36, 0306.95, 1605.21, and 1605.29 of the HTS shall be applied and administered with respect to imports from India—</text><subparagraph id="id2AD202D3A58D4A0EBBEB1FB51E945DA2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the column 1 general rate of duty column, by substituting <quote>40%</quote> for the rate of duty otherwise applicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70CD147C0740464981BC9011425B0968"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the column 2 rate of duty column, by substituting <quote>$1/kg</quote> for the rate of duty otherwise applicable. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id239f542fd8ed47258f9cd8133fb1c042"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Customs valuation</header><text>Notwithstanding section 402 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1401a">19 U.S.C. 1401a</external-xref>), or any other provision of law, shrimp imported into the United States from India shall be appraised, for purposes of that Act, as not less than the average of United States ex-vessel shrimp prices as of the date of exportation.</text></subsection></section><section id="id7372e3a03c4447e2935726a99b6bab90"><enum>5.</enum><header>Country of origin labeling for cooked shrimp and crawfish</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7cbcd2f5d34049bca2c6995b7f479a46"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 281(7)(B) of the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1638">7 U.S.C. 1638(7)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id96d8f6460d5f411ea377fb52a04d6c72"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id262b152df27e4f92b72abda07d1f470c"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>includes a fillet</quote> and inserting “includes—</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEDF0915A1F6E4EB5A61F501D581B600E"><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69003e9fa1684dfeb03a755feb741992"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a fillet</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id05f4d49eaa3b4d41804efd68147079d9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id20B91AAFB4DF41AA9471E0EE054159F8"><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id78a723369b7d4dc19decc4a39ff97489"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whole cooked shrimp and crawfish and cooked shrimp and crawfish sections.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id99363639afde4e68afc639c5cebc8001"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Modification of definition of processed food item</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture shall modify section 60.119 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), to ensure that cooked shrimp, cooked crawfish, cooked shrimp sections, and cooked crawfish sections are not considered processed food items for purposes of that section.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b08a4b6c86a4c2fb2fdb7d94985ca3f"><enum>6.</enum><header>Additional duty on shrimp</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id33e81e6bb35a4c419eec7b998b4dbb8a"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The President shall impose a duty on imports of shrimp under subheadings 0306.16.00, 0306.17.00, 0306.35, 0306.36, 0306.95, 1605.21, and 1605.29 of the HTS in an amount equal to $0.10 per kilogram.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide0ca09ff5536424aaec34d28142c8f12"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Use of amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall use an amount equal to the amount received by the United States pursuant to duties under subsection (a) to conduct inspections of shrimp and catfish imported into the United States.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3b25d33e59784a31a6f5243db3792ef5"><enum>7.</enum><header>Treatment of duties</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Duties under this Act are to be imposed in addition to any duty imposed under any other provision of law or pursuant to any other authority.</text></section><section id="ida99e7c24e47b41ddb1f3a94c3bf7f13f"><enum>8.</enum><header>Modification of schedule of concessions to GATT 1994</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">With due regard for the international obligations of the United States, particularly Article XXXVIII of the GATT 1947 requiring any suspension of trade agreement concessions to be made on a most-favored nation basis, the United States Trade Representative shall take the necessary steps to modify the Schedule of Concessions to accommodate the increase in the rate of duty applicable to shrimp from India under section 4 and the additional increase under section 6.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

