<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25E18-99C-92-520"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2737 IS: Veterans National Traumatic Brain Injury Treatment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2737</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250909">September 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to implement a pilot program to furnish hyperbaric oxygen therapy to certain veterans through community care providers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC"><section id="HE475148DBEAB4366A16A789ABA6C9BC2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans National Traumatic Brain Injury Treatment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H440162756B7741799BC59FE166020B87" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program to furnish hyperbaric oxygen therapy to a veteran with traumatic brain injury or post-traumatic stress disorder</header><subsection id="HB1B917C9CC1F43BA8CCE507CC74E0356"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall implement a pilot program to furnish HBOT to a veteran who has a traumatic brain injury or post-traumatic stress disorder through a health care provider described in section 1703(c)(5) of title 38, United States Code (in this section referred to as the <quote>pilot program</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HDD28359B39BA41F382C897F7E579B975"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Locations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall select two Veterans Integrated Service Networks of the Department of Veterans Affairs in which to operate the pilot program.</text></subsection><subsection id="H746F35C913B444F68C9CBB1CC4F8CB5F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Accreditation required</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that any medical facility at which a veteran receives HBOT under the pilot program is accredited by—</text><paragraph id="H16581679D247459A94269648126E831E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Hospital Organizations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57BFA41565EA45E8AEF35ECB95DEC1B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Undersea and Hyperbaric Medical Society; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C0DB67511E047928EE6F9DD645259DD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">another appropriate organization that has expertise and objectivity comparable to that of the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Hospital Organizations or the Undersea and Hyperbaric Medical Society.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H059D0FAD9F3249328CAC8413CC235DF6" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Funding</header><paragraph id="H20B86FEE1D1346A196540D4DC5FF81E4" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is in the general fund of the Treasury a fund to be known as the <quote>VA HBOT Fund</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Fund</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE52D998C0684146B4D79CA830E3FDEE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sole source of funds</header><text>The sole source of amounts deposited into the Fund shall be donations received by the Secretary for the express purpose of providing HBOT under the pilot program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E104812D2BF4CE383B46DB37C38CBA2" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts in the Fund shall be available to the Secretary without fiscal year limitation to pay for HBOT under the pilot program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD0BB93E0C1E4491C9D37694973EAA4F0" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The pilot program and the Fund shall terminate on the day that is three years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H506C6078D85E4FB2ACCE0EECCB207D65" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>HBOT defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>HBOT</term> means hyperbaric oxygen therapy provided to a patient with a medical device—</text><paragraph id="HA8A2FA3B0A4A4FBA8724528CB2EED65C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>approved by the Food and Drug Administration; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H720658073377487A9156E2D1FF38A56F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issued an investigational device exemption by the Food and Drug Administration.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2073CD41730A482396A2267261A9CDEB" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Comptroller General report on use of hyperbaric oxygen therapy to treat traumatic brain injury and post-traumatic stress disorder</header><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="idcebf5d2ff08149a8839dc2da1e42c24e"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives an update to the report of the Comptroller General published on December 18, 2015, and titled <quote>Research on Hyperbaric Oxygen Therapy to Treat Traumatic Brain Injury and Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder</quote> (GAO–16–154).</text></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="id9806595a7f924c069e365c32ac65109e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The update required under subsection (a) shall include an assessment by the Comptroller General of clinical trials conducted since the publication of the report specified in such subsection—</text><paragraph id="H093B5DC87824432EBE67782180A3D36B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regarding the use of hyperbaric oxygen therapy to treat traumatic brain injury and post-traumatic stress disorder; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD3A555E9C834E2CB5D9352B9CC6B62B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by—</text><subparagraph id="H83D61E8328BF41758D3EF771F28F3F84"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Veterans Affairs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4A16559987D4CDBB7F1C09EE9737826"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Defense; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD7CEEAB0BE149D392764B0326E359D3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>private entities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H890FC153F8BF4B4D99D4B4DAA3EBD0EE" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Extension of certain limits on payments of pension</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5503(d)(7) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>November 30, 2031</quote> and inserting <quote>October 30, 2034</quote>. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

