<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H751F71AE3A6444C5B2401893ED175068" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1194 IH: Federal Lands and Waters Leasing Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1194</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250211">February 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act and the Mineral Leasing Act to require reports on rejected bids, to clarify timelines for the issuance of leases, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC2F23A6450F84F89AAC043C6EA965916" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H694B3C75649146AB9CBBD6685BE6776D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Lands and Waters Leasing Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H813DC6BDA3C1498882270F40ADC11BEE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on the determination of the fair market value of offshore oil and gas lease bids</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 18 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1344">43 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA0C330B94C3543ABAFE175FA08D46CB3" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subsection id="H99EC9C1D986D43E380C724D3A3882A11"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Report on the determination of the fair market value of offshore oil and gas lease bids</header>
<paragraph id="HEC1CFAB124084A98B1B136BF1DA01371"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines pursuant to subsection (a)(4) that the Federal Government will not receive the fair market value from a bid for a covered lease tract, the Secretary shall provide to the bidder a report that explains the basis for such determination. If the bid was a qualified bid that was subject to a resource and economic evaluation, the report shall include information on how such qualified bid relates to the Mean Range of Values, Delay-adjusted Mean Range of Values, Adjusted Delayed Value, and Revised Arithmetic Average Measure for the covered lease tract.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H22065B13920F4BDEA9E5B54D28066C78"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered lease tract</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, The term <term>covered lease tract</term> means a lease tract for which the Secretary—</text>
<subparagraph id="H5D4591A3D3A74262B5CA7F7C8548B435"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">held a lease sale;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB6A30759F92B4097A42CCB3B20ED775F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">received at least one bid; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB9B2C5E09BDA4DF09FE8B501ABAED043"><enum>(C)</enum><text>did not issue a lease to the highest responsible qualified bidder.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H847F6290A27A4BE6A7073B7D42A8E07D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effect of court orders on deadline to issue onshore oil and gas leases</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 17(b)(1)(A) of the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/226">30 U.S.C. 226(b)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>No court order may prevent the Secretary from issuing a lease by such 60 day deadline unless the court finds that the issuance of the lease would violate a requirement of Federal law.</quote> after <quote>first lease year.</quote>.</text></section>
<section id="HB0315270AAA14E03AB1D79125316CFA1" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Civil actions challenging offshore lease sales</header>
<subsection id="H3214178E3B904ED7A32AD91AF325D35E" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a civil action challenging an offshore oil and gas lease sale conducted under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331 et seq.</external-xref>) shall not—</text> <paragraph id="H15B5FCAA34484748A02761E997F5C932" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affect the validity of any lease issued under such an offshore lease sale; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H96EAAAB8881C4B338E827AE731A86D23" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cause a delay in the timelines for the consideration of any exploration plan, development plan, development operations coordination document, applications for permit to drill, or other application for a Federal agency authorization or approval for activities on a lease issued under such an offshore lease sale.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H97EBFBA50F7B42F3888447016199B1C4" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Remand; processing of approvals and applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if, in a civil action described in subsection (a), a court finds that the offshore lease sale was not carried out in compliance with Federal law—</text>
<paragraph id="HC7858BCB134A44939F5A94B9E87CCC87" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the court shall not—</text> <subparagraph id="HBE6AA7FB1F5A42569669D252C70CBC89" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">set aside, vacate, or enjoin the offshore lease sale;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H32DF79428B2C4B1491F4AC05DA62D5E8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>set aside, vacate, or enjoin the leases issued pursuant to the offshore lease sale; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAA180D40836A4C0E94A2F37776AE6685" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enjoin the Secretary of the Interior from issuing leases to the highest bidders in the challenged offshore lease sale;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE954BF6584AF447FBBB16A70A334D8B9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the court shall remand the matter to the Secretary of the Interior and require the Secretary of the Interior to correct the noncompliance; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H23866A4297784DF1962EB1505B5483F4" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of the Interior shall continue to process all exploration plans, development and production plans, development operations coordination documents, applications for permit to drill, and other applications for a Federal agency authorization or other approval for activities requested under any lease issued under the challenged offshore lease sale in accordance with the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

