<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H3FAF3220E5C448D0BD97BA99F9300C4B">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5704 IH: Repeal the Smith-Mundt Modernization Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5704</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20251008">October 8, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To repeal the Smith-Mundt Modernization Act of 2013 and to prohibit domestic propagandization by the Federal Government.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H0B39E156966242B0AB4F6E429AB6BBEF">
<section id="HD15C0DE4A4AB4DA9AD94246C1D90DA96" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Repeal the Smith-Mundt Modernization Act of 2013</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAD872479338E4940BC3B009BD5A1AF69"><enum>2.</enum><header>Repeal smith-mundt domestic propagandization</header> <subsection id="H265BC719404A40AEB644B0E7C66CEDB3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>United states information and educational exchange act of 1948</header><text>Section 501 of the United States Information and Educational Exchange Act of 1948 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1461">22 U.S.C. 1461</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block id="H45B4833742B24DD08109B3AC1F5954CD" style="OLC">
<section id="H04F897E245BA40D193C23B182FCC4067"><enum>501.</enum><header>General authorization</header>
<subsection id="HB2BB9BF362FC49A7AE28208868C8F1F3">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Dissemination of information abroad</header>
 <text>The Secretary of State and the Chief Executive Officer of the United States Agency for Global Media (USAGM) are authorized to provide for the preparation and dissemination abroad of information about the United States, its people, and its policies, through press, publications, radio, motion pictures, the internet, and other information media, and through information centers and instructors abroad, except that such dissemination may not include the use of social media accounts, websites, or podcasts other than official platforms maintained by the Department of State or USAGM for purposes of foreign dissemination.</text>
            </subsection>
<subsection id="HC778ED641D7B465E9B091677119F0A0E">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Ability To review information domestically</header>
              <paragraph id="HEAE5C12C266449D29493ADC0C4AF5AFF">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>Any materials produced under subsection (a) shall, upon request, be made available in the English language, at all reasonable times following their release abroad, for examination at the Department of State or the United States Agency for Global Media, as appropriate, by representatives of United States press associations, newspapers, magazines, radio systems, and stations, and by Members of Congress. Except as provided in subsection (c), such materials may not be disseminated within the United States, except that Members of Congress may use such materials in the exercise of their official oversight functions.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H7E2AB689D61843B8B0E1F1520FBE8520">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>No funds authorized to be appropriated to the Department of State or the United States Agency for Global Media, or its component networks, shall be used for the purpose of influencing public opinion or propagandizing in the United States.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
<subsection id="H23046599BBCA444B8C96A66EEF22BC45"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Archival of records</header>
<paragraph id="HABC9D6887EB84ECCB92E9D6D4A28D013"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State and the Chief Executive Officer of the United States Agency for Global Media shall make available to the Archivist of the United States any materials produced under subsection (a). Such materials shall be maintained by the Archivist and made accessible to the public only for examination in a format that permits viewing but not reproduction or redistribution—</text> <subparagraph id="HDFB2B5D88DC74932A27F441140982817"><enum>(A)</enum><text>beginning on the date that is 20 years after the date on which such material was initially disseminated abroad; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H982EF5DBF0B840A8A6CDD458C02E4EC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of material that was prepared but never disseminated abroad, beginning on the date that is 20 years after the date on which such material was prepared.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4CD237F5639A4F6E8ECFC9E027A574AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Restriction on domestic dissemination</header><text>Any materials produced under subsection (a)—</text>
<subparagraph id="HE42BF7EAC48644639C11D1D0AC3157B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may not be distributed domestically by the Archivist before the expiration of the 20-year period described in paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H52F7F68225354BBE8FE2377403C9699A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any materials made accessible by the Archivist after such period, shall bear a clear and permanent identifier, watermark, or disclaimer indicating—</text>
<clause id="H3133B3C476AB432697E404243D0350A7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the United States Government entity responsible for its production;</text></clause> <clause id="H8F9CE08EEAF1432A95B2CDAD612577A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the foreign country or region for which the material was originally prepared or disseminated; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H0B0E5ED84520497EA70C0D6645AD6F31"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the purpose or program under which the material was produced, if applicable.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBBD7F8C50A264D18BC210C5D34CCB567"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Responsibilities of the archivist</header><text>The Archivist—</text>
<subparagraph id="H8E679041FA72419FB2CD65E805899552"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be the official custodian of the material described in paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H777DAC1FB80D4081A9303159C74C7D2A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall promulgate regulations to—</text>
<clause id="H8A664B2045494C92B058AE83F04D45F5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>facilitate public examination of such materials in accordance with paragraph (1); and</text></clause> <clause id="H10E7482AE065407B9E63F9EF2128E1D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>govern the release of such materials in accordance with paragraph (2), including requirements that any person seeking such release—</text>
<subclause id="H251909D039B4439A895F59535F6AC3FB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has secured all necessary United States rights and licenses; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HFC5A61FDEF854F9397F72603F8505320"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has paid a fee, in accordance with section 2116(c) of title 44, United States Code, sufficient to cover the costs incurred by the Archivist in providing such materials; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF91CFFBFA4534120BC80197D0314DEED"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall ensure that all fees collected under subparagraph (B)(ii)(II) are deposited into, administered, and expended as part of the National Archives Trust Fund.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H14AD2A51C141446B9C689A6A190D28DB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to require the Secretary of State or the Chief Executive Officer of the United States Agency for Global Media to make material disseminated abroad available in any format other than in the format disseminated abroad.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H5CB48890ED1343D7AC8452041DCF4C45"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Foreign relations authorizations act, fiscal years 1986 and 1987</header>
<paragraph id="H4751B75E0C9C4B4DA2970A47BBB93508">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
 <text>Section 208 of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1986 and 1987 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1461-1a">22 U.S.C. 1461–1a</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <quoted-block id="HE19AC729C77B44CDA86F96F27C1118AC" style="OLC">
            <section id="HAD289A171EB44547A226D80F2C555EA2">
              <enum>208.</enum>
              <header>Ban on domestic distribution of program material</header>
              <subsection id="HD73E545E542C479DB4029A12CE5BC17A">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <paragraph id="H702A1E6735AE44449742D8F93B440264">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>Use of funds</header>
 <text>No funds authorized to be appropriated to the Department of State or the United States Agency for Global Media (USAGM), or any of its component networks, may be used to influence public opinion in the United States.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H13BE3B4D3CBB4571A650CAC01A7191FA">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Restriction on domestic distribution</header>
 <text>No program material prepared by USAGM may be distributed in the United States, except as provided in section 501 of the United States Information and Educational Exchange Act of 1948 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1461">22 U.S.C. 1461</external-xref>).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H2FF5888D5ECC499CBBE8B7ECC6F3F2D0">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <header>Transparency exception</header>
 <text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prohibit or delay the Department of State or USAGM from providing factual information about their operations, policies, or programs, or from making such information available to members of the media, the public, or Congress, in accordance with other applicable law.</text>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="H80D46B5B49154D9CABFF5DC31065DDFB">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Rules of construction</header>
 <text>Nothing in this section may be construed—</text> <paragraph id="HCD559934ACB9484BB5A14BF66A8F1057"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>to apply to programs carried out pursuant to the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2451">22 U.S.C. 2451 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H03518171EBC846AEA1B16409EF384F73">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>to prohibit any employee of USAGM from responding to inquiries from members of the public about USAGM operations, policies, or programs.</text>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
            </section>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H069437A893E54BB3B42F9BFAA2A2975E">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Clerical amendment</header>
 <text>The table of contents for the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1986 and 1987 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1461-1a">22 U.S.C. 1461–1a</external-xref>) is amended by striking the item relating to section 208 and inserting the following:</text>
          <quoted-block id="H6196150AF14D42169D7A40A8752681A5" style="OLC">
            <toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
              <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 208 Ban on domestic distribution of program
                material.</toc-entry>
            </toc>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill>

