<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA5CC9E050302424882FDE8F2EEDC2B30" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 369 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Secretary of Health and Human Services should withdraw a reduction in public notice and comment opportunities.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 369</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250501">May 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Secretary of Health and Human Services should withdraw a reduction in public notice and comment opportunities.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas public participation in the regulatory process is essential to the formulation of fair and sound policy;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas open rulemaking mitigates the possibility of arbitrary, harmful, and ill-advised rulemaking;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the Department of Health and Human Services has successfully adhered to Administrative Procedure Act notice and comment period procedures for 54 years;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the daily lives of millions of Americans are profoundly affected by the regulations that are issued by the Department of Health and Human Services; and</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas it is critical that program beneficiaries, State and local governments, human services providers, and organizations continue to be afforded the opportunity for input whenever Health and Human Services regulatory changes are proposed: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H7C51FCCD3B6D48559998F164111861C0"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HDE2004E67E3243888E49D01AF87227DE"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that the Secretary of Health and Human Services should withdraw the notice published in the Federal Register on March 3, 2025 (90 Fed. Reg. 11029) that would reduce public notice and comment opportunities, and affirm practices as in effect on February 27, 2025, which involve the public in rulemaking procedures.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

