<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA9CB7F9AE3E94FBEB1A50C88BE3DAF3E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4286 IH: Strategy to Address Key Priorities Affecting Security and Empowerment in Haiti Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4286</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250702">July 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which
                was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign
                    Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Department of State to develop a comprehensive
            strategy to counter instability in Haiti and advance a Haitian-led solution to the
 ongoing crisis.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA9D4971EA17848A7A31A3915875C7E2F" style="OLC"><section id="H8305687DD8AF42A4BC7C3B8480BE384B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strategy to Address Key Priorities Affecting Security and Empowerment in Haiti Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAK PASE in Haiti Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD5C897660A144C31AE63C5C4E5ADF025" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HFDA422C883224F15A58455CA27B7FF25"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States has a national security interest in ameliorating the security, economic, political, and humanitarian crises in Haiti;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F8B62BA1C3B434CA27E54657D8DC190"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the gangs unleashing violence and suffering across Haiti represent a threat to stability in Haiti and the region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H897D7016F5E74BF98760E8CDBB0062F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>stabilization of the security situation and full participation of civil society in Haiti must be a precondition for open democratic political processes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9107950E4CF843B9B6993041EA383E0E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a lasting solution to the crisis in Haiti must garner support from and be led by the Haitian people.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H56B0FF675B094811A1BCEBFD7717442A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Strategy to counter gang violence and advance stability in Haiti</header><subsection id="HD5F44FAA9DE5419AA0D060249249FDF1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy required</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a comprehensive strategy to reestablish security and enhance stability in Haiti.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0ACA804794554A449841AF20975954B5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H0CA986A71A284B94822A1E41E21C758B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Bolstering security in Haiti with an assessment of—</text><subparagraph id="HE429B65D95664EACB1636E1A0DD1AC18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the importance of supporting the Haitian National Police, the Armed Forces of Haiti, the Multinational Security Support Mission, and other security force elements to counter gang activity and violence exacerbating instability in Haiti;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B1342723C46405AAA30989D570F17F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordination with international allies and partners, including the European Union, Canada, and Caribbean Community and Common Market (CARICOM) nations, to address the security crisis;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A796D8D225549DB8392FC21F91E5077"><enum>(C)</enum><text>collaboration with the United Nations and other international partners to evaluate the efficacy of the Multinational Security Support (MSS) mission and potential for a long-term United Nations Peacekeeping Operations (PKO) mission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CBC41686A3F4C6D8D5A1FB17B248C63"><enum>(D)</enum><text>feasibility of reducing the risk of gang violence in Haiti, including through the reintegration of former gang members into Haitian society; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BB9720679284A658D03DA84B19F332D"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ability of nongovernmental organizations, including humanitarian and faith-based organizations, to continue operations in Haiti.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0417189B51324001A0E99FD9586066F9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Addressing the flow of illicit arms, financial support, and political backing provided to gangs in Haiti with an assessment of—</text><subparagraph id="HD603F734E19346D1B03B2A9DA574AD4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>additional resources needed to address the security, political, and humanitarian instability in Haiti; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B9B6E96B4FE49BC92DC7B73DCB4B00F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordination with the Transitional Presidential Council and Interim Prime Minister to jointly develop and implement a strategy to counter gang activity and restore governance and the rule of law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2633FEBCAD8448FF9B4D01F6B548FB2E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Expanding economic opportunity for Haitians through the Haiti HOPE/HELP program or other programs with an assessment of—</text><subparagraph id="HB681EAE031CA4BF3BFDEC2057760A537"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the impact of sanctions on Haiti, including designations of foreign terrorist organizations, on the delivery of humanitarian assistance to Haiti; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7C2AF4A75DF4A209456CC5FEAFF447C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the difficulties of private capital mobilization in Haiti.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H50FA36E3CD9740CC818BF75C14E397F3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Supporting a solution that is by and for the Haitian people, in close partnership with Haitian civil society and the transitional leadership in Haiti.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7A48DF1EBC7B4A0EA6DEB43DDBE506DE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Required consultations</header><text>In developing the strategy required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall consult with the following:</text><paragraph id="H20E0E30BC03B43C5B2634D9C8A791FCE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Chief Executive Officer of the United States Development Finance Corporation, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, the United States Trade Representative, and the Director of the United States Trade and Development Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD816583229214D32A73F0D2D204AD4B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Private sector entities based in the United States that operate in Haiti.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5730178C942E4361AB257F13E4393D31"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Haitian stakeholders, including nongovernmental organizations and civil society in Haiti.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5C9B5A982F5D4A05832F0C880508DA6A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the submission of the strategy required by section 2(a), and annually thereafter for 5 years, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing progress made in implementing the strategy, including—</text><paragraph id="H1057663CDB7C47E0B38FBA87FE567C80"><enum>(1)</enum><text>status updates on consultations with Haitian civil society and governmental stakeholders;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C6FE7E006B246C19A12247642EE1799"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of coordination with international partners on sanctions and aid efforts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7456306E17647A0A3C92FEAABCC2A9D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>metrics and benchmarks used to evaluate the effectiveness of international support for security forces and security assistance in Haiti.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HA0A33DF0AF57422BB28A168923EEF8CA"><enum>5.</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="HD858EE4CCEA84FD2A5377490EF784963"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB775EC7E2A7C4250A99EE5F3E7A94B9C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

