<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2F28A0A622F6417B8D78ED56F1287C2F" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 506 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that Social Security should be preserved and protected for current beneficiaries, and for future generations to come.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 506</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250611">June 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000474">Mr. Flood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001098">Mr. Hamadeh of Arizona</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that Social Security should be preserved and protected for current beneficiaries, and for future generations to come.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Social Security provides essential income security through retirement, disability, and survivor benefits for over 66,000,000 Americans of all ages;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Social Security is essential to the dignity and security of the Nation’s elderly, disabled, and their families;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas each payday, American workers send their hard-earned payroll taxes to Social Security and in return are promised income security for themselves and their families upon retirement, disability, or death, and that commitment must be kept; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas workers’ ability to save and invest for their own retirement will continue to be particularly important, especially for younger workers, to enhance their own retirement security: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HD60DFF61B4E840AB8542985E774391E1"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H1CE43D3BF8C7451DA36DC6B76ED0A166"><enum/><text>That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that Social Security should be preserved and protected for current beneficiaries, and for future generations to come.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

