<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB6DD6B5022F3446883A2AC784929722D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3099 IH: Safety Training for Officers on Public Health Threats Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3099</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250430">April 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to local governments for the training of local law enforcement officers on public health threats arising from violations of building codes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5E7755AFA3774A34B704EDFE459FA87D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H90FD8A4B459D44B489E86761D0093238" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safety Training for Officers on Public Health Threats Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STOP Health Threats Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> 
<section id="H34ADFA54014044A58C713C8847278269" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants to train local enforcement officers on public health threats</header> 
<subsection id="H9CA08F1942334DAA9E556802D7F941C2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the heads of other relevant agencies engaged in regulating building codes determined necessary by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall award grants to local governments for the training of local enforcement officers on public health threats arising from violations of building codes.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDB52FB731B924F72B1BA17A315261292"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A local government receiving a grant under this section shall use the grant to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAE2E1791CBF346D394D83E6C07B26CAA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop and implement a training program for local enforcement officers on recognizing and responding to public health threats described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B9E232D44F646DEB8690D121BBE4027"><enum>(2)</enum><text>partner with other local governments to collaborate on such training;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B20608F58A1488C81A10C5288EACFDE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in carrying out paragraphs (1) and (2), coordinate with—</text> <subparagraph id="H6FC93682C63241CB8A61F102A01A354E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>relevant offices and agencies of the Federal, State, and local government, such as a public health department; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H34416D07792746EC9EA936E8A77D1EA3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">nongovernmental organizations with issue area expertise; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BFBCFA72DA14F7E8F213BAAED0DB4B8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>carry out any other activities deemed appropriate by the Secretary for training described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB0129C94B6CB4D6D961BBC0DD6C29405"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To seek a grant under subsection (a), a local government shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9E46B96D18734EDEBF13D70D922AB5CB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to applicants based on—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB9CD05609F384120B039C82BD67A0F49"><enum>(1)</enum><text>their capacity to provide the training described in subsection (a); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H917B746FE2194BA3ADCAC3AD6A782406"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prioritizing areas where threats have been identified.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD2FC58CA56DB49A5A3E8DE8710D73B4C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>enforcement officers</term> means those carrying out enforcement activities and implement relevant consensus-based codes, specifications, and standards that establish minimum acceptable criteria for the design, construction, and maintenance of residential structures and facilities.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

