<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2ACB690A245847618CDE853026D66067" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 679 IH: Honoring Paul Kawata for his unwavering commitment to communities of color, the LGBTQ+ community, and work to end the HIV epidemic.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 679</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250904">September 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring Paul Kawata for his unwavering commitment to communities of color, the LGBTQ+ community, and work to end the HIV epidemic.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Paul Kawata has served as the executive director of NMAC (formerly the National Minority AIDS Council) since 1989, becoming the longest serving leader of a national HIV/AIDS organization in the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, under Mr. Kawata’s transformative leadership, NMAC became a powerful national force advancing health equity for minority communities, with a mission rooted in lifting up communities of color, especially Black, Latino, Asian, Native American, and Native Hawaiian and Pacific Islander populations, who have been disproportionately affected by HIV/AIDS;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Paul Kawata has been a fearless and unapologetic voice for LGBTQ+ justice, ensuring that LGBTQ+ individuals, particularly queer people of color, are fully visible, represented, and protected in HIV/AIDS policy, service delivery, and community care;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Paul Kawata helped lay the foundation for equitable public health responses through his role as a founding member of the Federal AIDS Policy Partnership and a leader in shaping the Minority AIDS Initiative and the National HIV/AIDS Strategy;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Paul Kawata’s work has consistently confronted systemic racism, homophobia, and health disparities, creating pathways for inclusion, leadership, and advocacy among historically marginalized groups;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, throughout the darkest and most stigmatizing chapters of the HIV epidemic, Paul Kawata responded not with silence but with bold action and moral clarity, working to dismantle bias and build resilient, empowered communities;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, as a proud Japanese American, Paul Kawata shattered barriers and has long served as a mentor and inspiration to emerging leaders, particularly in the Asian-American, Pacific Islander, and LGBTQ+ movements, helping to amplify the voices of those too often left out of national conversations on health and equity; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Paul Kawata’s work exemplifies the power of intersectional leadership, always centering justice, dignity, and the lived experience of those most impacted: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H97CDE7A378BA46BD858E18765317846C"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H32697FA6D99B44DDA8E507B623E1E155"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H8C4D9EDEB680440DAE1B06519E7CC4D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors Paul Kawata for his groundbreaking leadership and enduring legacy of advocacy for communities of color and the LGBTQ+ community;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD0CF11274D9F45ACA92407AAB222ED58"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes Paul Kawata’s 38 years of visionary service at NMAC, where he reshaped public health through a lens of racial and queer justice;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H83911F7B1F724E359EEB7DD8B1CDD255"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commends Paul Kawata’s unwavering pursuit of equity, inclusion, and access for people living with HIV and all those affected by systemic discrimination;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB8F73D92B0E24A57A4EB76F70B67B023"><enum>(4)</enum><text>expresses profound gratitude for his lifelong contributions to civil rights, public health, and the empowerment of marginalized communities; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E2F1F10D15740548B8E6F1FBC5F364A"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">extends best wishes to Paul Kawata in his retirement, with the utmost respect for the indelible mark he leaves on the Nation.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

