<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCD3F7E975BAF48AABAEB5303F943C444" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 764 IH: Recognizing the continuing disparities in Black youth mental health access and treatment.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 764</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250923">September 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the continuing disparities in Black youth mental health access and treatment.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas September is National Suicide Prevention Month;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas suicide is the third leading cause of death for 14- to 18-year-olds;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the suicide rate among Black adolescents is increasing faster than other racial and ethnic groups;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, from 2007 to 2023, the suicide rate rose 149 percent for Black adolescents age 10 to 17;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2023, 1 in 5 Black high school students reported having seriously considered attempting suicide in the past year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas that same year nearly 16 percent of those students made a suicide plan, and 10.3 percent reported attempting suicide;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nearly 2 percent of Black high school students required medical attention as a result of their suicide attempt;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, while the overall youth suicide rate is trending downwards, the suicide rate for Black youth is showing a rise in most data;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Black adolescents are significantly less likely than peers in other demographic groups to receive mental healthcare;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2019, the Congressional Black Caucus established the Emergency Task Force on Black Youth Suicide and Mental Health to investigate the alarming rate of Black youth suicide;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Task Force held hearings, forums, events, and listening sessions to identify both the causes and potential solutions to this burgeoning crisis;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, with the help of a working group of experts in the field of mental health research and policy, the Task Force published a report entitled <quote>Ring the Alarm: The Crisis of Black Youth Suicide in America</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the report made several recommendations to address the growing disparities in mental healthcare for Black youth, including—</text><paragraph id="H4F1465B3450A40EA8AFADB875B3B1CF2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increasing the amount of research into topics relating to Black youth mental health and suicide at the National Institute of Health (NIH) and the National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC683AE1498B04ACF809A06E51A6B682B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increasing funding and resources for Black researchers who focused on these topics;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06B02DF0DDD14C169A00D95366F3ECD4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>funding and demonstrating evidence-based interventions targeting Black youth suicidal behaviors and depression in schools and other settings, including through government programs, public-private partnerships, and in collaboration with faith-based organizations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H990EBABA59C340CC818ED22C53D02061"><enum>(4)</enum><text>promoting the best and most promising practices that address the needs of Black youth; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H232A6142363B44F78D688D507182A8E2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>establishing and funding an awareness campaign about Black youth suicidal behaviors;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during the last administration, many positive developments took place, including the introduction of the 988 Lifeline, increased research and support to address the disparities in Black youth mental health, and increased funding in mental health programs that support children and adolescents;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, under the current administration, much of that progress has been reversed through cuts to research grants, termination of mental health services to schools, and the elimination of any reference or association with minority mental health;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas mental health is, and should remain, a non-partisan issue that needs the full support of the United States Congress; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the benefits of what was achieved since the release of the <quote>Ring the Alarm</quote> report must be protected, and the Federal Government must continue addressing disparities in mental healthcare: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HF4A9D4370810411AA9AE80973C6D6C6B"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H0303916CFB514576A5FA9084671E094E"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H0817F7888BFA4E1A9797889A0BA0BD83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the continuing disparities in Black youth mental health access and treatment; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81C35D9499E1480CAE5AC897A3A02F6F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls on the current administration to address these disparities by continuing the work of the previous administration and incorporating recommendations from <quote>Ring the Alarm: The Crisis of Black Youth Suicide in America</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE8972B718D941D6B271E59A0BB09D75"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of creating conversations in Black communities regarding mental health, encouraging individuals to seek help to prevent suicide and suicide attempts, and providing education programming, such as L.E.T.S. Save Lives, to reduce cultural stigma, foster conversations about mental health, and raise awareness of suicide prevention;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DB88BF36B274737B8F88B69024C2EEA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>calls for increased funding for all programs supporting mental health; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3FDE38F88AF4B96A238AFE6237D6A59"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supports the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Service Administration (SAMHSA) remaining an independent agency and not being absorbed into the Administration for a Healthy America (AHA).</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

