<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5BAB8146E7BF4A6D8EC2894DBC3FCAEA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4129 IH: Tailoring for Main Street’s Investors Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4129</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250625">June 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 to provide an exemption from the registration requirements under that Act to certain advisers of private funds, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1D2DD4E1A6D141F0B81D37AC33A1E52E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H63081A41D8E94FFD930ABC2262251BE6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tailoring for Main Street’s Investors Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H14968963071840A88BBD2BD773C7162F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exemption</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 203 of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80b-3">15 U.S.C. 80b–3</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8218E2A7F02E4B55974356F1FFA2734C" act-name="">
<subsection id="H45299412C40644018F30632C22F789E3"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Exemption from registration for certain private fund advisers</header>
<paragraph id="HE58BFB04C41F4CA58344A4D0AF8C1DD3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall provide an exemption from the registration requirements under this section to any investment adviser of private funds, if—</text> <subparagraph id="H500E1E2D66BC40A3A9F5773D6D5756A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the investment adviser acts solely as an investment adviser to private funds and has assets under management in the United States of less than $5,000,000,000;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEFF442AF782F4FB2ABED76E481B557CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each of the investors in each such private fund is—</text> <clause id="H9B492FDE35164D4EA0F1B98B0E555D69"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a qualified purchaser, as defined in section 2(a) of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-2">15 U.S.C. 80a–2(a)</external-xref>);</text></clause>
<clause id="H1E6EA682DD80410A91F1A144E9A51B38"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an accredited investor, as defined in section 230.501(a) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation; or</text></clause> <clause id="HAC8B543F7FDA40F5A32721A8D50AB9A4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an investment professional that is licensed by a national securities association registered pursuant to section 15A(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78o-3">15 U.S.C. 78o–3</external-xref>), if the Commission determines that the inclusion of such investment professionals would be appropriate; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H60C33AA09DA14D948A45127FD8FCE7A4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>none of those private funds offers any investor of the private fund redemption or similar liquidity rights, except in extraordinary circumstances.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB2BED72BD7A4CE1A98475ED8809F427"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>The Commission shall require investment advisers exempted by reason of this subsection to maintain such records and provide to the Commission every 2 years such reports as the Commission determines necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors, except that the requirements under this paragraph shall be no greater, and no more burdensome, than those under subsection (m)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="HB47F00996C52440CBA5E3676E4DF95FD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reporting for smaller advisers</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H17A925ACE1714A44B966B864C7BE6AEC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA363BE1D92984B00BDAF3AB3297B12A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Securities and Exchange Commission.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H88044196FE3A421D9067C586D25D0CC9"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Covered entity</header><text>The term <term>covered entity</term> means an entity that is required to submit Form ADV.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB9D92FC67532428EAA42371E87163F99"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form ADV</header><text>The term <term>Form ADV</term> means the form described in section 279.1 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2CE02F9BF689484583EA50A3105800BD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Frequency of filing</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law or regulation, beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, a covered entity that has less than $1,000,000,000 in assets, as of the last day of the most recent fiscal year of the entity, shall be required to file Form ADV with the Commission not more frequently than once every 2 years.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33D67FCE0A284FE59196AA68928BC8F3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Short form</header><text>Not later than 280 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall develop a short form version of Form ADV that a covered entity that has less than $1,000,000,000 in assets, as of the last day of the most recent fiscal year of the entity, may use to file Form ADV with the Commission.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

