<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEN25091-VGL-G0-H0D"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S340 IS: African Diaspora Heritage Month Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 340</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250130">January 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the President to designate a month as African Diaspora Heritage Month. </official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H5743881D28D5415D873B40B8FE6CD0C4"><section section-type="section-one" id="H0DA09ABCC83B4C29B2FCA7F021FB027E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>African Diaspora Heritage Month Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5FA80B230C29427B9201CF940DC241D4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="H753C405711E741429DAC0E5CAFA4C154"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the African diaspora population in the United States has grown significantly in recent years, with the number of African immigrants growing at a rate of almost 246 percent from 2000 to 2019;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id198f7b63f96a4e40ae2f41f1548c6d73"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as of 2024, the African diaspora in the United States was comprised of approximately 50,000,000 people;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDA8828C8CD04A81AC97D067BD583102"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the African diaspora community is one of the most diverse communities in the United States, inclusive of people who speak multiple languages, whose rich heritage comes from all across the African continent, and whose members practice various faiths;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BC9F0433C3148068B7A971463D00313"><enum>(4)</enum><text>during the 17th, 18th, and 19th centuries, a significant number of enslaved people from Africa were brought to the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF2C01732209468795D05AF39EC0A2DF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>immigrants of African origin boast some of the highest educational achievements of any immigrant group;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A8F116739C24E71A794199705291663"><enum>(6)</enum><text>African diaspora households contribute billions of dollars to the economy of the United States, with an estimated $10,100,000,000 in Federal taxes, $4,700,000,000 in State and local taxes, and a spending power of more than $40,300,000,000 in 2015;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81F92C5FB56046CF93D24873B7113FFC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Sub-Saharan African immigrants living in the United States, Europe, and elsewhere sent back $46,000,000,000 in remittances to the continent of Africa in 2021;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FF76D7696834CEC9FE3D7D83BC64EBF"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Government agencies, including the International Development Finance Corporation, the Department of Commerce, the Department of the Treasury, and the United States Trade Representative are critical to investments and enduring mutual partnerships between the United States and African nations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC80832AA682B499FA9FB826B3684B1C5"><enum>(9)</enum><text>in 2023, through the African Growth and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/3701">19 U.S.C. 3701 et seq.</external-xref>), the United States imported $9,700,000,000 in goods and resources; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36B45E64F3A74209962B8C00BFA24717"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Prosper Africa and other similar Government initiatives are critical to building and strengthening ties between the United States and African businesses;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EBC02DD44A7477AB68B7490A1D6FBE0"><enum>(11)</enum><text>the total two-way goods trade with Sub-Saharan Africa totaled $47,500,000,000 in 2023, a 6.2 percent increase from $44,700,000,000 in 2021;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5C4006F4C3643CD833EF1B1BE1C49F7"><enum>(12)</enum><text>the African diaspora plays an invaluable role in shaping Government policy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E34A23D11944A6E9E6E496153B09435"><enum>(13)</enum><text>members of the African diaspora have an invaluable understanding of cross-cultural engagement between the United States and Africa, existing relations and networks on the African continent, and can support efforts to facilitate stronger people-to-people ties between the United States and Africa;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4F3B5072E5D46E2BC85BD78DE812F22"><enum>(14)</enum><text>the United States is committed to strengthening the government-to-government relationships between the United States and countries throughout the African continent;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A41321FD871497EBE583198CCBD2F4B"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Congress strongly supports the hosting of the second United States-Africa Leaders Summit by the United States, which was held in December 2022, to boost collaboration between the Government and the African diaspora community in the United States, and to strengthen ties between the United States and African nations by bringing together approximately 49 African heads of state;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AE117B905824514AA6A682DD188276A"><enum>(16)</enum><text>the African diaspora harbors a deep commitment to family and community, an enduring work ethic, and a perseverance to succeed and contribute to the society of the United States; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H249F22F1F2AC47B1BED30DF11620FB3B"><enum>(17)</enum><text>all members of the African diaspora in the United States deserve access to any Federal resources they are legally eligible to receive and freedom to participate in civil life in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H58611F92EBD54187AA385C9D6E31A904"><enum>(18)</enum><text>the African diaspora community significantly contributes to the growth and prosperity of the United States, and Congress honors this abundant and growing community.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H635A0B3FA15A4A75AEE56ACC084329B2"><enum>3.</enum><header>African Diaspora Heritage Month</header><subsection id="HA087E983F35643ED9ED3A867E04169D5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/36/1">Chapter 1</external-xref> of title 36, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2D70A1B367F4D53B4399F19D47D8A8F"><section id="H04E9433E6C9A4EEDBC3A87FB0D1F2215"><enum>149.</enum><header>African Diaspora Heritage Month</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President shall issue each year a proclamation—</text><paragraph id="H199F32F302EC44AFBA76B535696B919C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designating a month as African Diaspora Heritage Month;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC0F0D7F3ABF4E40B2B10D8317C92CAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calling on State and local governments and the people of the United States to observe African Diaspora Heritage Month with appropriate programs and activities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7BE1D4899C14B9BAC7ECCEB5E53248F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urging civil and educational authorities of States and local governments to observe African Diaspora Heritage Month through appropriate programs and activities.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HF1E4F65F1F594122B8B032C9996DC413"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/36/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of title 36, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/36/148">section 148</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1701A84C8FD5449CA9FA9C796A676542"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">149. African Diaspora Heritage Month.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

