<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3499FCD90A494452807BCF13DDA0F8A1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4005 IH: Utilize No Phones in Learning to Unleash Growth in Grades and Educate Distraction-free Schools Grant Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4005</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish the UNPLUGGED Schools Grant Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2EDE69EDD4B249DF8DB12AEFBFDF39A4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H553FBCC94C1C442D8AFF05978DA675B0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Utilize No Phones in Learning to Unleash Growth in Grades and Educate Distraction-free Schools Grant Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>UNPLUGGED Schools Grant Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBCC70F564DEE4B27B349C824EBA09387"><enum>2.</enum><header>UNPLUGGED Schools Grants</header> <subsection id="HE00A8BB6C73C40A4B2CF3610275FA5CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7101">20 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H82ED7136E5424A3181F749B637678ACF" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<part id="H55921EB4BCB34DEC98A640F18A6535DD"><enum>G</enum><header>UNPLUGGED Schools Grants.</header> 
<section id="H21243248CA5B417A8560E37051D1F98E"><enum>4701.</enum><header>Grant program authorized</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a grant program to be known as the <quote>Utilize No Phones in Learning to Unleash Growth in Grades and Educate Distraction-free Schools Grant Program</quote> or the <quote>UNPLUGGED Schools Grant Program</quote> to award grants to State educational agencies to support public schools with implementing a personal electronic device policy described in section 4702(a).</text></section> <section id="H1BFCD4F1B7864769BACC93BF3063EE55"><enum>4702.</enum><header>Eligibility</header> <subsection id="H5AF3FF7E0EC64401A1AAF2CD33648435"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Personal electronic device policy required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this part, a State educational agency shall be required to have in effect a policy, designed in coordination with each local educational agency served by the State educational agency and in consultation with educators, parents, and students, that applies to each public school served by each such local educational agency that prohibits student possession or use of personal electronic devices in public schools during school hours. Such policy may permit exceptions—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE10B5CCCEC404AF4871AAC23EE8222A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for students with health conditions that require the use of a mobile phone or other personal electronic device as part of a treatment or monitoring plan, as certified by a licensed healthcare provider;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF44749ADE604B169D03E5B3B3BA31E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for students with disabilities or special needs for whom access to a mobile phone or other personal electronic device is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H99F4150733DF4005B1B23E20CBE7601C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>documented as necessary in an individualized education program; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H00F4698729FF43319BD3A4BF1B820A9A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>included as part of services or accommodations provided to the student pursuant to section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>) (commonly referred to as a <quote>Section 504 plan</quote>);</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCEF80C47816B42069DBE0508983C960D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>on an individualized basis, for students—</text> <subparagraph id="HC1E62DCFC0B74E0E99A0F5EC96AFCB1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who are English learners;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H76CDB69391CA435AB00E6954DD923E9B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who have a demonstrated need for a personal electronic device to facilitate instruction; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5AA0F8CE71FF483A97CD931F8476246F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acquire documentation in support of subparagraph (A) and (B) in accordance with procedures established by the State educational agency; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H701945A60A684D0C9AD9E47C54A3B971"><enum>(4)</enum><text>for additional students as determined appropriate by State educational agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H00BDFD68E02443DEA93716453DC6F478"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this part shall be construed as preempting or otherwise preventing a State, State educational agency, local educational agency, or public school from enacting or enforcing policies or procedures regarding student possession or use of personal electronic devices during school hours, on school grounds, or during school activities that is more restrictive than a personal electronic device policy described in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H34CDC4F5F033406F828E08406B37B725"><enum>4703.</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this part, a State educational agency shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including—</text> <paragraph id="H414FD386E1D7442597501CFB8ABD61FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a certification that the State educational agency has in effect a personal electronic device policy that satisfies the requirements described in section 4702(a); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF2D9494E1B574FE486DECBD507C27599" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a certification that the State educational agency permits public schools and local educational agencies served by the State educational agency to develop policies and procedures that enable—</text> <subparagraph id="H64F07D390A17493D8811C6D27153865F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">parents to notify students through public school personnel about forgotten items, changes in pick-up times, and other common issues; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE4DF949D3C3A4EC4B58A085FF20087DC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">public school personnel to communicate with parents regarding time-sensitive matters.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H57C6378AA29F4A64BC16D4BA296AC2D0"><enum>4704.</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A State educational agency that receives a grant under this part shall use such grant to acquire secure storage methods for use at public schools for safely storing personal electronic devices in accordance with a personal electronic device policy described in section 4702(a).</text></section> 
<section id="H167FCCC4BD534860841800E2EB39C745"><enum>4705.</enum><header>Allocations to State educational agencies</header> 
<subsection id="H54C4F422E9664FD69FE220125322096C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the total amount appropriated under section 4707 for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall allot to each State educational agency that has an approved application for a grant under this part an amount that bears the same relationship to the remainder as the amount that the State of such State educational agency received under subpart 2 of part A of title I for the preceding fiscal year bears to the amount all States received under that subpart for the preceding fiscal year.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA326057133FE464DAE6748DB7D4F23FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Small State minimum</header><text>No State educational agency receiving an allotment under this paragraph shall receive less than one-half of 1 percent of the total amount allotted under this paragraph.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD3F2DF0E3944458AB318DDE2933C4577"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reallotment of unused funds</header><text>If a State educational agency does not receive an allotment under this part for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall reallot the amount of the allotment that such State educational agency would have received to the remaining State educational agencies in accordance with this part.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="H2171746DBD2C4D7D948508EC84B03285"><enum>4706.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this part:</text> 
<paragraph id="H52B5C5DAD0054A6CAEEC5189D6106D54"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Individualized education program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>individualized education program</term> has the meaning given such term in section 602(14) of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1401">20 U.S.C. 1401(14)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H88F1EA2876F24B9C83A8ACE15025AC4A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mobile phone</header><text>The term <term>mobile phone</term> means any handheld communication device with cellular, Wi-Fi, or Bluetooth capability, including smartphones and similar devices.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H09BAE37994D74ECB862A993FEC535317"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Personal electronic device</header> 
<subparagraph id="HB2039779CDA345D8B3C10E3E49EAE7C9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>personal electronic device</term>, when used with respect to a device possessed or used by a student, includes a mobile phone, smartwatch, laptop, tablet, and other handheld or wearable device with communication, internet, or multimedia capabilities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3D7E28149D034E9E8B26BA49FCB713B3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>personal electronic device</term> does not include a laptop or tablet that—</text> 
<clause id="HFCEFB6BFE3D8433BBD91EFDB7A4624A4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a student is authorized by the school of the student to use during school hours;</text></clause> <clause id="H1C870A7D798248E7BFCFDBE0736EEFDB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is used by such student only for instructional purposes; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="HDD3BE76F538F40938B4C2D1F361EBE94"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is restricted from accessing social media platforms, personal email, personal messaging applications, texting services, and other non-academic applications during school hours.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE05D75B118D248CA88BD5EC7F3103BBE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public school</header><text>The term <term>public school</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC553380652E142949530688CA0F82FD0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a public elementary school; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H378C8F1BB16A45A89B729707810BE5FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a public secondary school.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B46C45B28E443DEBDBB7ACE081DFE0E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>School hours</header><text>The term <term>school hours</term> means the period from the start of the instructional day (as defined by the State educational agency) until the end of the instructional day.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9EB40789F32D4DE5BFA764CDABF95365" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secure storage methods</header><text>The term <term>secure storage methods</term> means storage solutions that are designed to keep personal electronic devices safely and securely stored and to prevent students from accessing such devices during school hours without permission, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDC18A444AF6146D69FFBC6F18A335576" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>lockable lockers;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB4DD2E4A6C514EB0B282091927D2D73A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>secure lock boxes;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFA5E23D09BB34A49BAF99CFE6EABC33D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>magnetic pouches or other signal-blocking storage devices; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF4C38FE19D9E4356936FB4E586A5118A" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other storage solutions as determined appropriate by the State educational agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H7D80C74F97234EBB93DA7BC7165EDE38"><enum>4707.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To carry out this part, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary.</text></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H0CECFF0C1A5E47BFBACB674C58582186"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents in section 2 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 4644 the following new items:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC6D69732F1514DC28B6841FB85A09965"> 
<toc> 
<toc-entry bold="off" level="part">Part G—UNPLUGGED Schools Grants</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 4701. Grant program authorized.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 4702. Eligibility.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 4703. Application.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 4704. Use of funds.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 4705. Allocations to State educational agencies.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 4706. Definitions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 4707. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

