<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H943F9430AEF44BFD87FA3E8739401D9D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4843 IH: Combating Law Enforcement Anonymity by Requiring Identification Disclosure Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4843</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250801">August 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000635">Ms. Dexter</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide that no Federal funds made available to the Department of Homeland Security may be used to carry out any civil immigration enforcement activity under the immigration laws unless each officer conducting such an action is not wearing a mask or facial covering that hides the identity of the officer, and clearly identifies themselves verbally and visibly, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7C48EC1FAF4646769A43337402D2E414" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA61C19F4FA0E424DA885775B334E8CDF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Combating Law Enforcement Anonymity by Requiring Identification Disclosure Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CLEAR ID Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HBF8FCE5598B34282845879AAA47D00B3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H281D779946324D9CA63ECC52C7C46C39"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There has been an increase in reported incidents where individuals are illegally impersonating immigration enforcement officers, including but not limited to U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement officers across the country.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC4D6EE94787C4163B50B6892E121084A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On June 14, 2025, a man in Chicago, Illinois, was arrested after impersonating a U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement officer while possessing a loaded semi-automatic weapon without a concealed carry license.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF49B420C32954E10B2DE4421D0D57BDE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>On June 8, 2025, in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, a man was arrested after zip-tying a woman and stealing money from a business while impersonating a U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement officer.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H62266040C7C84C7ABC763B0890962834"><enum>(4)</enum><text>On April 10, 2025, a woman in Bay County, Florida, was arrested for abducting another woman while impersonating a U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement officer while concealing her identity with a face mask.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B859AE3F8814BE2A09C5288E3E0D7CC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>On January 29, 2025, a man in Sullivan’s Island, South Carolina, was arrested for detaining a group of men while impersonating a U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement officer.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB4C3ED5882DE49CD96EBAA17FF872875"><enum>(6)</enum><text>On January 26, 2025, a man in Raleigh, North Carolina, was arrested after sexually assaulting a woman while impersonating a U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement officer.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1B55FCB65AB43B0B41C0C87DB06314D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The impersonation of a law enforcement officer is a violation of Federal, State, and local laws. It erodes public trust in law enforcement and deters actually law enforcement officers from doing their jobs.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HC344AD9C6DF5447685F98E5EF2BBE40F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitation on use of funds by the Department of Homeland Security</header> 
<subsection id="HA09A9ED4B512467D85AA5ACDF766CE41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, and except as provided in subsection (b), no Federal funds made available to the Department of Homleand Security may be used to conduct a civil immigration enforcement action under the immigration laws (as such term is defined in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>)) unless each covered immigration officer conducting such an action—</text> <paragraph id="H8D51DA4ACA804020B1EDD47D139CCCAF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is not wearing a mask or facial covering that hides the identity of the officer;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H45F14CE0E1CD41F18C3B99003CACF97F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the officer uses a vehicle to conduct an official operation in connection with such action, uses only a vehicle that clearly identifies the name of the agency involved in the action; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C3D6B79D7E84E16BAC0F94B19D172A9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>clearly identifies themselves verbally and visibly by showing identification of the agency that the covered immigration officer represents or is conducting official business on behalf of, including visibly presenting a badge and wearing a uniform that represents the agency involved in the enforcement action.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6FF7496765B94E16A052103A5FF17CF3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) shall not apply if a mask or facial covering is medically necessary or is required to preserve the integrity of an ongoing undercover operation that has been approved in accordance with the criteria described in subsection (c).</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HF7D50A9B217440BF8B1685423D63C6DC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Criteria described</header><text>The criteria described in this subsection for the approval of an undercover operation are the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H76ED2C9BB69E47B5866EC031216102C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The risk of personal injury to individuals, property damage, financial loss to persons or businesses, damage to reputation, and other harm.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAE57187931AA48E6A14152ADE320F40C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The risk of civil liability or other loss to the Government.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB9D10CC4EACE4E04BB5C6CA2069A7DC2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The risk of invasion of privacy or interference with privileged or confidential relationships.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB2633264F2864F93B1D8899E62F12A42"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The risk that individuals engaged in the undercover operation may become involved conduct that is unlawful under Federal law.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H727EB25321A44C778B0BC232CC6BDF86"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The suitability of Government participation in the type of activity that is expected to occur during the operation.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8DC9F0033CD64343B271B1CA83916BF4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>The term <term>covered immigration officer</term> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="H03C72DC87C7542FEAEF5A46797ABDF41"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">personnel of U.S. Customs and Border Protection;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H897E66B80D514D538476FB0E66992567"><enum>(2)</enum><text>personnel of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7366A4A84689489CBD62A22FA71CF9F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">personnel of any other Federal, State, or local agency authorized by the Secretary of Homeland Security to conduct civil immigration enforcement actions under the immigration laws (as such term is defined in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

