<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8DE5C9F34E364B4F9669D58A6BC21B75" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3963 IH: Public Inspectors for Safe Infrastructure Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3963</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 23, United States Code, to require that public employees perform construction inspection work for federally funded highway projects, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFEB872E56E804F85AD9A7631A1681A24" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H337DCAA8060D42A3B3E90685A5DEF71C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Inspectors for Safe Infrastructure Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5AB6AAEBCEF04A86BEA6146352872BFB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring construction inspection services for certain highway contracts to be performed by public employees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 112(b) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H9C6C92C98A48439C8A8BFD053209F2FD" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<paragraph id="HD237BF8165244994B2CF876D0DFAB9FC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Construction inspection services</header>
<subparagraph id="H334840B77C934AD28C7903630D457722"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In entering into a contract under this section for the construction of a project subject to subsection (a), including a design-build project under paragraph (3) and a project using a 2-phase contract under paragraph (4), a State transportation department or local transportation agency shall ensure that a public employee performs construction inspection functions for such project.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3DD2BBBDD9E242DF91D16118C3FEBFFD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If a State transportation department or local transportation agency does not have adequate existing or obtainable staff to perform construction inspection functions as required under subparagraph (A), the department or agency may obtain such services pursuant to temporary consultant contracts until the department or agency has adequate or existing staff to perform such functions.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H25AE400A2EC24939958C712DDE50CB13"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Time period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any temporary contracts to provide construction inspection services under this subsection shall not exceed the period that ends on the date that is 12 months after the date on which the contract is awarded.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4EF64E13EF624D99A1E42C26E744F359"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Reporting and Transparency</header> <clause id="H4D7A2098F53F49EDB252BD720176442C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>At least once each fiscal year, a State transportation department or local transportation agency utilizing the exception authority provided in subparagraph (B) shall submit to the Secretary a report containing—</text>
<subclause id="HE1BC28A3B08743A7BB8F66FFCE7DDDF3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a description of all construction inspection functions provided through temporary consultant contracts under such clause; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H421C886A5EA445A5904752D33E34A260"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a detailed justification of the need for each exception to the requirement of such clause.</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="HCB6CA7A28CE048568D3A6D9B67108D62"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Transparency</header><text>The Secretary shall make the report submitted under clause (i) available to the public through the website of the Department.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H07B09277A5EF48C6869F2A739394FFB5"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text>
<clause id="H715DC399071648F6B0C9065C00A24138"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Construction inspection function</header><text>The term ‘construction inspection function’ includes construction engineering, contract administration, on-site quality control inspection, materials testing, and the functions of a resident engineer or assistant resident engineer responsible for the acceptance or rejection of a project subject to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section.</text></clause> <clause id="H658B9906291E4C2E9613CFC460038AD7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Public employee</header><text>The term <quote>public employee</quote> means an employee of the Federal Government, a State government, or a local government.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

