<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-PAT25609-4M8-3N-7G8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2901 IS: Safer Emergency and Evacuation Routes Response Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2901</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250918" legis-day="20250916">September 18 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Transportation to establish a pilot program to improve the integration of real-time wildfire hazard alerts with State and local transportation closure information systems, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safer Emergency and Evacuation Routes Response Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id824a9a9602cc4e4a86f9ec71100c16f5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program</header><subsection id="id389d1490e7184c18b1fe4b0d205d122a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the <term>Secretary</term>), in coordination with the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the Chief of the Forest Service, shall establish a voluntary pilot program (referred to in this section as the <term>pilot program</term>) to improve the integration of real-time wildfire hazard alerts with State and local transportation closure information systems.</text></subsection><subsection id="idbb273a129d784959a3a65dc0c35c7b0f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the pilot program shall be to assist participating States in automatically relaying information on roadway closures, detours, and evacuation routes to drivers during wildfire events by linking existing National Weather Service hazard alert products with State and local traffic management and traveler information systems.</text></subsection><subsection id="idda966e3584024d6b875e0b9a4ea240d2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Scope</header><paragraph id="id0cba1c4426d54195b00b62c2ba94c90f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Voluntary</header><text>Participation in the pilot program shall be voluntary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida34da376173145bfa559bdec46b0e0f9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section grants the Secretary or the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration any authority to make or direct roadway closure decisions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id992f8f5fe56242b1a651d9738b8a7f04"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the pilot program—</text><subparagraph id="id94e9204794234e15ad1e3164c8579736"><enum>(A)</enum><text>uses existing data standards and formats to the maximum extent practicable;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideee62ed9039a4a9cb3621a9e91d67da8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not require States to adopt uniform systems or centralized infrastructure; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3b473ca052574024a74b02a2186f5136"><enum>(C)</enum><text>allows participating States flexibility to tailor integration to their existing traffic management systems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida1b0259f9cb34e0a9fcb354b85f24018"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The Secretary may carry out the pilot program using amounts otherwise available for surface transportation research and development under section 503(b) of title 23, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="id5392ea0652d7429c97a41d6d006269af"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>Not later than 2 years after implementation of the pilot program, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report evaluating the pilot program and the effectiveness of the pilot program in improving the timeliness and accuracy of wildfire-related driver notifications.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

