<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB058CF67F90F4F14958C4438C97B0D54" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 652 IH: To recognize and honor the heroes of the Fort Stewart, Georgia, shooting on August 6, 2025.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 652</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250815">August 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To recognize and honor the heroes of the Fort Stewart, Georgia, shooting on August 6, 2025.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Fort Stewart was established in 1940 and named in honor of General Daniel Stewart, a native of Liberty County, who fought in the Revolution;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, since its founding, Fort Stewart has been a steadfast cornerstone of Liberty County and the surrounding communities, serving as a source of pride and partnership between soldiers and civilians alike;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on August 6, 2025, a gunman launched a sudden and unprovoked attack against soldiers on base, with the intent to cause harm and fear;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, during this attack, 6 courageous soldiers acted decisively and without hesitation in the face of danger to subdue the gunman, thereby allowing medical personnel to administer timely aid to the wounded;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, through their bravery, these soldiers ensured that no lives were lost during the attack and that the assailant was apprehended without further harm;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on August 6, 2025, these 6 heroes ran toward danger and put their own safety at risk to protect others, exemplifying the highest ideals of military service by going above and beyond their call of duty;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas their swift, selfless actions saved countless lives;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the soldiers are First Sgt. Joshua Arnold, Master Sgt. Justin Thomas, Staff Sgt. Melissa Taylor, Staff Sgt. Robert Pacheco, Sgt. Aaron Turner, and Sgt. Eve Rodarte; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas our thoughts and prayers are with those injured in the attack, wishing them a full and speedy recovery, and we express our deep thankfulness to the brave soldiers whose actions prevented further harm: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H544B55C25F2E46AE9C31AFFE6DA00381"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H6E1D5C31AB1D4763BD816C2B1EAF156E"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H403F1C8D76A8415C82FCAF51E51A59DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes and honors the brave soldiers of Fort Stewart for their courage and sacrifice to stop the shooter and protect their fellow brothers and sisters in arms—</text> <subparagraph id="HB3D7D96212774E16A24DDE6790AD8A3E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">First Sgt. Joshua Arnold;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H752A80023A8B499FACF4A900FFE8965A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Master Sgt. Justin Thomas;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBA22C2AA4897476D97D533E6D6C48A2C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Staff Sgt. Melissa Taylor;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7CACF1B1148E4F408AFEF7B08723F011"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Staff Sgt. Robert Pacheco;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H817F04F243184A86B99D0009E71EDEA9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Sgt. Aaron Turner; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H84784847B8C747D58267C4993D9DC2C1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Sgt. Eve Rodarte; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF5C281FF50484AFC852395D11427BBBA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">extends its heartfelt wishes for a swift and full recovery to all of those who were injured in the attack.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

