<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-NEW25881-1J3-DT-G81"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 415 ATS: Designating the week of September 21 through September 27, 2025, as “Gold Star Families Remembrance Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 415</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250919" legis-day="20250916">September 19 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating the week of September 21 through September 27, 2025, as <quote>Gold Star Families Remembrance Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the last Sunday in September—</text><paragraph id="idB338DA6C79814BD2A789446C8F50131A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is designated as <quote>Gold Star Mother’s Day</quote> under section 111 of title 36, United States Code; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2EE78DBB8FE346DEA274D268A6347AD0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>was first designated as <quote>Gold Star Mother’s Day</quote> under the Joint Resolution entitled <quote>Joint Resolution designating the last Sunday in September as <quote>Gold Star Mother's Day</quote>, and for other purposes</quote>, approved June 23, 1936 (49 Stat. 1895);</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there is no date dedicated to families affected by the loss of a loved one who died in service to the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a gold star symbolizes a family member who died in the line of duty while serving in the Armed Forces;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the members and veterans of the Armed Forces, through their service, bear the burden of protecting the freedom of the people of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the selfless example of the service of the members and veterans of the Armed Forces, as well as the sacrifices made by the families of those individuals, inspires all individuals in the United States to sacrifice and work diligently for the good of the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the sacrifices of the families of the fallen members of the Armed Forces and the families of veterans of the Armed Forces should never be forgotten: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id54d4dd0e851f4b0891a2c220e7537963"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates the week of September 21 through September 27, 2025, as <quote>Gold Star Families Remembrance Week</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id65c441ed71ed4b75b9af2daa192e27ac"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors and recognizes the sacrifices made by—</text><subparagraph id="id6B4B3CF941C94BE08F3CEF59BC81596B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the families of members of the Armed Forces who made the ultimate sacrifice in order to defend freedom and protect the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4EF6E2082B95495A83A2A5AECC115077"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the families of veterans of the Armed Forces; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id96d0ab4ed3ab43ef84b98f617aeec61f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to observe Gold Star Families Remembrance Week by—</text><subparagraph id="id15b30b837cab46d7b400b85cb7a86c86"><enum>(A)</enum><text>performing acts of service and good will in their communities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida201010903d74a3d8df40cdc422b58ab"><enum>(B)</enum><text>celebrating families in which loved ones made the ultimate sacrifice so that others could continue to enjoy life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

