<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB2756BC63AB3402B8CB2EB447486E024" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4958 IH: Grocery Reform And Safety Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4958</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250812">August 12, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require notification to the Food and Drug Administration prior to use of substances as generally recognized as safe, reassessment of the safety of certain substances marketed as generally recognized as safe, provide resources for reviews and reassessments, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H2B8A299B810F430C8E61F93472000659" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H389AC7179FF748CCA94B51A56BDE50BE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Grocery Reform And Safety Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GRAS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3DFACDB2DC9E4E219B753094AAE1E945" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Removal of GRAS exemption from food additive definition</header> <subsection id="HA464D7475D9B4682A8EFEA891282E75F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 201(s) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321(s)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6CF6AEE4C8E94E329BCA162E5C3CC460"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (1) through (6) as clauses (A) through (G), respectively;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HBED84A42C4E9470EAECBCDEE18CBDABF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The term <term>food additive</term></quote> and inserting <quote>(1) The term <term>food additive</term></quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0EC86A8CC6D349EFA75DFAB5A0F84869"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, if such substance is</quote> and all that follows through <quote>of its intended use;</quote> and inserting <quote>, including a substance that is generally recognized as safe,</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H636FB1C5C3E84D389A86DA7EB27BBA42"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="traditional" id="H9B7CF5090C524270BB56B123122E301C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="HD040967E2F9D456892D9D69D5DA89628" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>generally recognized as safe</term> means, with respect to a substance used in food as described in subparagraph (1), that such substance is generally recognized, among experts qualified by scientific training and experience to evaluate its safety, as having been adequately shown through scientific procedures (or, in the case of a substance used in food prior to January 1, 1958, through either scientific procedures or experience based on common use in food) to be safe under the conditions of its intended use. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7120A2AF5D414E4CAC05F3F8728D0493"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 408(k)(2) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/346a">21 U.S.C. 346a(k)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 201(s)(4)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 201(s)(1)(D)</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H1825FEC0A0C24F7EA667D09D112C6396"><enum>3.</enum><header>GRAS notifications</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 409 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/348">21 U.S.C. 348</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC923EE1C394F476BBE76A0EA43B3F121"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1D2202E37407459395E917ED07DB603B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking the <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7B41FEEAB9D5462CB507F814255CA8DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H38DDF6FD89544BD3B1B791B82C5EEC5E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H94942B4654E24EAABBC1DFA7216238CA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H9E784334651D40178F11695520C2CC1D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the food additive is generally recognized as safe, and the procedural requirements of subsection (l) have been met with respect to the food additive.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H519EF4D24FA247F88DDAD4FF9C39FA52"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDEDBD6AA687C4731A7C9D006CB3D5BDF" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H0D7344BB57C148049E02C82392A89113"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Notices regarding use of GRAS substances</header> <paragraph id="HB6FAD8C595CD4203B82D0B14157B08D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person that manufactures, introduces, delivers for introduction, or receives a food substance in interstate commerce that is intending to treat such food substance as generally recognized as safe (in this subsection referred to as <quote>GRAS</quote>) shall, with respect to any new use of such substance or use of a food substance that was not marketed for use in foods in the United States before the date of enactment of this subsection, submit to the Secretary a notice prescribing the conditions under which such person determined such substance is GRAS.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6D60EFB690A348FBAC659F8B5931291E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required information</header><text>A notice submitted under paragraph (1) with respect to a food substance shall include publicly available supporting data and information sufficient to demonstrate the identity and composition, the manufacturing process, the intended effect, and the safety of the food substance, used as the basis of the GRAS determination, including full reports of investigations made with respect to the safety for use of such substance, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HBB945821FA58400C91AFA908C38D7DB8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information as to the methods and controls used in conducting such investigations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE6ABD9F1ADA7495CB675DA6A97E34225"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information on the cumulative effects of such substance;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF1CBE012AA9041D8BC9554ACA4FFFC17"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information on hazard, dose response, and exposure;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3AB57B10ED0E4ADA835629F81F97883C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>information on the application of adequately protective safety factors to ensure an appropriate margin of safety to take into account uncertainties in hazard identification, dose response, exposure, and sensitivities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC9134882E7404639B0E59CBC37C9BEE5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>information demonstrating the analysis that the weight of the evidence shows that such substance has not been found to be carcinogenic;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB3E49961E1224D69BD7976D1B4EFF38E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>information demonstrating the analysis that the weight of the evidence shows that such substance has not been found to induce reproductive toxicity or developmental toxicity in humans or animals, including through an endocrine mode of action; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H23C64AD508C6440FA3F19262C38C47FF"><enum>(G)</enum><text>such other information that forms the recognition of safety as the Secretary may publicly specify.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0D23DC03C04749E2B4EF663F5731A526"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form of notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A notice submitted under paragraph (1) with respect to a food substance shall be submitted in such form and manner as specified in subpart E of part 170 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC6E9FAC77C094E79A9C2B4F545906D42"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Statement not to object to use</header><text>A person may use a substance subject to a notice under paragraph (1) only if the Secretary has issued a written statement to not object to the determination that the substance is GRAS under the conditions prescribed in the notice.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7AE3E9D9C81C4A70A47AAEF81BF36E56"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Statement to object</header><text>The Secretary shall issue a written statement objecting to use of a substance subject to a notice under paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines that—</text> <subparagraph id="H6D60C189D4914CE481FAA1F7CD0B7F4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the notice does not contain the supporting data and information described in paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDECE02B1BFBB4E629DC58EDD63BF5CEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to any such supporting data and information that was provided by an expert, such expert appears to have a conflict of interest, as determined pursuant to guidance issued by the Secretary; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H54E3DAB7857F4131A19F29E3166E24C0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such supporting data and information does not adequately support a determination that the substance is GRAS under the conditions prescribed in the notice.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H73C3616684B84543996FBF527284CD38"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Determination timeline</header> 
<subparagraph id="H623F71A07B2E493C8EF7787D00B61B2E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <clause id="HD1325179A638475BA8FEF112A14A9952"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 180 days after the acceptance of a notice under paragraph (1), issue a written statement under paragraph (4) or (5); or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD8E931A4C35A4895BCF11DC1EE750AB4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide written notice to extend the 180-day period described in subparagraph (A) for one additional 90-day period, as specified in regulations.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H85E3D84EA90049FA9951518D3F6456AE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Corrections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The timeline set forth in subparagraph (A) shall not be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary to correct a statement of the Secretary to not object to the determination that the substance is GRAS if new evidence is subsequently presented or discovered.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB723A5920AD4F1EB5ACE02CEC9092E6"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Public availability and comment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H9F23BF586A0B451888BB85335BD421D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon acceptance of a notice under paragraph (1)—</text> 
<clause id="H3BA0268B92F7463FBB62A2B3707F972B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>make such notice, and the supporting data and information described in paragraph (2), publicly available in a single location on the website of the Food and Drug Administration; and</text></clause> <clause id="HFDAF06CC38D848829BA847A84FFF2B08"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide an opportunity for public comment for a period of not less than 60 days; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7919826C0A4D49E29A7DCC20FAF633E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon close of the comment period, make any written statement issued under paragraph (4) or (5) publicly available in the same location.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9110260F7AE4C59B409D015504501CB"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HC3A1239B5A894DD39C2F8EA27A3F98D8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reassessments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 409 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/348">21 U.S.C. 348</external-xref>), as amended by section 3, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H65A285AAE24440F7BE433E37D796591D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HF3F3ACD0EA9245BE8DFD9AF8D51A6165"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Reassessments</header> <paragraph id="H5D58895563E949C0BD547126B1FC2B6F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this subsection, and at least every 3 years thereafter, the Secretary shall systematically reassess the safety (including the safety of conditions of use), within the meaning of section 409, of at least 10 of the following substances (or classes thereof):</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6C00AF62B8DD4EC586DE50F0AD6B8100"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Food additives marketed pursuant to an order under subsection (c).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H391283ECF3D540A2AD1FF61B4EB8E03F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any substance which was, before the date of the enactment of this subsection, considered generally recognized as safe.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H42C95CEBCB9E4B039C9FBE7E79C12328"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Color additives.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H93620D3ECD514BD99863CB3686643B42"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior-sanctioned substances (as described in subparagraph (D) of section 201(s)(1)).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H82562FC0C2A843E0A91EE12245FCA01B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Food contact substances.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H62F2AA59936B444AAFD4EE89D83F6BE2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Safety evaluations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the reassessments under this subsection, the Secretary may require any person that manufactures, introduces, delivers for introduction, or receives a food substance described in paragraph (1) in interstate commerce to conduct, and submit to the Secretary, safety evaluations of such substance. Such a safety evaluation shall include, with respect to such substance, updated information on—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2EE11171C553431FA6EB012F217D3B02"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>estimates of dietary exposure among the United States population;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDF3ABA45DF6446E4B3DF6821820E1221" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the cumulative effects of such substance;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H098FC4F7ABE042B8A72EBD917E1B61A4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>hazard, dose response, and exposure;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC48FEDD658CD4A6396503A7C635DA6C6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the application of adequately protective safety factors to ensure an appropriate margin of safety to take into account uncertainties in hazard identification, dose response, exposure, and sensitivities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7EDC00B6250D4E3BBB326B97ADABD94D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>whether the weight of the evidence shows that such substance has not been found to be carcinogenic;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H440F464794E4439C91737D87395AAAAA"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the weight of the evidence shows that such substance has not been found to induce reproductive toxicity or developmental toxicity in humans or animals, including through an endocrine mode of action; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5EEA4CBD80684756B090622BF2B7AABA"><enum>(G)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may specify in regulation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A8B8C3181DE4103839295F906E2C267"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Revoking statement to not object</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines, with respect to a substance described in paragraph (1)(B), based on information received under paragraph (2) and publicly available information, that a concern about the safety of the substance, or the intended use of the substance, exists, the Secretary—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8DF4620662364451B7B2D773DF1261A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may revoke a written statement previously issued by the Secretary to not object to a determination that the substance is generally recognized as safe; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB6D63D7D53C54DEA8CE0DBF8D6D432FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall post such revocation in the location on the website of the Food and Drug Administration referred to in subsection (l)(7).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A5F2719AB8C4CA6AAEDC775C9992776"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notices of substances marketed as GRAS</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may require a person that manufactures, introduces, delivers for introduction, or receives a food substance described in paragraph (1) in interstate commerce that was marketed as generally recognized as safe before, on, and after the date of enactment of this subsection to submit to the Secretary a notification that such person so marketed the substance as generally recognized as safe.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9272B62702D9407BA2AD0B9FA6985A75"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Civil monetary penalties</header><text>In the case of a violation of this subsection, the Secretary shall assess a civil penalty in accordance with section 307.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H16543C235532460B9A7DB8380D925064"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph> </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HE958375F9A0B40778C40D619AC8222AB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header> <subsection id="H8935E38809CC499D93EF658F44BD1F16"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 409 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/348">21 U.S.C. 348</external-xref>), as amended by sections 3 and 4, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCC13F89F8DB14A718D4B80290F16273A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H04044246C6D44C5BB9633E419D03E412"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HB556D7E0928744D1837E98F8C58AED8E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Carcinogenic</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>carcinogenic</term> means, with respect to a substance, that such substance has been found—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFA1BB10A4D6142858E95832C9E779D74"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to induce cancer when ingested by humans or animals; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5B8D4CFAE82342B3BD855D58CC259D1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">after evaluation through appropriate testing methods, by research or assessment conducted by an authoritative scientific body (such as the Environmental Protection Agency, the International Agency for Research on Cancer, or the National Toxicology Program), to induce cancer in humans or animals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA3F659B6122D44D88443730892B700BF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Class</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>class</term>, with respect to a substance, means a group of chemicals that are chemically similar or cause similar or related pharmacological effects.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H91E6F74B79F7494F90C6B3D2C6DC3EAC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conflict of interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>conflict of interest</term> means a personal or financial interest that could potentially compromise the professional judgment or objectivity of an individual in designing, conducting, reporting, or reviewing research or the applicability of research, potentially undermining the integrity of such research.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDC23B0A588414045A6933D6EBEA71D41"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Cumulative effects</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>cumulative effects</term> means, with respect to a substance, the combined health effects of all chemically or pharmacologically-related substances.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H18C6BDCB64FB41CBA9981033E150789C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Developmental toxicity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>developmental toxicity</term> means, with respect to the effect of exposure to a substance on a human or animal, an adverse effect on the development of such human or animal that results from such exposure—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H37E50DA04946449E89D85876A65AAA66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to the mother prior to conception of, or during the prenatal period for, such human or animal; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDD91816F844B4558B8391EAC6C3228EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to such human or animal before the time of sexual maturity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5DF7303AB6F24DFB82D6662FB65B8C68"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Food contact substance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>food contact substance</term> means any substance intended for use as a component of materials used in manufacturing, packing, packaging, transporting, or holding food if such use is not intended to have any technical effect in such food.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73A3E048177E4B3FA1BE207D5CAF59AA" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>New use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>new use</term> means a use other than—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4DB0F972BDD945969D6235B7BBAA4C4B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a use of a substance generally recognized as safe before, on, and after the date of enactment of this subsection;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF4343B0DB0C54D0EB5DFD04D7697563B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a use of a substance treated as generally recognized as safe under subsection (l); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCE02A259957F470E8C6958FCEC887280" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a use of a prior-sanctioned substance (as described in subparagraph (D) of section 201(s)(1)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A947E9629A847679AF13C2A909AB999"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Reproductive toxicity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>reproductive toxicity</term> means, with respect to the effect of exposure to a substance on a human or animal, an adverse effect on the reproductive system of such human or animal, which may include alterations to reproductive system development, the endocrine system, fertility, pregnancy, pregnancy outcomes, or modifications in other functions that are dependent on the integrity of the reproductive system.</text> </paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HB268577F585641F884E16AB9364ED3A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="HD27A9430A28444E2AE6C348BBBEA2CBB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 201(q)(1)(B)(ii) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321(q)(1)(B)(ii)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 409(h)(6)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 409(n)</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF2B5838563548358E36DDE52F5E5029"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 409(h) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/348">21 U.S.C. 348(h)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (6).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H08743E04CB7243ACA3C2C95982954D3E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Food additive and GRAS substance fees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 743 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/379j-31">21 U.S.C. 379j–31</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1CF3369CF96E4AE7AF572A85C2BF03E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBFDA3C3EA8034BA8A007F2550C6E28E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE4A2C646E8D49B383172F91D5F8A0D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC638C14329CF4A7397B78F9AC436706C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6652C272C0644F02ACF1C41094FC9149" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H75C5D151B08240549583E7E21851BC91"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each person filing a petition or submitting a notice with respect to a food additive, for purposes of issuing regulations or reviewing notices under section 409 prescribing the conditions under which such food additive may be safely used; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H448698EEE9744FD0A037B7BB71003821"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each person that manufactures, introduces, delivers for introduction, or receives a food substance in interstate commerce that is subject to a reassessment under subsection (m) of section 409, for purposes of conducting such reassessment.</text></subparagraph> <after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H37B60CDF59A54965BA7C9713649C5568"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEB4BDECBA4744E2EAFF1019A72F3A395"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)(A)—</text> <clause id="HE9DCD5F71E6A4F86BE638C130CD5196B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA3AFB10FA74D43C9A3DE4195F825C882"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (iv), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF41DD1C2B9384010B2BFE5B48239D13A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC3104460B53D471AB21CCFF708D763C6" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<clause id="H89F6BC71C4504BD29E6064EFC782E1EE"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under subparagraph (E) or (F) of subsection (a)(1) for a fiscal year shall be based on the Secretary’s estimate of 100 percent of the costs of the activities described in such subparagraph (E) or (F) for such year.</text></clause> <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H888799FB95224C138441910F2FC1E818"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>clause (i), (ii), (iii), and (iv)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>clause (i), (ii), (iii), (iv), and (v)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H224B45E6FF3C415D8B39BAE0B215C68E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <subparagraph id="H92647D457CC9491DA9FE6A4EFC2C1641"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> 
<clause id="HC8D02CFD4AA940DEBDD4E0292E9FA903"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>fiscal year 2010</quote> and inserting <quote>fiscal year 2026</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H759A710C93F54960981B3E61B0AA1149"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>fiscal year 2009</quote> and inserting <quote>fiscal year 2025</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4C44D6D80FAC40D6A10404EE14DFFDDA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(B), by striking <quote>fiscal year 2009</quote> and inserting <quote>fiscal year 2025</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

