<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB35DCEAD05E4488D96A8803847D9580D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1063 IH: Farm Credit Administration Independent Authority Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1063</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250206">February 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001307">Mr. Baird</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000470">Mrs. Fischbach</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To affirm that the Farm Credit Administration is the sole and independent regulator of the Farm Credit System.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H40E552E081F3413BB2B1837F0592240F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H41E39626BE6640D1A837351023487B69" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Farm Credit Administration Independent Authority Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCD4E6FF838154FBA80E8C4F66238EFCD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Farmer loan data collection</header> <subsection id="HF0B6E84E972C4480929F3F5120AF94D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Farm Credit Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/2001">12 U.S.C. 2001 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 4.19 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H1C86D0A1283F4F4293E34E159B195808" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA09118EA3FCF427F8345A4A69CB49940"><enum>4.20.</enum><header>Small farmer loan data collection</header> 
<subsection id="HF114B0D9264B49C2B531A911D1AB44AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to affirm that the Farm Credit Administration is the sole and independent regulator of the Farm Credit System.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB92CA204DF464C4F8C2D126675BCC91D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>small farmer</term> means a <quote>small farmer, rancher, or producer or harvester of aquatic products</quote> as defined pursuant to section 4.19.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H490F672036B8486988BE584A93456A51"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Collection of demographic data by Farm Credit System lenders</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, Farm Credit System institutions, pursuant to regulations promulgated by the Farm Credit Administration, shall—</text> <paragraph id="H8727050A670346BC93271C9A7134C719"><enum>(1)</enum><text>request that loan applicants and borrowers that are small farmers disclose information identifying their race, sex, and ethnicity;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A1B6AC0DFB94C5E85E399311973393B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>collect and maintain the information resulting from the requests; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2691ECC870CD40CAA3B11CAB95D76C5F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>report to the Farm Credit Administration on an annual basis the information collected pursuant to the requests.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEEC463A1F88C49F8B5D339B91A0F6012"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Directions to the Farm Credit Administration</header><text>The Farm Credit Administration—</text> <paragraph id="HD63D983A68B14D37BBC642B77B3E0F28"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall collect the information gathered by Farm Credit System institutions under this section and make the information available to the public on an annual basis; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE88B6820095C40F9AC068B5AE30B1E6C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not require, in prescribing regulations to implement this section, that any Farm Credit System institution contradict the wishes of a customer who does not wish to voluntarily report race, sex, or ethnicity by requiring the Farm Credit System institution to report the race, sex, or ethnicity of the customer based on visual observation, surname, or any other method.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF9F084E94ECD4CCD8102E2337B0622D6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Protection of personally identifiable information</header><text>In reporting the information collected under this section, the Farm Credit Administration shall not include any information that would reveal the identify of any loan applicant or borrower.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1685660CF205423880328492F12AAD5E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall apply only to applications received and loans made 1 year or more after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="HEDC1A16E910449D683FE56AD0DD52C42"><enum>3.</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 704B(h)(1) of the Equal Credit Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1691c-2">15 U.S.C. 1691c–2(h)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, other than any entity that is supervised by the Farm Credit Administration</quote> before the period at the end.</text></section> 
<section id="HB6E15FE0FB0B48FCB732577598EB28C1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Cessation of compliance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If financial institutions subject to subpart B of part 1002 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, are not required to comply with the rule promulgated pursuant to that subpart, whether because a court invalidates the rule or the rule is otherwise repealed, the Farm Credit System institutions shall not be required to comply with any regulation promulgated pursuant to the amendments made by this Act.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

