<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB59BE74D23994264A474C539B5745685" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 819 IH: Recognizing the contributions made to the United States by the Indian American diaspora and condemning recent acts of racism against Indian Americans.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 819</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251017">October 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the contributions made to the United States by the Indian American diaspora and condemning recent acts of racism against Indian Americans.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the partnership between India and the United States, based on shared principles of democracy, religious pluralism, human rights, freedom, and the rule of law, stands as one of the most important democratic partnerships in the world;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the strong and mutually beneficial people-to-people ties between India and the United States are the backbone of this partnership;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Indian diaspora, a community of over 5,200,000 in the United States, has excelled in all areas of United States life, with over 77 percent of Americans of Indian heritage attaining college degrees and serving in public life, as elected officials, lawyers, doctors, nurses, judges, members of law enforcement, teachers, diplomats, businessmen, and members of the Armed Forces;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Indian Americans come from a variety of vibrant and diverse religious backgrounds including Hindu, Sikh, Muslim, Christian, Buddhist, and Jain communities;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Indian Americans continue to face hate incidents, often fueled by racism, religious intolerance, misinformation, inflammatory rhetoric, and racial scapegoating; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas anti-Hindu and anti-Indian sentiment has also surged online, with South Asians, including Hindus and Sikhs, experiencing a doubling of reported harassment incidents, corresponding with heightened visibility of Indian Americans in national politics: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas> </preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HC0B1B1EA5D5C4B68A5102018B36CB2DF"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H678245DA748F49D3B70151826F1ABCBA"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H197849DBF2244C13A053B12649EC691A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes Indian Americans and their contributions to the strength of America;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE3EF89F272CB470F8813962325AC1428"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acknowledges the people-to-people bonds of friendship between India and the United States Indian American diaspora;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88F763FF96874D90A936E1E0FF555C61"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the monumental role played by Americans of Indian heritage and their profound impact on the cultural, economic, and scientific advancement of the Nation; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF76A9A54656E463590CB5CC7910849D1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>condemns all acts of hate, discrimination, and violence against Indian Americans and the broader South Asian community, including those targeted for their Hindu, Sikh, Jain, Muslim, or other religious or cultural identity.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

