<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H74302364C72F472392742A4A9C8188FC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5331 IH: Auto Bailout Accident Victims Recovery Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5331</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250911">September 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To waive the statute of limitations for cases against the government related to the General Motors bailout that were filed on or before July 9, 2015, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H44411BF170014A52B1FA1E48843EE29F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H91ADE7089266469FAFD75B246F15BF66" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Auto Bailout Accident Victims Recovery Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9160733A96BE4B46B3DE284B07E3A2E1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Settlement of accident victim litigation related to the General Motors bailout; Waiver of statute of limitations</header> <subsection id="HDB29AC847AC34F32BFB70A3AEB7BE4D4"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any eligible civil action arising from the filing of an eligible complaint alleging a violation of the takings clause of amendment V to the United States Constitution is not subject to any statute of limitations.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC702579B5DE140869DEBFCA038B6387D"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The United States shall pay just compensation to an eligible claimant, consistent with amendment V to the Constitution of the United States, to resolve an eligible claim. Just compensation payments to eligible claimants shall be made pursuant to section 1304 of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB6686832ED7F498B9472DBBA46653FD7"><enum>(c)</enum><text>If a settlement agreement has not been submitted to the court presiding over an eligible complaint within 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall submit a report to Congress describing the reasons why a settlement agreement was not reached with counsel of record to an eligible complaint.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HCDE3E8602EBD481DBC9829102AB786D1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, the following definitions shall apply:</text> <paragraph id="HD8CDACB7F45A49E08FD53D5B6E3DE333"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>eligible claim</quote> means a claim asserted in an eligible complaint on behalf of all eligible claimants.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3DFBC0935EE14CF19EE818472B9E414A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>eligible claimant</quote> means a plaintiff, class member, or putative class member represented in an eligible complaint who holds an eligible claim and who filed a proof of claim in the bankruptcy case captioned In re Motors Liquidation Company, et al., No. 09–50026 (Bankr. S.D.N.Y), based on death or personal injuries that were caused by or attributable to alleged defects in motor vehicles designed for operation on public roadways, or by the component parts of such motor vehicles, and in each case, manufactured, sold, or delivered by General Motors Corporation or any of its subsidiaries on or before June 1, 2009.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB5FC25721E7B42CAA5A7149E377DFD93"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>eligible complaint</quote> means the complaint filed with the United States Court of Federal Claims by or on behalf of eligible claimants on July 9, 2015, captioned Campbell, et al., v. United States, No. 15–717, alleging violation by the United States of amendment V to the Constitution in connection with the acquisition on July 10, 2009, by NGMCO, Inc., a United States Treasury-sponsored entity, of substantially all the assets of General Motors Corporation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA861E15F580242328D74F4483BAE7DBB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <quote>just compensation</quote> means payment of a lump-sum amount equal to the sum of—</text> <subparagraph id="H9C21A4B1109240B3A7FB382E2AFF4ED4"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>2.5 times the <quote>allowed amount</quote> listed on the final claims register filed on June 3, 2021, in the In re Motors Liquidation Company et al. bankruptcy case in respect of a proof of claim filed by or on behalf of an eligible claimant, plus</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF0BF3AF5AF464DDBA7971C19939ED2A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">interest thereon from July 10, 2009, to the effective date of settlement at a rate of three and one-half percent (3.5 percent) per annum, compounded quarterly, plus</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE5D0313884AF4CB8B66453B64319FF2D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reasonable court-approved fees and costs to counsel of record on the eligible complaint, all without offset of any kind.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

