<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KIN25335-5XT-GC-5M7">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1782 IS: Charlotte Woodward Organ Transplant Discrimination Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 1782</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250515">May 15, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S439">Mrs. Moody</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of
                    Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr.
                    Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, and
                    <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>) introduced the following
                bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and
                Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To prohibit discrimination on the basis of mental or physical disability in
            cases of organ transplants.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H4701E966FCE9450E8C7516E019C87C4B">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="H9A10839C73744332ADA76070D1352EE3">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Charlotte Woodward Organ Transplant Discrimination Prevention Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="HE45E1EEDBE634F3E9A949026BD43587E">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H362E0C6C2F1B43CBB3B5EB7541C81C2D"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Auxiliary aids and services</header> <text>The term <term>auxiliary aids and services</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12103">42 U.S.C. 12103</external-xref>).</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HCABBA8EBBF9E46939D4DF71D6680C661">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Covered entity</header>
 <text>The term <term>covered entity</term> means any licensed provider of health care services (including licensed health care practitioners, hospitals, nursing facilities, laboratories, intermediate care facilities, psychiatric residential treatment facilities, institutions for individuals with intellectual or developmental disabilities, and prison health centers), and any transplant hospital (as defined in section 121.2 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations or a successor regulation), that—</text>
                <subparagraph id="H69778A6A9FCC423FB1DEB31F89057350">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>is in interstate commerce; or</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA853FDA167A44275A198DEA367518E28"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>provides health care services in a manner that—</text>
                    <clause id="H39AAB48749DC4C509C47A1BDCBBB8E46">
                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>substantially affects or has a substantial relation to interstate commerce; or</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="H512BF57784614CA8B6557FA07E3C6B91">
                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>includes use of an instrument (including an instrument of transportation or communication) of interstate commerce.</text>
                    </clause>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H1FB065960777456FB9ECA723265B8482">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Disability</header>
 <text>The term <term>disability</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</external-xref>).</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H215A2D65CBFB4DF2BEAD45660BB59AE3">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Human organ</header>
 <text>The term <term>human organ</term> has the meaning given the term in section 301(c) of the National Organ Transplant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/274e">42 U.S.C. 274e(c)</external-xref>).</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H80B8F18A2F424DD1BB243CC0196D852C">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Organ transplant</header>
 <text>The term <term>organ transplant</term> means the transplantation or transfusion of a donated human organ into the body of another human for the purpose of treating a medical condition.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HE823CCDB988B44169678E2C98F9AD5FB">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <header>Qualified individual</header>
 <text>The term <term>qualified individual</term> means an individual who, with or without a support network, provision of auxiliary aids and services, or reasonable modifications to policies or practices, meets eligibility requirements for the receipt of a human organ.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H2C98CB87D8674C20A04D99A2F5C7AC3E">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
                <header>Reasonable modifications to policies or practices</header>
 <text>The term <term>reasonable modifications to policies or practices</term> includes—</text>
                <subparagraph id="HA1B3E7EB525A4B4BA712634475FC4968">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>communication with persons responsible for supporting a qualified individual with postsurgical or other care following an organ transplant or related services, including support with medication;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H548D2DABD6FE403F9BA0E590FC985FFE">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>consideration, in determining whether a qualified individual will be able to comply with health requirements following an organ transplant or receipt of related services, of support networks available to the qualified individual, including family, friends, and providers of home and community-based services, including home and community-based services funded through the Medicare or Medicaid program under title XVIII or XIX, respectively, of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>, 1396 et seq.), another health plan in which the qualified individual is enrolled, or any program or source of funding available to the qualified individual; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HFF0B3846D59E4F02A0CBD43241B5F14D">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>the use of supported decision-making, when needed, by a qualified individual.</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H315B3B2D46F64F4889200738DA9DFEBA">
                <enum>(8)</enum>
                <header>Related services</header>
 <text>The term <term>related services</term> means services related to an organ transplant that consist of—</text>
                <subparagraph id="H13D9E05B30FC421D9A08D861721611AD">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>evaluation;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE5AA9D79668B44BD83A555B753C8F3CE"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>counseling;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H110B773AE0184B0DBA74048A408E602B">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>treatment, including postoperative treatment, and care;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H09A5D69B9AD7499E923DF3A57130E8FF"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>provision of information; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HA6AF27236AD344B48F4DDB9EA03F67AD">
                    <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>any other service recommended or required by a physician.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE9C5BD2AF5D4D3C822CDBC455F7BE6F"> <enum>(9)</enum> <header>Supported decision-making</header> <text>The term <term>supported decision-making</term> means the use of a support person to assist a qualified individual in making health care decisions, communicate information to the qualified individual, or ascertain a qualified individual’s wishes. Such term includes—</text>
                <subparagraph id="HAAADE0CF00934467AFEAC540E01E2C27">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the inclusion of the individual’s attorney-in-fact or health care proxy, or any person of the individual’s choice, in communications about the individual’s health care;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HD8EC0893E10C422B9F34012A8C8113C9">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>permitting the individual to designate a person of the individual’s choice for the purposes of supporting that individual in communicating, processing information, or making health care decisions;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H3F0F84A71A934F21B3622E0808FA14B1">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>providing auxiliary aids and services to facilitate the individual’s ability to communicate and process health-related information, including providing use of assistive communication technology;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HD15AB55392A94F76B196E998036B8C88">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>providing health information to persons designated by the individual, consistent with the regulations promulgated under section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-2">42 U.S.C. 1320d–2</external-xref> note) and other applicable laws and regulations governing disclosure of health information;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HAF8C9BC1B4C54844AD6618876A7DE223">
                    <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>providing health information in a format that is readily understandable by the individual; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HE9101260AB674A18BF1F124961DB3EB5">
                    <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>working with a court-appointed guardian or other person responsible for making health care decisions on behalf of the individual, to ensure that the individual is included in decisions involving the health care of the individual and that health care decisions are in accordance with the individual’s own expressed interests.</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H28A0302EA7994FF5AA57258231353E71">
                <enum>(10)</enum>
                <header>Support network</header>
 <text>The term <term>support network</term> means, with respect to a qualified individual, 1 or more people who are—</text>
                <subparagraph id="H9359EEA26F5747E9B29FD8CCE8B28404">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>selected by the qualified individual or by the qualified individual and the guardian of the qualified individual, to provide assistance to the qualified individual or guidance to that qualified individual in understanding issues, making plans for the future, or making complex decisions; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H5426E358E9DF4DCD9C5B0EEFD509200A">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>who may include the family members, friends, unpaid supporters, members of the religious congregation, and appropriate personnel at a community center, of or serving the qualified individual.</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="H59FEB6CCAC724CF782EDECBCCB57E2E3">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Prohibition of discriminatory policy</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The board of directors described in section 372(b)(1)(B) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/274">42 U.S.C. 274(b)(1)(B)</external-xref>) shall not issue policies, recommendations, or other memoranda that would prohibit, or otherwise hinder, a qualified individual’s access to an organ transplant solely on the basis of that individual’s disability.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="H962021B4EC7640B797D94EF433BA5325">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>Prohibition of discrimination</header>
            <subsection id="HC75484091B3C4A68AC24E052A58DF666">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>Subject to subsection (b), a covered entity may not, solely on the basis of a qualified individual’s disability—</text>
                <paragraph id="H86E4E8574EBD4006A4DD07D0A7FB26AF">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>determine that the individual is ineligible to receive an organ transplant or related services;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HE5508553A6C74DC4AFB41E147D49DEE5">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>deny the individual an organ transplant or related services;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HBEB92183CCEC4FA89B5FD8A36A924E10"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>refuse to refer the individual to an organ transplant center or other related specialist for the purpose of receipt of an organ transplant or other related services; or</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H8D547C0336574B1C89CBEB95AD621577">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>refuse to place the individual on an organ transplant waiting list.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H3E835A3E91604B79A4A7F9F871A7187B"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Exception</header> <paragraph id="H74B9979F4E9742908C1229CF16C8AD4D"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <subparagraph id="HEAA9D63B9E234E69B692BF56EFBAB27B"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>Medically significant disabilities</header> <text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), a covered entity may take a qualified individual’s disability into account when making a health care treatment or coverage recommendation or decision, solely to the extent that the disability has been found by a physician, following an individualized evaluation of the potential recipient, to be medically significant to the receipt of the organ transplant or related services, as the case may be.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H62D47B849B0545E2A373ED286DA99B95">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <header>Construction</header>
 <text>Subparagraph (A) shall not be construed to require a referral or recommendation for, or the performance of, a medically inappropriate organ transplant or medically inappropriate related services.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H7B14032AFF814D23A1F5EC610BD2D64F">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Clarification</header>
 <text>If a qualified individual has the necessary support network to provide a reasonable assurance that the qualified individual will be able to comply with health requirements following an organ transplant or receipt of related services, as the case may be, the qualified individual’s inability to independently comply with those requirements may not be construed to be medically significant for purposes of paragraph (1).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H82F1FA855AE544C1B6B2F9D2989636BD">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Reasonable modifications</header>
 <text>A covered entity shall make reasonable modifications to policies or practices (including procedures) of such entity if such modifications are necessary to make an organ transplant or related services available to qualified individuals with disabilities, unless the entity can demonstrate that making such modifications would fundamentally alter the nature of such policies or practices.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HDBD343AC27A94CB2A771BD882209ED1D">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Clarifications</header>
                <paragraph id="H773F298CEE244D87951DA8C1139C92B6">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>No denial of services because of absence of auxiliary aids and
                        services</header>
 <text>For purposes of this section, a covered entity shall take such steps as may be necessary to ensure that a qualified individual with a disability is not denied a procedure associated with the receipt of an organ transplant or related services, because of the absence of auxiliary aids and services, unless the covered entity can demonstrate that taking such steps would fundamentally alter the nature of the procedure being offered or would result in an undue burden on the entity.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H9DBA2611A22642F6A92EB80B63FE3A31">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Compliance with other law</header>
 <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed—</text> <subparagraph id="HEA19170A241C41FB8D49A95B86A46C42"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>to prevent a covered entity from providing organ transplants or related services at a level that is greater than the level that is required by this section; or</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HD56664E43BB641F9A5647220B953877F">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>to limit the rights of an individual with a disability under, or to replace or limit the scope of obligations imposed by, the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>) including the provisions added to such Act by the ADA Amendments Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/325">Public Law 110–325</external-xref>), section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>), section 1557 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18116">42 U.S.C. 18116</external-xref>), or any other applicable law.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H6F9ADDB420F94C68965636459C96A968">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Enforcement</header>
                <paragraph id="HDF6E85D33947468184C7329D6176DD0E">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>Any individual who alleges that a qualified individual was subject to a violation of this section by a covered entity may bring a claim regarding the allegation to the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Health and Human Services, for expedited resolution, as appropriate.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H9FCC7D8EFF0243E79C33C55A08AEDCE2">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Rule of construction</header>
 <text>Nothing in this subsection is intended to limit or replace available remedies under the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>) or any other applicable law.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="HF38D694AAB9A4B2EADFF8B15192D6CCA">
            <enum>5.</enum>
            <header>Application to each part of process</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The provisions of this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H1714B4976DF146FA8380DE244ECF1C5E"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>that apply to an organ transplant, also apply to the evaluation and listing of a qualified individual, and to the organ transplant and post-organ-transplant treatment of such an individual; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H7A24959A756448559AD1692B147F0283">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>that apply to related services, also apply to the process for receipt of related services by such an individual.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="H94E7919CACD44292877FD8014BACAAC0">
            <enum>6.</enum>
            <header>Effect on other laws</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to supersede any provision of any State or local law that provides greater rights to qualified individuals with respect to organ transplants than the rights established under this Act.</text>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

