<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H50CC37176536432BB60CD640EEDD6336" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2651 IH: One Door to Work Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2651</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250403">April 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act to establish a State innovation demonstration authority.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H36C2CBE6F11947A9A71E8F601F706F5E" style="OLC"><section id="HE514AB834F9C46399C1571BBB5956689" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>One Door to Work Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB2DE5E132A994E18B07062ACAD2D2349" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>State innovation demonstration authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 190 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3250">29 U.S.C. 3250</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="HAE0C76796C244FE5A65A48C561D8EDB1" style="OLC"><section id="H2950DBE0E4F046859396DE7CBB6EF898"><enum>190.</enum><header>State innovation demonstration authority</header><subsection id="HC5E36F69675740F5B39835DA17337349"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to—</text><paragraph id="HD3266BC0ADCD44B0B733E91B7F124998"><enum>(1)</enum><text>authorize States to apply under this section on behalf of the entire State, or on behalf of a local area or a consortium of local areas in the State, to receive the allotments or allocations of the State or the local areas, respectively, for youth workforce investment activities and adult and dislocated worker employment and training activities under this Act, as a consolidated grant for 5 years for the purpose of carrying out a demonstration project to pursue innovative reforms to achieve better outcomes for jobseekers, employers, and taxpayers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E49EBFFDCAC40948C4DA55E5A017EE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require that rigorous evaluations be conducted to demonstrate if better outcomes and associated innovative reforms were achieved as a result of such demonstration projects.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H01BE30B7A945439A8748253AAFC3F456"><enum>(b)</enum><header>General authority</header><paragraph id="HCA5CC78748D84FD4BEB176EF44735C2C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Waivers and demonstration grant amounts</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, during the demonstration period applicable to a demonstration project approved for a State pursuant to subsection (d)(3), the Secretary shall comply with each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H7AFB20341D36459DA6FFE1782D2EFF85"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Waivers</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), waive for the State as a whole, or for the local area or the consortium of local areas in such State selected by the State to carry out such demonstration project, all the statutory and regulatory requirements of subtitle A and subtitle B.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF95375DA78814AB6BFDEFE0E9065BA11"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Demonstration grant amounts</header><text>For each fiscal year applicable to such demonstration period:</text><clause id="HE67BA0AC04524668B5ABB05641754285"><enum>(i)</enum><header>State as a whole</header><text>In a case of a State approved to carry out a demonstration project under this section on behalf of the State as a whole, distribute as a consolidated sum to the State, for purposes of carrying out the project, the State’s total allotment for such fiscal year under—</text><subclause id="HF5E8D3BC6BCC452A8DBE41219DD01AE6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>subsections (b)(1)(C) and subsection (c) of section 127;</text></subclause><subclause id="HC88F15CE9805485A9FF2F876CB376E5E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>paragraphs (1)(B) and (2)(B) of section 132(b); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H43D3542FB92949728D7F0ABE45E3EE58"><enum>(III)</enum><text>section 132(c).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H0E852F73F00449CFB22C26F474AFD063"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Local area</header><text>In a case of a local area selected by a State to carry out a demonstration project under this section, require the State to—</text><subclause id="H824B395918B24842A108FBBCEEC8410E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>distribute as a consolidated sum to the local board for such local area, for purposes of carrying out the project, the local area’s allocation for such fiscal year under—</text><item id="H00843D4E7160439EBE53A4AC4940E3A8"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>subsections (b) and (c) of section 128; and</text></item><item id="H08CDD45DCFA74855993C384920EB6953"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>subsections (b) and (c) of section 133; or</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H01B843E56CBD4C088C707B69ACD45876"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the local board of the local area enters into a written agreement with the State for the State to serve as the fiscal agent for the local board during the demonstration project, use the funds described in subclause (I) for purposes of carrying out the project on behalf of the local board.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H8CBE0B990D14480D875D38C5E6FC42C1"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Consortium of local areas</header><text>In a case of a consortium of local areas selected by a State to carry out a demonstration project under this section, require the State to—</text><subclause id="HCF96230177D74695851B10D034638669"><enum>(I)</enum><text>distribute as a consolidated sum to the consortium, for purposes of carrying out the project, the total amount of the allocations for the local areas in such consortium for such fiscal year under—</text><item id="HBD4B5C20DAEE432686C7218D8C7A8968"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>subsections (b) and (c) of section 128; and</text></item><item id="H2FF7A5DF213B429B9D1965E797D7660B"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>subsections (b) and (c) of section 133; or</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HDCE3BC219846452694E8752DB2FFC996"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the consortium enters into a written agreement with the State for the State to serve as the fiscal agent for the consortium during the demonstration project, use the funds described in subclause (I) for purposes of carrying out the project on behalf of such consortium.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F8BB5485D984C76BEC1EA3A2022BE8D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><subparagraph id="H4CBB75DC69154E4EAC08700E1F14F639"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State, local area, or consortium of local areas carrying out a demonstration project under this section shall comply with statutory or regulatory requirements of this Act relating to—</text><clause id="H3282CC01697645ADA84209CA2F2352AE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>performance accountability and reporting, except as otherwise provided in this section;</text></clause><clause id="H19B6A667AA044B5FBDA1E2393282BE7B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the membership of local or State boards in instances where a State carrying out a demonstration project will maintain the use of such boards during the demonstration period; and</text></clause><clause id="H47A084E9BB8242C8820195338E569422"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the priority of service described in section 134(c)(3)(E).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC83F4DF408644C18A9DBE21E57CB1784"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicability of defined terms</header><text>In carrying out a demonstration project under this section, a State, local area, or consortium of local areas may only use a term defined in section 3 to describe an activity carried out under such demonstration project if the State, local area, or consortium of local areas gives such term the same meaning as such term is given under such section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5643E2018E94DBF86F2F990A1060373"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authority for third-party evaluation</header><subparagraph id="HB844ED9328B24BCEAB4BD0DC5CC42888"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the first demonstration project is approved under this section, the Secretary shall contract with a third-party evaluator to conduct a rigorous evaluation of each demonstration project approved under this section. The evaluation shall—</text><clause id="HD7D3DC5E84C44C33AD2D0EAA1DA8A870"><enum>(i)</enum><text>cover the 5-year period of each demonstration project;</text></clause><clause id="HC7067204C7E74F419F35AA9FAD2D1929"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>compare the employment and earnings outcomes of participants in activities carried out under the demonstration project to—</text><subclause id="HC77C6566B71B4D7599399296CFEE286E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the outcomes of similarly situated individuals that do not participate in such activities who are located in such State, local area, or a local area in such consortium; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H6145CD2A60664CF2A7BE603D7623B4A2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the outcomes of participants in activities under this chapter in the State, local area, or a local area in the consortium that was awarded a waiver prior to the award of such waiver;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H8984E83099F1482C8315AB924AE478D8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>conduct a qualitative analysis that identifies any promising practices or innovative strategies that—</text><subclause id="H13D9A9367FDA4A7BA40BCCBE6BCF8433"><enum>(I)</enum><text>would not have been conducted without the waiving of statutory or regulatory provisions through the demonstration project; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H8017444FEBC5465298E4CDFF0EF2A5E4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>lead to positive employment and earnings outcomes for the participants; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HE5CBDA98466A4B788B204BB00D9AF9EF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>compare the outcomes for subclauses (I) and (II) of clause (ii) with respect to the subpopulations described in section 116(d)(2)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFD7B7768D0E484DA9E117288BDE7C4D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the fifth year of each demonstration project approved under this section, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions, the results of the evaluation of such conducted under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H35AD67E788BC4084AA440AEA26BB27A2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Demonstration period; limitations</header><paragraph id="H6D4CFFE717A74F30BDD9714691617F17"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A demonstration project approved under this section for a State, local area, or consortium—</text><subparagraph id="HB8BC1C6838E14DBAA2CBCC8668575472"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be carried out for a 5-year demonstration period; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93AA4D9FEFFA48ABA4BA6856790EA8C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be renewed for an additional 5-year demonstration period, if the State, local area, or consortium—</text><clause id="H58D06E84900D4C7C90A01434419C0934"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for each of the final 3 years of the preceding 5-year demonstration period, meets its expected levels of performance established under subsection (f)(1)(C); and</text></clause><clause id="H2DAD25D7890D4B198F5452C0C9040E6F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>on the final year of the preceding 5-year demonstration period, achieves a performance improvement of not less than an average of a 5-percent increase across all of the indicators of performance described in clauses (i) and (ii) of subsection (f)(1)(A), compared with—</text><subclause id="H30483B322425438CA32F9BB56DAAEFEB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the highest level of performance for the corresponding indicators of performance, as described in subsection (f)(1)(B)(i) with respect to such State, for the most recent program year that ended prior to the beginning of the first year of the preceding 5-year demonstration period; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H40C7AE08DE474CBF9DCF9A6E1C606C36"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the alternate baseline level of performance for the corresponding indicators of performance that is agreed upon between the State and the Secretary under subsection (f)(1)(B)(ii).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBBC9DC25E3C43D9B99CC2C70D83B811"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations</header><subparagraph id="H22528996601C43A4942C76FCD2FCB312"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Demonstration period limitations</header><text>For each 5-year demonstration period (including renewals of such period) the Secretary may not approve—</text><clause id="H27AAAD36000F47E2BA773347146E53D8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>more than 8 demonstration projects for States to carry out a demonstration project described in subsection (b)(1)(B)(i); and</text></clause><clause id="HCA0971F123464DFBB0CDB8B5BE86AA10"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>more than 8 demonstration projects for local areas (or consortia of local areas) to carry out a demonstration project described in clause (ii) or (iii) of subsection (b)(1)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD495BEAA53142629C7B0243C68C0E75"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State limitations</header><text>No more than 1 demonstration project may be approved under this section per State. For purposes of this subparagraph, a demonstration project described in clause (ii) or (iii) of subsection (b)(1)(B) approved for a local area or a consortium of local areas, respectively, in a State shall be considered a demonstration project approved under this section for the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D70DC4813054278A38F288065F62A5D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><paragraph id="H080AA6AB7A5F48EA9738173968F60F37"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to carry out a demonstration project under this section, a State shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may reasonably require, and containing the information described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA0756C5CDB04B9B9C43ED386406E209"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Content</header><text>Each application submitted by a State under this subsection shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="H2CFBCFC944D54448B86BEAD0FDFD42FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the demonstration project to be carried out under this section, including—</text><clause id="HFFADEE2558D047E79F26D1D9CA58A28B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whether the project will be carried out—</text><subclause id="H1C2703A96F654E2797F990C211067627"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by the State as a whole;</text></subclause><subclause id="H6D2A479F9DD04FE8AE546B01038546A6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by a local area, and if so—</text><item id="HA86D1C7D210A4F569D8D8E856B979173"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>an identification of—</text><subitem id="H317C703FEAE444249923556AAE9349C7"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>such local area;</text></subitem><subitem id="H2BA59253C697490D8A7451C04F7B93DE"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>whether the local board for such local area is the fiscal agent for the project, or whether the local board has entered into a written agreement with the State for the State to serve as the fiscal agent during the project; and</text></subitem></item><item id="HF33C6E02649441A282A1331CC10AE61F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>written verification from the local board for such local area that such local board agrees—</text><subitem id="H6EEB205939B34174AEB58372589513D1"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>to carry out such project; and</text></subitem><subitem id="HA5112BF6F2104F8695BFA0BDD7A3521C"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>to the fiscal agent identified in item (aa)(BB); and</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="H244D54B72FAF402AB0AEADE246B4A6B4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by a consortium of local areas in the State, and if so—</text><item id="H9FBCECE1CCB142FF9A802ABFC59F466D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>an identification of—</text><subitem id="H575BBE06F2114CC993B0D178E40E7EFF"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>each local area that comprises the consortium; and</text></subitem><subitem id="H2A55E69ABDA54AFC8E94133C802E0284"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the local area that will serve as the fiscal agent for the consortium during the project, or whether the consortium has entered into a written agreement with the State for the State to serve as the fiscal agent; and</text></subitem></item><item id="H60E5AB3D63874E68AE7C3C7F2559AF67"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>written verification from each local board of each local area identified in item (aa)(AA) that such local board agrees—</text><subitem id="H401F1F3FECC3493FB4726E0E74F2F46A"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>to carry out such project as a consortium; and</text></subitem><subitem id="HA283FBB58C3C4EA7AB34FC27E182E0AF"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>to the fiscal agent for the consortium identified in item (aa)(BB);</text></subitem></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H506C52E8399D4AE28E46097590401A00"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of the activities to be carried out under the project; and</text></clause><clause id="H81DA9B3BF9DF409CB658650147CFC2CE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the goals the State, local area, or consortium intends to achieve through such activities, which shall be aligned with the purpose described in subsection (a).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B2605EF94BF436BB6663172BFE6DD58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the performance outcomes the State, the local area, or consortium expects to achieve for such activities for each year of the demonstration period as described in subsection (f)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2897FF691E6442C3ADD799BDCB691828"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of how the State, local area, or consortium consulted with employers, the State board, and the local boards in the State in determining the activities to carry out under the demonstration project.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE0AD9F32D3944C9A6B2488F2DF3E865"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A description of how the State will make such activities available to jobseekers and employers in each of the local areas in the State or, in a case of a project that will be carried out by a local area or a consortium, a description of how such services will be made available to jobseekers and employers in such local area or each of the local areas in the consortium.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H100C859129F048E98AE6F434A66C1883"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A description, if appropriate, of how the State, local area, or consortium will integrate the funds received, and the activities carried out, under the demonstration project under this section with State workforce development programs and other Federal, State, or local workforce, education, or social service programs (including the programs and activities listed in section 103(a)(2), the program of adult education and literacy activities authorized under title II, and the program authorized under title I of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/720">29 U.S.C. 720 et seq.</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D18241C3D0E4135BFF09840B9649575"><enum>(F)</enum><text>An assurance that the State, local area, or consortium will meet the requirements of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H51F9F03E8C7345499ACC4D036E4D58DD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretarial approval</header><subparagraph id="HF6E4C79CE74946F2A3225480A12935BB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which a State submits an application under this subsection, the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="HF5F737421F27490EA1E8BC033E480A9D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in a case in which the application meets the requirements of this section and is not subject to the limitations described in subsection (c)(2), approve such application and the demonstration project described in such application; or</text></clause><clause id="H95F271D4647A4A8BAB8A993600E50F20"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide to the State a written explanation of initial disapproval that meets the requirements of subparagraph (C).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6C2C6929958400BABC706FC0E8C2A1E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Default approval</header><text>With respect to an application submitted by a State under this subsection that is not subject to the limitations described in subsection (c), if the Secretary fails to approve such application or provide an explanation of initial disapproval for such application as required under subparagraph (A), the application and the demonstration project described in such application shall be deemed approved by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF2FA7836AB049D0B49ADC299E9AEE63"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Initial disapproval</header><text>An explanation of initial disapproval provided by the Secretary to a State under subparagraph (A)(ii) shall provide the State—</text><clause id="H3E3F226F789143E89BA1B6F37CF75C33"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a detailed explanation of why the application does not meet the requirements of this section; and</text></clause><clause id="H219980B51D16433487EA4B21061195E3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the State is not subject to the limitations described in subsection (c), an opportunity to revise and resubmit the State’s application under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA6D410136D09441295EE51996521346E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>State demonstration project requirements</header><text>A State, local area, or consortium that has been approved to carry out a demonstration project under this section shall meet each of the following requirements:</text><paragraph id="H893C7E290DE84B0EB32834D9B23A3E7B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Use the funds received pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(B) solely to carry out the activities of the demonstration project to achieve the goals described in subsection (d)(2)(A).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H701961100AAE4B3EAD154AF40363B1A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative costs limitation</header><text>Use not more than 10 percent of the funds received pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(B) for a fiscal year for the administrative costs of carrying out the demonstration project.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1F7497B9CEE4090A7534EDFB6ACEE88"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority for services</header><text>Give priority for services under the project to veterans and their eligible spouses in accordance with the requirements of section 4215 of title 38, United States Code, recipients of public assistance, low-income individuals, and individuals who are basic skills deficient.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4EC043AD82B44B7AA826C22524D34A3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Number of participants</header><text>Serve a number of participants under the activities of the demonstration project for each year of the demonstration period that—</text><subparagraph id="H9F32292CB55D48A19095456D8D85818B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is greater than the number of participants served by such State, local area, or consortium under the programs described in subparagraph (A) of the definition of the term <quote>core program provision</quote> under section 3 for the most recent program year that ended prior to the beginning of the first year of the demonstration period; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8475D7CD7964F2F9AF7B4141205CFF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not less than the number of participants to be served under the activities of the demonstration project that is agreed upon between the State, local area, or consortium, and the Secretary—</text><clause id="HBD53D083951A4BAB88AB1C6933895C24"><enum>(i)</enum><text>prior to the Secretary’s approval of the application submitted under subsection (d); and</text></clause><clause id="HEB93FB0A6DB142EE937CEE62ECD2E4AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>after the Secretary takes into account—</text><subclause id="HF77C8F71C9F64E24BFF9C8D19500E44C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the goals the State, local area, or consortium intends to achieve through the demonstration project; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HEA5C5A8A55754E0881A46C56E36CFBAF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the participants the State, local area, or consortium intends to serve under such project; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HBFF6EE1017BB49CF95374FCE35BFC435"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prior to approval of the application submitted under subsection (d).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9495A254B17841F9B7413C842BBA0588"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reporting outcomes</header><text>Submit, on an annual basis, to the Secretary a report, with respect to such State, local area, or consortium, on—</text><subparagraph id="H7F16A2CB20394439B721458DBE5ACE5D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>participant outcomes for each indicator of performance described in subsection (f)(1)(A) for the activities carried out under the project; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9570A8A3183E4C06828E3F50AF3C9469"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the applicable requirements of section 116(d)(2), including subparagraphs (B) through (G) and subparagraph (J), as such subparagraphs are applicable to activities under the demonstration project.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC88AAE2D09E420299CF9BEC029B20CF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Compliance with certain existing requirements</header><text>Comply with the statutory or regulatory requirements listed in subsection (b)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4E78E420A3B34DA2B31CFBCD1FCB6666"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Performance accountability</header><paragraph id="HAFD77C3978F947EFB888CA74513E6D49"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment of baseline level for performance</header><subparagraph id="H5D393892FD2E42A097C407CDA108AD52"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each State shall describe in the application submitted under subsection (d), for each year of the demonstration period—</text><clause id="HD23E8F0C261644FDB4A34F65539AEA3C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to participants who are at least 25 years old, the expected levels of performance for each of the indicators of performance under section 116(b)(2)(A)(i) for the activities carried out under the project under this section, which shall meet the requirements of subparagraph (B); and</text></clause><clause id="H51B15C87C4614253B7892AB280E897E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to participants who are at least 16 years old and no older than 24 years old, the expected levels of performance for each of the indicators of performance under section 116(b)(2)(A)(ii) for the activities carried out under the project under this section, which shall meet the requirements of subparagraph (B).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73AD28B587B040A8ABAA37D0A1877EF1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>5th year</header><text>Each of the expected levels of performance established pursuant to subparagraph (A) for each of the indicators of performance for the 5th year of the demonstration period shall be higher than—</text><clause id="H8F7BFB9EC953449EB21363D1A4E10E87"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the highest level of performance for the corresponding indicator of performance for the programs described in subparagraph (A) of the definition of the term <quote>core program provisions</quote> under section 3 for the most recent program year for such State that ended prior to the beginning of the first year of the demonstration period; or</text></clause><clause id="H1C531DDF87E54E9A96930E7138E12312"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an alternate baseline level of performance that is agreed upon between the State and the Secretary—</text><subclause id="H02CF00C499F44F969E91454E295EF3A6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>prior to the Secretary’s approval of the application submitted under subsection (d); and</text></subclause><subclause id="HF0E6339C5B0B4DBB9BCE3E5959C44317"><enum>(II)</enum><text>after the Secretary takes into account—</text><item id="H65EE3037B1FE447B820CCF267A20F6DA"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the goals the State intends to achieve through the demonstration project; and</text></item><item id="H79ABB15E06644E12B959045AD6FCC910"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the participants the State intends to serve under such project.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CE9DBFF071F455DB735ECEE8465BDDB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Agreed level for performance on expected levels of performance</header><text>Prior to approving an application for a demonstration project submitted by a State, and using the expected levels of performance described in such application, the Secretary shall reach an agreement with such State on the expected levels of performance for each of the indicators of performance. In reaching an agreement on such expected levels of performance, the Secretary and the State may consider the factors described in section 116(b)(3)(A)(v).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDECFD49069D34B94A03F34497E9CCAAD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sanctions</header><subparagraph id="H50B88FA9DC4B4782A79668B53CD8B9BC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The sanctions described in section 116(f)(1)(B) shall apply to a State, local area, or consortium beginning on the 3rd year of the demonstration period for such State, local area, or consortium, except that the levels of performance established under subsection (f)(1)(C) of this section shall be—</text><clause id="H74083BA012D24DC383CAC2AE2DA20916"><enum>(i)</enum><text>deemed to be the State negotiated levels of performance for purposes of this paragraph; and</text></clause><clause id="H003A6B5E8D02489CB1470EEF9B616F96"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>adjusted at the end of each program year to reflect the actual characteristics of participants served and the actual economic conditions experienced using a statistical adjustment model similar to the model described in section 116(b)(3)(A)(viii).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H631BEB48C793451CB5A323AB26D60DB8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ineligibility for renewal</header><text>A State, local area, or consortium that is subject to such sanctions shall be ineligible to renew its demonstration period under subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD35F4F2840D4448783A49C3216D05197"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Impact of local or consortium demonstrations on statewide accountability</header><text>With respect to a State with an approved demonstration project for a local area or consortium of local areas in the State—</text><subparagraph id="H6395162B9CA04B649E37067786F241FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the performance of such local area or consortium for the programs described in subparagraph (A) of the definition of the term <quote>core program provision</quote> under section 3 shall not be included in the levels of performance for such State for any of such programs for purposes of section 116 for any program year that is applicable to any year of the demonstration period; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46C2FA912D7343A18135C3884864E76A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to any local areas of the State that are not part of the demonstration project, the State shall reach a new agreement with the Secretary, for purposes of section 116(b)(3)(A), on levels of performance for such programs for such program years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

