<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6037E4FFD70244FB9169335467E01A0D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3879 IH: Broadcast Varied Ownership Incentives for Community Expanded Service Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3879</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250610">June 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Federal Communications Commission to take certain actions to increase diversity of ownership in the broadcasting industry, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF56A130D8E1F41BEA4B6A787070B3F9D" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HEC7975E452904AEA874DA49688676D54"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Broadcast Varied Ownership Incentives for Community Expanded Service Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Broadcast VOICES Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H31E7917C9D984B1A9524967EE0756114"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H005091F40FDE4D25925136D003C0E535"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Broadcast station</header><text>The term <term>broadcast station</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/153">47 U.S.C. 153</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6A60FF8359548479A09535E4A3F517D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Communications Commission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H066F8DCE3C024226875CD833B451ECAA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Owned by socially disadvantaged individuals</header><text>The term <term>owned by socially disadvantaged individuals</term> has the meaning given the term in section 346(a) of the Communications Act of 1934, as added by section 5(a)(1) of this Act.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H98C9C36415914AA6A318A06DAC2A9E52"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA7DAC6C241AE47799BFC662E0E341457"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One of the main missions of the Commission, and a compelling governmental interest, is to ensure that there is a diversity of ownership and viewpoints in the broadcasting industry.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H81099C39D94F4A32A84BF8F136889DAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Commission should continue to collect relevant data on the diversity described in paragraph (1), adopt improvements to that data collection and related studies, and make appropriate recommendations to Congress regarding how to increase the number of minority- and women-owned broadcast stations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA08F6642A4F142B29A143E30BA83EA4A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Data from 2021 shows that, of the nearly 1,760 full power commercial broadcast television stations in the United States, less than 6 percent are owned by women and less than 4 percent are minority-owned. With respect to full power commercial radio stations, women owned approximately 9 percent of FM broadcast radio stations, and minorities owned less than 3 percent of those stations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B3E60264EFB4769BE8656665F9FE4CA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In the 17 years that a minority tax certificate program was in place at the Commission between 1978 and 1995, the Commission issued 287 certificates for radio stations, and 40 certificates for television stations, under that program.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H643568D6400B4CDA972740846C725F0D"><enum>4.</enum><header>FCC reports to Congress</header> 
<subsection id="H3BD4DDA3C45845178E02B263EDB943E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Biennial report containing recommendations for increasing number and value of broadcast stations owned by socially disadvantaged individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than once every 2 years thereafter, the Commission shall submit to Congress a report containing recommendations for how to increase the total number, and the value, of broadcast stations that are owned by socially disadvantaged individuals.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H74CEBB73B25A405993EE5CB9E2457B58"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Biennial report on number of broadcast stations owned by socially disadvantaged individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than once every 2 years thereafter, the Commission shall submit to Congress a report that identifies the total number of broadcast stations that are owned by socially disadvantaged individuals, based on data reported to the Commission on Form 323 of the Commission.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H7FA71FA8527C441F85BB67755A2B520B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Tax certificate program for broadcast station transactions furthering ownership by socially disadvantaged individuals</header> 
<subsection id="H586BABEA3B3B4ED2ACE6D4F769C79736"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements for issuance of certificate by FCC</header> 
<paragraph id="H22CF88378E1E4E8CA2C46F27C7B6EEBD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part I of title III of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/301">47 U.S.C. 301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H85859440761A4B1685A1C464BC68F0B6"> <section id="H82E6BA1CD62F4C93BF8764D039E22BC8"><enum>346.</enum><header>Tax certificate program for broadcast station transactions furthering ownership by socially disadvantaged individuals</header> <subsection id="H2BFED52921F2442C916449F00EB716FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB4507330152A4F168824F116589F8D89"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Owned by socially disadvantaged individuals</header><text>The term <term>owned by socially disadvantaged individuals</term> means, with respect to a broadcast station, that—</text> <subparagraph id="H64A0F09E2E9C4BA6847285AF049BE12A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the station is more than 50 percent (or some other percentage determined by the Commission) owned by 1 or more socially disadvantaged individuals, or, in the case of any publicly traded broadcast station, more than 50 percent (or some other percentage determined by the Commission) of the securities of such station is owned by 1 or more socially disadvantaged individuals; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFDFEDF96DFDB4190B95E7CE055BBD920"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the management and daily business operations of the station are controlled by 1 or more socially disadvantaged individuals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87C1EC96CF6E41F6B7DF300480FDD441"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Socially disadvantaged individual</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>socially disadvantaged individual</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H906FE7F9FF2F45468C6AECFE8B51A9DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a woman; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H37D2BAE551644B409B176B2102FE0970"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individual who has been subjected to racial or ethnic prejudice or cultural bias because of the identity of the individual as a member of a group, without regard to the individual qualities of the individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H11EC8CA11219414ABE4763B4F6F53099"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Issuance of certificate by Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the rules adopted by the Commission under subsection (d), upon application by a person that engages in a sale described in subsection (c), the Commission shall issue to that person a certificate stating that the sale meets the requirements of this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAF6CA304FEAE401CA337A679768CDF75"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sales described</header><text>A sale described in this subsection is either of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0C04120E2416426FB19C96A2EE5209EE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Sale resulting in or preserving ownership and control by socially disadvantaged individuals</header><text>A sale of an interest in a broadcast station if, immediately after the sale, the station is owned by socially disadvantaged individuals, without regard to whether, before the sale, the station was owned by socially disadvantaged individuals.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD22B69AE8924812AEAF8269B7F00574"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sale by investor in station owned by socially disadvantaged individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a person that has contributed capital in exchange for an interest in a broadcast station that is owned by socially disadvantaged individuals, a sale by that person of some or all of that interest.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8F4CFA54C54946FABF0B4234FE4E09A0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rules</header><text>The Commission shall adopt rules for the issuance of a certificate under subsection (b) that provide for the following:</text> <paragraph id="H03934B564A82455E8FBE1B63128A1A2F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limit on value of sale</header><text>A limit on the value of an interest the sale of which qualifies for the issuance of such a certificate, which shall be not greater than $50,000,000.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0FC682ADD48944658C812D3C9C0D657A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum holding period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a sale described in subsection (c)(1), a minimum period after the sale during which the broadcast station shall remain owned by socially disadvantaged individuals, which shall be not shorter than 2 years and not longer than 3 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H366105074FC04165821E3CB9E4742E52"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cumulative limit on number or value of sales</header><text>A limit on the total number of sales per year or the total value of sales per year, or both, for which a person may be issued certificates under subsection (b).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H4897C6E8DE454309AD19E195CA931399"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Participation in station management by socially disadvantaged individuals</header><text>Requirements for participation by socially disadvantaged individuals in the management of the broadcast station.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HB36FC30B6DDD4AEEB80F85D877C65987"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Certification</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H87E0FE9A26394466884C19BEB72C707D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a sale described in subsection (c)(1), a requirement that the buyer of the interest in the broadcast station certify, every 180 days during the minimum holding period adopted under paragraph (2), compliance with the rules issued under that paragraph and paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HB92737D42F9B4C4B830CEE6070F41D21"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Failure to comply</header><text>With respect to a failure to make a certification required under subparagraph (A), the Commission shall—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HA81B66BD849C4D53B059BB86AA87E7CF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>report the failure to the Commissioner of Internal Revenue; and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H521D8AFC446B4B19A22AADE9C4F1B592"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include the failure in the report to Congress submitted under subsection (e) that covers the period during which the failure occurred.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBE1241362CA64FA68305758DCBC2B340"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual report to Congress</header><text>The Commission shall submit to Congress an annual report describing the sales for which certificates have been issued under subsection (b) during the period covered by the report.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF61B70A48A124D08B6AE946218123510"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline for issuance of rules</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall issue rules to implement section 346 of the Communications Act of 1934, as added by paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDCAFDC40542546A6BAEDA608EC26BAE2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report to Congress on program expansion</header><text>Not later than 6 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit to Congress a report regarding whether Congress should expand section 346 of the Communications Act of 1934, as added by paragraph (1), beyond broadcast stations to cover other entities regulated by the Commission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD89902E53D084BB6B2F541825C4632F0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Examination and report to Congress on nexus between diversity of ownership and diversity of viewpoint</header> 
<subparagraph id="HD068845966704B1280B8D22CD544451A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Examination</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall initiate an examination of whether there is a nexus between diversity of ownership or control of broadcast stations (including ownership or control by members of minority groups or women, or by both members of minority groups and women) and diversity of the viewpoints expressed in the matter that is broadcast by broadcast stations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H85973C4172F541D5834264B5CD67817C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit to Congress a report on the findings of the Commission in the examination under subparagraph (A), including supporting data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD376591764CF4F1BA443B7E018A1689C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Nonrecognition of gain or loss for tax purposes</header> 
<paragraph id="H34F0D284C7E1493FAD69B4FB5E89A702"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter O of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after part IV the following new part:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H34914974DE9742DC9E3B82FE08EFDA25"> <part id="H49A1F0915FE442DDA17EDEB30B4CD49C"><enum>V</enum><header>SALE OF INTEREST IN CERTAIN BROADCAST STATIONS</header> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1071. Nonrecognition of gain or loss from sale of interest in certain broadcast stations.</toc-entry></toc> <section id="HA5D7BA507DD44610B2F73AE75151BC87"><enum>1071.</enum><header>Nonrecognition of gain or loss from sale of interest in certain broadcast stations</header> <subsection id="H623D77FF2FD444D4A02E9E3E0F19BF4A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Nonrecognition of Gain or Loss</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a sale of an interest in a broadcast station, within the meaning of section 346 of the Communications Act of 1934, is certified by the Federal Communications Commission under such section, such sale shall, if the taxpayer so elects, be treated as an involuntary conversion of such property within the meaning of section 1033. For purposes of such section as made applicable by the provisions of this section, stock of a corporation operating a broadcast station shall be treated as property similar or related in service or use to the property so converted. The part of the gain, if any, on such sale to which section 1033 is not applied shall nevertheless not be recognized, if the taxpayer so elects, to the extent that it is applied to reduce the basis for determining gain or loss on any such sale, of a character subject to the allowance for depreciation under section 167, remaining in the hands of the taxpayer immediately after the sale, or acquired in the same taxable year. The manner and amount of such reduction shall be determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary. Any election made by the taxpayer under this section shall be made by a statement to that effect in his return for the taxable year in which the sale takes place, and such election shall be binding for the taxable year and all subsequent taxable years.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE75F2FA1FA884AE08DAE70CBA4996FF6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Minimum holding period; continued management</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If—</text> <paragraph id="H6BC77CA18BF746C08175FD53F20CA5C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>there is nonrecognition of gain or loss to a taxpayer under this section with respect to a sale of property (determined without regard to this paragraph), and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2C4222E03D0A4FF8B239D2499B668924"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the taxpayer ceases to fulfill any requirements of the rules adopted by the Federal Communications Commission under paragraph (2) or (4) of section 346(d) of the Communications Act of 1934 (as such rules are in effect on the date of such sale),</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">there shall be no nonrecognition of gain or loss under this section to the taxpayer with respect to such sale, except that any gain or loss recognized by the taxpayer by reason of this subsection shall be taken into account as of the date on which the taxpayer so ceases to fulfill such requirements.</continuation-text></subsection> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3B0B6EBE7764B229D177B5B9D9AECC2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Basis</header><text>For basis of property acquired on a sale treated as an involuntary conversion under subsection (a), see section 1033(b).</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3667298ADF3041E2A1C6AAA848B70954"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of parts for subchapter O of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after the item relating to part IV the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="tax" id="H6AD714D512EA4AD8BCF11F435C2A6099" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="HF56A130D8E1F41BEA4B6A787070B3F9D" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> <toc-entry idref="HF56A130D8E1F41BEA4B6A787070B3F9D" level="part">Part V. Sale of interest in certain broadcast stations.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H928F4B53EA9D433EBE826AE5837DDF0F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to sales of interests in broadcast stations after the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0031B5E6F0FE46328B971BAE74A87A1B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall not apply with respect to sales of interests in broadcast stations after the date that is 16 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H8F7036E6689B4AB7B51B02530E2CAFB1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Credit for certain contributions with respect to broadcast stations</header> <subsection id="H5F738B2DF35B4FC99A59EF2CF436FBDA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12AFF1BB66AA4A48832355A769D8C78A"> 
<section id="H6874E8500EFE4055A38FC9D546FB6214"><enum>45BB.</enum><header>Credit for certain contributions with respect to broadcast stations</header> 
<subsection id="H747F1B062C434CA8B772F8DEBD6719AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of section 38, the broadcast station contribution credit determined under this section for any taxable year is an amount equal to the fair market value of any broadcast station, or any interest in a broadcast station, which is contributed in a qualified contribution during such taxable year.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H28C3EF15BA3848F9B00D8CA2F0987E51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified contribution</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="H422ED8528F5E458389F5949DDAD17BDD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified contribution</term> means a contribution or gift to or for the use of an entity described in section 170(c)(2) which has as a part of its charitable purpose the training of socially disadvantaged individuals in the management and operation of broadcast stations (as certified by the Federal Communications Commission), but only if the recipient holds such station or interest for not less than 2 years after the date of the contribution.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H72A24A838F5E48798196D8A148A7BBEA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Socially disadvantaged individual</header><text>The term <term>socially disadvantaged individual</term> has the meaning given such term in section 346(a)(2) of the Communications Act of 1934.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H53405206181346C88FBBD7E18D24C375"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Broadcast station</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>broadcast station</term> has the same meaning as when used in section 346 of the Communications Act of 1934.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDF251DF1411E4A8594CF774C0CEA5E63"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Denial of deduction</header><text>No deduction shall be allowed under section 170 with respect to any contribution for which credit is allowed under this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4D9449B98972468980E98E214A2794FC">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Credit To be part of general business credit</header>
 <text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/38">Section 38(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (40), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (41) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
        <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="H62576C3787FA4E7A9FCD548E4CFAD2D8">
          <paragraph id="HB0F819E8AB8B4FAFB2BEEC383BDA56BF">
            <enum>(42)</enum>
 <text>the broadcast station contribution credit determined under section 45BB(a).</text> </paragraph> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </subsection> <subsection id="HB0E67535D1F44FE2983168192D4FFA86"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9AEE8005637043CC9E0C27F76C55FF89"> 
<toc> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H6874E8500EFE4055A38FC9D546FB6214">Sec. 45BB. Credit for certain contributions with respect to broadcast stations.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAEE3C5547AC543DAB2F4042F16C55BC3" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to contributions made in taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

