<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6A6A805ACBB145328D24742145ECED79" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3237 IH: No Student Visas for Sanctuary Cities Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3237</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250507">May 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for a limitation on availability of student visas for institutions in sanctuary jurisdictions.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB9DEB7426E2447EA8E94DE740377B5C3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H59CF6BB2338D4916BF45A3BE6D252694" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Student Visas for Sanctuary Cities Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HB4594F32EDFE4AC591087108F46A7257"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on availability of F-visas and M-visas for institutions in sanctuary jurisdictions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 214(m) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1184">8 U.S.C. 1184(m)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5E07BDCB8D6D4A7BADA113A15DE75C11" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H3E22AF9BC0EA4221A3246E6CD17D5BA7" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum> 
<subparagraph id="HD50E932ECAE54F9485C6779C5BEBB41A" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall, for each fiscal year, identify sanctuary jurisdictions for purposes of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H20815176AD864BDCA5CC57A9AA4BE4A5" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an alien who seeks a visa under or to be accorded status as a nonimmigrant under section 101(a)(15)(F) to pursue a course of study at an established college, university, conservatory, academic high school, elementary school, or other academic institution or in an accredited language training program in the United States, if such college, university, conservatory, academic high school, elementary school, or other academic institution or accredited language training program is located in a sanctuary jurisdiction, such visa may not be issued nor may such status be accorded.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6EAD66CA98B34DE88F93B3490B2BA0F2" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an alien who seeks a visa under or to be accorded status as a nonimmigrant under section 101(a)(15)(M) to pursue a full course of study at an established vocational or other recognized nonacademic institution (other than in a language training program) in the United States, if such vocational or other recognized nonacademic institution is located in a sanctuary jurisdiction, such visa may not be issued nor may such status be accorded.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC9334312DEB6473BA0959C07A70A5D28" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The prohibition under subparagraphs (B) and (C) do not apply for a fiscal year in the case of a State or unit of local government identified as a sanctuary jurisdiction if the Secretary of Homeland Security thereafter determines that such State or unit of local government is no longer a sanctuary jurisdiction and submits a report to Congress to that effect.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFD8E7E7A51E24D56A7F789755C08BEB4" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>sanctuary jurisdiction</quote> means any State or unit of local government that has laws, ordinances, regulations, resolutions, policies, or other practices that obstruct immigration enforcement and shield criminals from U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, including by—</text> <clause id="HE9788B631E19410CBD33FC355083ECDD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>refusing to or prohibiting agencies from complying with U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement detainers;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDEBE41D9DEDF410880583812A5236245"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">imposing unreasonable conditions on U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement detainer compliance;</text></clause> <clause id="H5C365C6EC1D64955A61F51F182F26FCC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">denying U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement access to interview incarcerated aliens; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H26A0490E62BB48E18C854E23C2159213"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">otherwise impeding communication or information exchanges between the jurisdiction’s personnel and Federal immigration officers.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

