<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3A888BEA4822424994A07D4440F2CC66" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3072 IH: DOGE Codification Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3072</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250429">April 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To codify actions taken by the Department of Government Efficiency (commonly referred to as a DOGE), and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE020B484BFE74A15A68D463EF0A2C175" style="OLC"><section id="H2DBA9B37F5784297939034D93BAFB162" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DOGE Codification Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC68F27082235490B800C8CDBD187180B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Codification of Actions</header><subsection id="HA694A4BB9ABE4BABA185ACF9842B5701"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Retention of Reforms</header><text>All rules, policies, guidance, and procedures issued, directed, authorized or implemented by the Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE), as established by the Executive order <quote>Establishing and Implementing the Presidents Department of Government Efficiency</quote>, as well as any action taken by any agency pursuant to such issuance, direction, authorization, or action of DOGE, is hereby authorized and shall have the full force and effect of law.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFA234708E9C64606AB317BF23631B4F6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulatory Review</header><text>Any regulations rescinded or modified by the DOGE, as well as any action taken by any agency pursuant to an issuance, direction, authorization, or action of DOGE, shall remain in their revised form until modified by DOGE or an act of Congress.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5CE91B186DCB408DA1F2D4B55971FC50"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cost-Saving Measures</header><text>Any budgetary savings or efficiency measures identified, issued, directed, authorized or implemented by the DOGE, as well as any budgetary savings or efficiency taken by any agency pursuant to such identification, issuance, direction, authorization, or action of DOGE, shall be maintained, notwithstanding any other provision in law or appropriation.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

