<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG25F48-Y55-JM-H21">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2601 IS: To improve the planning, programming, and budget coordination for operations of cyber mission force of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2601</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250731">July 31, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</sponsor> introduced the following bill;
                which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To improve the planning, programming, and budget coordination for operations
            of cyber mission force of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="idFAEDD3EC0A3C4E58BD581F2D1ADB2FF2" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Planning, programming, and budget coordination for operations of cyber mission
                force</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 167b of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text>
            <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide2a98ddeadc8498cb4a87da9888e045f">
                <subsection id="idd47ae8aa01a842b1b91ed0ee07f6ac12">
                    <enum>(f)</enum>
                    <header>Planning, programming, and budgeting</header>
                    <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id3aada65ea4eb419881c91b5a0cadc78c">
                        <enum>(1)</enum>
                        <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="ide5c4b2d3b4fc43cfa10b76a6caee24d2">
                            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>In addition to the activities of a combatant command for which funding may be requested under section 166(b) of this title, the Commander of the United States Cyber Command shall, subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Principal Cyber Advisor of the Department of Defense, be responsible for directly controlling and managing the planning, programming, budgeting, and execution of resources to train, equip, operate, and sustain the cyber mission force, which shall include the following:</text>
                            <clause id="id0cc5e4e96303445b907cffa85e9d6a4d" indent="up2">
                                <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>Preparation of a program objective memorandum and budget estimate submission for the resources required to train, equip, operate, and sustain the cyber mission force.</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="idf561303748614f36b57d33774be879e1" indent="up2">
                                <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>Preparation of budget materials pertaining to the United States Cyber Command for inclusion in the budget justification materials that are submitted to Congress in support of the budget of the Department of Defense for a fiscal year, as submitted with the budget of the President under section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code, that is separate from any other military department or component of the Department of Defense.</text>
                            </clause>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="id109af47774fd420faec448389ad67764" indent="up2">
                            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>The responsibilities assigned to the Commander of the United States Cyber Command pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall not include the following:</text>
                            <clause id="id2562af0a215149e78fab4d93a681de05">
                                <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>Military pay and allowances.</text> </clause> <clause id="iddc5090a41d6d49efb5712db039f3498e"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>Funding for facility support that is provided by the military departments.</text>
                            </clause>
                        </subparagraph>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf1406ee8d508475db5d9093313b313de" indent="up1">
                        <enum>(2)</enum>
                        <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idcb4fc4a4aba34d1fa7a1550d20639d51">
                            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before the budget proposal for the United States Cyber Command for any fiscal year is submitted to the Secretary of Defense, the Commander of the United States Cyber Command shall consult with the Secretaries of the military departments concerning funding for units of the reserve components within the cyber mission force. If the Secretary of a military department does not concur in the recommended level of funding with respect to any such unit that is under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the military department, the Commander shall include with the budget proposal submitted to the Secretary of Defense the views of the Secretary of the military department concerning such funding.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id82ae63691b714a33a2d83392cf58f2b4">
                            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>Before the budget proposal for a military department for any fiscal year is submitted to the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the military department shall consult with the Commander of the United States Cyber Command concerning funding for cyber mission forces within the reserve component in the military personnel budget for that military department. If the Commander does not concur in the recommended level of funding with respect to individual augmentees or units within the reserve component, the Secretary of the military department shall include with the budget proposal submitted to the Secretary of Defense the views of the Commander.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                    </paragraph>
                </subsection>
                <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

