<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KAT25709-3JF-56-418"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2880 IS: Great Lakes Mass Marking Program Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2880</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250918" legis-day="20250916">September 18 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S438">Mr. Husted</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish the Great Lakes Mass Marking Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H7105D397E2384786AE415CA05FAADF62"><section section-type="section-one" id="H031D1F94AF144D2EB063528569135924"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Great Lakes Mass Marking Program Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB60E2EF93E4A46F98B2085FB6057EE52"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="HDC0F49EAC69C411E974B540D040394A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Great Lakes have experienced rapid changes in recent years due to—</text><subparagraph id="H59224F6981134FCFAB964CA75EFF4A1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the introduction of multiple aquatic invasive species;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E58C5C25C364023B795333A4C84BF7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>alterations in the food web; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1513C970E8904273B9730C1CA026939A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>decreases in the abundance of prey species;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8EBF0B2003348BA993EAE1CEC8B21D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>due to rapid biological change in the Great Lakes, the Great Lakes need a collaborative, science-based program to assist in making management actions relating to fish stocking rates, the rehabilitation of important fish species, and habitat restoration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAEF7DA23C304619BF544552827CC6A2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the States of Illinois, Indiana, Michigan, Minnesota, Ohio, Pennsylvania, New York, and Wisconsin and Indian Tribes in those States, working through the Council of Lake Committees of the Great Lakes Fishery Commission, have identified that mass marking is—</text><subparagraph id="H6A9386BC64E34D1C8BBC7CDE9BEE3405"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a precise tool to keep hatchery-produced fish in balance with wild fish; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E0828D49E7B4A4E8AD9BD8225AD29B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>essential to achieving fishery management and research objectives through producing a better understanding of—</text><clause id="HE022EEA6938742CC84DB516470920492"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the quantity of hatchery-produced fish compared to wild fish in the Great Lakes;</text></clause><clause id="HF7D2649C731B4DC081B54C81548F061A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the effectiveness of hatchery operations; and</text></clause><clause id="HEBB631DAD12B46979EDC91AA07F355F1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the effectiveness of fishery management actions;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F251C54220242F7A866E2B60682FBDB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the mass marking program of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service in the Great Lakes—</text><subparagraph id="HBFF9B45D902D41058DA141ED05E1C1B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was initiated in 2010 on a limited scale;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31F095F2A6A747818838BE13A66DFD7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>annually tags approximately 9,000,000 to 11,000,000 of the hatchery-produced fish stocked in the Great Lakes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1DF8817F27048728E1D63995C6C7005"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is a basinwide cooperative effort among the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, Indian Tribes, and State management agencies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA03D5BFEE8BB48F38A185C5769C0DA32"><enum>(D)</enum><text>produces data used by State and Tribal fish management agencies to make management decisions regarding Great Lakes fisheries;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E3EA0C01A434DF28C0A9121E6A4C404"><enum>(5)</enum><text>annually, Federal, State, and Tribal agencies stock approximately 21,000,000 hatchery-produced fish in the Great Lakes to support—</text><subparagraph id="H8B748BB4C30E4FF5AFF621886D2F9678"><enum>(A)</enum><text>native species recovery; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89AB302DDC494B6084E846D100A88FDE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recreational and commercial fishing;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D59BF3B07E1487ABC592377924155A8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>mass marking of hatchery-produced fish, using automated technology, is an efficient method of implementing a collaborative, science-based fishery program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1482F6270284217BEE4BF2743D706EC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Great Lakes are an important and valued resource that—</text><subparagraph id="HCFD78EF01176403986C6EC993F6E06F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>supports a robust regional economy valued at more than $7,000,000,000; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1851C066E275498AB4B6193B1199FC8C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides stability to the economy of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H50C3AE20C6FC4A01A8B661B77A4A6D4F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H62138C28095943209160CABEF996824F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C6B216CB6C84C3CBBDBAEE29896F03E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>Program</term> means the Great Lakes Mass Marking Program established by section 4(a).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H855DC0BA77ED48F88FE3207A604EB1EF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Great Lakes Mass Marking Program</header><subsection id="HC989E3701D6043E38F39BFD26094EBD6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To assist in determining the effectiveness of hatchery operations and fisheries management actions and to support Great Lakes fisheries, there is established within the United States Fish and Wildlife Service a program for the mass marking of hatchery-produced fish in the Great Lakes basin, to be known as the <quote>Great Lakes Mass Marking Program</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBA4A110D2BD14A1FBE7F6C55D92B694B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorized actions</header><text>In carrying out the Program, the Director may—</text><paragraph id="H900F95E4F7C24045AD44404E5FBECD4C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>purchase capital and expendable equipment, fish tags, and other items necessary to support and carry out tagging and tag recovery operations, including data processing and data dissemination relating to those operations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE507305E7E7B450284EFB38DDA05DB1E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>hire additional personnel, as necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB03DDFE75E234635833708FE0EF84A95"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Required collaboration</header><text>In carrying out the Program, the Director shall collaborate with applicable Federal, State, and Tribal fish management agencies, the Council of Lake Committees of the Great Lakes Fishery Commission, and signatories to the Joint Strategic Plan for Management of Great Lakes Fisheries.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5160C289537A486C80E5B83DC91E4D8D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Availability of data</header><text>The Director shall make the data collected under the Program available to applicable Federal, State, and Tribal fish management agencies—</text><paragraph id="HBA66FFF36E9E4F73BBC656270461BF1C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to increase the understanding of the outcomes of management action;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AFCE8B6E1D148DA91839536E713C632"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to assist in meeting the restoration objectives of the Great Lakes, including the fish community objectives and fish management plans described in the Joint Strategic Plan for Management of Great Lakes Fisheries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H74AFA6F05A4B4E8FB75A6061D4F2A80C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to assist in balancing predators and prey;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB894FB3466EC4127A566C36DC239E367"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to support and improve the economic status of Tribal, recreational, and commercial fisheries; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96AB79BAF1BD4DF885F3F9277E8A4C35"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to assist in evaluating the effectiveness of habitat restoration efforts in the Great Lakes.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H572ADAED34B54547A865C394719E3E2D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out the Program $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

