<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC3CF0F00FF7A425290D3BFF630CD73B4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 709 IH: National Training Center for Counter-Unmanned Aircraft Systems Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 709</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250123">January 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001220">Mr. Strong</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security, to establish counter-UAS system training and require the Attorney General and Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to establish related standards for initial and recurrent training programs or certifications for individuals seeking to operate counter-UAS detection and mitigation systems, equipment, or technology, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H38B150929CB3470EBC71AB5AFC72CE0C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3B36E007FF31461AAAFAA03676A3D1FC" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Training Center for Counter-Unmanned Aircraft Systems Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HDEE69666726D449AA8785200F59085F4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of counter-UAS system training</header> <subsection id="H691EE8689BDA434E84603A82E982B994"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle A of title II of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/121">6 U.S.C. 121 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sections:</text>
<quoted-block id="H4A90709F407146E393BFF3E33438C422">
<section id="H11A6DACA9DCB4E709B5647CE50AA95B5"><enum>210H.</enum><header>Counter-UAS system training</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary (acting through the Director of the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers), may—</text> <paragraph id="H46EF242EF03449A6B9380CE1224FDEAE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide training relating to measures to take the actions described in subsection (b)(1) of section 210G; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8600055A5B354AD782794A4096DF03C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish or designate one or more facilities or training centers for the purpose described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HF55A56BBC55B4E3BB1E4F6977DBBE5C5"><enum>210I.</enum><header>Counter-UAS detection and mitigation system operator qualification and training criteria</header> <subsection id="HDC7E068F1E0A4C73ABD19E595D79342A" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security and Attorney General, in coordination with the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, shall establish standards for initial and recurrent training programs or certifications for individuals seeking to operate counter-UAS detection and mitigation systems, equipment, or technology.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H3919603643A24178872C563F38316E1E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>To carry out subsection (a), the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Attorney General shall, at a minimum—</text> <paragraph id="H4DC1646BAC684749965F08067E0A3340"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider the potential impacts of the systems, equipment, and technology referred to in such subsection on aviation safety, civil aviation and aerospace operations, aircraft airworthiness, or the civilian use of airspace, and appropriate actions to maintain aviation safety, as determined by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H31054EBC6EE945BFA796B7846D3DA18A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish—</text> <subparagraph id="H46A546E1DCF74B299A6A8E9C14663C1F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>interagency coordination requirements prior to deployment of such systems, equipment, and technology; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H23747E4CBDFB4C6D86F7A953451B3D0B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the frequency at which an individual authorized to operate such systems, equipment, or technology shall complete and renew such training or certification.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF3D884724EF047AC9AF62BD5BD581979"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H6717B2A0AECD4C6CA8DC511B5A67E55D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>UAS</header><text>The term <quote>UAS</quote> means an unmanned aircraft system.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0E258BB59A94803AA7CE3A8C132A20E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unmanned aircraft</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>unmanned aircraft</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 44801, of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H90BA78D373924585B3CEB529C46A6CEB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Unmanned aircraft system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>unmanned aircraft system</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 44801, of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H3833266F73FD4FAFA692033DEB138F22"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 210G the following new item:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC30E4589FB764292A46F41186EA70608" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 210H. Counter-UAS system training.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 210I. Counter-UAS detection and mitigation system operator qualification and training criteria.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

