<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HED071EEDE90E48DABFA98060E6D99991" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4514 IH: Local Journalism Sustainability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4514</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001231">Mr. Mannion</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide tax incentives that support local newspapers and other local media, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H26B8C92CFD22451AA2ED3A699102A9A6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA2EBAC5913A4420793CF9267E4B8AF15" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Local Journalism Sustainability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB2A7E44497FC49B48A90865F3904C200"><enum>2.</enum><header>Credit for local newspaper subscriptions</header> <subsection id="H5391915B96DB47348C3FDE2AF9831AF4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart A of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 25E the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4D61867EB5224B41BACB0D65C9A9AFF8" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H989F1AB2F70A4977AB55550D38262C61"><enum>25F.</enum><header>Local newspaper subscriptions</header> 
<subsection id="HA44DCCA6AE69478ABDA7E53B610B76CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year an amount equal to the applicable percentage of amounts paid or incurred for subscriptions to one or more local newspapers for the personal use of the taxpayer.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4CF79EECF63448E8A942EBA0EF1A3301"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual dollar limitation</header><text>The credit allowed under subsection (a) to any taxpayer for any taxable year shall not exceed $250.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF0656CB99D7641C8B32C32DD1D95BD31"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>applicable percentage</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H423D867908FC45BAB6D2CB3079AF2146"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of the first taxable year to which this section applies, 80 percent, and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF26BBDFF90034958821797E02A06058C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of any subsequent taxable year, 50 percent.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H35A5DC98D16142DC86835871D5BF4026"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Local newspaper</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9FF6082D056C4E3D9701B4711F1E70AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>local newspaper</term> means any print or digital publication if—</text> <subparagraph id="HE775D8C38CC543AEA19DB46B40D0C6DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the primary content of such publication is original content derived from primary sources and relating to news and current events,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H809D97ECFF1C4840BB238AD60B782770"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such publication primarily serves the needs of a regional or local community,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBF5C9574C87A43A2992A524C549377A9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the publisher of such publication employs at least one local news journalist who resides in such regional or local community, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0B28E8B40FCC4BF48D22102CC5D7BECE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the publisher of such publication employs not greater than 750 employees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0EF5103AC61E4E61B970F31E397C4113"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Local news journalist</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1)(C), the term <term>local news journalist</term> means any individual who regularly gathers, collects, photographs, records, writes, or reports news or information that concerns local events or other matters of local public interest.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE542529CC59D49F99D67AE1313487C3A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Aggregation rule</header> 
<subparagraph id="H55D7666300A54993ACA6C0F04B379B7A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraphs (C) and (D) of paragraph (1), all persons treated as a single employer under subsection (a) or (b) of section 52, or subsection (m) or (o) of section 414, shall be treated as one person.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9CA91337C761489E88B041361E36FDE0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply unless such persons are involved in the production of the same print or digital publication.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8E488CD971F1487DADD60EFA98516886"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Continuous qualification</header><text>The requirements of subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) shall not be treated as met unless such requirements are met at all times during the period beginning on the date which is 2 years before the date of the enactment of this section and ending on the date that the subscription described in subsection (a) is paid or incurred.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA7843108EE746FE8F48D828F6009902"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Application to certain organizations exempt from tax</header><text>In the case of any print or digital publication which is published by any organization described in section 501(c) and exempt from tax under section 501(a)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDC3A796A492C46718AF257BC58EBD01D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such publication shall be treated as a local newspaper only if the publication of print and digital publications is the primary activity of such organization, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA43EF031260541809C4689F60F1BF538"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any person making a charitable contribution (as defined in section 170(c)) to such organization may elect to treat such contribution as an amount paid or incurred for a subscription to which this section applies in lieu of treating such contribution as a charitable contribution for purposes of section 170.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5218957A454241ABA7C95F376FAC014C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under this section for any amount paid or incurred in a taxable year ending after the close of 5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HF58B4AD81D7543C88C5FF7FEA708E638"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart A of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 25E the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6B73A026491741ADB7662EBEE9532B8A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H4D61867EB5224B41BACB0D65C9A9AFF8" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="H989F1AB2F70A4977AB55550D38262C61" level="section">Sec. 25F. Local newpaper subscriptions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H87DC0EE258534A7BA583522C5AEEB634"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to amounts paid or incurred in taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H7806AD48A42D4EE1B79E797C16240093"><enum>3.</enum><header>Payroll credit for compensation of local news journalists</header> <subsection id="H053BFAFF83B4425B909331BF76234339"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an eligible local newspaper publisher, there shall be allowed as a credit against the taxes imposed by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3111">section 3111(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for each calendar quarter an amount equal to the applicable percentage of wages paid by such publisher to local news journalists for such calendar quarter.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H70B139611B0343C8A5F0356F1DDA31FF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations and refundability</header> 
<paragraph id="H619688A8AC6C44868A0A40F0E06E0C02"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Wages taken into account</header><text>The amount of wages paid with respect to any individual which may be taken into account under subsection (a) during any calendar quarter by the eligible local newspaper publisher shall not exceed $12,500.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE87882F35C8F4BBAB319802CBB145A11"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Credit limited to employment taxes</header><text>The credit allowed by subsection (a) with respect to any calendar quarter shall not exceed the applicable employment taxes (reduced by any credits allowed under subsections (e) and (f) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3111">section 3111</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) on the wages paid with respect to the employment of all the employees of the eligible local newspaper publisher for such calendar quarter.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H635A87753B0C4BAFA906C2EC66B93827"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Refundability of excess credit</header> 
<subparagraph id="H9F396D9F781D40208150FC60B3128AF4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the amount of the credit under subsection (a) exceeds the limitation of paragraph (2) for any calendar quarter, such excess shall be treated as an overpayment that shall be refunded under sections 6402(a) and 6413(b) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF5CE929C62474F0593067807F54D0D7E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of payments</header><text>For purposes of section 1324 of title 31, United States Code, any amounts due to the employer under this paragraph shall be treated in the same manner as a refund due from a credit provision referred to in subsection (b)(2) of such section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8D15B0C54B3B4BCDBD55E181E7B0096D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H9581BEE1D2134599BDF10B7E6B1FF787"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text>The term <term>applicable percentage</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA2A090492FEC4CFDB84D5B79112FF540"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of each of the first 4 calendar quarters to which this section applies, 50 percent; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H829B8DD8A60546A79F09AE6D3D865F35"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of each calendar quarter thereafter, 30 percent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H809A20F4FBF741789767FC7CD81236AF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible local newspaper publisher</header><text>The term <term>eligible local newspaper publisher</term> means, with respect to any calendar quarter, any employer if substantially all of the gross receipts of such employer for such calendar quarter are derived in the trade or business of publishing local newspapers (as defined in section 25F(d)(1)).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D2ED2FFF7864EE2955D39A2C59497DD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Local news journalist</header><text>The term <quote>local news journalist</quote> means, with respect to any eligible local newspaper publisher for any calendar quarter, any individual who provides at least 100 hours of service as a local news journalist (as defined in section 25F(d)(2)) during such calendar quarter to such eligible local newspaper publisher.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE713E1F1B8394E15B67051A07647872D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary’s delegate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6AAEB968734240DA86AD4A9464AB6DE7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Other terms</header><text>Any term used in this section which is also used in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/21">chapter 21</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall have the same meaning as when used in such chapter.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0ACE9B290DDB471CBC727B8531961E5D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Aggregation rule</header> 
<paragraph id="HE654E21B1E9C4BD7BC1D69C3B2491574"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All persons treated as a single employer under subsection (a) or (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/52">section 52</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, or subsection (m) or (o) of section 414 of such Code, shall be treated as one employer for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H203F27C68AEC4042B444A65AD8FE3E01"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply unless such persons are involved in the production of the same print or digital publication.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1910F692B9A5427797D3967D2C9FD8E1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Certain rules To apply</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, rules similar to the rules of sections 51(i)(1) and 280C(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall apply.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE3D33CC96FE14715A31973A0EF17D345" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Certain governmental employers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This credit shall not apply to the Government of the United States, the government of any State or political subdivision thereof, or any agency or instrumentality of any of the foregoing.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7F29A611967746DFBB3B785B77CF657E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Election To have section Not apply</header><text>This section shall not apply with respect to any eligible local newspaper publisher for any calendar quarter if such person elects (at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe) not to have this section apply.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3CE06679185D4612AD33CE435D859930"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Special rules</header> <paragraph id="H42EC70516EFE41F7A6831C9188440F3D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Employee not taken into account more than once</header><text>An employee shall not be included for purposes of this section for any period with respect to any employer if such employer is allowed a credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/51">section 51</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to such employee for such period.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6CE3F4407C3F4E578729B6A73227E051"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text>Any wages taken into account in determining the credit allowed under this section shall not be taken into account for purposes of determining the credit allowed under section 45S of such Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89552CF6A82F4D5EAC7F5F429F3F9192"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Third-party payors</header><text>Any credit allowed under this section shall be treated as a credit described in section 3511(d)(2) of such Code.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H976733F785044D60A3CDE5E91F51FBB7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Transfers to Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund</header><text>There are hereby appropriated to the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund established under section 201 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/401">42 U.S.C. 401</external-xref>) amounts equal to the reduction in revenues to the Treasury by reason of this section (without regard to this subsection). Amounts appropriated by the preceding sentence shall be transferred from the general fund at such times and in such manner as to replicate to the extent possible the transfers which would have occurred to such Trust Fund or Account had this section not been enacted.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H30922160745B41C6BD193E85A77D9B48" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Treatment of deposits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall waive any penalty under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6656">section 6656</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for any failure to make a deposit of any applicable employment taxes if the Secretary determines that such failure was due to the reasonable anticipation of the credit allowed under this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H82DCA693B40A41909289FBF0DA80A956"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Regulations and guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue such forms, instructions, regulations, and guidance as are necessary—</text> <paragraph id="HAB63A5E507C54E658E0DEF7083ACFFA0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to allow the advance payment of the credit under subsection (a), subject to the limitations provided in this section, based on such information as the Secretary shall require;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1EACDA65D70D4DBAB59908914BBF0D0E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide for the reconciliation of such advance payment with the amount advanced at the time of filing the return of tax for the applicable calendar quarter or taxable year; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAE35BB7269764AD49A972D173DD54EE0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>with respect to the application of the credit under subsection (a) to third-party payors (including professional employer organizations, certified professional employer organizations, or agents under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3504">section 3504</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986), including regulations or guidance allowing such payors to submit documentation necessary to substantiate the eligible employer status of employers that use such payors.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H08075770E41948E1BE7FB35217AC0B57"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall only apply to calendar quarters during the first 5 calendar years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HCE2FA92D17D34E178E00014A73D82AB1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Credit for advertising in local newspapers and local media</header> <subsection id="H1144AC9C98E5418CAF46A36AAEE5B81C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC3AD5305BC54DF2B6A9710E321CA37A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2AB12D0D1E6F431AA6FE6CA9494361FD"><enum>45BB.</enum><header>Advertising in local newspapers and local media</header> 
<subsection id="HFC32B8A194CB4E37A5813AB11316454D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 38, in the case of any eligible small business, the local media advertising credit determined under this section for any taxable year is an amount equal to the applicable percentage of the qualified local media advertising expenses paid or incurred by the taxpayer during such taxable year.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3EF1FC61904C4294A0ABB9D4F65B9F08"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The credit allowed under subsection (a) to any taxpayer for any taxable year shall not exceed—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0B938731646E46BE920F9FBC1364DA54"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of the first taxable year to which this section applies, $5,000, and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA5A605CE5A1422FB397B6AFFAE3D64B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of any subsequent taxable year, $2,500.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H963A90981BC0414A8BD6918190C2398C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>applicable percentage</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H95C2221F543445988513FFA1D91A89FC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of the first taxable year to which this section applies, 80 percent, and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA171AFC4D01B4F64BA3E9CD28C8CD410"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of any subsequent taxable year, 50 percent.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H912A268DA3E74E7C82F218416F9296B4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible small business</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>eligible small business</term> means any person for any taxable year if the average number of full-time employees (as determined for purposes of determining whether an employer is an applicable large employer for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4980H">section 4980H(c)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) employed by such person during such taxable year was less than 50.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD998755E9B1B48BB8D64195194A894D8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Qualified local media advertising expenses</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="HA1F4E25683C14F11B711C7C7C7C38714"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified local media advertising expenses</term> means amounts paid or incurred in the ordinary course of a trade or business for advertising in a local newspaper (as defined in section 25F(d)) or a broadcast of a local radio or television station.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0351D6C1C2724C77B3244B02E369E0E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Local radio or television station</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>local radio or television station</quote> means any broadcast radio or television station licensed by the Federal Communications Commission to serve a local community.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6281C8E681744EEF8051FF6A1E6DE918"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Special rules</header> <paragraph id="H3BF70B53BD344C7AA5F283A34EE6229F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text>No deduction shall be allowed for any qualified local media advertising expenses otherwise allowable as a deduction for the taxable year which is equal to the amount of the credit determined for such taxable year under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDB8D5F14EFE8431894D6C0C21D3A1196" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aggregation rule</header><text>All persons treated as a single employer under subsection (a) or (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/52">section 52</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, or subsection (m) or (o) of section 414 of such Code, shall be treated as one employer for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE76BD41250A34E188136C01C815A2E1F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under this section for any amount paid or incurred in a taxable year ending after the close of 5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4B7D4F1EE0BF4E92B99D72B6FB14DCEE" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit allowed as part of general business credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 38(b) is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (40), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (41) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D196B082CA6466B9FD39C14BFBB13FA" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H2069DF7855D849BE9F6C797F37FCB5BE" commented="no"><enum>(42)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an eligible small business, the local media advertising credit determined under section 45BB(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H475EB52746CC4A86A234FE6DB803E993"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC67DE821D4DE41E58860B57B1E7F13AF" style="OLC"> <toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="HEC3AD5305BC54DF2B6A9710E321CA37A" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"> <toc-entry idref="H2AB12D0D1E6F431AA6FE6CA9494361FD" level="section">Sec. 45BB. Advertising in local newspapers and local media.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HAC748A7F3C8E40299ED4182EA07CA6D0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to amounts paid or incurred in taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

