<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H57CA88FEF9AA4688BCD585B52BB0B360" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4291 IH: Sanctions Lists Harmonization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4291</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250702">July 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a review of whether individuals or entities subject to the imposition of certain sanctions through inclusion on certain sanctions lists should also be subject to the imposition of other sanctions and included on other sanctions lists.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H57B92CCED6F3475DBA880812AE140745" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA72CFEDA2CC94579A6DF088512569585" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sanctions Lists Harmonization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H46977D1DEF7E463B8F9A4E8EA74C5849"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirements to include individuals and entities subject to united states sanctions on certain other sanctions lists</header> <subsection id="HF37AFA60C9874335B389A3827E861BB4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notification to other Federal officials</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which an individual or entity is included on one of the lists described in subsection (d), the Federal official responsible for administering such list shall notify the Federal officials responsible for administering the other lists described in subsection (d) of the inclusion of the individual or entity on such list.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H841EBBB661F54BC180E8FAE926CF01FF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination and other requirements of other Federal official</header> 
<paragraph id="HD078B27937B54211AD221897113D863B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Review</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which a Federal official receives a notification under subsection (a) of the inclusion of an individual or entity on one of the lists described in subsection (d), such Federal official shall initiate a review regarding whether such individual or entity warrants inclusion on such other lists.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H075BC6A417FC45A4ABAD7F7A5E20285C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which a Federal official receives a notification under subsection (a) of the inclusion of an individual or entity on one of the lists described in subsection (d), such Federal official shall make a determination of whether to include such individual or entity on such other lists.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0978DF405A4647A08F8D406CA747E1ED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<paragraph id="H632FA9E4A5F14D1887C0A0C54F09CB07"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the enactment of this Act, each Federal agency maintaining a list described in subsection (d) shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report—</text> <subparagraph id="H03D8981AED9247F8AAE62395E74DFF70" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>certifying compliance with subsections (a) and (b) of this section;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4A5FA7AC86E5427B8AC810E8568D81C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>explaining the agency’s deliberative process to meet the requirements in subsections (a) and (b); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC087BDE3D9B84E04ABB1208E3C973AF2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enumerating any instances in which the requirements in subsections (a) and (b) led to the inclusion of additional individuals or entities to one of the lists described in subsection (d).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H96D956AB49B24E3DA8CAD5C38699FC8B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by this subsection shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8F5D0BA920444E2E9AE61B218231E056"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Lists described</header><text>The lists described in this subsection are the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H20799C76BC3A48CEB98A48B26D6E1A0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The list of specially designated nationals and blocked persons maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FA156145E084CC79D7E21062D29A60D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The list maintained and set forth in Supplement No. 4 to part 744 of the Export Administration Regulations (commonly known as the <quote>Entity List</quote>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H915EAEA41CD942E1B9A3CEE1EC67898D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Department of Defense’s list maintained and published under 1260H of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/113">10 U.S.C. 113</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD8288367DA124185BD06364DE4FC91DB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Non-SDN Chinese Military-Industrial Complex Companies (NS–CMIC) List of the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB3790300E84342FA8D2C5AB09A6EAEDF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Sectoral Sanctions List of the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H97D92B92087248D6B663063772472EA0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Military End User List of the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFF57F5E1FB8C4FC4A659116DE19B376B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header>
<paragraph id="H06FEC128ABBF40E285A38F7A91AA2D34"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H1AC815E855CE496797196AA5E6A1596B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Armed Services, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB903FDFF34484FCCAD163D8DE97CF09D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, the Committee on Armed Services, the Select Committee on Intelligence, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF9961DBB85C4C899935F20192F1B18A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Export Administration Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Export Administration Regulations</quote> means the regulations set forth in subchapter C of chapter VII of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

