<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF8796AF37AAE49A78C6A8F01F6DD8FC0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4007 IH: Prevent Halting of Active Research Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4007</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To unfreeze and release funding for grant agreements of the National Institutes of Health, prohibit termination of such agreements for active and ongoing research, require the inclusion of termination clauses in such agreements, and prohibit termination of such agreements for no longer effectuating program goals or agency priorities.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF773DC4EC15841D4A1B7BB089B3440C5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7828789D21654B589C4277086EDEECE2" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prevent Halting of Active Research Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PHARA Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H54A6967AB77A41DAB1712E15226551C2"> <enum>2.</enum> <header>Releasing NIH grant funding</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>)—</text>
      <paragraph id="H5F03CDBFA34E41239A887EF6451AD4E7" commented="no">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>shall, immediately after the date of the enactment of this Act, with respect to a grant agreement or cooperative agreement entered into by the Secretary—</text>
        <subparagraph id="HFD0692A0CF124A2DB50DFDAFD83205E7" commented="no">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>release and expend all funding to the extent required by such agreement; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H060A96318064480A87368BD37D0D9A3F" commented="no"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>otherwise fully implement such agreement;</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HF94E5070A6BE429EBFE73B37B5DA1D94">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall, as rapidly as possible after the date of the enactment of this Act, pay all pending reimbursement requests owed by the Secretary under the agreements described in paragraph (1); and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H2F6A99CC886B4D4A96E31EB3A3F6CE42">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>may not cancel any agreement described in paragraph (1) under which an awardee is performing active and ongoing research.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
<section id="HF167472AB9564720BCCB11E025D9D16F">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Inclusion of termination clauses in NIH grant agreements and cooperative
        agreements</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any grant agreement or cooperative agreement from the National Institutes of Health that is entered into after the date of the enactment of this Act shall include a termination clause. Such clause shall specify that the agreement may only be terminated in cases of material breach, change in circumstances, or mutual agreement of all parties, provided that—</text>
      <paragraph id="H33963D8F6A2C4739B5F2798630784517">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the terminating party invoking such clause submits to all non-terminating parties a written notice of the intent to terminate at least 90 days before the date of termination; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H37BA01368C264C4AA1A5D8B2B7696AB1">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>before the date of termination, the terminating party attempts to amend the terms of the grant agreement or cooperative agreement with each non-terminating party.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
<section id="H1B1F3B25AA094B0693C921C993DC82F8"><enum>4.</enum><header>No termination of NIH grant agreements or cooperative agreements for no longer effectuating program goals or agency priorities</header> 
<subsection id="H61C317ED4E964A12A02D8A90A54ADA95"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Institutes of Health may not terminate, in whole or in part, a grant agreement or cooperative agreement that is entered into after the date of the enactment of this Act on the basis of such agreement no longer effectuating the program goals or agency priorities.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HECD2B73D5F8340C4895E11761366CA7C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulatory revision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health, shall revise section 200.340(a) of title 2, Code of Federal Regulations, in order to comply with subsection (a) of this section.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

