<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL25528-VKV-GD-J0C"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1571 IS: Advancing Frequent and Tailored Education to Rebuild Safe Communities and Help Orchestrate Opportunities and Learning Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1571</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250501">May 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To award grants to local educational agencies and nonprofit organizations to operate after school programs in certain areas with a high rate of juvenile crime.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advancing Frequent and Tailored Education to Rebuild Safe Communities and Help Orchestrate Opportunities and Learning Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>AFTER SCHOOL Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide14becb2045c469e861beb0c4d1b61eb"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants for after school programs</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idffd25152e07c48d089674e793585e57e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc5e43faad629424e8f8238815dee54eb"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ESEA terms</header><text>The terms <term>local educational agency</term> and <term>secondary school</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idecf2acb9d85c4e7b85b13622a4738f1d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible applicant</header><text>The term <term>eligible applicant</term> means an eligible local educational agency or an eligible nonprofit organization.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida34eeb1ed1c144ba92e77f0b5a9d50ae"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligible local educational agency</header><text>The term <term>eligible local educational agency</term> means a local educational agency that serves 1 or more secondary schools that are located in a county in which the juvenile offense rate for the most recent fiscal year for which data is available was not less than 10 percent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idde073bae1ec84b77b40b960cf4822d34"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible nonprofit organization</header><text>The term <term>eligible nonprofit organization</term> means an organization described in section 501(c)(3) and exempt from tax under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd3ee8b7db13046eb9b06eb4b5e95274a"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has experience in operating an after school program or similar program for secondary school students; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7b9ff886aa9f4cc7a9fe0adb037133d3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is located in a county in which the juvenile offense rate for the most recent fiscal year for which data is available was not less than 10 percent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0506e26484974e3e9ebcbb7bcceba76b"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Eligible students</header><text>The term <term>eligible students</term> means students in any of grades 6 through 12.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida680344e1df742b5a1c5d812f3ddf19a"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Juvenile offense rate</header><text>The term <term>juvenile offense rate</term> means the percentage of violent offenses committed by any individual who is not more than 19 years of age as compared to the total number of violent offenses committed by all age groups in a given county, as published in the Uniform Crime Reporting Program of the Federal Bureau of Investigation. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida86af22b6c9e4ec4887ea254bbd16420"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program established</header><text>The Attorney General shall award grants, in accordance with subsection (c), to eligible applicants that have an approved application in order to enable those eligible applicants to provide after school programs for eligible students, as described in subsection (f). </text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf31d9b3123e044caa97051c2aa16f418"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Formula</header><text>From the total amount made available to carry out this section, the Attorney General shall allot to each eligible applicant having an application approved under subsection (e), an amount that bears the same relationship to that total amount as the number of eligible students who will be served by such eligible applicant under this section bears to the number of eligible students who will be served by all eligible applicants under this section.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id14006894d96348c4918b9e53a3a7d828"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice of eligibility</header><text>On the first day of the first fiscal year beginning after the date of enactment of this Act, and of each fiscal year thereafter, the Attorney General shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide9c1bb9025a141c4a0c8f3e36ca2e70c"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine which counties in the United States had a juvenile offense rate of not less than 10 percent during the most recent fiscal year for which data is available;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc55c1ccd573a4b36806719609419e2b6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publish the determination of the Attorney General under paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf8acf64931ba43ad8adf3e7397af88d3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>publish an application that eligible applicants seeking a grant under this section can submit.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8c46397d871c4897b29a0c91d9ef44ea"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Application</header><text>An eligible applicant seeking a grant under this section shall submit the application described in subsection (d)(3) to the Attorney General at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Attorney General may require, including—</text><paragraph id="id319cff4317444f18b6f0c6ebef9693db"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the juvenile offense rate for the most recent fiscal year for which data are available for—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id21618ffe664e4c30affcaa27acea4e3c"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the eligible applicant is an eligible local educational agency, the county in which 1 or more secondary schools served by the eligible local educational agency are located; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id424cd65d87e440c7a3296a7935de0a9c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the eligible applicant is an eligible nonprofit organization, the county in which the eligible nonprofit organization is located;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf8d92e91eb4946139d4041658c6e29e0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assurance that the eligible applicant—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida341bf9624a2454c8a3230ec852b88e7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the eligible applicant is an eligible local educational agency, will carry out the after school programs or will partner only with an eligible nonprofit organization to carry out such programs; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6078be76035a4fe8bc9c667a0da8ab01"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the eligible applicant is an eligible nonprofit organization, will carry out the after school programs; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida0bc4ed8fcaf40c9938bea898218c31b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>information about the activities and frequency of the after school programs that will be carried out with grant funds under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id800891ee542a4d0bbc5c588d0928326d"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0fbc313258b54a87abe3fcaf05044027"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible applicant that receives a grant under this section shall use such grant funds to operate after school programs for eligible students, which may include—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75d90d7ff68c4e51b1a60358f0a1e54a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>expanding existing after school programs for eligible students;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb4966567a2714d8f907768d84b28765f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>developing and carrying out new after school programs for eligible students; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id06e383299d8f4d4d9b5454cd300c6ea4"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the eligible applicant is an eligible local educational agency, partnering with an eligible nonprofit organization to administer and operate after school programs for eligible students.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ec0141140ba486685684ed489cdc481"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Comprehensive program activities</header><text>An eligible applicant that receives a grant under this section shall ensure that the after school programs carried out with grant funds are programs that— </text><subparagraph id="idd2b3c9ec67a74cd180fea77b71ce4876"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are held when school is out of session; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5558d6f82b01411bb94849ddee72ebc1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include activities that have an educational purpose that aim to—</text><clause id="id6c0d03c7f44940d0a9ab7a668633fd5c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>expand learning opportunities,</text></clause><clause id="id6a903b9c118e4ca6b2ff71e1e74cafea"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>foster foundational skill development,</text></clause><clause id="idcbd7513ba09143bb9a2bb7245ad3be49"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide youth leadership opportunities; and</text></clause><clause id="id3e8c2ea36d124e778d7a7db5ab4564b6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>provide a safe and supportive environment.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd95282b83b88485da572692169743522"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6d3b34ee425242b7a37006926cf15fe6"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligible applicant reports</header><text>Each eligible applicant that receives a grant under this section shall submit an annual report to the Attorney General that describes—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4757a5cd74c345c5a2f159f4a7e03713"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of schools served by an after school program established or maintained using funds under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2a1b9277efc446cba6a48f756186b639"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of children served at each such school; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1cd5e6a9e5944238bb98d961b1fa315c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the general successes and vulnerabilities of the after school programs established or maintained using funds under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0fd05facf6df448d84a3924e43ee2edd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Attorney General report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date as of which the Attorney General has received all the reports for a year under paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall submit to Congress a report summarizing the reports received under that paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id97554d002f0840e5a1b6806fa24c7f33"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026, 2027, 2028, and 2029, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

