<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1BD022CCC282427AA0B8FE55B55AFB9A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5146 IH: Federal Receivership Fairness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5146</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250904">September 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000585">Mr. LaHood</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for certain rules regarding determination of tax in the case of a receivership.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA2A5D89A68E84378A3F18339C8DC3AC1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HED3A1713DB174FE29B2FBD89BA62C1A0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Receivership Fairness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section>
<section id="H3943A31E518B438E856EB06126CC1253"><enum>2.</enum><header>Determination of tax liability of receivership estate</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB68678238E6D43E49F7B09C4093976E6"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/70">chapter 70</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9138079BB6C4B8983A0A6AC74DC3729"> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBAB1B5B3E99548DDA0CBC8C2AE05CD13"><enum>6874.</enum><header>Determination of tax liability by courts</header> <subsection id="H20908075622E45A08EE698B60570896E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), the court appointing a receiver in any receivership proceeding before any court of the United States or of any State or the District of Columbia may determine the amount or legality of any Federal tax, any fine or penalty relating to such a tax, or any addition to such tax, whether or not previously assessed, whether or not paid, and whether or not contested before and adjudicated by a judicial or administrative tribunal of competent jurisdiction.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0FFCC709A34D40589910782B28274E01"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The court described in subsection (a) shall not determine—</text> <paragraph id="HFC2F42D0118D4DA29537DF6043DBF9BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the amount or legality of any Federal tax, fine, penalty, or addition to tax if such amount or legality was contested before and adjudicated by a judicial or administrative tribunal of competent jurisdiction before the commencement of the receivership,</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H288C9A800182453BAF30E4F692E2F270"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any right of the estate to a Federal tax refund, before the earlier of—</text> <subparagraph id="HF9E84AE05BFE4CC8A1B295164AD39CE1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>120 days after the receiver properly requests such refund, or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA7271163A0494B9E9528BD7D6F953982"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a determination by the appropriate governmental unit of such request, or</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD8A8A97EB0A485A82DEB22647FCAD6D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the amount or legality of any amount arising in connection with an ad valorem tax on real or personal property of the receivership estate, if the applicable period for contesting or redetermining that amount under any otherwise applicable law has expired.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4F7D0FF638840A88AA65E75EFDB8549"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Request for determination</header> 
<paragraph id="H3DC0D872B173459E9B26FC29BBEA7657"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Provision of address, etc</header><text>The clerk of the court described in subsection (a) shall maintain records under which the appropriate governmental unit may—</text> <subparagraph id="H404DC6D3C3814DEEB7385878754135B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designate an address for service of requests under paragraph (2), and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H71728D8EA9EE4FFDBB3C33B43DC374BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describe where further information concerning additional requirements for filing such requests may be found.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">If the appropriate governmental unit does not designate an address and provide such address to the clerk under subparagraph (A), any request made under paragraph (2) may be served at the address for the filing of a tax return or protest with respect to Federal taxes.</continuation-text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB780727929CF4A11B83F21CBD9BD5727"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Request for determination</header><text>A receiver may request a determination of any unpaid liability of the estate for any tax incurred before or during the administration of the case by submitting a tax return for such tax and a request for such a determination at the address and in the manner designated in paragraph (1). Unless such return is fraudulent, or contains a material misrepresentation, the estate, the receiver, the individual or entity in receivership, and any successor to such individual or entity are all discharged from any liability for such tax—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD3ADEBAFA0924594AACA8739CFA22373"><enum>(A)</enum><text>upon payment of the tax shown on such return, if—</text> <clause id="HA6A9DCBBD621495B8B9521FB6EEBD585"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the appropriate governmental unit does not notify the receiver, within 60 days after such request, that such return has been selected for examination, or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0170FB28B6E34E149EFA102D097F4E10"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the appropriate governmental unit does not complete such an examination and notify the receiver of any tax due within 180 days after such request or within such additional time as the court, for cause, permits,</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H46571FA24991444BB7C5901EAE1578AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon payment of the tax determined by the court, after notice and a hearing, after completion by the appropriate governmental unit of such examination; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H115F364EF7C84775AA4CA5B2FCAEE8EB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>upon payment of the tax determined by the appropriate governmental unit to be due.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H19B884B48CFE4783B6C0F772BAC67BAB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>After determination by the court of a tax under this section, the appropriate governmental unit may assess such tax against the estate, the individual or entity in receivership, any successor to such individual or entity, or any entity arising out of the receivership, as the case may be, subject to any otherwise applicable law.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28BB2E5416AE48078C6162D10EECDD8B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H158804AE52CC4DB0B1485FCA2B4F7C60"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Receiver</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8208610E69F64B38B3DD9F946E6C898E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>receiver</term> means any person or entity appointed or recognized as a receiver in any action or proceeding by order of a Federal or State court.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E59B17945D246FAB42BA3F8AE621011"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>receiver</term> does not include—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E27DDBB404B4838A1395C3C01D444B5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a bankruptcy trustee appointed in a bankruptcy case under title 11, United States Code, or</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A8AA1199BBB423D8E00F0DA5F604F00"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an executor of a decedent's estate whose rights and responsibilities as to Federal tax matters are set forth in or governed by other Federal or State law.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC8E6BCC824A24CBAA29F992BA8D02ACE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate governmental unit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate governmental unit</term> means a Federal, State, or local governmental unit responsible for the collection of taxes within the jurisdiction of such governmental unit.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA29F77225BF44C3B8218779E0D44132D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Waiver of sovereign immunity</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16530AC4C4194F01923D0D97228E179A"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Notwithstanding an assertion of sovereign immunity, sovereign immunity is abrogated as to the appropriate governmental unit to the extent set forth in this subsection with respect to the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HC67476CF2C394E02B75AE44732B33FD7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>All matters in subsections (a) through (e).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5B2FA90478284857AA22546EE13358D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The court described in subsection (a) may hear and determine any issue arising with respect to the application of this section to the appropriate governmental unit.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9680A89B45B240ACAB068DADC37EF3D4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The court may issue against the appropriate governmental unit an order, process, or judgment under this section or under the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure, including an order or judgment awarding a money recovery, but not including an award of punitive damages. Such order or judgment for costs or fees under this section or the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure against the appropriate governmental unit shall be consistent with the provisions and limitations of section 2412(d)(2)(A) of title 28, United States Code.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H79CD3D5A2BDE49449F3A9AAAF2652CBB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The enforcement of any such order, process, or judgment against the appropriate governmental unit shall be consistent with appropriate law applicable to the governmental unit and, in the case of a money judgment against the United States, shall be paid as if it is a judgment rendered by a district court of the United States or any State court.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60F995050BDA4EEAAB9E4FB877744964"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Nothing in this section shall create any substantive claim for relief or cause of action not otherwise existing under the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure or other applicable law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD08F52E711B14D43B22BED3CD983B938"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deemed waiver</header><text>If the appropriate governmental unit asserts a claim in any receivership case, the appropriate governmental unit is deemed to have waived sovereign immunity with respect to a claim against the appropriate governmental unit that is property of the receivership estate therein and that arose out of the same transaction or occurrence out of which the claim of the appropriate governmental unit arose.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA705FCB73014343BFD0CA4B5259FA56"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Offset of claims</header><text>Notwithstanding any assertion of sovereign immunity by the appropriate governmental unit, there shall be offset against a claim or interest of the appropriate governmental unit any claim against such governmental unit that is property of the receivership estate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H08FF7AED8A7A4D61B3D8239DE2A8E5B3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Federal court option</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (a), if the appropriate governmental unit objects to state court jurisdiction over any determination under this section, the matter may be transferred to, removed to, or otherwise heard by the United States District Court for the district in which the receivership is pending</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4CB38DAA7A34994AE9FFD4E988E252F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/70">chapter 70</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H03FD756218384DA2880D23B758344824"> 
<toc> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HBAB1B5B3E99548DDA0CBC8C2AE05CD13">Sec. 6874. Determination of tax liability by courts.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H383480B5133B4A9FAE620F2B31E27959"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB035F9EC0B1744A88C8B0E093B519210"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2201(a) of title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>, a proceeding under section 6874 of such Code</quote> after <quote>the Internal Revenue Code of 1986</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H24EE928B15BA4D22808E3283D740C6D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 3713(a)(2) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>, or to any receivership case or proceeding or any receivership estate governed by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6874">section 6874</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986</quote> after <quote>title 11</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDD66997AF33D4F4BAE9D8DC08635E7BB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 3713(b) of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7A4B601AB3A4F8496549BBB013A6E6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>(except a trustee acting under title 11)</quote>,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5891116881F480EB73BAD128D740B81"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>(b)(1)</quote>, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H41E8BF313B5D45B6BD94994E95EE8400"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H125DB9E3925E4F14B179CAA8DD5BA72F"> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3E6C013FC9E47FC8F59747ABDB15423" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1E27A05191747D2AF7150EC4E749A76"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a trustee acting under title 11; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H64A1542632B74250A38694846DED77D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any receiver, as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6874">section 6874(e)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, exercising the rights afforded to receivers by such section 6874.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1F9657ECC3B44DBB047F512AB430D14"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to returns for which the period during which an assessment of tax or an amendment or review or audit of the return is open as of the date of the enactment of this Act, and to returns filed on or after such date of enactment.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

