<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8CDC12F3745D4E408A478789F719B1BA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5104 IH: Preventing Health Emergencies And Temperature-related Illness and Deaths Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5104</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250903">September 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000635">Ms. Dexter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reduce the health risks of heat by establishing the National Integrated Heat Health Information System within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the National Integrated Heat Health Information System Interagency Committee to improve extreme heat preparedness, planning, and response, requiring a study, and establishing financial assistance programs to address heat effects, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8BEFC7556D584D89BDBFE13135F2C454" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H71B0A31C1C234332833D72E2E0256983"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Health Emergencies And Temperature-related Illness and Deaths Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Preventing HEAT Illness and Deaths Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H15494522B47A4DF3BAD31531D8FF32B3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H4440573243E0402686329925C54565B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community with environmental justice concerns</header><text>The term <term>community with environmental justice concerns</term> means a community with significant representation of communities of color, low-income communities, or Tribal and indigenous communities, that experiences, or is at risk of experiencing, higher or more adverse human health or environmental effects as compared to other communities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF4CD7425749486A84C0E8B834966756"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extreme heat</header><text>The term <term>extreme heat</term> means heat that substantially exceeds local climatological norms in terms of any combination of the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H7BB72E95A20E4A82A1E4F80FF65C5905"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Duration.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H14B0F3D7E3CF4419A71922AE0007E721"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Intensity.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4872472AEF7F406D87637599822DC537"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Season length.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9712E1603C4D451CB6C46429D292D64A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Frequency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H53DA3C9A64D143CCB6E7A6533BAD9010"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Heat</header><text>The term <term>heat</term> means any combination of the atmospheric parameters associated with modulating human thermoregulation, such as air temperature, humidity, solar exposure, and wind speed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H08D5E42BB2DD42039651227BDBF06C2D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Heat event</header><text>The term <term>heat event</term> means an occurrence of extreme heat of 2 days or more that may have heat-health implications.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H42AFBE1D2D154B9E8DF5984539D83590"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Heat-health</header><text>The term <term>heat-health</term> means health effects to humans from heat, during or outside of heat events, including from vulnerability and exposure, or the risk of such effects.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA2986ECE08BC492FB3783D0E70B0546E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given that term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEDA909B167624813A960E959485B09D9"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Native hawaiian organization</header><text>The term <term>Native Hawaiian organization</term> has the meaning given that term in section 6207 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7517">20 U.S.C. 7517</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1CC2268C989F44228D5914557C6FE80D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Planning</header><text>The term <term>planning</term> means activities performed across timescales (including days, weeks, months, years, and decades) with scenario-based, probabilistic or deterministic information to identify and take actions to proactively mitigate heat-health risks from increased frequency, duration, and intensity of heat waves and increased ambient temperature.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC28D6E25DE1B40E38D5CF4C449E9F6B0"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Preparedness</header><text>The term <term>preparedness</term> means activities performed across timescales (including days, weeks, months, years, and decades) with decision support tools to manage risk in advance of a heat event and increased ambient temperature.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA5F03987B58C492895539621D035C9E7"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Response</header><text>The term <term>response</term> means activities performed during and after a heat event to address heat-health and other impacts and assess improvements to planning and preparedness activities.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HA8FC12927EA846C6894C4B619D4CFD46"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Urban heat island</header><text>The term <term>urban heat island</term> means the phenomenon observed in urbanized areas in which heat is more extreme than in the surrounding exurban areas and heat is heterogeneously distributed within urbanized areas, due to factors including—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2B5974C16F2D4C5788F6B66E6100BA7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>low albedo and impervious surfaces;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HE15DBFAE5A114F368529838B13F07D2B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>low vegetation coverage; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HDCB70AAFBB1D4459836C564A94C5994D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>waste heat produced in urban areas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section>
<section id="HFFC1C9839B89412E89EF66FAEB4B8C94"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="H34DBEF5831AC43BDA671EBA336902E37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Extreme heat events have been the leading cause of weather-related death in the United States over the last 30 years, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the National Weather Service.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEDCE3A01E24447089395DCE0222B08AC">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>The fourth National Climate Assessment, mandated by the Global Change Research Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2921">15 U.S.C. 2921 et seq.</external-xref>), finds that during the next few decades, annual average temperature over the contiguous United States is projected to increase by a further 2.2°F relative to current temperatures, regardless of future scenarios. The National Climate Assessment projects that the frequency and intensity of extreme heat events will increase in the future as global temperature increases.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H52EAAD9F2B0745BD95DC6F4FD2F15CC5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Exposure to extreme heat can cause acute heat-related illnesses, such as heat stroke, which already result in more than 65,000 emergency room visits each year and exacerbate respiratory and cardiovascular illnesses.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D09F39D5F6240549706EB483DB7B8A3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Heat poses the greatest health risks for adults older than 65 years of age, pregnant people, young children, low-income communities, urban communities, communities with low air conditioning prevalence, socially isolated individuals, people with mental or physical disabilities, people with underlying medical conditions, agricultural or other outdoor workers, workers without sufficient access to cooling, athletes, incarcerated individuals, people experiencing homelessness, and military personnel.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8EAE39FAF75E444F854D0AA394FD6BC9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Extreme heat is significantly associated with serious adverse pregnancy outcomes across the United States. Those adverse pregnancy outcomes disproportionately impact Black mothers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H96A89B3D4CFF4CD99E18BA8C8DF0A4BE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Heat exposure is an issue of environmental justice, as people living in low-income communities, communities of color, and Tribal nations face a number of interacting factors that render them more vulnerable to extreme heat.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H00202CA2BCFA4C6A977587954B000462"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The impacts of heat on human health are more severe in urban areas where land surface properties create an urban heat island, particularly in neighborhoods with limited availability of or access to green spaces, shade, and tree cover, due to higher density of building structures and more vehicular traffic.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0414A38825944358AA270E720E42B836"> <enum>(8)</enum> <text>Limited availability of tree cover and higher temperatures are correlated with low-income neighborhoods in urban areas. In Richmond, Virginia, Baltimore, Maryland, and Washington, DC, researchers found that risk of exposure to extreme heat is disproportionately distributed to communities of color in patterns associated with segregation and redlining.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD21E0E321DD242AAAFB3766D792EE849"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Researchers have found that few communities in the United States have sufficient climate and health information, guidance, and resources for heat planning, preparedness, and response.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFCAA97DBD80849299AC868A49145BD06"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The risks associated with extreme heat have complex interactions and impacts, and the management of those risks requires a transdisciplinary approach.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF7BBB03547AB4E3CBAAA25B5CD30DC21"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Regions, communities, and populations that face the greatest health consequences of extreme heat often may experience the lowest heat risk perceptions, have limited incentives, or have access to the fewest resources for responding to extreme heat, and as such, may be less likely to take precautions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3703B12B72AD420FAE93C0E6744AB698"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Research on the impacts of extreme heat on human health and the effectiveness of solutions under varying climate, social, and other contexts is stymied by a lack of access to reliable, timely health observations and surveillance due to proprietary data rights, expense, privacy and security concerns, inconsistent reporting of health outcomes and contributory factors, poor data integration and interoperability, few incentives and little systematic coordination to address those problems, and a lack of adequate climate observation, modeling, and assessment in rural, urban, indoor, and occupational settings.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H89603EF346AA44B7B74A5038D6680160"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Integrated climate and health research and information, when developed in a collaborative, transdisciplinary manner, can inform long- and medium-range scenario-based planning and decision making to protect communities with environmental justice concerns and other populations from extreme heat, reduce exposure to extreme heat, and address factors that increase vulnerability.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H651FDB6AD3B14581AAC4DB721651D415"> <enum>(14)</enum> <text>The Federal Government has developed, and should maintain, preserve, or reinstate, various science-informed heat-health tools for communities with environmental justice concerns, workers, employers, and the public to understand heat risk and resources, including the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention Heat and Health Tracker, the Office of Climate Change and Health Equity Climate and Health Outlook, the National Weather Service HeatRisk portal, the National Emergency Medical Services Information System Heat-related Emergency Management Service Activation Surveillance Dashboard, and the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Program and Extreme Heat website.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4C60AF1B2C6A4FE1A113A1E78FA67FEE"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Increased heat can have cascading and compounding impacts across and among sectors including energy, food supply and quality, transportation, housing, infrastructure, hospital and healthcare delivery, and education, all of which affect health and well-being.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF302BE67ED64542AD8A9879B93CB977"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Heat action plans and early warning systems can reduce heat-related morbidity and mortality by clearly identifying roles and responsibilities as well as evidence-based actions and thresholds to enhance preparedness, and by promoting behavior changes and actions taken by local governments, communities, and individuals through awareness and increased risk perception among those most vulnerable to the health impacts of heat.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H0983633F64C24E2D9B969DBAAC299554"><enum>4.</enum><header>National Integrated Heat Health Information System Interagency Committee</header>
<subsection id="H43A7528E8B96445488BDAEAA0BB0113C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of committee</header><text>There is established within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration an interagency committee, to be known as the <quote>National Integrated Heat Health Information System Interagency Committee</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD7FD8C9AC2544966AB5C0FDEDDCCD59B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The Committee shall coordinate, plan, and direct agencies represented on the Committee to execute, as appropriate, activities across such agencies to ensure a united Federal approach to reducing health risks from heat across timescales (including days, weeks, months, years, and decades).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H5A9CCB17044F402DA059B7F81B80F003"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header>
<paragraph id="H8EEE1D808761411C936C724334C2F962"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order to carry out and achieve the purpose described in subsection (b), the Committee shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HA3834CDB2CFC446A9C6E5C9C4E56811F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Director of the National Integrated Heat Health Information System.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H93F5538516F04F9B8C8148A7B2245B5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Not fewer than 1 representative from each of the following:</text> <clause id="H0D9B994AD52240BDBA2047C6CE605C44"><enum>(i)</enum><text>From the Department of Commerce, the following:</text>
<subclause id="HA5F508B00FFA42F8A5DC66B84B8C5993"><enum>(I)</enum><text>From the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the following:</text> <item id="H5B936CB4B43144E19C4C43F93B80FEA5"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>The National Weather Service.</text></item>
<item id="HDBCB294596594D539DB58236D38BADC7"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>The Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research.</text></item> <item id="HCAE3878DC2C44C09AEBDBB787CF134C2"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>The National Environmental Satellite, Data, and Information Service.</text></item></subclause>
<subclause id="H986F2C0234104CC8BB3B5A34879CDAB3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF8222E59A8844AB483B3C71DAA3C5973"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The Bureau of the Census.</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="HF01A80C398C54AE791953C364BD24E06"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>From the Department of Health and Human Services, the following:</text> <subclause id="HBA7B6D5476E644848AA932FA0220D293"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, including the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health.</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H76ED540BD045452CBCA4FC206A0A4639"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The Office of the Assistant Secretary of Health and Human Services for Preparedness and Response.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H4BD3A1D3C8014C8E9FE63A3CEAFF527C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration.</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H3A9871F1DAF2413A8488E1F5BB24FB22"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>The National Institutes of Health.</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB85A124992E1494DAF0188EA6FCE93E7"><enum>(V)</enum><text>The Indian Health Service.</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H9095EE7504A54367B0C7AF209D504936"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>The Administration for Children and Families.</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H07CD9C2A06314C119A880BFA661C852C"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>The Administration for Community Living.</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="HFBA4C0C24C384416B80790214FC517C4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>From the Department of the Interior, the following:</text> <subclause id="H5CD890B7F6D44E6384E5F10791C93E5A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Bureau of Indian Affairs.</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H5FF32285E1184747A9F0B4C2CD934C8F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The Bureau of Land Management.</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E63CB3AACFF41FD8EB86000B50F802D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The National Park Service.</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HD38A07248E8548F5953C529E872A6440"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>The Office of Hawaiian Relations.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H1CB9F5E01FB04DEA92C0DF9D74383175"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>From the Environmental Protection Agency, the following:</text>
<subclause id="H493CA46F65E34707ABAEC66AFB418DEE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Office of Environmental Justice and External Civil Rights.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H5DE686656DAC4FFE8A8775DCF37F6104"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The Office of Air and Radiation, if the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency determines appropriate.</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HEF0F6C880FC64D12A320F59139FB7FF0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The Office of Research and Development, if the Administrator determines appropriate.</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H60427AA383494AD9A3C9A2B0151F1FD7"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>The Office of International and Tribal Affairs.</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H992391A9B18F45109758B024996A3310"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The Department of Homeland Security, including the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text></clause> <clause id="H3BDC6DBEA8264A4C9B176BB17163BC2F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The Department of Defense.</text></clause>
<clause id="H3AF1E91F57DC4C19A0A1E2067B6B3C6B"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The Department of Agriculture, including the United States Forest Service.</text></clause> <clause id="H4D83668193364ED0AFC87ADB3B477AB0"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text></clause>
<clause id="H1DFC064B5C5D425FAE4E3CDBCCE7267B"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>The Department of Transportation.</text></clause> <clause id="HDEA3E34E9A3B47178B9621759B63AB1D"><enum>(x)</enum><text>The Department of Energy.</text></clause>
<clause id="H0192BEE67CB04D35B0D7EAD6F8895059"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>The Department of Labor, including the Occupational Safety and Health Administration.</text></clause> <clause id="HC1CC5B05FDA44B1DB6EE91C840C6F4A4"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>The Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></clause>
<clause id="H4694A3F92AA24B95A3DC1DF5E528411B"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>The Department of Education.</text></clause> <clause id="H68AA867F89BE4EB3973B0497E477BA97"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>The Department of State.</text></clause>
<clause id="H067188399D514D338931A84170592B19"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>The Small Business Administration.</text></clause> <clause id="H244DBCAE2EA14558813264E4BF0C4063"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text>Such other Federal agencies as the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere considers appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HF4A0FDD24B7C44FDA0FB8D4C2C16EF75"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection of representatives</header><text>The head of an agency specified in paragraph (1)(B) shall, in appointing representatives of the agency to the Committee, select representatives who have expertise in areas relevant to the responsibilities of the Committee, such as weather and climate prediction, health impacts, environmental justice, urban planning, behavioral science, public health hazard preparedness and response, or mental health services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H782A49934D9640CF871B4BEFB234F731"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Co-chairs</header> <subparagraph id="HF001879B217E46CCB778E79EB21F0C1A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The members of the Committee shall select 3 individuals from among such members to serve as co-chairs of the Committee, subject to the approval of the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H10F56387D07F4ACF9E87D2CBF19245B5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Selection</header>
<clause id="H60E9C66D20B24286B9C4ECE945AD7A2C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Initial selection</header><text>Of the co-chairs first selected, one co-chair shall be from each of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Department of Health and Human Services, and the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text></clause> <clause id="H9473DF7E1166478AAFF7C57BAF0E41B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Subsequent selection</header><text>Subsequent co-chairs shall be selected from among the members of the Committee, except the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall have the opportunity to maintain a co-chair position.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H00B482AB175049A9A89D0FF223A7AC0B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>Each co-chair shall serve for a term of not more than 5 years, except the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall have the opportunity to maintain a co-chair position.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H96DB508C964749638FF088EC8D1D6D10"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Representation of National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If determined appropriate by the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere, 1 co-chair of the Committee shall be a representative from the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE9C3FADA1FDA435F98CB2B51213FE0BA"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Responsibilities of co-chairs</header><text>The co-chairs of the Committee shall work with the Director of the National Integrated Heat Health Information System—</text> <clause id="HFB5816D2096846EDA358CDD0DB191B61"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to determine the agenda of the Committee, in consultation with other members of the Committee;</text></clause>
<clause id="H9F7CDA46B84C4CE3AC0BB717B1F04173"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to direct the work of the Committee; and</text></clause> <clause id="HE6E4953552AA4B55A80DB5D72F434E75"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to convene meetings of the Committee not less frequently than once each fiscal quarter.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H56173440FFBD4E4FAB7A3AB3A8504257"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Responsibilities of Committee</header><text>The Committee shall promote an integrated, Federal Government-wide approach to reducing health risks and impacts of heat, including by—</text> <paragraph id="HB2097090E9904F90A5FC823C41FCCD83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>developing the strategic plan and implementation plans required by subsection (e);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC77806189C5F4656BA5EE21849EC66CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinating across Federal agencies on heat-health communication, engagement, research, service delivery, financial assistance, contracting, and workforce development; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA4379D083124A0A82807E71BCCB2AD6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>building capacity and partnerships with Federal and non-Federal entities.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H16053F7EC3BC4A0B9A1414346DC8ABBE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Strategic plan</header>
<paragraph id="H5BE8C49B06F941999207ECCBD682A2D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Committee shall submit to Congress and make available on a public website a 5-year strategic plan that outlines the goals and projects of the Committee, including how the Committee will improve coordination and integration of interagency Federal capacity and capabilities to address health risks of heat, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H9704A3D2504341AC8D1FD64843566FA0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a strategy for improving and coordinating existing Federal data collection and data management to include sharing of data and statistics on heat-related illnesses and mortalities and other impacts, such as agricultural losses, energy and transportation system disruptions, and labor productivity, to inform heat-related activities;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H07BBD1260753433B9A6A2AD30783B511"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a strategy for improving and coordinating Federal activities to understand user gaps and needs, conduct research, foster innovative solutions, and provide actionable information and services for extreme heat prevention and response; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2571A0E958434F749F188D2858AD8B95"><enum>(C)</enum><text>mechanisms for financing heat planning, and preparedness, and response within such agencies as the Committee considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H67A9E956111E40B9BB22C639BBB208B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The head of an agency represented on the Committee may implement the portions of the strategic plan required by paragraph (1) that are relevant to that agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H10240F4AF695401FAF06E1749324C4C5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the submission of the strategic plan required by paragraph (1), and every 5 years thereafter, the Committee shall brief Congress on an update of the plan, which shall include progress made toward goals outlined in the plan and new priorities that emerge.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC393CA8FB1C64AF8800E583B7145CE69"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Administrative support</header><text>The Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere shall provide technical and administrative support to the Committee, using amounts authorized to be appropriated to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0814DA2525B44E8582DD7DDD5E7F02EF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out the responsibilities of the Committee, the Committee shall consult with relevant—</text>
<paragraph id="HBEEE686749D743118E9672088E3EC6EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>regional, State, and local governments, and Indian Tribes;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0C95DDEF98AA4CF6AAE37AF73371C418"><enum>(2)</enum><text>international organizations and partners;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H10DE9C7A8A51401FB54075FD0B05549C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>research institutions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8CEF3A4CB551498482C62FBE5D3D8F28"><enum>(4)</enum><text>nongovernmental organizations and associations;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA4EF48FA848C4CE59943B541CB379342"><enum>(5)</enum><text>medical experts with expertise in emergency response; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD97BABEC08EE40A2871CE6EF7B7850BF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>environmental health, economic or business development, or community engagement organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H68C302AEEFD34D08AC83C743B0705F33"><enum>5.</enum><header>National Integrated Heat Health Information System</header>
<subsection id="H67B02EE140AE439991E0A9F843738B04"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere shall establish within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration a system, to be known as the <quote>National Integrated Heat Health Information System</quote> (NIHHIS) (in this section referred to as the <quote>System</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H28C67D295F084A719914A752960AD64F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the System is to reduce heat-related impacts by—</text>
<paragraph id="H169CD20156524147B94C96FEA51C9BBB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improving the delivery of data, information, forecasts, warnings, predictions, and projections related to temperature, extreme heat, and related impacts, especially for disproportionately affected communities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H253E7D284D4342E5A5B2E751FBE4187A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>through the Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research, developing, maintaining, and preserving science-based solutions and tools to build capacity and improve impact-based decision support services for heat resilience, particularly human life; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF9DCFE933B654DEB8C90F37E89F903AE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>entering into grant agreements with centers of excellence that provide technical and other assistance to support heat resilience.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA639440235BA40D59453EB6A8655D821"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The System shall be headed by a Director.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HB946F789D12E47C8A0AB329283942109"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>In carrying out the purpose described in subsection (b), the Director of the System shall—</text> <paragraph id="H3A81464E0D4C486B9DC5861C944C4541"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop and sustain robust relationships with Federal and non-Federal partners and decisionmakers, representing different geographic (including urban and rural) regions and including—</text>
<subparagraph id="H9F7DF44EC8EF409391E78A2F773F9840" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>members of the emergency management field and emergency response providers, including fire service, law enforcement, hazardous materials response, emergency medical services, and emergency management personnel, or organizations representing such individuals;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H92871B8BA42840D8AF92BEF5E456E247"><enum>(B)</enum><text>health scientists, emergency and inpatient medical providers, public health professionals, and healthcare providers at Federally Qualified Health Centers;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H332FA8F4EFF442CDA17244EC1B5E30EA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>experts from Federal, State, and local governments and Indian Tribes, and the private sector, representing standards-setting and accrediting organizations, including representatives from the voluntary consensus codes and standards development community, particularly those with expertise in the emergency preparedness and response field;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF2DD8BBC32A249B6ABBC34ECD590A580"><enum>(D)</enum><text>state and local government and Indian Tribes officials with expertise in preparedness, protection, response, recovery, and mitigation, including Adjutants General;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H11814A0BC1C1457FB49CCD03160FBCA2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>elected State and local government and Indian Tribe executives;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4DE349CD84248A3B756B57EDE809FC2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>representatives of individuals from communities who have a high proportion of extreme heat survivors and communities with environmental justice concerns;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H945856B941B344ECB3EE534AF0AAAB88"><enum>(G)</enum><text>representatives of individuals with disabilities and other populations with special needs;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD4A2F46127640A3895722B15AEE0C7A"><enum>(H)</enum><text>representatives of individuals from the private, nonprofit, and public energy sector that help to protect consumers from energy shutoffs and assist with energy rebate funding; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7A45109A872C4691BCA0F944F7EA17D8" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such other individuals as the Under Secretary of Commerce considers appropriate—</text> <clause id="H98257235BE884296B229AD2342AFD535" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to identify and respond to the demand for actionable weather- and climate-related information that reduces health risks on multiple timescales;</text></clause>
<clause id="H84ECF990CA104C9DB5334EB84A1BCF95" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to conduct research and scientific innovation; and</text></clause> <clause id="H09EE3D6ABE5E4BE291D340E0776EE2A2" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to develop and deliver timely and accessible decision support services, solutions, tools, and information to inform planning, preparedness, and risk-reducing actions across timescales;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H67A03C459911420DBD8415DA3523787D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinate and collaborate with the international community and global partners to conduct research and learn from, leverage, and contribute to global knowledge as it pertains to predicting and preventing the impacts of increased heat;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBBAC228F29A2494BA12772BDAE50E1FD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>enhance observations, surveillance, monitoring, and analysis necessary for the activities described in paragraphs (1) and (2); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA490C7A121D84068840C338FED61C005"><enum>(4)</enum><text>communicate, educate, and build awareness regarding the risks and impacts of increased heat and extreme heat events to communities, educational and economic sectors, Indian Tribes, and other relevant stakeholders.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB8AA4748603945C5BDB88A18EB24463B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Data management</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9CB64DD494124AEDA68C92F14767EB26"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Availability of data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the System shall coordinate with interagency partners to ensure that data and metadata associated with the System is fully and openly available, within the legal right to redistribute, in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Federal Records Act of 1950</quote>), and the Foundations for Evidence-Based Policymaking Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/435">Public Law 115–435</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 5529) and the amendments made by that Act, to maximize use of such data to support the goals of the System.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEBCA934D432F4A39AEBB6440F4AD9D06"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Data management strategies</header><text>In coordination with the activities described in paragraph (1), the Director of the System and interagency partners shall—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB385C1D869444090B65CAD56BD805400"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop data management strategies to ensure that data and metadata are adequately stewarded, maintained, and archived in accordance with—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H45D999AA94434B9CBEE5A6552DA66657"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">findable, accessible, interoperable, and reusable (FAIR) principles;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H553E39F56A73483F9A7E8E5D67D6EF82"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Foundations for Evidence-Based Policymaking Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/435">Public Law 115–435</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 5529) and the amendments made by that Act; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5C168B1B1334EE2A1D716AD1AB1E79C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collective benefit, authority to control, responsibility, and ethics (CARE) principles; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E3D716B36874D6FA8EB1B6AF3285FD0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preserve and curate such data and metadata, in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0D937AEA5F6946AE824341F3DC5E2F3C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National Centers for Environmental Information</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF4626FFB59BF4B8280C26068EE4C9F88"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere shall manage, maintain, and steward archival data and metadata associated with the System within the National Centers for Environmental Information.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD66E110C2FCF45D49FCCF8764ACB1A60"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Warning coordination meteorologist</header><text>The Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere shall designate at least one warning coordination meteorologist with expertise in heat warnings, as described in section 405 of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8545">15 U.S.C. 8545</external-xref>), at the National Centers for Environmental Information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF4A178FF1D5B47D082D83E2BAD6C8D99"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Research program</header><text>The Director of the System shall develop and implement a climate and health research grant program, in coordination with the financial assistance program under section 7 and other Federal programs—</text> <paragraph id="H5592EB39565340D8905271185A8F70AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to improve understanding of—</text>
<subparagraph id="HFFE09CCE351A462BB1798A2D7FBE8C30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the climate epidemiology and social, behavioral, and economic drivers of heat-health vulnerability and risk;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBA3EF04D35C546BAACD153422C330219"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the drivers of climate variability, predictability, and changes in extreme heat; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H69F08ACEDB9640AF96276E76AB6E2A12"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the impacts of extreme heat, compound hazards, and cascading impacts across timescales;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D4AE7ED84E14D0D92D021E983964F39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to investigate and evaluate the effectiveness of risk management actions, interventions, policies, standards, codes, and guidelines; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD04ABE791AC94A88816AA2D169C0E4CD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to address other topics as appropriate, including topics outlined in the strategic plan required by section 4(e)(1) and the financial assistance program under section 7.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1E91B6A0FA4545E4B4DC38145CEB1D1C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Additional activities</header><text>The Director of the System shall carry out such other activities as the National Integrated Heat Health Information System Interagency Committee established under section 5 considers appropriate.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H47C90633114A408C9ADD55467ABF21A3"><enum>6.</enum><header>Study on extreme heat information and response</header>
<subsection id="HD9018ECDB1AF49F3AECCCDD3D93DA266"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header>
<paragraph id="HDD24C4A84E1A4ABAA7034895BE4F31AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere, in consultation with the National Integrated Heat Health Information System Interagency Committee established under section 4 (in this section referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>) and the individuals and entities described in section 4(g), shall seek to enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to conduct a study on extreme heat information and response, to be completed not later than 3 years after such date of enactment.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC6215FAFC91468B871769B24F791DAA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The study described in paragraph (1) shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H2C17EE85A570482BA312806F9EAD0AA6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify policy and research gaps, which may include—</text> <clause id="HE8888E254C644BDEA2206E3DC4E091B1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>regions of the United States with the largest gaps between awareness, preparedness, and capacity to address extreme heat; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HE25DBC64BD1D4CD5BF1D9508635F488A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>heat-related gaps in data, such as—</text> <subclause id="H2AE56AE64D53498196BA2E8CF8D9279D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of schools, prisons, and other public facilities that lack air conditioning;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H03C9C3C310824D93942FDA2546B44AEB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the demographic breakdown of people affected by heat events, including by race, age, gender, occupation, and income;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H25EB123B8FB6431A807A27F44684CAA2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>capacity building, research, and heat resilience resource shortages in rural and urban communities;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H3612FBD1686D46CA8F26904F719A62B0"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>medical coding in health care facilities (such as hospitals, emergency rooms, and health centers) that indicate heat-related illnesses (such as kidney failure, dehydration, and fainting spells);</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8AD504DCFE3148EFB7DEF8D7E073874D"><enum>(V)</enum><text>with respect to public policy at the State and community level that enhances vulnerabilities to extreme heat (such as outdoor working conditions and thresholds to protect workers, animals, and others susceptible to heat-related illness); and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H0C69E44A5C0F4083A22203D616A1B31F" commented="no">
                <enum>(VI)</enum>
 <text>the extent to which Federal heat-health tools that have been discontinued, dismantled, or otherwise limited in public accessibility and availability, including the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention Heat and Health Tracker, the Office of Climate Change and Health Equity Climate and Health Outlook, the National Weather Service HeatRisk portal, the National Emergency Medical Services Information System Heat-related Emergency Management Service Activation Surveillance Dashboard, and the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Program and Extreme Heat website, have contributed to changes in extreme heat risk, education, and data collection;</text>
              </subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2697AFF0BCCD4FA8999B9FBAD281BAB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide recommendations for addressing gaps with respect to policy, research, operations, communications, and data, including the gaps identified under subparagraph (A), affecting heat-health planning, preparedness, response, resilience, adaptation, and environmental justice and equity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H815B86F950FA408F8A2A5CCA54D02E7E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide such other recommendations as the Director of the National Integrated Heat Health Information System established under section 5 considers appropriate, which may include strategies for—</text>
<clause id="H8D884BA2E16146B191E0903748A5AC31"><enum>(i)</enum><text>communicating warnings to and providing impact-based decision support to promote preparedness actions and resilience of populations with limited opportunities to avoid extreme heat, including to individuals who may have barriers to such information;</text></clause> <clause id="HA55A6D8A3E554DE0A9D22634E1DFEA25"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>understanding compound and cascading risks, and implementing alternative heat-health risk reduction interventions to manage those risks collectively, such as reducing risk of the transmission of infectious diseases during heat waves by creating outdoor cooling locations or increasing ventilation and filtration in indoor cooling centers;</text></clause>
<clause id="HE3B00C4B9A1143719879D979E336DCE8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>promoting community resilience to heat events and incorporating principles of environmental justice in community response to heat waves;</text></clause> <clause id="HDE50705A8553437AA7EEE94791C3F6B5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>addressing the impacts of extreme heat on energy cost, affordability, and reliability for residential and commercial infrastructure (such as weatherization, energy costs, electric power systems, and water supply and treatment systems); and</text></clause>
<clause id="HC8C3918853824FFFA243B98FC141A7B3"><enum>(v)</enum><text>developing protections for workers for the effects of indoor and outdoor heat; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H43FC334352A54F098F6DACE190509DCA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>consider such other subjects as the Committee considers appropriate, which may include—</text>
<clause id="HC40D25AAE11946F2B8D971126495C681"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the feasibility of enhancing and standardizing existing nationwide data collection on heat-related illnesses and mortalities to improve and ensure consistent collection of national-level heat illness data across all 50 States, territories, and local jurisdictions of the United States;</text></clause> <clause id="H6D56E197BF054337A0349E7B065F4042"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>mechanisms for financing heat preparedness; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HC1D6E5F596C04843B49BFF1424AE3C5B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the effectiveness of county-or local-level heat awareness and communication approaches, heat action, and tools, preparedness plans, or mitigation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H79ABD81AF46B4FF6B422724DB39324BC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Development of definitions</header><text>Following the study described in paragraph (1), the Committee shall work with heat experts across disciplines to comprehensively identify impacts of increased heat to inform consistent and agreed upon definitions for heat events, heat waves, and other relevant terms.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H678D100C59184E6DA09B32A039D017D4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after completing the study described in subsection (a)(1), the Committee shall—</text> <paragraph id="HEF52090513B446129AD15440FE61EFC4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make available to the public on a Federal internet website of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration a report on the findings and conclusions of the study; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD29FB56CC2AC4073974E8AF50315C52B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit the report to—</text> <subparagraph id="H6005675CACA34275845296912FEC83E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H651194FED65B4A86BAB639ECC6C1F407"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1ED089684E4C4B47974FE622AF73D74B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1F991D01D2D24074B62B897941643BB0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H742345656D8A4007AA8DFD6721ABD68A"> <enum>(E)</enum> <text>the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives.</text>
          </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H3DBE8C078A0D40DC81BAD587968DEC15"><enum>7.</enum><header>Financial assistance for resilience in addressing extreme heat and health risks</header>
<subsection id="H25902D088507448F87CB3D1D70F60DA0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Community heat resilience program</header>
<paragraph id="H9BE94BCDAE4F44B1804E9269EC3F9547"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Integrated Heat Health Information System established under section 5 (in this section referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>) may, in coordination with the National Integrated Heat Health Information System Interagency Committee established under section 4 (in this section referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>), establish and administer a community heat resilience program to provide financial assistance to eligible entities to carry out projects described in subsection (e) to ameliorate human health impacts of extreme heat events.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7838A175609641CC94F6F7F71069F6AF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Revision</header><text>Upon completion of the strategic plan required by section 4(e)(1), the Committee may revise the community heat resilience program to ensure the program aligns with the strategic plan and is administered in accordance with the plan.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H1177079979794665A61E1AD4B6258B9B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the financial assistance provided under this section is to improve community resilience to heat and heat-health impacts and further scientific research to address adaptation gaps and priorities.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2CFCFE10E92F4E5CA3154B3CBC473C23"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Forms of assistance</header><text>Financial assistance provided under this section may be in the form of prizes, contracts, grants, or cooperative agreements.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H81E5C3BA7BCA42A7BFACD387D0B7276A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>Entities eligible to receive financial assistance under this section to carry out projects described in subsection (e) include—</text> <paragraph id="HC8032CD2E4924FE19A3DD831A640CFAA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>nonprofit entities;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE5FF6DE265A84070BAABF643FC156D98"><enum>(2)</enum><text>States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC96F19AFCEE4E1E974BB76C2DF1BD10"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Indian Tribes;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9CAB2EFA59544D19BF96B46024722C04"><enum>(4)</enum><text>local governments;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA475756F7F1F4B8FBB06D9EFD01B76F2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>local workforce development boards;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H78DB5FEA37D642AAB905F0AD3924E60D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>academic institutions; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38EA0FF88DE54F3D81D2E1D9A4A582DC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>centers of excellence designated by the National Integrated Heat Health Information System.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H09B54BC3CC844927A489DBFF538B5655"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Eligible projects</header><text>Projects described in this subsection include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H05BA9F22E9654C0EA07B1DC7608982EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Projects to reduce heat-health risks, including sustainable heat reduction and mitigation solutions such as for cool roofs, cool pavements, urban forestry or tree plantings and maintenance, the provision of shade, cooling and resilience centers, retrofitting buildings for cooling, improving the resilience of the power grid to ensure reliable air conditioning, energy efficiency, acquisitions or upgrades of filtration systems or high-efficiency air conditioning systems, and strategies to improve community level response before and during a heat event.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAB3992161BED4547A7C47BA41998C393"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Training programs to support the development and integration of education and training programs for identifying and addressing risks associated with climate change for vulnerable individuals.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94B7F03D238D425681C8C7A964305745"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Projects designed to improve heat risk mitigation capacity, research, and resource access and deployment in rural and urban communities.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H035611C3E05B4D9EB544BD957CE17526"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Projects focusing on being responsive to heat-related needs from communities heard from engagements at different geographic scales (national to regional to local) including—</text> <subparagraph id="HF98799FBB9244989AC1C6E461E549CA0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to expand public awareness of heat risks;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H45B2ED99693E48D29D4AFADA1F918448"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to conduct community-based climate and health observational campaigns;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD529E67454EB44F2BBC86CA827C69821"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to conduct scientific research to assess and address gaps and priorities regarding the risks of extreme heat in communities;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF34C960D6EC74E5386707341EF7D6286"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to communicate risks and warnings to isolated communities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H22F29EB6EF434E41B746D2CA35714C3C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to support the establishment of workplace policies and practices to reduce the risk of extreme heat illness among workers;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H99545A4863914459834DEB54AEE8BF1B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to educate such communities about how to respond to extreme heat events; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF1933F4E0824488C87BFC97C038FC818"><enum>(G)</enum><text>to establish local, city, and county heat planning and heat-related emergency action plans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9E63F8E80F149459DBB01AB06E1A607"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other projects that the Director determines will achieve a significant reduction in heat risk or increased resilience to increased heat or extreme heat events.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HCB62A0BF751943E5941BA555C92140D6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Priorities</header><text>In selecting eligible entities to receive financial assistance under this section, the Director shall prioritize entities that will carry out projects that provide benefits for historically disadvantaged communities and communities with significant heat disparities associated with race, ethnicity, or income.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HBFD1EAF6390F43DA9A2FEBC784CDBE2F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Distribution of assistance</header>
<paragraph id="H75DBB956E66048E1856274D3291EDA48">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Communities with environmental justice concerns and low-income
            communities</header>
 <text>Not less than 40 percent of the amount of financial assistance provided under this section in any fiscal year shall be provided to eligible entities to implement projects described in subsection (e) in communities with environmental justice concerns or low-income communities.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H71ADC1FCFC244E7A92EC84D57D02D2DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Equitable distribution</header><text>The Director shall seek to equitably distribute financial assistance provided under this section based on geographic location or such other factors as the Director determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H4DF347DCE98C418D872F3673AB0CB3CD"><enum>8.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> <subsection id="H3BB8130265314C2C94EC5E06EEA9170F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National Integrated Heat Health Information System Interagency Committee; National Integrated Heat Health Information System</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to carry out sections 4 and 5, including for any administrative costs for the National Integrated Heat Health Information System Interagency Committee and the National Integrated Heat Health Information System, the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H947B73D22C2D4EBD8F16D39F759FCA65"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2026, $20,000,000.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9219BEB792C409E948D46993E5E7E14"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2027, $20,000,000.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H39A5F4B19FB94A5AA51E2846C6261579"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2028, $20,000,000.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H84E35411E8FC4D72AC025AAEBAED59C8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2029, $20,000,000.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H367F18D62B91498CB63FE15E6FCD86FF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2030, $20,000,000.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2DE99D2FC56A465DBC792ADCD70F9C23"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study on extreme heat information and response</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to contract with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to carry out section 6 $500,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2028.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HFDB9854A12834415AA994FC62EEEB9EC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Financial assistance for resilience in addressing extreme heat and health risks</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to carry out section 7 the following:</text> <paragraph id="H19547149D0FF40538E78894016E1DA7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2026, $10,000,000.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDE846277A8E240BC95D628295DC4CEDD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2027, $10,000,000.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC36B6BFB70404829AB5088E7BE379102"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2028, $20,000,000.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6F23F539404E4A1F94FFFDD09F011393"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2029, $30,000,000.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAED1D73359F940128CA8AD00C8E45713"><enum>(5)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2030, $30,000,000.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

