<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE47CB0BE92344778A4ED02073FC0D8B2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2086 IH: Rights for the Transportation Security Administration Workforce Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2086</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250311">March 11, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000598">Mr. LaLota</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To enhance the security operations of the Transportation Security Administration and stability of the transportation security workforce by applying the personnel system under title 5, United States Code, to employees of the Transportation Security Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H6B62922C6A8C40EDA6663479185571FE" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H957EE1FD73BA410EBF0E0A8D69403B8D"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rights for the Transportation Security Administration Workforce Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Rights for the TSA Workforce Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H5A4BEEA55DD74660ABD8E852A2EA9EB3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF05F409A525B4EB68DB980AA11F42DB3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>2022 Determination</term> means the publication, entitled <quote>Determination on Transportation Security Officers and Collective Bargaining</quote>, issued on December 30, 2022, by Administrator David P. Pekoske, as modified, or any superseding subsequent determination;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H086FBAFB97694FF591A0AB1326237398"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>adjusted basic pay</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HC856BCF9300B474CB58C20D239765571"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the rate of pay fixed by law or administrative action for a position occupied by a covered employee before any deductions; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H80D0367BD9FF4677BEA96630726E63BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any regular, fixed supplemental payment for non-overtime hours of work creditable as basic pay for retirement purposes, including any applicable locality payment and any special rate supplement;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7E65EDF36AEF483DA92B5BA5118CE9CA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>Administration</term> means the Transportation Security Administration;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HF5ED89864369438EBF1C14250E8459BF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Administration;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE6CDD9076A9C4BD5B87CFF1C79A09213"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means— </text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HACDD623824F8419FBF2D50AA3CBDB14B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDCAE3DE7F0EC41CA917F372C8FE38036" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H481DC7DB1D6444A18334E622B90E20EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBEA53D80918F4A599B3BC2F3D48D2A63"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives; </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD384C215AE704AC3A53D72EDC67E3534"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>conversion date</term> means the date on which subparagraphs (A) through (F) of section 3(c)(1) take effect;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H46B9580E4A934708B2D5856E91389EC9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the term <term>covered employee</term> means an employee who occupies a covered position;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F18A69111194E6AAA508E1C81E16CB4"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the term <term>covered position</term> means a position within the Administration;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H575B577F53A3478AADD137A3079821EF"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the term <term>employee</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2105 of title 5, United States Code;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H54CF7ADBF9034D4CB99203C3BF898228"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the term <term>screening agent</term> means a full- or part-time non-supervisory covered employee carrying out screening functions under section 44901 of title 49, United States Code; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3DA5E31E5CC1404F9CE7A8C5EE1C84BA"><enum>(11)</enum><text>the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H495E3B7408154DB2AC70490A86EF5A96"><enum>(12)</enum><text>the term <term>TSA personnel management system</term> means any personnel management system established or modified under—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H026E04A0E72C4F55BB2D2E5D45E1F24A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 111(d) of the Aviation and Transportation Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44935">49 U.S.C. 44935</external-xref> note); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H90B58394D3D04CF39C1F857548E2774D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 114(n) of title 49, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H0F52551E8D684564BA78FEAA0AF31EA9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Conversion of TSA personnel</header> 
<subsection id="HABE9C7DEF511496DB6AE3E6FB8B72A80"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Restrictions on certain personnel authorities</header> 
<paragraph id="H9C312361BD664FCFBEA27B960F345FFB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, effective as of the date of enactment of this Act—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H31A60FE0E2864E6DB8C2C8D2B59A8BFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any TSA personnel management system in use for covered employees and covered positions on the day before that date of enactment, and any personnel management policy, letter, guideline, or directive of the Administration in effect on that day, may not be modified;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HDD042FDF5E3D48AFB8E1AFE50A965555"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no personnel management policy, letter, guideline, or directive of the Administration that was not established before that date issued pursuant to section 111(d) of the Aviation and Transportation Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44935">49 U.S.C. 44935</external-xref> note) or section 114(n) of title 49, United States Code, may be established; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H470FF460B3164CF688C8F728CC3D673A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any authority to establish or adjust a human resources management system under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/97">chapter 97</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall terminate with respect to covered employees and covered positions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEC2FF4511F52461B9734418EFB44001D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header> 
<subparagraph id="H29E76A944450473E85DCD44FC1B3F235"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Pay</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (1)(A), the limitation in that paragraph shall not apply to any personnel management policy, letter, guideline, or directive of the Administration relating to annual adjustments to pay schedules and locality-based comparability payments in order to maintain parity with those adjustments authorized under sections 5303, 5304, 5304a, and 5318 of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2FFA156DF39E4326BCDC352518AF1BCA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (1)(B), new personnel management policy of the Administration may be issued if—</text> 
<clause id="H08656682951B41D9B6BF95F0C275BC1C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that policy is needed to resolve a matter not specifically addressed in policy in effect on that date of enactment; and</text></clause> <clause id="H0B2DC8C86BFB4F88BC39E7ADC67F8F12"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Secretary provides that policy, with an explanation of the necessity of that policy, to the appropriate congressional committees not later than 7 days after the date on which the policy is issued.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6E8C1044DF21467BB359CBA9E3050A61"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Emerging threats to transportation security during transition period</header> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D8E358CC26D4D2BA83D82D7355334C8"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), any personnel management policy, letter, guideline, or directive of the Administration relating to an emerging threat to transportation security, including national emergencies or disasters and public health threats to transportation security, may be modified or established until the conversion date. </text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H68B70DDE36714C4D90B38788ED6ACD62"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 7 days after the date on which any personnel management policy, letter, guideline, or directive of the Administration is modified or established under clause (i), the Secretary shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees that established or modified policy, letter, guideline, or directive, as applicable, which shall contain an explanation of the necessity of that establishment or modification.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H8F0F1789950A418FB7036564E153D8AA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Personnel authorities during transition period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any TSA personnel management system in use for covered employees and covered positions on the day before the date of enactment of this Act, and any personnel management policy, letter, guideline, or directive of the Administration in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act, shall remain in effect until the conversion date.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5F01A2715EF5484493BE52B42E717733"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transition to title 5</header> <paragraph id="HCF96EC4213E64D1B87C0C1D855B7B8B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), effective beginning on a date determined by the Secretary, but in no event later than December 31, 2025—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H50D3C2201DE84A558BB67D117DCDE344"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all TSA personnel management systems shall cease to be in effect;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H43B8F42147364CE89F462D9F25AD0058"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 114(n) of title 49, United States Code, is repealed;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7175155D8A704C7F9D443973648E364F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 111(d) of the Aviation and Transportation Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/71">Public Law 107–71</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44935">49 U.S.C. 44935</external-xref> note) is repealed; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H0EC97D08B7454C509ED192278E42982A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any personnel management policy, letter, guideline, or directive of the Administration, including the 2022 Determination, shall cease to be effective;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H271B777FB6534D8187CDB1A7787D1F83"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any human resources management system established or adjusted under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/97">chapter 97</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, with respect to covered employees or covered positions shall cease to be effective; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2C64D528A72457AB5C9649CE1F21F39"><enum>(F)</enum><text>covered employees and covered positions shall be subject to the provisions of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD63B9F1B79544E209F8806C4FACD8AE9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chapters 71 and 77 of title 5</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act—</text> <subparagraph id="H8B752382D2904B738888DBBCD5E677A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">chapters 71 and 77 of title 5, United States Code, shall apply to covered employees carrying out screening functions pursuant to section 44901 of title 49, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDFEA967E17314387B263F159B6B43717"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any policy, letter, guideline, or directive issued under section 111(d) of the Aviation and Transportation Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44935">49 U.S.C. 44935</external-xref> note) relating to matters otherwise covered by chapter 71 or 77 of title 5, United States Code, shall cease to be in effect.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1B3667550B954D99BFD068F3B05A4193"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assistance of other agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, or December 31, 2025, whichever is earlier—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8783BD671CAE4587997DCAE78334D002"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall establish a position series and classification standard for the positions of Transportation Security Officer, Federal air marshal, Transportation Security Inspector, and other positions requested by the Administrator; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4B566F283E20461AA17677FEE5519429"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the National Finance Center of the Department of Agriculture shall make necessary changes to Financial Management Services and Human Resources Management Services to ensure payroll, leave, and other personnel processing systems for covered employees are consistent with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, and provide functions as needed to implement this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H82AB8D0AC5524E6FA2373DD09A568D7E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Safeguards on grievances and appeals</header> 
<paragraph id="H5CBF4B7B70B34CE59DE6B6FE35FD0D30"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each covered employee with a grievance or appeal pending within the Administration on the date of enactment of this Act or initiated during the transition period described in subsection (c) may have that grievance or appeal removed to proceedings pursuant to title 5, United States Code, or continued within TSA.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD0AAEF97DBE74AD58212E34B5DA36DC7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>With respect to any grievance or appeal continued within the Administration under paragraph (1), the Administrator may consider and finally adjudicate that grievance or appeal notwithstanding any other provision of this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HED9DA947F3074F7E9ED32BD1D5B9D73C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Preservation of rights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any appeal or grievance continued under this section that is not finally adjudicated under paragraph (2) shall be preserved and all timelines tolled until the rights afforded by application of chapters 71 and 77 of title 5, United States Code, are made available under subsection (c)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HBB8C6958D0E44EDFA0C126C6816015A7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Transition rules</header> <subsection id="H6E0CE57FEB0A4B30ADDEC5B2C2D23296"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Nonreduction in pay and compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under such pay conversion rules as the Secretary may prescribe to carry out this Act, a covered employee converted from a TSA personnel management system to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, under section 3(c)(1)(F)—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA44ED6E550BA44228203064875083D31"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not be subject to any reduction in either the rate of adjusted basic pay payable or law enforcement availability pay payable to that covered employee; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5DADCBCE7CAA4E25A495406286608539"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be credited for years of service in a specific pay band under a TSA personnel management system as if the covered employee had served in an equivalent General Schedule position at the same grade, for purposes of determining the appropriate step within a grade at which to establish the converted rate of pay of the covered employee.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H259F7717248B4E7E99B09C9FB8773808"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Retirement pay</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H70457D1CE6724BEDBAF7774D017A2DDA"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a proposal, including proposed legislative changes if needed, for determining the average pay of any covered employee who retires not later than 3 years after the conversion date for purposes of calculating the retirement annuity of the covered employee. </text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB8A0A05BE1174568B074C735172B67B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The proposal required under paragraph (1) shall be structured in a manner that—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD96CF31C91F54C7884B8E909DA42F470"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is consistent with title 5, United States Code; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA7C5E0DE3F584BFDAC321957A58D8E49"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">appropriately accounts for the service of a covered employee to which the proposal applies, and the annual rate of basic pay of such a covered employee, following the conversion date.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8873A037B5C74BD690F7CF37F02BDC69"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation on premium pay</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4733BC786C642188C5D79A86048F303"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 5547 of title 5, United States Code, or any other provision of law, a Federal air marshal or criminal investigator who is appointed to that position before the date of enactment of this Act may be eligible for premium pay up to the maximum level allowed by the Administrator before the date of enactment of this Act. </text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C64FC5C59434A7FA447ABB07392C23F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>OPM recognition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall recognize premium pay paid pursuant to paragraph (1) as fully creditable for the purposes of calculating pay and retirement benefits.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H0C75B5F0BF9F4456AA1EDC0B94D7B346"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Preservation of law enforcement availability pay and overtime pay rates for Federal air marshals</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HE1D25BD52761499D8CB2B40A5345DF79"><enum>(1)</enum><header>LEAP</header><text>Section 5545a of title 5, United States Code, is amended— </text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8923D4CB7A3C49E19FE090B61F427D50"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>subsection (k)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (l)</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5B2F99EF8FF347EBADCC4D2F99619D56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (k) as subsection (l); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4E0567291534826A8B987169EA7B402"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after subsection (j) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA70252772E47487491F285D7DDAA15BB"> 
<subsection commented="no" id="HF304FDD8A3A44416BB89404F3F627AA6"><enum>(k)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of subsections (a) through (h) providing for availability pay shall apply to any Federal air marshal who is an employee of the Transportation Security Administration.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H0A56AE020FB245AB922225AAEC3ADA33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Overtime</header><text>Section 5542 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC3DEA532E3AC4A018A9CB8C796C358D6"> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H85BFB4AF608D4A2298E7DCED2D5777F1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a Federal air marshal who is an employee of the Transportation Security Administration shall receive overtime pay under this section, at such a rate and in such a manner so that such Federal air marshal does not receive less overtime pay than such Federal air marshal would receive were that Federal air marshal subject to the overtime pay provisions of section 7 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/207">29 U.S.C. 207</external-xref>).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HA8FE1B184CB748989C718044A3AE92AC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by paragraphs (1) and (2) shall apply beginning on the conversion date.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8F500AD147564E37AB025B7C16EDED57"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Collective bargaining unit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 7112 of title 5, United States Code, following the application of chapter 71 of that title pursuant to section 3(c)(2) of this Act, screening agents shall remain eligible to form a collective bargaining unit.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB54785A699C84E42836EC277CC8E9F00"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Preservation of other rights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall take any actions necessary to ensure that the following rights are preserved and available for each covered employee beginning on the conversion date, and for any covered employee appointed after the conversion date, and continue to remain available to covered employees after the conversion date:</text> 
<paragraph id="HCC039CBAC15540ECA86523B7141D85A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any annual leave, sick leave, or other paid leave accrued, accumulated, or otherwise available to a covered employee immediately before the conversion date shall remain available to the covered employee until used, subject to any limitation on accumulated leave under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H075BEA76268345DA9858095C035E3BE7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part-time screening agents pay premiums under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, on the same basis as full-time covered employees. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA7D2BE98F89A4053A715581A53CBA7CE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 6329a of title 5, United States Code, covered employees are provided appropriate leave during national emergencies to assist the covered employees and ensure the Administration meets mission requirements. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD75E9FFF53A6421FAE7809CE31BFAA8F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligible screening agents receive a split-shift differential for regularly scheduled split-shift work as well as regularly scheduled overtime and irregular and occasional split-shift work.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1CB1AF945B8741B7AFC78721CD768522"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding sections subsections (c), (e), and (f) of section 5754 of title 5, United States Code, eligible covered employees receive group retention incentives, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H2246D7626AA64655A7713AD7E0503245"><enum>5.</enum><header>Consultation requirement</header> <subsection id="H3FFFCF26F96147CD86B009801F23E05E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exclusive representative</header> <paragraph id="H87DE2FDBC9ED4166933709A58F541683"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header> <subparagraph id="H043BE12E558444D6BFAD444098E020D7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Beginning on the date that <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/71">chapter 71</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (referred to in this subsection as <quote>chapter 71</quote>), begins to apply to covered employees under section 3(c)(2), the labor organization certified by the Federal Labor Relations Authority on June 29, 2011, or any successor labor organization, shall be treated as the exclusive representative of screening agents and shall be the exclusive representative for screening agents under chapter 71, with full rights under chapter 71.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF6940FAEE13A45E0A5C09A84206F6222"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prevent covered employees from selecting an exclusive representative other than the labor organization described in paragraph (1) for purposes of collective bargaining under chapter 71. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE8EF949C1BB94FCFAD61CBC73B42ED1B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National level</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA848E65B7E5B4B2EB81B43AC67E5CFE0"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any provision of chapter 71, collective bargaining for any unit of covered employees shall occur at the national level, but may be supplemented by local level bargaining and local level agreements in furtherance of elements of a national agreement or on issues of any local unit of covered employees not otherwise covered by a national agreement.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7549E47C1D2C4D6D829C87A136556F3E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Mutual consent required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Local-level bargaining and local-level agreements described in subparagraph (A) shall occur only by mutual consent of the exclusive representative of screening agents and the Federal Security Director (or a designee of such an official) of those screening agents.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H52F8B5EC2653465B9D44D11667EF2B47"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Current agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any collective bargaining agreement covering such personnel in effect on the date of enactment of this Act shall remain in effect until a collective bargaining agreement is entered into under chapter 71, unless the Administrator and exclusive representative mutually agree to revisions to such an agreement.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H77361F0A974D4A8B95FB320B022FC215"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation process</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA434AB26FA4E4564839368FF592A742C"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 7 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall consult with the exclusive representative for the screening agents described in subsection (a)(1) under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/71">chapter 71</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, on the formulation of plans and deadlines to carry out the conversion, under this Act, of those screening agents. </text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC576EB4799D475D91EF571F8F581125"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Written plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before the date that <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/71">chapter 71</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, begins to apply under section 3(c)(2), the Secretary shall provide (in writing) to the exclusive representative described in paragraph (1) the plans for how the Secretary intends to carry out the conversion of covered employees under this Act, including with respect to such matters as—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFC6944DA56F34A0A8F5384CB9A9C7457"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the anticipated conversion date; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBC7725108FD74A288D7D82B1BBFF6270"><enum>(B)</enum><text>measures to ensure compliance with sections 3 and 4.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB615B0582A994BBEAFE2A12376C3EE4C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Required agency response</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any views or recommendations are presented under subsection (b) by the exclusive representative described in that subsection, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H80533014E71240F89B416930159B3D25"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider the views or recommendations before taking final action on any matter with respect to which the views or recommendations are presented; and </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C43E4EA4820450298EFCD3FF09896FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide the exclusive representative a written statement of the reasons for the final actions to be taken.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H21B5F5C17A074868AAF171BFF8846211"><enum>6.</enum><header>No right to strike</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> Nothing in this Act may be considered—</text> 
<paragraph id="H05088E7865164FC9A2D0894769403750"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to repeal or otherwise affect—</text> <subparagraph id="HCC440A948C1F40E8A1EBE398281DAEC8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 1918 of title 18, United States Code (relating to disloyalty and asserting the right to strike against the Government); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF3AAD85DB9AA49D6AD777F1D39719DE1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 7311 of title 5, United States Code (relating to loyalty and striking); or</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE69522D94B243BCAE0F6852D9532E7A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to otherwise authorize any activity that is not permitted under a provision of law described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section commented="no" id="H057CA80A18E74D43B97D73530AE503B1"><enum>7.</enum><header>Proposal on hiring and contracting background check requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a plan to harmonize and update, for the purposes of making appointments and for authorizing or entering into any contract for service, the restrictions under section 70105(c) of title 46, United States Code, (relating to the issuance of transportation security cards) and section 44936 of title 49, United States Code, (relating to employment investigations and restrictions). </text></section> <section id="HEB8C14C029824914A78680610E11A8A2"><enum>8.</enum><header>Comptroller General reviews</header> <subsection id="H833C637727C04AFBBF5DA7263E84ABCE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review of recruitment</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2147512D8A4B4CB59C6266F25613D038"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the efforts of the Administration regarding recruitment, including recruitment efforts relating to veterans, the dependents of veterans, members of the Armed Forces, and the dependents of such members. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0DAB370E647D4D52BEACE72357CEF459"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recruitment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under paragraph (1) shall include recommendations regarding how the Administration may improve the recruitment efforts described in that paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H08A8744CCB754330A6A7F3647713BAAA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review of implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall— </text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03B20CDD3EA648769A79454B9B54EF1E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 60 days after the conversion date, commence a review of the implementation of this Act; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C1B1F30BD184E88B718C1F210FC851E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 1 year after the conversion date, submit to Congress a report on the review conducted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0BEA1ED3CCA04FD9AF69C0D88760CCDB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review of promotion policies and leadership diversity</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report— </text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C16206CA5DB42E8AA49ECFB3EE49598"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on the efforts of the Administration to ensure that recruitment, appointment, promotion, and advancement opportunities within the Administration are equitable and provide for demographics among senior leadership that are reflective of the workforce demographics of the United States; and </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B38F3D8B3AC4B668D5BB5A02759F50A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that, to the extent possible, includes— </text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4EDF513EAB984605B570F9337D25ACBC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an overview and analysis of the current (as of the date on which the report is submitted) demographics of the leadership of the Administration; and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H60F0C4AB0BAC48F2B12530EA03C4BDC2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as appropriate, recommendations to improve appointment and promotion procedures and diversity in leadership roles, which may include recommendations for how the Administration can better promote from within the Administration and retain and advance covered employees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H88420DFF08C24F169E1FCDC91AFEF1C7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Review of harassment and assault policies and protections</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF16578B44B88430CB36045DC2D9361A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the efforts of the Administration to ensure the safety of the staff of the Administration with respect to harassment and assault in the workplace, such as incidents— </text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B976714ECDA4D6B858BF02BA340F74E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of sexual harassment and violence and harassment and violence motivated by the perceived race, ethnicity, religion, gender identity, or sexuality of an individual; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAC046AE37C3F4ABF93675136266C51E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in which the alleged perpetrator is a member of the general public. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H40E08FA5434449278BC8D3BD42753A8E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under paragraph (1) shall include— </text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB81EED09FE094449AC8A80081B436558"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an overview and analysis of the current (as of the date on which the report is submitted) policies and response procedures of the Administration; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H734AE0F119864DEAB590FA469EF57376"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detailed description of if, when, and how the policies described in subparagraph (A) fail to adequately protect covered employees; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D7A235058CB42818C66134A648B2861"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as appropriate, recommendations for steps the Administration can take to better protect covered employees from harassment and violence in the workplace. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C3E90A5324C4DF9A69BF89597BAE9FF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Opportunity for comment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the review required under this subsection, the Comptroller General of the United States shall provide opportunities for covered employees of all levels and positions, and labor organizations and associations representing those covered employees, to submit comments, including in an anonymous form, and take those comments into account in the final recommendations of the Comptroller General.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HAF908A0A35FA4CD6B8D5E73AC680364E"><enum>9.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC91119DE7C6E41769E862C9F70C600D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>TSA personnel management systems provide insufficient benefits and workplace protections to the workforce that secures the transportation systems of the United States; </text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C3D700F18264E96AF507C47A6514FC7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">covered employees should be provided protections and benefits under title 5, United States Code; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7EAC5BBA9D1940478953EADF52015E9C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the provision of the protections and benefits described in paragraph (2) should not result in a reduction of pay or benefits to current covered employees.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HB071C88332324A25A84743231B50AFD3"><enum>10.</enum><header>Assistance for Federal Air Marshal Service</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Administrator shall communicate with organizations representing a significant number of Federal air marshals, to the extent provided by law, to address concerns regarding Federal Air Marshals related to the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HCDAC63462C264A91B6D2893B5409C171"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Mental health.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E8CADCB33624D14A3E108B588C0AC1B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Suicide rates.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H04F2A6DCDC034E08AF4DEECBBF5EB038"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Morale and recruitment.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H622CAEDEA5BB4F18A817B8C4F457CE05"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Equipment and training.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H981E60ED86954CF4BD6BD07BC351D23A"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Work schedules and shifts, including mandated periods of rest.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H623227BE26594271BA56768C8EBE85B0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any other personnel issues the Administrator determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HF6F614F5C0C441FABA1BFB2A8BED310D"><enum>11.</enum><header>Briefing on assaults and threats on TSA employees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall brief the appropriate congressional committees regarding the following:</text> <paragraph id="HD74F22FBA8B84F7C87077C95F3150238"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reports to the Administrator of instances of physical or verbal assaults or threats made by members of the general public against screening agents since January 1, 2019.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAB850D8D9C584EDA879CACEEB15F015E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Procedures for reporting the assaults and threats described in paragraph (1), including information on how the Administrator communicates the availability of those procedures.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H47B1AEC5A32E4AF9AA0D37A0DBBFE131"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any steps taken by the Administration to prevent and respond to the assaults and threats described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD927074336C44809A0418A4699D8EC14"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any related civil actions and criminal referrals made annually since January 1, 2019.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H16FFD09310ED4B9DBF822EE75C077A51"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any additional authorities needed by the Administrator to better prevent or respond to the assaults and threats described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HA1FA47FC48D74404A0E6916BBBB9E313"><enum>12.</enum><header>Annual reports on TSA workforce</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains the following:</text> <paragraph id="H870DFC6D43F542B5B3B8080B20B72CB5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of the Federal Employee Viewpoint Survey of the Office of Personnel Management to determine job satisfaction rates of covered employees.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H93E989769BB04D10B285650170EC9FAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information relating to retention rates of covered employees at each airport, including transfers, in addition to aggregate retention rates of covered employees across the workforce of the Administration.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H98F870D0D77A4BA6808B31C062216C96"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information relating to actions taken by the Administration intended to improve workforce morale and retention.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HCDF73DB82D604BDC824599391B38BE49"><enum>13.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary, to remain available until expended, to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act. </text></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

