<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC718D4AB1F984A4EA7EA535588157145" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1817 IH: Arturo Alfonso Schomburg Congressional Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1817</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250303">March 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To award a Congressional Gold Medal to Arturo Alfonso Schomburg, in recognition of his pioneering work in collecting and preserving the history and culture of the African diaspora.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H56D11BCE23D14422A0B318E3B4FA4C11" style="OLC"><section id="HB7452884EC8A4481B6882573A8232F22" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Arturo Alfonso Schomburg Congressional Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFBAECA466504447DA243FD0B051E7F68"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="H75AA09BF6C174488918001C11714F280"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Arturo Alfonso Schomburg was born on January 24, 1874, in Santurce, Puerto Rico, to a Puerto Rican father of German descent and an Afro-Caribbean mother from St. Croix.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBBA5E3D2C124568B36D2BB77E7623D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In his youth, a teacher told Schomburg that people of African descent had no history, heroes, or accomplishments, which inspired him to dedicate his life to proving this notion wrong by collecting evidence of the contributions of Africans and their descendants.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FF55F556D88448DB82278297FFDEE7C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>At the age of 17, Schomburg immigrated to New York City, where he became an active member of the intellectual community during the Harlem Renaissance, contributing significantly to the promotion of African and African American culture and history.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7ED9925DDF02416D80FFE8A040890037"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Schomburg amassed a personal collection of over 10,000 items related to Black history and the African diaspora, which he made accessible to the public.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H470AAE0508D64DDDACB3B2D229D0E2BB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>His collection featured original newspapers published by Frederick Douglass, poems by Phillis Wheatley, letters from Toussaint Louverture, books and journals by Paul Cuffe, and music composed by Chevalier de Saint-Georges.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD2651FF653747248C0BEC5C6DFDEABE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>During the 1920s, Schomburg was an active member of the Negro Society for Historical Research and the American Negro Academy, writing on the history of the global African diaspora and Cuban poets of African descent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C6C9B38B14C4B0398BB2CA36ED3BAFD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In 1926, the New York Public Library acquired Schomburg’s collection, which became the foundation for the Schomburg Center for Research in Black Culture in Harlem, a world-renowned institution for the study of the global Black experience.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H74D376AA279E4AE6A7C54F0CAD652AB3"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Schomburg’s archive has grown to more than 10 million items.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H893B6598103F495A978A4E8E6069C0CC"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Schomburg’s efforts have inspired generations of scholars, writers, and artists to explore and celebrate the rich history and culture of the African diaspora.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBC46A56FFC5449C9AC4DA1A472236D0"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Congressional Gold Medal would be an appropriate way to honor Schomburg’s legacy and his role in laying the foundation for future scholarship and global recognition of Black contributions to society.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2C02D6E935CB4D478F60732CFA9B26B5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header><subsection id="H81467863B9A74DA88E664B2C465A3285"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Award authorized</header><text>The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the posthumous presentation, on behalf of Congress, of a gold medal of appropriate design to Arturo Alfonso Schomburg, in recognition of his pioneering work in collecting and preserving the history and culture of the African diaspora.</text></subsection><subsection id="H323DE015C2A14329A3A2EE413867C584"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text>For the purposes of the presentation referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0EAEEB6E01044B3EADAF6AC28FE5B296"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Smithsonian institution</header><paragraph id="H3512052E77E44D55AA3CCCB97E399F8D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Following the award of the gold medal under subsection (a), the gold medal shall be given to the National Museum of African American History and Culture of the Smithsonian Institution, where it shall be displayed as appropriate and made available for research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E7F3883EC8B4ECE93E89842B70834ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Smithsonian Institution should make the gold medal received under paragraph (1) available for display elsewhere, particularly at other locations and events associated with Arturo Alfonso Schomburg.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H98258E9256C44F7BADF8D4F8912BA7EC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to section 3, at a price sufficient to cover the cost thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section><section id="H4AD14EBBD6D042D3B4E4CCB6DF9EBFF0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header><subsection id="H798A45EF42E7430D8F425CDB6CD24C22"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>The medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE7C39DE51BBB44DA9526610D1946CB75"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>or purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE716BBAB3BB64FD4B787F62B689A9434"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority To use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header><subsection id="H108D63F210EC4290B667BBAB57BD819D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To use fund amounts</header><text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3AC1CD1E547840B88DC150D4792375C9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 4 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

