<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA75BF362854D4229B580A3CE5777E75F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4755 IH: LEO K9 Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4755</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250725">July 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001314">Mr. Bean of Florida</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001216">Mr. Mills</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit harming animals used in law enforcement, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFF00B4294D734DAF97B4653E482535DD" style="OLC"><section id="HBB2546C6D94E42C89BAA0826144B8953" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>LEO K9 Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB8A0E82D2A8D481D9DC622DECF6E1AFC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Harming animals used in law enforcement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1368 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking subsection (b) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H4DCE7EE0CDE34652981444B23A2494EB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H5248D321440F4EE187FFBF5B53E471C4"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever, in the commission of any act described in subsection (a), uses a deadly or dangerous weapon (including a weapon intended to cause death or danger but that fails to do so by reason of a defective component), shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 15 years, or both.</text></subsection><subsection id="H824D69B623B8433289CF93D6325CB17C"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>police animal</quote> means a dog or horse in the service of a Federal agency (whether in the executive, legislative, or judicial branch), or in the service of a State, county, or local agency that is assisting a Federal agency—</text><paragraph id="HF01484551AEE4E2A8D81618F882E7396"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for the principal purpose of aiding in the detection of criminal activity, enforcement of laws, or the apprehension of criminal offenders, the detection of flammable materials, the investigation of fires, the detection of missing persons (including persons who are lost, who are trapped under debris as the result of a natural, manmade, or technological disaster, or who are drowning victims); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H748FBD4BEB1B4263A51E81D3F8BB33E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>used in any official military capacity by the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD27C5A1C3E394C43897B0D3F547E4431"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section does not apply to a person who acts in good faith to provide emergency veterinary care to an injured police animal.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HEB756F327C0E4E37BDC4C0FBF56A9532"><enum>3.</enum><header>Medical transportation for police dogs injured in official duty</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation, acting through the Office of Emergency Medical Services Initiatives at the National Highway Transportation Safety Administration, shall publish guidance for emergency medical services personnel in order to care for police dogs injured while such police dog is engaged in official duties of the dog. The Secretary shall develop such guidance using existing Federal guidelines of the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Defense, the Canine Tactical Combat Casualty Care Guidelines, and other resources already available at Federal agencies. The Secretary may consult accredited veterinarians, as necessary, in developing the guidance under this section.</text></section><section id="H6D5D5CCC519C4F38BB4E5D53A03534E7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Regulations for Emergency Medical Transportation Services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 240 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall promulgate regulations to ensure that—</text><paragraph id="H2EC463F4888E4817AADA4AADCCA2E072"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a police dog injured while such police dog is engaged in official duties of the dog may be transported to a veterinary clinic or similar facility if there is no individual requiring medical attention or transport at that time; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4680D3E090A940C68B97896D185A645E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a paramedic or an emergency medical technician may provide emergency medical care to a police dog while such police dog is engaged in official duties of the dog while at the scene of the emergency or while the police dog is being transported to a veterinary clinic or similar facility.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H1456557E5EED4A039F1BC056952F260B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>police dog</quote> means a police animal (as such term is defined in section 1368 of title 18, United States Code) that is a dog, and includes a similar dog working in the service of a State, county, or local agency.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

