<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BON25101-17G-98-355"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2032 IS: Choose Medicare Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2032</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250611">June 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for the establishment of Medicare part E public health plans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H1EDD429D2A1F4C23BC86D4A5A1E15956"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Choose Medicare Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idD58988E0751247DF9E95AE0437738968"><enum>2.</enum><header>Public health plan</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id12206f61ca064591a24ad19ed9afc162"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Social Security Act is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB7B1E6BE39E84DAE8E4D76CA3AB0D6F4"><section id="idFEFC7D444FB649D589BB4ED5DEFF12A6"><enum>2201.</enum><header>Title XXII—Medicare part E public health plans</header><text><header-in-text level="subsection" style="traditional">Public health plans.—</header-in-text></text><subsection id="id912174730AA845CE8EE2A464897F2DB3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish public health plans (to be known as <quote>Medicare part E plans</quote>) that are available in the individual market, small group market, and large group market.</text></subsection><subsection id="idB8054AE026114F88A0C4314F942DF016"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Benefits</header><paragraph id="id045EB0AED5234957BD689CF0D7F7C990"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each Medicare part E plan, regardless of whether the plan is offered in the individual market, small group market, or large group market, shall be a qualified health plan within the meaning of section 1301(a) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18021">42 U.S.C. 18021(a)</external-xref>) that—</text><subparagraph id="id5200793E6FE44E25A0D65E64BBF58D91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>meets all requirements applicable to qualified health plans under subtitle D of title I of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18021">42 U.S.C. 18021 et seq.</external-xref>) (other than the requirement under section 1301(a)(1)(C)(ii) of such Act) and title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg">42 U.S.C. 300gg et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD98FA2E5A0EF4183BF5136FFC0FFF9A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides coverage of—</text><clause id="id1C07687C54E04188AAABF9F7DD7CE965"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the essential health benefits described in section 1302(b) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18022">42 U.S.C. 18022(b)</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause id="idD8D37CE8221F4F06BBB0AE1FCE3E529E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all items and services for which benefits are available under title XVIII;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2F684FF9F29548E3A527B26FE85F4529"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides gold-level coverage described in section 1302(d)(1)(C) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18022">42 U.S.C. 18022(d)(1)(C)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0E874B5E7FF94D76A47DFFA5E8E30FAB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provides coverage of abortions and all other reproductive services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id617EB12A876D41BBBDF4182A6A5FBFA2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Preemption</header><text>Notwithstanding section 1303(a)(1) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18023">42 U.S.C. 18023(a)(1)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="idFBB35AD08A7F43C899856BFC8E053320"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State may not prohibit a Medicare part E plan from offering the coverage described in paragraph (1)(D); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id58F41A4D11D246A883BDA770C2C5BF72"><enum>(B)</enum><text>no provision of State law that would prohibit such a plan from offering such coverage shall apply to such plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2C8C1187510542B39DFECB1351AB6AEC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility; enrollment</header><paragraph id="id4335B05660B64DB3B9AA624454E5E116"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Availability on the Exchanges</header><text>The Medicare part E plans offered in the individual and small group markets shall be offered through the Federal and State Exchanges, including the Small Business Health Options Program Exchanges (commonly referred to as the <quote>SHOP Exchanges</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id012729BAFD4D4A0CB43BA5C60A1A6706"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><subparagraph id="id2A5FE4FA957F4AB1A1599FBD5EAD493D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any individual who is a resident of the United States, as determined by the Secretary under subparagraph (C), and who is not an individual described in subparagraph (B), is eligible to enroll in a Medicare part E plan.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id76EFAB3B8EA2488A97762A03041981CE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>An individual described in this subparagraph is any individual who is—</text><clause id="idBD881511B00B4A558373A76AB41871B0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>entitled to, or enrolled for, benefits under title XVIII;</text></clause><clause id="id970ED017C9024B3491226442824CF449"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>eligible for medical assistance under a State plan under title XIX; or</text></clause><clause id="id9A65472D2D554131AA3D64EFF660B01E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>enrolled for child health assistance or pregnancy-related assistance under a State plan under title XXI.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5303A37404CC4A049570B0BAD328A7EE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall promulgate a rule for determining residency for purposes of subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idB428381E6A2B4CD2BB4B55F151C972D5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Employer-sponsored plans</header><subparagraph id="id073B288D89DF4BBAA4F1553EB8C5788D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Employer enrollment</header><text>Effective with respect to the first plan year that begins 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Choose Medicare Act</short-title> and each plan year thereafter, the Secretary shall provide options for Medicare part E plans in the small group market and large group market that are voluntary, and available to all employers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD5A67C48CCA44A0DB3B8906B59DEFCDE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Group health plans</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Administrator for the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, at the request of a plan sponsor, shall serve as a third party administrator of a group health plan that is a Medicare part E plan offered by such sponsor.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD5A0921158A442D593658953AF84AC48"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Portability for employer-sponsored plans</header><text>The Secretary shall develop a process for allowing individuals enrolled in a Medicare part E plan offered in the small group market or large group market to maintain health insurance coverage through a Medicare part E plan if the individual subsequently loses eligibility for enrollment in such a plan based on termination of the employment relationship. The ability to maintain such coverage shall exist regardless of whether the individual has the option to enroll in other health insurance coverage, including coverage offered in the individual market or through a subsequent employer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id636D60CB536B42D091123A66FDF87E0C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Premiums</header><text>The Secretary shall establish premium rates for the Medicare part E plans that—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id9D32776E2FAD46C19362531DBFF89D66"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are adjusted based on—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id62E25FDD3FAF4745B086312F01022D06"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether the plan is offered in the individual market, small group market, or large group market; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id05FBD81AAF7F4126905361EB09DE1589"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the applicable rating area;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idAE973320B8C942109657453E3D611975"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are at a level sufficient to fully finance—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id4DFF529A2FF845168A3A6CF29D2205DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the costs of health benefits provided by such plans; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idC8367E6519004F8EB1CD26EAE39A6A33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>administrative costs related to operating the plans; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idD6E39457E91648DD969D3625347C511D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>comply with the requirements under section 2701 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg">42 U.S.C. 300gg</external-xref>), including for such plans that are offered in the large group market.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idD384274478324BF099D340B51A78AEFB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Providers and reimbursement rates</header><paragraph commented="no" id="idFEEAFE5E06154200A0DC5B438F1988BB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a rate schedule for reimbursing types of health care providers furnishing items and services under the Medicare part E plans at rates that are consistent with the negotiations described in paragraph (2) and are necessary to maintain network adequacy.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id450F083DEC7E4EDEA14A0AA09C76DF53"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Manner of negotiation</header><text>The Secretary shall negotiate the rates described in paragraph (1) in a manner that results in payment rates that are not lower, in the aggregate, than rates under title XVIII, and not higher, in the aggregate, than the average rates paid by other health insurance issuers offering health insurance coverage through an Exchange.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1d14befe4338406eabe7a692e77c50fe"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Participating providers</header><subparagraph id="id77e3271dc4a24b0481a20ced9e371038"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A health care provider that is a participating provider of services or supplier under the Medicare program under title XVIII on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Choose Medicare Act</short-title> shall be a participating provider for Medicare part E plans.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7196847e8fb6468d88705b728904f3bf"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional providers</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a process to allow health care providers not described in subparagraph (A) to become participating providers for Medicare part E plans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id8DA6026694D74EDAA3886F08689D38E6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitations on balance billing</header><text>The limitations on balance billing pursuant to the provisions of section 1866(a)(1)(A) shall apply to participating providers for Medicare part E plans in the same manner as such provisions apply to participating providers under the Medicare program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id7E59F281DCD44CB6BCC7803EB3E4BA78"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Encouraging use of alternative payment models</header><text>The Secretary shall, as applicable, utilize alternative payment models, including those described in section 1833(z)(3)(C), in making payments for items and services (including prescription drugs) furnished under Medicare part E plans. The payment rates under such alternative payment models shall comply with the requirement for negotiated rates under subsection (e)(2).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id2E0D6401835947F195D0B2A310FB4890"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Prescription drugs</header><text>The Secretary shall apply the provisions of part E of title XI to prescription drugs under Medicare part E plans in the same manner as such provisions apply with respect to selected drugs under part E of title XI.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idC903BACFC85E403F886ACBC1D04CEB9D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Appropriations</header><paragraph commented="no" id="id2E817C09918F492DAF2F567F80BCC08F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Start up funding</header><text>For purposes of establishing the Medicare part E plans, there is appropriated to the Secretary, out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise obligated, $2,000,000,000, for fiscal year 2026.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id56728E23C0F44B9E883524187003A86D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial reserves</header><text>There is appropriated to the Secretary, out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise obligated, such sums as may be necessary, based on projected enrollment in the Medicare part E plans in the first plan year in which such plans are offered, to provide reserves for the purpose of paying claims filed during the initial 90-day period of such plan year.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id8D325B4B398E4FF1B3159C86C2383572"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>Any provision of law restricting the use of Federal funds with respect to any reproductive health service shall not apply to funds appropriated under paragraph (1) or (2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idC3FD116BB10543F8B626845C16B8107D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Health insurance issuer</header><text>With respect to any Medicare part E plan, the Secretary shall be considered a health insurance issuer, within the meaning of section 2791(b) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-91">42 U.S.C. 300gg–91(b)</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id5b250070495241c8a436ac9f3941c0b3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application of excise tax for noncompliance with negotiation requirements</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5000D">Section 5000D(e)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Such term shall apply to any drug treated in the same manner as a drug described in the preceding sentence by reason of section 2201(g) of the Social Security Act.</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="id0E59375681C24CCFB7AA6F3B167E7216"><enum>3.</enum><header>Notice and navigator referral for employees under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938</header><subsection id="idEE52B9FF079346F8A979BBA161CC534A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 18B of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/218b">29 U.S.C. 218b</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idF2B080A8C5DD4EDC86E151CA6B43FEA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">to</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">and navigator referral for</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7E351A29C0084E55ADB335D5FFEC838E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (b) as subsection (c);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA37A1326536B4B47AA97F68AE18C5AAC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id57768A2D4E68490D8498E68D9CE8CE43"><subsection id="idE8A7AA60ED0E4E26A6EDFFFE945588C2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Navigator referral</header><paragraph id="id5AA482FAD1E24E059E10C01312DB5F44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An employer described in paragraph (3) shall refer each employee who is a full-time employee (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4980H">section 4980H(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) to—</text><subparagraph id="id4E9D2D22723A46EF84E965492B39FF68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an entity that serves as a navigator under section 1311(i) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18031">42 U.S.C. 18031(i)</external-xref>) for the Exchange operating in the State of the employer; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id07846BFD4F834B0282CA90DFFCCC3198"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the Exchange operating in the State of the employer does not have an entity serving as such a navigator, another entity that shall carry out equivalent activities as such a navigator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5CD1549B3DE54BA9B91DF56BB94EC61D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Referral</header><text>The referral described in paragraph (1) shall occur—</text><subparagraph id="id2C4E967EE2944BD3876E565275464F63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at the time the employer hires the employee; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id628F96818E1342DBBFDA5D9DABEBAFCD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on the effective date described in subsection (c)(2) with respect to an employee who is currently employed by the employer on such date.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id6DC36373A21746CE9B87611F8CBD04DD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Employer</header><text>An employer described in this paragraph is any employer that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id45AC3BA167BC4AB3A13994FC0C580DD3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>does not provide an eligible employer-sponsored plan as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5000A">section 5000A(f)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idE4422E9F838D400EACEE9FCA222FB771"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides such an eligible employer-sponsored plan, but the plan is determined—</text><clause commented="no" id="id0C9BB9DB188741E7B6B513B7BEDEACB2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to be unaffordable to the employee under clause (i) of section 36B(c)(2)(C) of such Code; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idF6A591B6840D452787C9D877954EA54B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to not provide the required minimum value under clause (ii) of such section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id2A0194596EB94AA4853C967A5FC7D245"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (c), as so redesignated—</text><subparagraph id="idC0D2E918D3054FCB8101ED235A6D6C06"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Effective date</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Effective dates</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC300C14029204249BAC66FC17B492482"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Subsection (a)</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBCB811E267374AECA6EA20395A61E294"><paragraph id="idA69796A5B6A745A69625628DB77EB56F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Subsection (a)</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id92131BD1D02C4D5381D7BF02BE0E7BF8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD1029A0C8EFB417391419E5580AD09DC"><paragraph id="idAAAE823AE61A4DFDBE68C9735CAF468A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Navigator referral</header><text>Subsection (b) shall take effect with respect to employers in a State beginning on the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Choose Medicare Act</short-title>.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idEDE215C237134076ACDA5D19C594DE6D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2030, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the impact of the requirements under section 18B of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/218b">29 U.S.C. 218b</external-xref>), including the amendments made by subsection (a), on the rate of individuals without minimum essential coverage as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5000A">section 5000A(f)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 in the United States and in each State.</text></subsection><subsection id="id8BA76BD4FF3440099BB70CD867E96040"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding for navigator program</header><text>Section 1311(i)(6) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18031">42 U.S.C. 18031(i)(6)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id03B7DEA471A445CC939D6AE62C719C28"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Grants</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFDD8F35AE77A45489846C3A1319EEF02"><subparagraph id="id2DC89578BE854082B4AEF354BA94C54B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Grants</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idAF4F1024C86D41D7BA9A44A87707FB9D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1670999C0A0C48038D1FD9ADA9F30DF7"><subparagraph id="idD945F040371B42319A2A14057868FD15"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to address capacity limitations of entities serving as navigators through a grant under this subsection.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id1230690CB04749348E3C1CE3F926D1A4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Protecting against high out-of-pocket expenditures for Medicare fee-for-service benefits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1D8C00D9FC7540969687BAEE02887181"><section id="id8F0D1CF66A53458FB581957746ED509A"><enum>1899C.</enum><header>Protection against high out-of-pocket expenditures</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id4FCDACF3530B46B6A6B89D79C25CEC92"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, in the case of an individual entitled to, or enrolled for, benefits under part A or enrolled in part B, if the amount of the out-of-pocket cost-sharing of such individual for a year (beginning with 2027) equals or exceeds the annual out-of-pocket limit under subsection (b) for that year, the individual shall not be responsible for additional out-of-pocket cost-sharing incurred during that year.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id640A234D435D48ABB87731A65012BB38"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual out-of-Pocket limit</header><paragraph commented="no" id="idACFCB044011649F7981C7C88783EC3ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount of the annual out-of-pocket limit under this subsection shall be—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="idDE53C29A28BD4EA9A671686DD86F42A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for 2027, $6,700; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id214CC2B09CD94A4888453F7561ABF180"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for a subsequent year, the amount specified in this subsection for the preceding year increased or decreased by the percentage change in the medical care component of the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers for the 12-month period ending with June of such preceding year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id1C89442DF0AA40D19E85AD2841D695F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any amount determined under paragraph (1)(B) is not a multiple of $5, such amount shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $5.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id40D68E8B0FE648CDA9704720336DCD86"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Out-of-Pocket cost-Sharing defined</header><paragraph id="id68530BBB30CB478F8C7C13BCDF8ECCB8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), in this section, the term <term>out-of-pocket cost-sharing</term> means, with respect to an individual, the amount of the expenses incurred by the individual that are attributable to—</text><subparagraph id="id8D6EBFADD9854D549905D23B86E7D80D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>deductibles, coinsurance, and copayments applicable under part A or B; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB91F464E6EBE4E07A72B1480E0EFFCF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for items and services that would have otherwise been covered under part A or B but for the exhaustion of those benefits.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1B68663E80854043B8D72D1D237C855C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certain costs not included</header><subparagraph id="idFDCDB5375AC44EE880AC7456FDDFD536"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Non-covered items and services</header><text>Expenses incurred for items and services which are not covered under part A or B shall not be considered incurred expenses for purposes of determining out-of-pocket cost-sharing under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0FB4D76467C248B4844CB1A49F2DD09A"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Items and services not furnished on an assignment-related basis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an item or service is furnished to an individual under this title and is not furnished on an assignment-related basis, any additional expenses the individual incurs above the amount the individual would have incurred if the item or service was furnished on an assignment-related basis shall not be considered incurred expenses for purposes of determining out-of-pocket cost-sharing under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id919E32CD3E53494D932DD70044E185DF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Source of payment</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consider expenses to be incurred by the individual without regard to whether the individual or another person, including a State program, an employer, a medicare supplemental policy, or other third-party coverage, has paid for such expenses.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7A0B17DC564E4C16AF070606DF1D152B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Announcement of the annual out-of-Pocket limit</header><text>The Secretary shall (beginning in 2026) announce (in a manner intended to provide notice to all interested parties) the annual out-of-pocket limit under this section that will be applicable for the succeeding year.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section commented="no" id="idACF203E3260944399F8910064AF5A6E8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Enhancement of premium assistance credit</header><subsection id="id3DF18B7C47BD4020AAE3E0DE951EF598"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Use of gold level plan for benchmark</header><paragraph id="idA27DD40A5BB446E59FC21556695EA045"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Clause (i) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B(b)(2)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>applicable second lowest cost silver plan</quote> and inserting <quote>applicable second lowest cost gold plan</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id03ED54A1135F4B048A37E03638F613EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment related to affordability</header><text>Section 36B(c)(4)(C)(i)(I) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>second lowest cost silver plan</quote> and inserting <quote>second lowest cost gold plan</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2881DAC25E0D4BE3B32F7B72602E0C5C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other conforming amendments</header><text>Subparagraphs (B) and (C) of section 36B(b)(3) of such Code are each amended by striking <quote>silver plan</quote> each place it appears in the text and the heading and inserting <quote>gold plan</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id0298CB22140648AFADCAE3B7A098F8E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Permanent extension of eligibility rules</header><paragraph commented="no" id="id81FBBA20415E4C218862DBC75A7DD570"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">Section 36B(c)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9b61b427f58e41809a5e7080eb07851e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>but does not exceed 400 percent</quote>, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaeb4f238daab472297c04a59eeaea440"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subparagraph (E).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id6E5A9160FC084710B5C4B964B65A8A58"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of applicable percentage</header><text>Subparagraph (A) of section 36B(b)(3) of such Code is amended by striking all that precedes the table in clause (iii)(II) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAACB709BBEE64C63B542AA387042D071"><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc5d0ce9b285d41838bb60e967168998f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (2), except as provided in clause (ii), the applicable percentage for any taxable year shall be the percentage such that the applicable percentage for any taxpayer whose household income is within an income tier specified in the following table shall increase, on a sliding scale in a linear manner, from the initial premium percentage to the final premium percentage specified in such table for such income tier:</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8D70571236244396BB00665B5AE8661D"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section><section id="idC9E5EABF6FF04C6896A6E77D0A49B793"><enum>6.</enum><header>Enhancements for reduced cost sharing</header><subsection id="id2EA7D485C1E74398BA963F2C9B8A392C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of eligible individual</header><text>Section 1402(b)(1) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18071">42 U.S.C. 18071(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>silver level</quote> and inserting <quote>gold level</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="id816D1004423D40149FDCA43AF6762B36"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Modification of amount</header><paragraph id="id5E373D22E7274209BAE0EE4F261B5766"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1402(c)(2) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF0A13CF2DF5D4153847C192BFD14C5E6"><paragraph id="id42e1ef0497ef43b18a7540e88ec9d161"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional reduction</header><text>The Secretary shall establish procedures under which the issuer of a qualified health plan to which this section applies shall further reduce cost-sharing under the plan in a manner sufficient to—</text><subparagraph id="id0bdddc9917254f4c9b489cda9969ed60"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible insured whose household income is not less than 100 percent but not more than 133 percent of the poverty line for a family of the size involved, increase the plan’s share of the total allowed costs of benefits provided under the plan to 94 percent of such costs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c54906ab2f2475a9cd4bb818a7619a7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible insured whose household income is more than 133 percent but not more than 150 percent of the poverty line for a family of the size involved, increase the plan’s share of the total allowed costs of benefits provided under the plan to 92 percent of such costs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id50D3AC59420C4B73AEBAAB4C078B89F9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an eligible insured whose household income is more than 150 percent but not more than 200 percent of the poverty line for a family of the size involved, increase the plan’s share of the total allowed costs of benefits provided under the plan to 90 percent of such costs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF0DCD2E9BC4644EDA7166A81FA0D0D08"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an eligible insured whose household income is more than 200 percent but not more than 300 percent of the poverty line for a family of the size involved, increase the plan’s share of the total allowed costs of benefits provided under the plan to 85 percent of such costs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1a049bf14e0441dabeeb65a8f60e34ee"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible insured whose household income is more than 300 percent but not more than 400 percent of the poverty line for a family of the size involved, increase the plan’s share of the total allowed costs of benefits provided under the plan to 80 percent of such costs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id4EA1A49A96F34F559C542C05D9DAFDBF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Clause (i) of section 1402(c)(1)(B) of such Act is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8BC881AB950E40BA8EFC352DB6B93414"><clause commented="no" id="idbc20dd7b15f24de3b7f505f4ea6ea1c0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure the reduction under this paragraph shall not result in an increase in the plan’s share of the total allowed costs of benefits provided under the plan above—</text><subclause commented="no" id="ideeb8874526ff4c788c70c9d96156f669"><enum>(I)</enum><text>94 percent in the case of an eligible insured described in paragraph (2)(A);</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7DA1215AAF38437386D24D22C2FEB11B"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">92 percent in the case of an eligible insured described in paragraph (2)(B);</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB363DA387CAC4A329A1DB3DA38E981E4"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">90 percent in the case of an eligible insured described in paragraph (2)(C);</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id0e172e5a20ca4ee4bf36f2ab28b86dae"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>85 percent in the case of an eligible insured described in paragraph (2)(D); and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="ide797d712aa23487ea1abb2c7bfeda1bc"><enum>(V)</enum><text>80 percent in the case of an eligible insured described in paragraph (2)(E).</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2C1879DECC234620B25FCE0528234B5C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to plan years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="id60800fbdaec84a648e479c504dcbcb66"><enum>7.</enum><header>Reinsurance and affordability fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part 5 of subtitle D of title I of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act is amended by inserting after section 1341 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18061">42 U.S.C. 18061</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idABD2CD39DB5940E8A6DDA38AA28183B3"><section id="id6973FC3B6A664BE684D74DC9DE0534B8"><enum>1341A.</enum><header>Reinsurance and affordability fund for the individual market in each State</header><subsection id="id77C84B70CF9B4C1C8FFC71801A007CAD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, shall establish a program to enable each State, for any plan year beginning in the 3-year period beginning January 1, 2026, to—</text><paragraph id="HDCCCB2E78171498AABA938A03C4C5C04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide reinsurance payments to health insurance issuers with respect to individuals enrolled under individual health insurance coverage offered by such issuers; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE564050F6CCD4128B537A9D1C6EC34D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide assistance (other than through payments described in paragraph (1)) to reduce out-of-pocket costs, such as copayments, coinsurance, premiums, and deductibles, of individuals enrolled under qualified health plans offered in the individual market through an Exchange.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idD8D658420D5E49BFA31799CA31EB2CCA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appropriations</header><text>There is appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $30,000,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2026 to 2028 for purposes of establishing and administering the program established under this section. Such amount shall remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section commented="no" id="idFEA573C144D5472EAEF0A0F7282C3EE1"><enum>8.</enum><header>Expanding rating rules to large group market</header><subsection id="id05AB7A02EC834B76B44FB1088802E7B2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 2701(a) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg">42 U.S.C. 300gg(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id8FB804BC1CE84F5F810D378E7B76CA92"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>small</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id33A41B1E6D6B4507BC42DDC4BD8FFB07"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (5).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id7E13C61E89C44DEC8EF73422911079C8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply to plans offered in the first plan year beginning after the date of enactment of this Act and any plan year thereafter.</text></subsection></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H0C0965A9D9D64A6C95E567F03184FD60"><enum>9.</enum><header>Protection of consumers from excessive, unjustified, or unfairly discriminatory rates</header><subsection id="H0211F77513124FBEA9FB5BE3B51E7CC5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Protection from excessive, unjustified, or unfairly discriminatory rates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2794 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-94">42 U.S.C. 300gg–94</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H11CB17D499BB4E89BBBFD252AF99BA22"><subsection id="H5BB865E8CD9D47C7864C9A2CCEA6D1A2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Protection from excessive, unjustified, or unfairly discriminatory rates</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H813F795880BD47C4A3F7E0C732175498"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority of States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit a State from imposing requirements (including requirements relating to rate review standards and procedures and information reporting) on health insurance issuers with respect to rates that are in addition to the requirements of this section and are more protective of consumers than such requirements.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H958D87FC98DA4B149607CF7AECE9492A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation in rate review process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall consult with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners and consumer groups.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9A733150BE1540CB9D143F8476837096"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Determination of who conducts reviews for each State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall determine, after the date of enactment of this subsection and periodically thereafter, the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9CF98964269F4365BFB651889A1483CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In which markets in each State the State insurance commissioner or relevant State regulator shall undertake the corrective actions under <internal-xref idref="H86D9C992871E4D4EBD7AA18631AFFEFD" legis-path="(e)(4)">paragraph (4)</internal-xref>, based on the Secretary’s determination that the State insurance commissioner or relevant State regulator is adequately undertaking and utilizing such actions in that market.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H867608D6823B4A9ABF43892D07C408AA"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In which markets in each State the Secretary shall undertake the corrective actions under <internal-xref idref="H86D9C992871E4D4EBD7AA18631AFFEFD" legis-path="(e)(4)">paragraph (4)</internal-xref>, in cooperation with the relevant State insurance commissioner or State regulator, based on the Secretary’s determination that the State is not adequately undertaking and utilizing such actions in that market.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86D9C992871E4D4EBD7AA18631AFFEFD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Corrective action for excessive, unjustified, or unfairly discriminatory rates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with the process established under this section, the Secretary or the relevant State insurance commissioner or State regulator shall take corrective actions to ensure that any excessive, unjustified, or unfairly discriminatory rates are corrected prior to implementation, or as soon as possible thereafter, through mechanisms such as—</text><subparagraph id="H1D24A642F79845CC8E3AE20351081B8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>denying rates;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C7946DF005146EE8C04443614B1AB73"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">modifying rates; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5C5929094C14FE88C4D19F378BA62A7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>requiring rebates to consumers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idEF0A2F6B4B30421E91D0AF38BAE3B3FF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Noncompliance</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4354284da0ca43f3ade313fe162a80a6"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Failure to comply with any corrective action taken by the Secretary under this subsection may result in the application of civil monetary penalties described in subparagraph (B) and, if the Secretary determines appropriate, make the plan involved ineligible for classification as a qualified health plan.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id44664a2b32e44aab99c3ddc0f775c0e0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Civil monetary penalties</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8626c89495364217b2db2662879823cd"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of section 1128A of the Social Security Act, other than subsection (a) and (b) and the first sentence of subsection (c)(1) of such section, shall apply to civil monetary penalties under this paragraph in the same manner as such provisions apply to a penalty or proceeding under section 1128A of the Social Security Act.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcffc605cbed444ee8f93151c64cb54b7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of subparagraph (C) of section 2723(b)(2) shall apply to civil monetary penalties under this paragraph in the same manner as such provisions apply to a penalty under such section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H2ECA32477BBC43118D93864C4788AE2D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification of Regulatory Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2794 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-94">42 U.S.C. 300gg–94</external-xref>) is further amended—</text><paragraph id="HEA925EBB05B4444CAB0A09BC927201A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H639367B525FE474EA63D05E4DF3FCAF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">premium</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">rate</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1B7620B3D844DC2A27EE3FDC1694D07"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>unreasonable increases in premiums</quote> and inserting <quote>potentially excessive, unjustified, or unfairly discriminatory rates, including premiums,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B1BB76AD31145A68D3B23F9C98BE15E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><clause id="H30C0B417BF7247D894F9D43B99D9D377"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>an unreasonable premium increase</quote> and inserting <quote>a potentially excessive, unjustified, or unfairly discriminatory rate</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="HD324CEBFBC1D4B0989B3494B4C839264"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the increase</quote> and inserting <quote>the rate</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H6697BD3B7BA14BC69B2DFCEA700BA3AF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>such increases</quote> and inserting <quote>such rates</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5618BDD269F14A41B8BDAAB53E9B30E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H830CECF206E14B128FC02F795BEA0331"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Premium</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Rate</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE2A84EF615D34078B9D3C16197054609"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>premium increases</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>rates</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7E901F74D434460B1AC8659CAF34AED"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd372b0ae3a0844da93945d7bb821b326"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Premium Increase</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Rate</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0e1aa92503e443b5b4d343c289e65fe3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>excessive or unjustified</quote> and inserting <quote>excessive, unjustified, or unfairly discriminatory</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1FCC75279A51428A8A0E80284D6449B6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><clause id="id39711FEC79A4404BBB24CB491920877A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Premium Increases</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Rates</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="id22979B66662F4DD382B5DAE05B1003A4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>premium</quote> and inserting <quote>rate</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1B1145D801F94CF38F5C60372574A528"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 1311(e)(2) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18031">42 U.S.C. 18031(e)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>excessive or unjustified premium increases</quote> and inserting <quote>excessive, unjustified, or unfairly discriminatory rates</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBEA3AA1497254448930E5B729E73BA8B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability to grandfathered health plans</header><text>Section 1251(a)(5) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18011">42 U.S.C. 18011(a)(5)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id00ca18cbc33e42f19f9f3850afb9a6fc"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>Sections 2799A–1</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28D33A75A90D490E83F280E24622B5DD"><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida1ee3cc600ae4d8a981710d96c2c3e87"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Sections 2799A–1</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id0060212d62c144c09b8924d1a607390f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id45F142BFCFAC4EF9990E65B7BA586A06"><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6c7c5c9983d84ed3bbfbbdd224024953"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ensuring that consumers get value for their dollars</header><text>Section 2794 of the Public Health Service Act shall apply to grandfathered health plans for plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2026.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided0ee83426e74accb069c649ec01781c"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act and shall be implemented with respect to health plans beginning not later than January 1, 2026.</text></subsection></section><section id="id4E3406BCA85C4C75B3BF65673466AA31"><enum>10.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that—</text><paragraph id="idf24385b7675845b3893963149e012f25"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Federal Government, acting in its capacity as an insurer, employer, or health care provider, should serve as a model for the Nation to ensure coverage of all reproductive services; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id279331ced81f4ddb8c0e4976415c812f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>all restrictions on coverage of reproductive services in the private insurance market should end.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

