<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8A44E0AE98204FE389D070F73C966FE8" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 165 IH: Expressing support for the designation of February 28, 2025, as Community Arts Education Day.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 165</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250225">February 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Vel&#225;zquez</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of February 28, 2025, as Community Arts Education Day.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas community arts education is a dynamic and inclusive approach to learning and engagement in the arts, fostering creativity, cultural expression, and social transformation within communities;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas community arts education encompasses a broad range of artistic disciplines and practices that empower individuals to develop their artistic skills, deepen their cultural understanding, and cultivate a sense of belonging and agency within themselves and their communities;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas community arts education is a participatory and transformative practice that engages individuals in the creation, exploration, and critical dialogue of the arts within a community context, and community arts education goes beyond individual skill-building or personal expression and it connects through a larger social context;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas community arts education leaders, which can include culture bearers, teaching artists, and administrators, play a vital role in providing essential arts instruction and learning to diverse communities, both within and outside of formal educational settings;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas community arts education is liberatory by uplifting our communities’ culture, heritage, and history in many forms such as dance, music, theatre, literary arts and other modes of self-expression;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas community arts education can build people’s imaginations, build critical learning and life skills, promote better health, and generate a sense of shared culture and community belonging;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas research has shown that community arts education positively impacts individuals of all ages and develops social emotional competencies like confidence in self-expression and ideas, social awareness, and self-regulating emotions; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas students who actively participate in the arts tend to enroll in competitive colleges, as well as four-year colleges in general, at higher rates compared to students with lower engagement in the arts: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HD72642C5C48D4EAF96635E02452AF12F"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H682E0A96BB724743B883B1A195F4BDA9"><text>That the House of Representatives supports Community Arts Education Day and recognizes Community Arts Education Day is more crucial than ever as a vehicle for activism, individual and collective self-expression, and healing.</text></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

