<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP25826-GCV-SW-P3X"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2544 IS: Guarding Unprotected Aging Retirees from Deception Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2544</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250730">July 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To permit State, local, and Tribal law enforcement agencies and grantees that receive eligible Federal grant funds to use such funds for investigating elder financial fraud, pig butchering, and general financial fraud, and to clarify that Federal law enforcement agencies may assist State, local, and Tribal law enforcement agencies in the use of tracing tools for blockchain and related technology, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Guarding Unprotected Aging Retirees from Deception Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GUARD Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id5afb8bd752a943d4bcab8a9d719ecd03"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HE2E8DDEB4E8C4CA49B428DAE3602A6CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Elder financial fraud</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>elder financial fraud</term> means the illegal or improper use of the money, property, or other resources of an elderly individual or adult with a disability for monetary or personal benefit, profit, or gain.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DD96CA874E24A02892FE185F29CA480"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible Federal grant funds</header><text>The term <term>eligible Federal grant funds</term> means funds received under any of the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H55AE9B7CAB974ADA810F28B8887A344F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title IV of the Prioritizing Resources and Organization for Intellectual Property Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/30103">34 U.S.C. 30103 et seq.</external-xref>) (commonly known as the <quote>Economic, High-Technology, White Collar, and Internet Crime Prevention National Training and Technical Assistance Program</quote>), including relating to the use of technology to solve crimes and to facilitate prosecutions (commonly known as the <quote>Internet of Things (IoT) National Training and Technical Assistance Program</quote>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E89FF9062B441008E07E6D1A85111ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Title 28, Code of Federal Regulations, part 23 (commonly known as <quote>Justice Information Sharing Training and Technical Assistance Program</quote>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A7D1F4AC5964ADFA1F48393024073FE"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1401 of the Violence Against Women Act Reauthorization Act of 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/30107">34 U.S.C. 30107</external-xref>) to a local law enforcement agency for enforcement of cybercrimes against individuals.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1B9158F0CFD40149489F6F8CB8D73F3"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1701 title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10381">34 U.S.C. 10381</external-xref>), relating to developing and acquiring effective equipment, technologies, and interoperable communications that assist in responding to and preventing crime (commonly known as the <quote>COPS Technology and Equipment Program</quote>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B8103FCE1164375B6CE52D30BA928E3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>General financial fraud</header><text>The term <term>general financial fraud</term> means, in order to obtain money or other things of value—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idafde94829ff4425cbde2423d92efc27f"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">intentional misrepresentation of information or identity to deceive an individual;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1feb180d231d40ae95e5f03e1d7eed27"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">unlawful use of a credit card, debit card, or automated teller machine; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9d9cefafc8a54e298985be748aadb917"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use of electronic means to transmit deceptive information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H830EA147DA694AF387C8BAAE7C23566B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Pig butchering</header><text>The term <term>pig butchering</term> means a confidence and investment fraud in which the victim is gradually lured into making increasing monetary contributions, generally in the form of cryptocurrency, to a seemingly sound investment before the scammer disappears with the contributed monies.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc415a1f4b844a958def55458ff5b13a"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Scam</header><text>The term <term>scam</term> means a financial crime undertaken through the use of social engineering that uses deceptive inducement to acquire—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb57ca55f83d3408f821a846385cfa168"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authorized access to funds; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc185840d76cd4cea97ca667b8791bafb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>personal or sensitive information that can facilitate the theft of financial assets.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H776C3597E3724DDA99ECDE0A7B5096F6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, and each territory of the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5F4F5611FBCE4411B775906C3C24DB96"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal grants used for investigating elder financial fraud, pig butchering, and general financial fraud</header><subsection id="H88D4E5044C0240D7B730ACE3F503D46F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State, local, and Tribal law enforcement agencies and grantees that receive eligible Federal grant funds may use such funds for investigating elder financial fraud, pig butchering, and general financial fraud, including by—</text><paragraph id="HC2BFD9129917447793BED51833CA020C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>hiring and retaining analysts, agents, experts, and other personnel;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H448971F92BBC47FD93D110653DCD4247"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing training specific to complex financial investigations, including training on—</text><subparagraph id="H51F7971722584BF59E582F46FE77BC4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coordination and collaboration between State, local, Tribal, and Federal law enforcement agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69FF15EA85CC4D56A4D6A096ED356D69"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assisting victims of financial fraud and exploitation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15FA9FC9995B40A59A2F8BCA6D9DE856"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of blockchain intelligence tools and related capabilities relating to emerging technologies identified in the February 2024 <quote>Critical and Emerging Technology List Update</quote> of the Fast Track Action Subcommittee on Critical and Emerging Technologies of the National Science and Technology Council (the <quote>Critical and Emerging Technology List</quote>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B584797A9D64C0EB8B949B519C188F8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>unique aspects of fraud investigations, including transnational financial investigations and emerging technologies identified in the Critical and Emerging Technology List;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A70E4ED11DC454ABA2A1504749B46A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>obtaining software and technical tools to conduct financial fraud and exploitation investigations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B70DDCCEFB545D79DB40B455645CB39"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encouraging improved data collection and reporting;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3178c61c30654b8a85583cb78baf8898"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supporting training and tabletop exercises to enhance coordination and communication between financial institutions and State, local, Tribal, and Federal law enforcement agencies for the purpose of stopping fraud and scams; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0018727566994a05a528c92be598cbaf"><enum>(6)</enum><text>designating a financial sector liaison to serve as a point of contact for financial institutions to share and exchange with State, local, Tribal, and Federal law enforcement agencies information relevant to the investigation of fraud and scams.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H593F0BD768544BB987C0BB4A1A75F83D"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Report to grant provider</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each law enforcement agency and grantee that makes use of eligible Federal grant funds for a purpose specified under subsection (a) shall, not later than 1 year after making such use of the funds, submit to the Federal agency that provided the eligible Federal grant funds, a report containing—</text>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="HEDBE0CD56DDF44A19A1D1BA924632180">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>an explanation of the amount of funds so used, and the specific purpose for which the funds were used;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="HE9A42D0A67BE40A99F8A08ADBA8652DE">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">statistics with respect to elder financial fraud, pig butchering, and general financial fraud in the jurisdiction of the law enforcement agency, along with an analysis of how the use of the funds for a purpose specified under subsection (a) affected such statistics; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H095AA055F9F140AE9D237F0D80584826" commented="no"
          display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the ability of the law enforcement agency to deter elder financial fraud, pig butchering, and general financial fraud.</text>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection></section><section id="ide05a72cb87e94553ae6c8a3a9fd25d60"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on general financial fraud, pig butchering, and elder financial fraud</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury and the Director of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network in consultation with the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the appropriate Federal banking agencies and Federal functional regulators shall, jointly, submit to Congress a report on efforts and recommendations related to general financial fraud, pig butchering, elder financial fraud, and scams.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idaa513851d54a47618d4a21e4b12ff715"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report on the state of scams in the United States</header><subsection id="idd4e324508632434eb8e13f93b3f246d1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury and the Director of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network, in consultation with the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the appropriate Federal banking agencies and Federal functional regulators, shall submit a report to Congress on the state of scams in the United States that—</text><paragraph id="id3dafd0d070314418890679372a82fc3f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>estimates—</text><subparagraph id="id7417312f55724a14b970272f85d99c66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of financial fraud, pig butchering, elder financial fraud, and scams committed against American consumers each year, including—</text><clause id="id18bf2f16007949cb8d3df5ba16c9967f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>attempted scams, including through social media, online dating services, email, impersonation of financial institutions and nonbank financial institutions; and</text></clause><clause id="idbda94a3f05ef4c2fbe0c136c63657672"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>successful scams, including through social media, online dating services, email, impersonation of financial institutions and nonbank financial institutions;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id579d55120aa1433bbb103323586b67a3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of consumers each year that lose money to 1 or more scams;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id109988610a7340b9a7f1fe467f7163a1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the dollar amount of consumer losses to scams each year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbe6d1bd4de934309a7d5e17d2ef6145b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the percentage of scams each year that can be attributed to—</text><clause id="ida5de225423184af48c2d4afc1b13047f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>overseas actors; and</text></clause><clause id="id3aee9823a95e466aa1863407316480f8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>organized crime;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8042b363d126491d80c78084cc075037"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the number of attempted scams each year that involve the impersonation of phone numbers associated with financial institutions and nonbank financial institutions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbe51608db73b4c37921a9630e035df89"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an estimate of the number of synthetic identities impersonating American consumers each year;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc9363b785f7f4148b0ba6bae30cae46c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides an overview of the Federal civil and criminal enforcement actions brought against the recipients of the proceeds of financial fraud, pig butchering, elder financial fraud, and scams during the period covered by the report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="id913a1fa2fcb24bcb8f765c47e5396521"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of such enforcement actions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6b967cf560394b29808e1fde96d9d40c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an evaluation of the effectiveness of such enforcement actions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0cbe19d9a3ff49a6b8f1fde7b7bedef4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an identification of the types of claims brought against the recipients of the proceeds of financial fraud, pig butchering, elder financial fraud, and scams;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id969608b8d60c4c5cb2db2e27872b1cf8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an identification of the types of penalties imposed through such enforcement actions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id387540af73c0423aa00608dbf59d95ac"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an identification of the types of relief obtained through such enforcement actions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id097d972f92c74b94a3b6054373a13ce8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the number of such enforcement actions that are connected to a Suspicious Activity Report; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id218bdf0c5f3e45529ecdc33b82f15a5f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifies amounts made available and amounts expended to address financial fraud, pig butchering, elder financial fraud, and scams during the period covered by the report by—</text><subparagraph id="id24b74882d0c7401984ead6b2be66036e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida43d19ccb0ba4fc6924f08d3fc60640b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of Justice;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ided1bdac3b8ee4f6895cf552f7635649d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6b9847339d90405589c224e8b52164e3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Federal Communications Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf9bc40da1e5e46199b213a9b15705031"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve Board;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaeebafcb0aae4d4b9f7f8175d3a00ba9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Federal Trade Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb8e4b91343ca4790b96cb4fc106fd4fc"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idada134b78f284a1b8f2c44f88fd2cd02"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Securities and Exchange Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id93d5376478494034be259fdaf9f4c22c"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Social Security Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6302c37f20d24e98ac371abd4f30dfb4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Solicitation of public comment</header><text>In carrying out the report required under subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury shall solicit comments from consumers, social media companies, email providers, telecommunications companies, financial institutions, and nonbank financial institutions.</text></subsection></section><section id="id57915fb67b12488db33145e2e306f86e"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Each Federal agency that provides eligible Federal grant funds that are used for a purpose specified under section 3(a) shall issue an annual report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name>, and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name> containing the information received from law enforcement agencies under section 3(b).</text></section><section id="id9eac4e1ee8144895b2f1b9a88d3f91ac"><enum>7.</enum><header>Federal law enforcement agencies assisting State, local, and Tribal law enforcement and fusion centers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Federal law enforcement agencies may assist State, local, and Tribal law enforcement agencies and fusion centers in the use of tracing tools for blockchain and related technology tools.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

