<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H03480FC6FDA34963A55D0900E16292AD" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 607 IH: Supporting the designation of the week of August 25 through August 29, 2025, as the third annual “National Community Health Worker Awareness Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 607</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of the week of August 25 through August 29, 2025, as the third annual <quote>National Community Health Worker Awareness Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas a community health worker is a frontline public health worker who is a trusted member, or has an unusually close understanding, of the community served;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas this trusting relationship enables the worker to serve as a liaison, link, or intermediary between health and social services and the community, facilitate access to services, improve the quality and cultural competence of service delivery, build individual and community capacity, and increase health knowledge and self-sufficiency through a range of activities such as outreach, community education, informal counseling, social support, and advocacy;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas community health workers are a unique workforce, recognized in 27 States with a professional certification;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas community health workers are a community-based workforce that builds relationships and capacity for health and well-being in underserved areas;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas community health workers are a historic and diverse workforce that goes back hundreds of years in the United States and reflects the diversity of the Nation;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas community health workers are known by more than 250 valued and respected titles, including community health representatives, promotores de salud, aunties, and outreach workers;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas community health workers are a cross-sector workforce that connects community members to health care and other social services, reducing barriers to health and well-being;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas community health workers are a proven workforce with decades of research documenting effectiveness in maternal and child health, chronic disease interventions, immunization, oral health, HIV, primary care, and many other disciplines, and have a documented return on investment for many programs;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas sustainable funding of community health workers supports fair market wages and enhanced recruitment and retention of the workforce;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas community health workers fulfill a wide range of roles, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="idc39cd9a7933a411683a6e10b9a52d2ac"><enum>(1)</enum><text>providing cultural mediation among individuals, communities, and health and social service systems;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id4f0ad6d7491b4cffa8f1b9207b93f2e2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>offering culturally appropriate health education and information;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id26ec57e747664fff9eac325c72f2e656"><enum>(3)</enum><text>offering care coordination, case management, and system navigation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id7e75b57edf884353961725608eef2893"><enum>(4)</enum><text>providing coaching and social support;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idf344001a731c465dbbe14c9fbcea96b8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>advocating for individuals and communities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id35a7b13fe98f4c3789e32c8b72e4c5a8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>building individual and community capacity;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idec87cc1e5a7641068e2b3a90fe511103"><enum>(7)</enum><text>providing direct services, including screening tests (such as weight and blood pressure screening), providing basic services (such as diabetic foot checks), and meeting basic needs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idff21a5ad064f4c95bdd7f90d1d6f1927"><enum>(8)</enum><text>implementing individual and community assessments;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idc413eeb75e714d0597fca4de4facc87e"><enum>(9)</enum><text>conducting outreach; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id7aa4845ff237401b89fc46f0c16d5034"><enum>(10)</enum><text>participating in evaluation and research; and</text></paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas community health worker networks are statewide, regional, or local community-based organizations, including community health worker associations and coalitions with leadership or membership that is comprised of 50 percent or more of community health workers, promotores, or community health representatives, and whose mission and activities focus on workforce development, mentoring, member mobilization, and advocacy: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H23BA360BCC834D6AA8E065421CB20F65"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H8E19A35A54AB47C6B425EB8409606121"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H59893FD5F3C64CACBFE340805E39E878"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of the third annual National Community Health Worker Awareness Week;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC83FF16416746F88E099847F2FF1C99"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the significant contributions of community health workers to health and social care systems and communities across the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H06B396B305CF4979B4EFFB0F7DD7F132"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages collaboration at the local, State, and Federal levels to raise awareness of the important role of community health workers; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H70DA5B70B0EF4ECFB2A988583C46A0D6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the work of community health workers to improve the health of communities across the United States. </text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

