<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0CC348877DA541868BD7F0A2B0A258C3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5750 IH: Ensuring a Qualified Civil Service Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5750</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251014">October 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 5, United States Code, to modify probationary periods with respect to positions in the competitive service, to establish trial periods for positions in the excepted service, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1AAF1E4C07CE40BE9F28A34D051E22AB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA83DAFDCA33843ECB6E84178578CE8E0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring a Qualified Civil Service Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>EQUALS Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H503C0B236E4B46C793177C65A65D15DC" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extension of probationary period for positions within the competitive service</header> <subsection id="HE3B479B724534428AB34ABA42AAF20EB" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3321 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCF74E9BF21EC418BB2A6E81917AD437F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a), by striking <quote>The President</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to subsections (c), (d), and (e), the President</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF4DF0B6EEAA4DCE9CFB4AA1C4708461"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (c) as subsection (f); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCCD712A151BD4F57B51B59270B557950" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H33BB4ECF0F82495DB2A9E4E97C74379A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HE1B44FD5B7CA412287DC61E5F7CC5EEC" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum> <paragraph id="H067139E93F9E4798A45B8CA21FD0C0C6" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum> <subparagraph id="HE7AAA1CE1F0D46F18DC556B7CFC1C160" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B) or otherwise specified in law, an individual’s initial appointment to a position in the competitive service shall become final only after the individual has served a 2-year probationary period.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAF72C6AF0B9749898A5FEFF778C36863" indent="up2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A preference eligible’s initial appointment to a position in the competitive service shall become final only after the individual has served a 1-year probationary period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8556310D527F49E191247FFF108B44AB" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During an employee’s probationary period under paragraph (1), the employing agency shall evaluate the fitness of the employee and whether the employee’s continued employment advances the public interest. An employee shall be terminated from the civil service on the last day of the employee’s probationary period unless the employing agency certifies, to the Director of the Office of Personnel Management within the 30 days before such date, that finalizing the employee’s appointment advances the public interest. Before an agency terminates an employee serving under a probationary period pursuant to this subsection, the agency shall provide notice (in writing) to the employee of the effective date of such termination.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H496400B7360D40A59FAF30B45842A4B5" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The appointment of an employee serving under a probationary period may not become final until the employee has demonstrated to the employee’s supervisor, through official performance and other metrics as determined by the agency head in conformance with guidance issued by the Office of Personnel Management, that the employee’s continued employment in the civil service is in the public interest.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H91E39C09D89245CA893499A7EDA7E17B" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>With respect to any certification under paragraph (2), the agency head may consider, in the head’s sole and exclusive discretion—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC500E8AB9639445A932590EC46B4AF02" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the employee’s performance and conduct;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8FC8B075BAD046DDAA074D4B9D5C047E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the needs and interests of the agency;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7C080BE460EA447C858CF2CA3D401BD0" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether the employee’s continued employment would advance organizational goals of the agency or the Federal Government; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H809CD9C608E54A5ABA3466DB7D59EBD6" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>whether the employee’s continued employment would advance the efficiency of the civil service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H09D1D3A3D934497087EA1F0A4C49677E" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the head of an agency fails to make a certification under paragraph (2) due to an administrative error, the head may petition the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, within 30 days after the date an employee was terminated from the civil service, to reinstate the employee. Any employee reinstated within such 30-day period shall be entitled to backpay in accordance with section 5596 of this title.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE92ED93282A54820B42AD2E42C1314CD" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>This subsection—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE1ECD174510C45178E25769BADB1C240" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall apply to an employee appointed under chapter 73 or 74 of title 38, notwithstanding section 7401 of such title; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H355BFE9567914F4A9361738932918863" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not apply to—</text> 
<clause id="HC8E77EB3015A450F93CAB9D693527F68" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an employee serving a probationary period due to being initially promoted, transferred, or otherwise assigned to a position as a supervisor (as that term is defined in section 7103 of this title) or any other managerial position, unless such employee is required to concurrently serve both a probationary period in such position and a probationary period following initial appointment or reinstatement;</text></clause> <clause id="H560A4EB3A2D046DDA5F4A138A44EFE27"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an employee of the United States Postal Service or the Postal Regulatory Commission; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF344DF8444C94F1BAFE103BEE242F2F4" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Congress or any congressional agency.</text></clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4BF9C80DF0EF4C908A84004E3EEE6878"><enum>(d)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAAF13CAD08F743E6863F74AB06EE1CCC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the length of a probationary period established under subsection (a) shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H663C72175DB04CFDA6C99218572E7319" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to any position that requires formal training, begin on the date of appointment to the position and end on the date that is 2 years after the date on which such formal training is completed;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0394D422C5174ACEAB24AF348F6F0ABF" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to any position that requires a license, begin on the date of appointment to the position and end on the date that is 2 years after the date on which such license is granted; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1E4492EB8EB349D694AD0B3D4C9F8A62" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to any position not covered by subparagraph (A) or (B), be a period of 2 years beginning on the date of the appointment to the position.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H70C5D4506946459AA0FF7A0373B2DBBB" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>With respect to any preference eligible, paragraph (1) shall be applied by substituting <quote>1 year</quote> for <quote>2 years</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3586BA15F40243828A73781980BCE250" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H05763E6D21C54C7383A4BB9E76874A48"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <quote>formal training</quote> means, with respect to any position, a training program required by law, rule, or regulation, or otherwise required by the employing agency, to be completed by the employee before the employee is able to successfully execute the duties of the applicable position; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5C7302F5B44946958D497CE155442105"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>license</quote> means a license, certification, or other grant of permission to engage in a particular activity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC424BF1183C44D85AE5318B6E3F816AB"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each agency shall, in the administration of this section, take appropriate measures to ensure that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDEBDB3F541E7410DBC339B976B137B01"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any announcement of a vacant position within the agency and any offer of appointment made to any individual with respect to any such position clearly states the terms and conditions of any applicable probationary period, including any formal training period and any license requirement;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0CD8BE44D8144EAD84E9D4BF8CCAAB4A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any individual who is required to complete a probationary period under this section receives timely notice of any requirements, including performance requirements, that must be met in order to satisfactorily complete such period;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H46B38750030C4EE4AF9124FB484F1B55"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any supervisor or manager of an individual who is required to complete a probationary period under this section receives periodic notifications of the end date of such period not later than 1 year, 6 months, 3 months, and 30 days before such end date; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H947B1DB90EAA4ED0942C5805B9E88DE9"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the head decides to retain an individual after the completion of a probationary period under this section, the head submits a certification to that effect, supported by a brief statement of the basis for the certification, in such form and manner as the President may by regulation prescribe.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1BBFB649032341F9803EDFD17953334A" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3321(f) of title 5, United States Code (as redesignated by subsection (a)(2) of this section), is amended by striking <quote>Subsections (a) and (b)</quote> and inserting <quote>Subsections (a) through (e)</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HADDFEEB749754A6D95D6D5C321CEDC23"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section and the amendments made by this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="H937412EB405D46EF8251E527FCAB8561"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall take effect 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FF93C04799E4FF5A8EF88874899A9C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall apply to any individual appointed to a position in the competitive service, or any individual who is initially promoted, transferred, or otherwise assigned to be a supervisor and who is required to serve a probationary period under section 3321(c)(6)(B)(i) of title 5, United States Code (as added by subsection (a) of this section), on or after the effective date in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
<section id="HCE0AA098D65B4E7EB197F79DF3ADF23D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Trial period in excepted service</header> 
<subsection id="HF170033F462645E29E6E4004280C6D84"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/3321">section 3321</external-xref> the following (and conforming the table of contents of such subchapter accordingly):</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H3D616A44FFF246869600F2FAE79F845B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H723CC152DABF42A2937EB783222EA60D"><enum>3321a.</enum><header>Excepted service; trial period</header> <subsection id="H017D903766E443EC9C5A8D4D67FA016B"><enum>(a)</enum> <paragraph id="HA6B659CFB4B34742916A7496AAB012E4" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), an employee appointed to a position in the excepted service shall serve a 2-year trial period.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD23D789A9AD64CCAAE6241DE4CB6E536" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A preference eligible appointed to a position in the excepted service shall serve a 1-year trial period.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6A558579DA724473A5F5EB858CB981BF"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employee serving under a trial period pursuant to subsection (a) and who is transferred, promoted, demoted, or reassigned to any other excepted service position before the end of such trial period shall complete the remainder of such trial period in the new position.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8F3CC18818B142FAA265564E16A9D6DF"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who separates from the civil service for a period of more than 30 days after completing a trial period under this section and who is reappointed to an excepted service position shall complete a new trial period unless such individual is appointed to the same or a substantially similar position in the same agency the employee held immediately before separation.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC3A196714ACB4D948D36C7C038ABF22D" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><text>This section shall not apply to any agency or employee described in section 3321(c)(6)(B).</text> </subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA5B1F9D5E00B428A97CDD67ACBADF154"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section and the amendments made by this section—</text> <paragraph id="H6E56D37EAA7949268E8842963247949A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall take effect 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8F1BAF880D14EA9AC9D4DEEEC19F240"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall apply to any individual appointed to a position in the excepted service on or after the effective date in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H7EB99AF9825D4F38AD00A5C54743728B"><enum>4.</enum><header>FAA and TSA</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 40122(g)(2) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA9F86000F86F4A1D92F31F2D6D8A5C65"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (I);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H35B029339731469C924392826AB11841"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (J) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H42B563BC662F4E2CBAFC0F843870C6DE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HA3CB8F563D5741FC93A97AB2420814F2" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H5A272782F5C74CD0A5D331D739A4C38C"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sections 3321 and 3321a relating to probationary and trial periods, respectively.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section commented="no" id="H6190B60FB5434E7BBBDA1A6EBB663E13"><enum>5.</enum><header>Adverse actions</header> 
<subsection id="HC61C3F7B23E347C6AA0C549AA064B92D" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Actions based on unacceptable performance</header><text>Section 4303(f) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HABF59133293A4F4C9C0E4C7944DB752D" commented="no"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>1 year of current continuous employment</quote> and inserting <quote>, with respect to a preference eligible 1 year of current continuous employment, and with respect to any other employee 2 years of current continuous employment,</quote>; and</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA7A78B9AAD3640B8BB7778E693B4831A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>1 year of current continuous employment</quote> and inserting <quote>, with respect to a preference eligible 1 year of current continuous employment, and with respect to any other employee 2 years of current continuous employment,</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H17CAF5F7123D47FFBAD1176F241F6948"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/75">chapter 75</external-xref> of title 5</header><text>Section 7501(1) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H23D02A471D7C4D70B469D59850D32E77"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or who has</quote> and inserting <quote>and who has</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCDAC3D2D59FE490D88C1203768B86DD9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>1 year of current continuous employment</quote> and inserting <quote>, with respect to a preference eligible 1 year of current continuous employment, and with respect to any other employee 2 years of current continuous employment,</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="HDD6C834EE7A64B2DA5F127CAB08F0BA6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/75">chapter 75</external-xref> of title 5</header><text>Section 7511(a)(1) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H0C66EC8295874E339DC46A5E68A9AC66"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEF719D9B5E2A4F3DAEB39E255655A1A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H21BBCA39D4074E24969A64DA5BC57B53"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>1 year of current continuous service</quote> and inserting <quote>, with respect to a preference eligible 1 year of current continuous service, and with respect to any other employee 2 years of current continuous service,</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H33D458F6B33B4EFC8781A5ECBAC5BCC6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)(i), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting <quote>; and</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H4D0CC1D0653645279A6BC78250285D64"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date; application</header><text>The amendments made by subsections (a), (b), and (c)—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H479F593FAB7A4B95B0E0FC648739C941"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall take effect 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HA238E99C665343D6A96B4FB92C0FFEC8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall apply in the case of any individual appointed to a position in the competitive service or excepted service on or after the effective date in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
<section id="H457EF9FF8A334C9AB21DE3C09DDF8B3A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Regulations required</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall issue such regulations as are necessary to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

