<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HB2C12062D0904289B8AE8AD1F0527708" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 189 EH: Securities and Exchange Commission Real Estate Leasing Authority Revocation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 189</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend title 40, United States Code, to eliminate the leasing authority of the Securities and Exchange Commission, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H922C99E341A94BAAA0E900B06C5E11B0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H82AF847D9A7B4C939E8C57F33C45125F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securities and Exchange Commission Real Estate Leasing Authority Revocation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6D7C323D89F544C29F1B6EEDF8F070F3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Leasing of space for Securities and Exchange Commission</header> <subsection id="HBF2D177ADC0745648BC69945576B8CD3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3304 of title 40, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H617C36D1AEE04128B4660367764B29F3" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HB53BB2946BD046D1BB1C1E79C9F20A07"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Leasing of space for Securities and Exchange Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, on and after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Securities and Exchange Commission may not lease general purpose office space. The Administrator may lease such space for the Securities and Exchange Commission under section 585 and this chapter.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H511DDC3F6E1C406A97A5A82FDC798829"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on statutory construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) may not be construed to invalidate or otherwise affect a lease entered into by the Securities and Exchange Commission before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H67E89366CC334454BAA305B7F50B2CAA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Independent leasing authorities</header> 
<subsection id="H344F10713C5440F6B7C70508A54F946B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the review described in subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDD11B068877446CC9FCE162BD1B37BBC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The Comptroller General shall complete a review under which the Comptroller General shall update the 2016 report of the Comptroller General (GAO–16–648) with a specific focus on the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HFC608E3FC68142DF891C82E5C75F7ABD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Updating the information included in Appendix II: Federal Entities That Reported Having Independent Leasing Authority for Domestic Offices and Warehouses of such report.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H843D136C90E94D2687ABBDAC49DBB214"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Determining to what extent Federal entities with independent leasing authorities have had such authorities rescinded or amended and the number and amount of office and warehouse space such entities lease.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8D3DD723870A42EBA598419AB7D3EDEB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Determining to what extent have agencies with independent leasing authority utilized the General Services Administration for leasing, including utilization of delegation of authority.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBE48BFBF866D4B01836C91E32AEFCF84"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Identifying progress made on implementing the recommendations in such report.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250113" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives January 13, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


