<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD6E545AD7A5349A2ABB06880FD9A7AD5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3347 IH: Sovereign States Emergency Management Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3347</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250513">May 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To abolish FEMA and establish a block grant program for disaster relief, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H159B469C34BD492ABA1B04363F2FEDE9" style="OLC">
<section id="H92DE6FFFD7B642F08D7FD0ACCE1197FF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sovereign States Emergency Management Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2355BA0C0F0E4910946848AB839E3244" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Abolishment of FEMA</header> <subsection id="H242A111965DB48278E0374470E500A0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Abolishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Emergency Management Agency is abolished effective on the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H96DE228B470F4F108BE759EAC31EBC21"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Unobligated funds</header><text>Any funds made available to the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency that are unobligated on the abolishment date described in subsection (a) shall be transferred to the general fund of the Treasury and made available to carry out the program established under section 2.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4DD3FD74E2C34E59976199D0B90C1BFE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transfer of functions</header><text>All functions that immediately before the abolishment date specified in subsection (a) are authorized to be performed by the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, any other officer or employee of the Agency acting in that capacity, or any agency or office of the Agency, are transferred to the President effective on such abolishment date.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H6E6DE4D3B9D446F3AE7DE31E2267D975" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Personnel and assets</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in this Act, so much of the personnel, property, and records employed, used, held, available, or to be made available in connection with a function transferred to the President under subsection (c) shall be available to the President, at such time or times as the President directs for use in connection with the functions transferred.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H222AE695AF404E67830EC141B00A8D14"><enum>(e)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in any other Federal law, Executive order, rule, regulation, or delegation of authority, or any document of or pertaining to the Federal Emergency Management Agency—</text> 
<paragraph id="H95670DBD4FC04C50A4F5B711499C1531"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency is deemed to refer to the President; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H91F617A59F5B4BC88CEB75FF976DA519"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the Federal Emergency Management Agency is deemed to refer to the Executive Office of the President.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H95C8E87C798E49B7939AED9E4C4ACEB1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Disaster relief block grant program</header> 
<subsection id="H53FFC2B1011048B9A134F18CD07BA1A8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall establish a program to provide grants to States for natural disaster and emergency relief.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2E024689C8C542E3966668BF9558F28C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant terms</header> <paragraph id="H15C818B7F6314902835AB9127B598159"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program established under this section, the Secretary shall provide a grant to each State in an amount determined in accordance with the formula established pursuant to paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2B18E38D6BF42DBBE76C48A7DEF5EE9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allocation of funds</header> 
<subparagraph id="H1AB6B079580249A6B19F7B44ABE35D2E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall, by rule, establish a formula for the allocation of grant funds to each State under this section.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBED87065FE72436FB669DBFC22171CEA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In establishing the formula under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall consider the following:</text> 
<clause id="H381B2631EE004A008F8D0EF793B692F9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Population size.</text></clause> <clause id="HFACCAFBE964D45D5ABC25CF9488DA4C1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Historical disaster frequency and severity during the 20-year period preceding the date of enactment of this Act.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H12EB638447F844A1ABA3DFC590B80DD3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Geographic risk factors (such as seismic zones, flood plains, hurricane-prone areas).</text></clause> <clause id="HF778C8C1CB1D48BB974BE245F5DA49B9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Economic need, as determined by per capita income.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H99FB8FC5F5F645638621DA20F1D240F4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A State may use a grant provided under this section to carry out—</text> <subparagraph id="HEBD48CCC07F740AF991A121697700BC3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disaster preparedness training and acquire and maintain related equipment;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1A23479AB2294B5F9C0F246ABA14EBD1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>response and recovery operations following a natural disaster or emergency; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H66EC27A94B63453BB396BFC4780E3015"><enum>(C)</enum><text>mitigation projects to reduce future disaster risks.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB4B0F0E2BF94757B3BEC9705D5D18ED"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>A State may use not more than 5 percent of the amount allocated to such State under this subsection for administrative costs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3F47FCF4068346309071A9BFC525C612"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Allocation</header><text>The Secretary may not allocate grant funds to a State for a fiscal year under this section unless and until the Secretary, pursuant to subsection (c), approves the emergency management plan submitted by such State for such fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H044B5F48004E4F9EABC69E567E78779D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State emergency management plans</header><text>Not later than April 1 of each year, each State shall develop and submit for approval by the Secretary an emergency management plan for the fiscal year beginning on October 1 of such year, and such plan shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HD227D3E0A5C14C30AC17FA90ED853F2C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how the State intends to use funds allocated under this section;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2DB72A68D7B4C868CB31AFCACAAB1B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>documentation of coordination between the State, local governments, and Tribal authorities in developing and implementing such emergency management plan; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB706536D29E34A09821B6712AC22A0FE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>measurable goals for disaster preparedness and response.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7D63BE4CC0FB40D2A52F5A20BB8C9B54"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the end of each fiscal year, each State shall submit to the Secretary a report describing—</text> <paragraph id="H732A8AEC2CC747579AAE546BA1FCB46D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>how funds allocated under this section were used during the preceding fiscal year;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4AF86C4C913C4BD28ABB5F2D403714C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">outcomes achieved with such funds, including improvements in preparedness metrics, response times, and completed mitigation projects; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H703E1331C3D04583854EC6DD805248C1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which the State complied with the emergency management plan developed under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEFBAEB09C04A44BA82563E7BF96A8F28" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duplication of benefits</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that no State receives a grant under this section if such State receives assistance from any other Federal source for the same purposes for which such a grant may be used.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDE19C2D3938D4421A76F4737FEF2A5AA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Audit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less frequently than annually, the Secretary shall conduct an audit of the program established under this section and submit a report thereon to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, Homeland Security, and Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF6B248035E484ACC9C44EB80E03F4B26"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Administrative and audit expenses</header><text>Of the amounts made available to carry out this section, 10 percent shall be for expenses related to administering the program established under this section and 10 percent shall be for expenses related to carrying out the audit of such program required under subsection (f).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAF2315054C5545E3AF78D8093083420C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The program established under this section shall terminate on the date that is 4 years after the date on which the Secretary issues the rule required by subsection (b)(2).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H77A7782AA84D4284BE5E1604AAC770D8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HF12F3F805CB948CB9D7915E6662FF63D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Emergency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>emergency</quote> means an occasion or instance for which assistance is needed to save lives and to protect property and public health and safety, or to lessen or avert the threat of a catastrophe in any part of a State.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A1B4F82F7AA406ABF80C8EB5953760B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Natural disaster</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>natural disaster</quote> means any natural catastrophe (including any hurricane, tornado, storm, high water, winddriven water, tidal wave, tsunami, earthquake, volcanic eruption, landslide, mudslide, snowstorm, or drought), or, regardless of cause, any fire, flood, or explosion, in any part of a State, for which assistance is needed to alleviate the damage, loss, hardship, or suffering caused thereby.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H97FD7A8D0D964ACBB5C1A4BD6ED44C5B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>State</quote> any of the fifty States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

