<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR25023-MY8-K6-MH2"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S120 IS: Disaster Housing Reform for American Families Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 120</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250116">January 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to establish a pilot program for the construction of temporary disaster assistance housing, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Disaster Housing Reform for American Families Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idE6D270A6DAEF4D6088065737C6CCD548"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disaster assistance housing pilot program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 408(c) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC99A7203DBBF4B138166B076F9F8A5E4"><paragraph id="id819E531D282D405DA466BB744E44F9C6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><subparagraph id="id27d947b8046c407c85df91e290a06bc5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text><clause id="id35D9E41B6F9644448B52F3B86A673528"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Distributor; manufactured home; manufacturer; retailer</header><text>The terms <term>distributor</term>, <term>manufactured home</term>, <term>manufacturer</term>, and <term>retailer</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 603 of the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5402">42 U.S.C. 5402</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="id19C98AAC24BD4301B3B21F7AA32319F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6dcfd98d2cf642aebd3bac7148f23fae"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a manufacturer, distributor, or retailer of a manufactured home or a modular home; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id81bded2f87f448e9afa398f787a009a7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a producer of modular housing.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idB93993192165416FB1A67E333F4E1AFD"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, in coordination with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8DCB15C7C00D46C8AB3E672CAD4F10D5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The President shall establish a pilot program under which the President enters into a contract with an eligible entity for the purpose of constructing temporary housing to serve as a type of housing available to individuals and households under subsection (b)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id52E68A4ACBF34C1FB350FBAA117711EA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Housing constructed pursuant to subparagraph (B) shall—</text><clause id="idDCECE49458714043A86D949801C8C2B6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be in the form of a manufactured or modular housing structure with not more than 4 units;</text></clause><clause id="id35D894F98DF44418AC3BC0C83BFECF1C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be available to individuals and households not later than 90 days (or 120 days, upon extension by the Secretary) after the date on which the President declares a major disaster;</text></clause><clause id="idB7180058D5174BA5B51E6CAC10873E88"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>subject to subparagraph (D)(ii), conform with, as applicable—</text><subclause id="idDC31CD2BC7114BC59BD4B8D7EC52AAEC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>construction standards of the National Flood Insurance Program;</text></subclause><subclause id="id2A7C7BB761CF4A92A0089DAE68D0BFBD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>standards for new construction under the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5401">42 U.S.C. 5401 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subclause><subclause id="id62D305DF476D452C9AA2FCDB980E16F5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>standards under the most recent or second most recent edition of the International Residential Code;</text></subclause><subclause id="id8C10DE408167406DBDA81F1743C5FD00"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>applicable building codes in the State, local, or Tribal jurisdiction in which the housing is located;</text></subclause><subclause id="id13CE85CB3C514AE6A0D5A9BBD8A1F879"><enum>(V)</enum><text>requirements of the Federal Flood Risk Management Standard of the Federal Emergency Management Agency; </text></subclause><subclause id="id47A09D8A458E407DBAC426FDA8C147C2"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>local zoning ordinances;</text></subclause><subclause id="id0b8a4705e40d429db19a9e0a497f3f79"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>the national technical standard for flood resistant design and construction (ASCE/SEI 24–14); or</text></subclause><subclause id="id03e8991f2d6d437a92b64266317923b6"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>the manufactured home and construction safety standards under part 3280 of title 24, Code of Regulations, or any successor regulation;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id758780161DE84268A51C64C91029A411"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>reflect the needs of the community in which the housing is constructed according to the type of major disaster experienced by the community; and</text></clause><clause id="id59717B27C5EC41F3A958A95B6E212214"><enum>(v)</enum><text>provide a minimum level of protection against natural hazards for the purpose of protecting the health, safety, and general welfare of the users of the housing against disasters.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id60101F0C777046629AF5C03B25847C9C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Permanence; waiver</header><text>Housing constructed pursuant to subparagraph (B) may—</text><clause id="id89825DBCBB934868B7899A99522824C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have the capacity to become permanent housing after the date on which a major disaster declaration terminates; and</text></clause><clause id="id6CBAB92BB5964DEFB466E96538EBC451"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>receive a waiver for a requirement described in subparagraph (C)(iii) from the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEA96A531094444C1A6859F6CA88C1AB0"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Transfer guidelines</header><text>The President, in coordination with the Secretary, shall establish guidelines for the transfer of housing constructed under subparagraph (B) to an established affordable housing program administered by a locality, public housing authority, nonprofit organization, or affordable housing developer after the date on which the disaster declaration for the major disaster for which the housing is constructed terminates.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF392DB3DC86A4BF3A0862163061DCCD3"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The program established pursuant to subparagraph (B) shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Disaster Housing Reform for American Families Act</short-title>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0D837F419E404775892DEED6F1E14025"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Closing costs</header><text>The President may provide financial assistance to individuals or households affected by a major disaster and purchasing a residential property for closing costs associated with obtaining a mortgage from a Federal program that provides affordable financing options.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

