<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-LAN25062-3F0-49-KLJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 396 IS: Condemning the tragic act of violence on September 10, 2025, in Evergreen, Colorado, recognizing the victims, survivors, and responders, and expressing condolences and support to their families and their communities.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 396</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250916">September 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning the tragic act of violence on September 10, 2025, in Evergreen, Colorado, recognizing the victims, survivors, and responders, and expressing condolences and support to their families and their communities.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on September 10, 2025, a student violently opened fire at Evergreen High School in Evergreen, Colorado;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this tragic shooting traumatized the staff and students of Evergreen High School and resulted in the hospitalization of 2 victims;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas responders from the Jefferson County Sheriff's Office and Jeffco Public Schools R–1 security officers arrived within 2 minutes of the school's lockdown;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the swift actions of educators, staff, and neighbors helped protect students and staff and prevent further harm, demonstrating courage and dedication in the face of crisis;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the medical care of the trauma staff at CommonSpirit St. Anthony Hospital and Children's Hospital Colorado gave the victims a chance to survive their wounds;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas countless students, educators, and faculty experienced significant trauma as a result of this shooting;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the entire Evergreen, Colorado, community has been forever changed by this tragic event; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas all children should be able to attend school without fearing for their lives: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id1fe2e72c64ad48d9937a8219195503d6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns the horrific act of violence that occurred at Evergreen High School in Evergreen, Colorado, on September 10, 2025;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id56164886b87a44f894cec59de4c7a0b5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the victims and survivors of this horrifying incident;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id049932544a2447a5b6a07e139db8472d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>extends its deepest condolences and support to the friends and families of the victims and survivors, and to the communities of Evergreen High School and Jefferson County, Colorado;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id86d0d35ad1ee4060a25957dcf537718a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recognizes the strength of the Evergreen community in responding to this tragedy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id01440cfee08b43b69029cfaab8ea8d95"><enum>(5)</enum><text>honors the law enforcement, school safety officers, health care providers, educators, faculty, and neighbors whose quick actions safeguarded lives during and after the attack.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

