<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCE21B1E2B50F4FCE8CAAA8FD1EC6CBC3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5706 IH: Mental Health Emergency Responder Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5706</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251008">October 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a grant program to assist eligible entities in developing or expanding behavioral health crisis response programs that do not rely primarily on law enforcement, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H78F7CE4E461F408AA19F9E7CC6F3D6F5" style="OLC"><section id="H80A3914584B74BB7A625CBF118227E52" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mental Health Emergency Responder Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H88F87FECCC8D4257A4F4CE61AA501407"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program to expand behavioral health crisis response</header><subsection id="H678BF02B22564004AF299E05354350B4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, shall establish a competitive grant program (in this section referred to as the <quote>program</quote>) to assist eligible entities in developing or expanding behavioral health crisis response programs that do not rely primarily on law enforcement.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC63D6D104CA74EB5940E7F36510FFDC4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>The following entities shall be eligible to receive grants under the program—</text><paragraph id="H2EC017CE01CB4DC7A7B82C13098C98FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a local or Tribal government;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44566B91DC0C48209B9D7D737DE8AC64"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a regional emergency medical services agency or fire department;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2139C25EFB844BF6B053D2267382C5AC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a certified community behavioral health clinic, as defined by section 1905(jj) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(jj)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF30A5D3291574B148C1D71D214B10F5F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization in partnership with a local government or health authority.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H03952F3B6C1C4239B8F0271EB9351168"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of grant funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grant funds received by an eligible entity under the program may be used—</text><paragraph id="H5542D78CB95448BB8AE3B980867A6975"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to recruit, train, and equip behavioral health professionals and paramedics for a behavioral health crisis response;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD80D6EE01D8340808559CB1B30AE8115"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to integrate co-response teams into 911 or 988 call dispatch systems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC84DEFE9989479C94C4F45B5072629F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to provide community education and outreach regarding alternatives to police-led crisis response;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC79CC05DE53B4C6CA99CE971FBD10F75"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop or implement protocols to enable emergency medical services agencies to accept custody of civilians from police for transport to mental health facilities, if permitted under State law; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA911C3B4550B4B038C2E0D1326BFDF09"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to establish emergency medical services agencies, or clinician-led mobile crisis teams, as the primary responders to behavioral health emergencies in lieu of law enforcement, in a manner consistent with State and local laws.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H508830947A344DB69F96A3CA0B8EB9C8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on statutory construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed—</text><paragraph id="HFD4A71ADFD9343AD974CA4660CAC096E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to require any State or local government to modify an emergency detention or custody law; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63F0115DB8434100871A673F2F8C35CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to authorize any entity to engage in emergency detention or involuntary transport beyond what is permitted under an applicable State law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2A9EC27FBB0B4F5FB17573E728D72D6F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require each recipient of a grant under the program to submit to the Secretary, during such period of time as the Secretary determines appropriate, an annual report detailing response outcomes, diversion rates, and community feedback.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB05B8A278D23483E934416CBD62D3C62"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Priority consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under the program, the Secretary shall prioritize applications from eligible entities located in jurisdictions that do not currently operate a non-law enforcement behavioral health crisis response program, or whose existing programs are limited in scope or capacity.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB51D6F3C1A014BEA98112CAC52FCF041"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Co-Response team defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>co-response team</quote> means a team that includes at least one behavioral health professional (such as a licensed clinician or social worker) and at least one emergency medical services provider, firefighter, or peace officer who jointly respond to behavioral health crisis calls in real time.</text></subsection><subsection id="H77C49D8C4CF1420490546809CB7AFA53"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

