<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-LAN25069-J9J-KS-MG0"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 402 IS: Recognizing Lloyd Ashburn Williams’s unparalleled dedication to fostering economic empowerment, cultural pride, and social equity in Harlem.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 402</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250918" legis-day="20250916">September 18 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing Lloyd Ashburn Williams’s unparalleled dedication to fostering economic empowerment, cultural pride, and social equity in Harlem.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Lloyd Ashburn Williams was born on January 16, 1945, in Jamaica and immigrated to New York City at the age of 2, where he was raised in Harlem and committed his life to the advancement and empowerment of the Harlem community;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Mr. Williams attended Syracuse University and developed a lifelong passion for civic engagement, economic development, and cultural preservation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1988, Mr. Williams was appointed President and Chief Executive Officer of The Greater Harlem Chamber of Commerce, becoming one of the longest-serving leaders of the organization, guiding the Chamber through periods of economic challenges and revitalization over more than 4 decades;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, under his visionary leadership, The Greater Harlem Chamber of Commerce expanded its mission to promote minority-owned businesses, attract investments, foster entrepreneurship, and support workforce development initiatives that improved economic opportunities for Harlem residents;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1974, Mr. Williams, along with Manhattan Borough President Percy E. Sutton, Voza Rivers, and others, co-founded HARLEM WEEK, which was initially designed as a 1-day event to restore community pride and combat negative stereotypes and grew into a multi-week cultural festival celebrating Harlem’s history, art, music, business, and contributions to society and attracting millions of attendees annually;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas he championed key social issues, including affordable housing, education reform, health equity, climate change awareness, and bridging the digital divide, working tirelessly to ensure that Harlem’s growth was inclusive and reflective of the needs of its diverse population;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Mr. Williams served as Vice Chairman of the Harlem Arts Alliance, an Executive Committee Member of NYC &amp; Company, Chairman of the President’s Executive Advisory Board at The City College of New York, Founding Board Member of the Apollo Theater, and Executive Board Member of the National Jazz Museum in Harlem, strengthening Harlem’s cultural institutions and heritage;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas he was also a dedicated mentor, advisor, and educator, serving as a guest lecturer at prestigious institutions such as Columbia University, Rutgers University, and Fordham University, sharing his expertise in urban economics, tourism, business development, and public policy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Mr. Williams received numerous awards and honors recognizing his significant contributions, including an Honorary Doctor of Laws Degree from the University of the West Indies, designation as one of the <quote>Top 100 Most Influential New Yorkers</quote> by the city and State of New York, acknowledgment as one of the <quote>Top 25 Most Influential Black New Yorkers</quote> by the New York Amsterdam News, and recognition as one of the <quote>Most Influential Black Professionals</quote> by the New York Christian Times;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas he was a lifelong member of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People and the National Action Network, demonstrating his enduring commitment to civil rights, social justice, and community advocacy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Lloyd Ashburn Williams passed away on August 6, 2025, and is survived by his wife, Valorie Roberson-Williams, his son and grandson, and two brothers and a sister; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas he leaves behind a profound legacy that transformed Harlem’s economic landscape, cultural identity, and community spirit: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H9A3628EE5B9C4A4C8E9FD146F1E6D0C0"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H40292CCB0EF14D5282FB14D997DFE846"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the Senate recognizes Lloyd Ashburn Williams’s unparalleled dedication to fostering economic empowerment, cultural pride, and social equity in Harlem.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

