<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2B437D14E31C4A759AAE9824105ED48F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 607 IH: ATF Accountability Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 607</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250122">January 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide procedures for appealing certain Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives rulings or determinations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8B35D42831E748A2A15DB8CDEB9C8067" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HFC5B2049081E479EB4F8F8A5C9F37D33"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>ATF Accountability Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF96F8CE4D61140D28591AC6F63A38755"><enum>2.</enum><header>Procedures for appealing certain Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives rulings or determinations</header> <subsection id="H7AB2C0531C234EBD8EFEB484E87D2722"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 923 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D87DE3620CB4D7491663F906EA19803">
<subsection id="H413C0646F1954A26A95926A4336FB18D"><enum>(m)</enum>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA51105FC7719497AA3BC7CE0FE3C2DB5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a licensed manufacturer, licensed importer, or licensed dealer transmits to the Attorney General a product classification request or a written question regarding any regulatory matter, including but not limited to the legal status or classification of a product, regulated business practice, or a recordkeeping practice, under any law administered, in whole or in part, by the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, the Attorney General shall, not later than 90 days after receipt of the request or question, make a ruling or determination in writing on the question, and transmit the ruling or determination to the licensee.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE39D726E79E4A9D8C0DD92DEB86B7ED" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAE5BCB6ED96B4CC095A82F11AF1D2716"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Within 30 calendar days after receipt of a copy of the ruling or determination, the licensee may appeal the ruling or determination (or a cease and desist letter) by filing with any Director of Industry Operations having jurisdiction over a premises of the licensee subject to a license issued to the licensee under this chapter a request for review of the ruling or determination, which shall include a statement of the reasons for the appeal, and the relief requested.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H04F7DE6A782E487BB55F9663D8B51CF0" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Within 30 calendar days after receipt of the request for the appeal, the Director of Industry Operations shall render a decision on the appeal in writing and transmit a copy of the decision to the licensee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H767F0581A29543579FA4EE6A01AA26CE" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCD7A383B4803425EAFEDB1DF5317A2E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding whether the licensee appeals the ruling or determination to the Director of Industry Operations, the licensee may, within 75 calendar days after receipt of a copy of the initial ruling or determination or, within 14 days after receipt of the determination by the Director of Industry Operations, which ever is later, request for the appeal to be determined on the record after opportunity for a hearing before an administrative law judge. Upon such request the administrative law judge shall—</text>
<clause id="H9149AB761AA84132BEFDF0A74E8EE8E5" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">set a time and place for a hearing on the appeal at a location convenient to the licensee within 90 days from the date of the request; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA8776E63D21345CD86D2687376FBA767" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at least 10 days before the date set for the hearing, serve on the licensee and the Director of Industry Operations a notice of the hearing.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H90EB30A37B684DABB2A552C5D2E3F28A" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The hearing shall be conducted in accordance with the hearing procedures prescribed in subsections (b) through (e) of section 556 and section 557(d) of title 5.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H570195E7B06B4869A9278A5BCDD09C3D" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 90 days after the conclusion of the hearing, the administrative law judge shall—</text>
<clause id="H075A505EEE184258945EE8E469508386"><enum>(i)</enum><text>render a decision on the appeal, which shall consist of—</text> <subclause id="H9C3144874CB64CA0AB32A6BC228574DA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a brief statement of the issues of fact involved in the proceeding;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HA2F24DAE25064FCF9E567E8373187CEF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the findings and conclusions of the administrative law judge, and the reasons or basis therefor with record references, on all material issues of fact, law, or discretion presented on the record; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HFFD21C6414DE41569832E105E0047A2E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the decision of the administrative law judge to reverse or affirm the ruling or determination involved;</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H66F21B88C04C4926B6D92456559751F9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>certify to the complete record of the proceeding;</text></clause> <clause id="H65D5627B47D14A2CA8F3A5AC154E06FA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>forward the complete certified record and a copy of the decision to the Director of Industry Operations;</text></clause>
<clause id="H88B792D000EF40AF8F7A0B364F72095D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>serve a copy of the decision on the licensee or counsel for the licensee; and</text></clause> <clause id="H19DF86A88D5F42329550CCDF06B40894"><enum>(v)</enum><text>transmit a copy of the decision to the attorney representing the United States in the proceeding.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCB3F078A84DF47C280DD5C1525F0A932" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The decision of the administrative law judge or the Director of Industry Operations, or the ruling of another officer or employee of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, as the case may be, pursuant to this subsection shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HB3B48A8A407C4CF99634B031F91F1A05"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">constitute final agency action;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1B3998653D914E398A38AB9282CBC2B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be subject to judicial review under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF5647A0C8C964E608C998957A5CFC444"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be binding on the United States and the licensee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4961B434ECE84F46A0E6DAAE764F90DC" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The submission of an administrative appeal pursuant to paragraph (2) or (3) shall postpone the effective date of the ruling or determination until the administrative appeal and any subsequent judicial process is complete. The effect shall be as if the ruling or determination had not issued until such process is complete. </text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H0532FEE541C14412AA725E6E7DDFCD96"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to determinations made before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

