<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FLO25096-J7H-18-J6M"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1575 IS: Review and Evaluation of Strategies for Equitable Reservations for Visitor Experiences Federal Land Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1575</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250501">May 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of the Interior to enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences to carry out a study on reservation systems for Federal land. </official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="idea04d40b-801a-4ba9-89b4-ce8b3844170c" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Review and Evaluation of Strategies for Equitable Reservations for Visitor Experiences Federal Land Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RESERVE Federal Land Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id21c86dcb-e635-490f-b78c-e6cc229f8ae2" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id05d7dc94-1713-44cf-ad4b-711db469499e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Booking window</header><text>The term <term>booking window</term>, with respect to a Federal reservation system, means the time period during which a reservation or lottery entry is available to the public.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf6e12b04-238f-4d21-b01b-92d0279b8def" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text>The term <term>Federal land</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id3d11bc0a-82fc-4643-a0ab-0c84c1ad9707" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>public lands (as defined in section 103 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1702">43 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5ce54854-5fdd-4fed-8649-f92be46114ea" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>National Forest System land;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbbd8b06f-c10d-4e79-9e0d-709ad2990ecb" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>units of the National Park System;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6980680d-16e1-435e-9375-9a4b21c119ef" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">units of the National Wildlife Refuge System;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id30c74526-e61c-40be-9e30-3ac91c6e266c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><text>sites administered by the Bureau of Reclamation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9605304e-36db-4ce5-8146-917030e60efc" changed="not-changed"><enum>(F)</enum><text>sites administered by the Corps of Engineers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7e98ef63a9aa4bea9c7e2a498309ab1d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal reservation system</header><subparagraph id="id9d0c9d8ddc7541468ec623da287e6d40" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>Federal reservation system</term> means any platform or method used by managers of Federal land to manage the quantity, type, distribution, and timing of recreational activities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id10afa8eebba14fda84d998e1cf168399" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>Federal reservation system</term> includes reservation, permit, lottery, metering, pricing, merit-based, and other similar management methods via online, telephone, paper, in-person, or other methods. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id598aefd6a8f84fedad5e40595f5e14d4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Recreational activity</header><text>The term <term>recreational activity</term> includes camping, backpacking, climbing, paddling sports, fishing, hiking, driving, and other recreational opportunities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3b21483491a244909a7d9f5d1b0611d6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretaries</header><text>The term <term>Secretaries</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id624b21ee61434b8d855d6fd6c050b93e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idef8a917a626645839db1f7fe471f4133" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc8b632ea7f1c4b678eee9bd8c7e556b1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id0c161537-c280-46e7-a4d1-e03f57d900f1" changed="not-changed"><enum>3.</enum><header>National academy of sciences study of Federal reservation systems for recreational activities on Federal land</header><subsection id="id463bdd5c-fcfd-4d74-b765-7139e41dc0ee" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><paragraph id="id3110bcdb-ef42-4e7f-965e-6e00494e3528" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretaries, acting jointly, shall, not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences to carry out a study of Federal reservation systems for recreational activities on Federal land.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8e9dfc29-dff1-430c-b073-a007fff682be" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In carrying out the study under paragraph (1), the National Academy of Sciences shall consult with the Secretaries to carry out the following:</text><subparagraph id="id03ad6d9ff7ea494280448e4d229aca14" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A review of the history of Federal reservation systems, such as recreation.gov, including a review of—</text><clause id="id465a36d36e9a489898681dba594de484" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the considerations, including data, that led to the establishment of the applicable Federal reservation system;</text></clause><clause id="id0fa6c58f1fc34cdea506f1e5de3606ae" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the iterations of the applicable Federal reservation system over time to meet the needs of the applicable Federal agency;</text></clause><clause id="id42e3b4b1573e45e4be0a7b06aec4bff9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any visitor feedback provided with respect to the applicable Federal reservation system; and</text></clause><clause id="id83afab9e62434e639f37a24d12cdb41e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>scientific literature or studies examining the efficacy of Federal reservation systems, including user preferences with respect to Federal reservation system design and implementation. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f91bc4c-e0ec-4ed0-92b1-c33da2f872d4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Based on available data and existing research, answer the following questions:</text><clause id="id69983e18748b4ce9a061d09f738b71a8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>What are the benefits and challenges of implementing Federal reservation systems to achieve management goals for Federal land, including resource protection, enjoyable visitor experiences, and sustainable operations and facility use?</text></clause><clause id="id558c505b1f894c93970b6e03228bfcfa" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>What data are available, and what additional data are needed, to understand demand for recreation on Federal land? How can the data be used to balance visitor management and conservation goals?</text></clause><clause id="idccf2bf4589ae4535890412015ebabb21" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>What information is available regarding Federal land users and Federal reservation system users? What information is available or needs to be collected regarding demographics and characteristics of successful and unsuccessful applicants using the Federal reservation systems?</text></clause><clause id="id379b3d3899f54ac885979868d9899132" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Do Federal reservation systems pose a barrier for certain communities, including international communities, and user groups to access appropriate recreation opportunities on Federal land? If so, what is the nature of any barriers identified?</text></clause><clause id="id2c4d0fb43bac4ee9a3382a60a2956a63" changed="not-changed"><enum>(v)</enum><text>What best practices should be considered in Federal reservation system design, including visitation management system options and booking windows, options to respond to the needs specific to individual Federal land management units, and equitable access to recreational activities? What metrics can be used to record outcomes of Federal reservation system design?</text></clause><clause id="id401fac2ee25b41e5b0b889d4682f273e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>How have fees been collected for Federal reservation systems over time to meet the needs of the applicable Federal agency? How are the revenues from fees for Federal reservation systems split between, and spent by, Federal land units, Federal agencies, and third-party contractors? How is the fee structure disseminated to users? How could dissemination of information with respect to the fee structure be improved?</text></clause><clause id="id36a02dc5357644949dd40e16aeaf3e81" changed="not-changed"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>What are the odds of success with respect to securing a reservation under Federal reservation systems? How are the odds of success disseminated to users? How could dissemination of information with respect to the odds of success be improved?</text></clause><clause id="id996bcd44cdc94094abd94eb5b322fa70" changed="not-changed"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>How are data, including data collected by contractors, on Federal reservation systems shared with Federal land managers, researchers, and the public? How can transparency be improved to inform the decision making of users of Federal reservation systems?</text></clause><clause id="idaf70596c040c4037a96b1c457b3ab003" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>How are Federal reservation systems incorporating and adapting to emerging technologies, such as geofencing, bots, or third-party websites monitoring and reselling reservations? Are Federal reservation systems resilient to cyber threats?</text></clause><clause id="id366d2e7d300340dcb0cadd2701c1f7b4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(x)</enum><text>How can Federal reservation systems be improved to reduce <quote>no shows</quote> and ensure that recreation sites are being used during periods of high demand? Would an increase in first-come, first-served opportunities increase equitable access to outdoor recreation on Federal land? </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77fc40c6-633f-4a1e-98a2-bdeeb6ba09c8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The agreement entered into under subsection (a)(1) shall include a requirement that, not later than 18 months after the date on which the agreement is entered into, the National Academy of Sciences shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that describes the results of the study carried out under that subsection.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

