<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H148C7D009A9E48B2ADF5F35C75FBFA4A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5340 IH: To prohibit the disclosure of records by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development of individuals for the purposes of immigration enforcement, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5340</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250911">September 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000607">Mr. Liccardo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000620">Ms. Rivas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the disclosure of records by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development of individuals for the purposes of immigration enforcement, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4FB8ED7CF42D457BB893EC0FE44F35C2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE7DEC1CFD74546979989D086B1C7B0BF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Confidentiality of Department of Housing and Urban Development records</header> 
<subsection id="H19E10B451227458DA55F407BF0540388"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 552a(b)(7) of title 5, United States Code, or any other law, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (hereafter referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) may not, for the purposes of immigration enforcement, disclose any record which is contained in a system of records by any means of communication to any person, or to another agency, except pursuant to a written request made in a language of proficiency by, or with the prior consent of, the individual to whom the record pertains, regardless of the immigration status of such individual.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB029E8FD9DB844AF9FB8E0B04DE89C3F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public housing agencies</header><text>The Secretary may not compel a public housing agency to disclose any record as described in subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD7AC9DAD146E481BA8487DE8080FAFAE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a report which contains—</text> <paragraph id="HA4C9ADC62E3B4C2CBB6B70B3234287A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a timeline for how the Secretary will comply with this Act;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H92D7EC8A961D4E26ADF3CD960F3D49BF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a confirmation that the records described in this Act have been secured;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD95EF9C5164B48E08E8B5E5470AE15CA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of how records described in subsection (a) have been shared before the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HACB8C661460E4D69953294ECDBFE5828"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of how the Secretary will ensure compliance with this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4AFDA568EF5F4429816759444F10FB3A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF60925A79B094221AFABA55425F2B05F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <quote>agency</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB5891BFD794E414B875626CD8081FFC0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Immigration enforcement</header><text>The term <quote>immigration enforcement</quote> means, with respect to an individual with an alleged immigration violation, any law enforcement action pursuant to title 8, United States Code.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE0A128115D254E289E24B59FD98CC6B6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public housing agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>public housing agency</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 3(b) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H05ACC1D1C61E428C834B73241BB7BBDA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Record</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>record</quote> means any item, collection, or grouping of information about an individual that is maintained by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development or a public housing agency.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5DBFEFA3A5540B0BD13A72ABEAC7A88"><enum>(5)</enum><header>System of records</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>system of records</quote> means a group of any records under the control of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development or a public housing agency from which information is retrieved by the name of an individual or by some identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to an individual.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

