<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25112-J5P-FJ-46K"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S666 IS: First Responders Wellness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 666</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250220">February 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To increase access to mental health, substance use, and counseling services for first responders, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>First Responders Wellness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id7ae9514769b34accac1590eb4b499cc9"><enum>2.</enum><header>First responders mental health hotline</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part P of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g">42 U.S.C. 280g et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf26d9a0b3d6245e7900a445000c4a0d3"><section id="id0449bba023dd4ef5ad06277fd866600f"><enum>399V–8.</enum><header>First responders mental health hotline</header><subsection id="ida688bbfea07d410d968ae98278fabaa5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>First Responders Wellness Act</short-title>, the Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, shall maintain, directly or by contract or grant, a national first responders emergency hotline to provide peer and emotional support, information, brief intervention, and mental and behavioral health and substance use disorder resources and referrals to first responders and to their families or household members.</text></subsection><subsection id="id015598fcc9ad49229f9563045d0a5db3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements for hotline</header><text>The hotline established under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="id5379e5f06b19460ebbfabf754660e4cf"><enum>(1)</enum><text>operate as a separate, widely recognizable number with bidirectional transfer options with the 988 Suicide and Crisis Lifeline established pursuant to section 520E–3;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4a8120167c5447ffad053c75a569e795"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide toll-free, real-time, live assistance 24/7;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc2c102e7a4af48f6b0d28d2ad54ecd6c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide voice and text support;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide2178f83ffc5434da088b2cf53ddd565"><enum>(4)</enum><text>be sufficiently staffed by, at a minimum, culturally competent first responder peer specialists or first responder mental health services providers who have distinct knowledge of, and are trained on—</text><subparagraph id="id967cae47f01d4a6aa0b3c6d8a0e5d3d2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the essential functions of first responders and public safety organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0c99089b3b4540a690369aaea33aad0c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the working conditions unique to first responders;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc7b65b91924546e388a4e0378d25e490"><enum>(C)</enum><text>common and novel stressors inherent in public safety and emergency response work;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id55cef9e901d44fad93cfceaaf4e55a4e"><enum>(D)</enum><text>normal and abnormal adaptation to occupational stress and trauma; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id084c3dd824a34832b53284ade71930ef"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the unique aspects of confidentiality and testimonial privilege; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id142cabfe99f3462384fe469d50fc3254"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide peer support, mental and behavioral health and substance use disorder assistance, and referral services to meet the needs of first responders and family members or household members at risk of experiencing mental or behavioral health or substance use disorders.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc0c0071245d14046bf4c2f5869ea5932"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><paragraph id="ida0d787150f0e4df08cf90d4a273f6f31"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In maintaining the hotline under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="id52979131221644de8d95cd60e9965105"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consult with the National Domestic Violence Hotline, the 988 Suicide and Crisis Lifeline, and the Veterans Crisis Line to ensure that first responders are connected in real-time to the appropriate specialized hotline service, when applicable;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb645c82a0d5543178e92eb13ceb9be1e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conduct a public awareness campaign for the hotline under subsection (a);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd7070af2531d45ea8d6fd47b06d3a759"><enum>(C)</enum><text>consult with Federal departments and agencies, including the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration and the Department of Justice, to increase awareness regarding the hotline under subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2616e20d73eb41a7ac7be85e34905724"><enum>(D)</enum><text>consult with organizations that operate existing crisis or peer support hotlines for first responders with respect to best practices for operating such hotlines.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idaa6039082efb426b9baa02a9406a78aa"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Existing hotlines</header><text>The Secretary or an entity receiving a grant or contract under subsection (a), as applicable, shall form partnerships between the existing national first responders mental health hotline and other first responder helplines and websites.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0c8bf85e272446f388f8bded2e79b2a5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that calls from public safety personnel received through the 988 Suicide and Crisis Lifeline are appropriately referred to the hotline under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide7d1999ac5cc4c9f9aad6c37a7af1b4d"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Training curriculum</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>First Responders Wellness Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall develop, in coordination with mental health providers and first responder associations or personnel, trauma-informed and culturally competent training, guidance, and standards for 988 Suicide and Crisis Lifeline network center personnel on the unique concerns, resources, linkages, and stressors of first responders.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb3e06c4c349148548539872a99888fb2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The Secretary shall submit an annual report to Congress on the hotline under subsection (a) and implementation of this section, including—</text><paragraph id="id9b8d946d8c16473bbcf2d1ba6742de35"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an evaluation of the effectiveness of activities conducted or supported under subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddc99b79bf3044a728fe028a05ba8772b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an evaluation of staffing levels necessary to maintain adequate services;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id27a8938b0f6b4bfdaed5bc829ad427ac"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a directory of entities or organizations to which staff maintaining the hotline funded under this section may make referrals; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddf7dbd0ab9fe4312a9d06beacf4fec6d"><enum>(4)</enum><text>such additional information as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0fee5c83e8ed4b5ba253bc86e1985f71"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id567085769a154a5eac144925abbda8c8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Culturally competent first responder peer specialist</header><text>The term <term>culturally competent first responder peer specialist</term> means an individual—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id02886fa7c6fd4d2096eb16ad9836bd7a"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with familiarity with, and understanding of, the duties and unique stressors of first responders, which may include experience working as a first responder; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0cebcaa99bcb47ddb62f5de226f55422"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who completed a trauma-informed and culturally competent training curriculum developed pursuant to subsection (c)(4), or another trauma-informed and culturally competent training curriculum, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id11a06b5b94614333b2ef46e3a0a14369"><enum>(2)</enum><header>First responder</header><text>The term <term>first responder</term>—</text><subparagraph id="id6b010d7630824494a2b79f28b0d228d1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means—</text><clause id="idd9cc915d8c6240a99e259551175468da"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a law enforcement officer, firefighter, or member of a rescue squad or ambulance crew (as such terms are defined in section 1204 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968); or</text></clause><clause id="idc058f17ac88242aba887ed8c3e8dd46a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a public safety telecommunicator, including 9–1–1 operators and dispatchers; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd89bbf772cd34bdc9ecda8ba4e5b38aa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a retired first responder.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id70011b04eeb24089977b4372f1fba26a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>First responder mental health services provider</header><text>The term <term>first responder mental health services provider</term> includes a State-licensed or State-certified counselor, trauma counselor, psychologist or other State licensed or certified mental health professional who—</text><subparagraph id="id02a93d82154646da9e3f46f8ee42155f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is qualified under State law to provide mental or behavioral health services; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7dff42a4623d4560936e44df39803a64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has a familiarity with and understanding of the duties and unique stressors of first responders.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3999a67f56944bcc8947c81c43151d85"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2031.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id3984da8ab24149a3ba74dba541791276"><enum>3.</enum><header>Crisis counseling assistance and training</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 416(a) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5183">42 U.S.C. 5183(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>and to qualified emergency response providers responding to major disasters</quote> after <quote>victims of major disasters</quote>.</text></section><section id="idda6cc88f464f44429cb0de05e833e706"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on on-site services during a national disaster</header><subsection id="id43378681b6d8480a8344bff4a435d85e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, shall issue a report on best practices and recommendations to establish a new mobile health care delivery site to provide integrated, short-term crisis services to qualified emergency response providers of a major disaster. Such services shall—</text><paragraph id="idc2bb74400d6c4e9d8f750958523ac7ac"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be culturally and linguistically appropriate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idab9d74559b8a4cd4bca757ba57bf5457"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be trauma-informed; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3bfc87a6f1e64a668d797cc0e0e486dc"><enum>(3)</enum><text>incorporate disaster behavioral interventions.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd3b418a8a65e4957b61175fd48fdca94"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id96a67d67dd9d4ebbade0208bb1d38d76"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Major disaster</header><text>The term <term>major disaster</term> has the meaning given such term in section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4cee0e0fd3c44df6a23b511f5c143820"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Major disaster area</header><text>The term <term>major disaster area</term> has the meaning given such term in section 625.2 of title 20, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6d25b99ec0f140939352c599dd187faa"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified emergency response providers</header><text>The term <term>qualified emergency response providers</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id567aa1ecc134414fb64f06026df1a572"><enum>(A)</enum><text>emergency response providers (as defined in section 2 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/101">6 U.S.C. 101</external-xref>)); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0dda88061db041048ae2ca9ce93b6688"><enum>(B)</enum><text>public safety telecommunicators.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

