<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEF916DEA3B814925A6C6E28144AAE09D" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 593 IH: Congratulating the Oncology Nursing Society on the occasion of its 50th anniversary, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 593</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the Oncology Nursing Society on the occasion of its 50th anniversary, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Oncology Nursing Society (ONS) was founded in 1975 with the mission to promote excellence in oncology nursing and quality cancer care;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ONS has grown to represent over 100,000 oncology nurses in the United States and serves as the professional home to more than 35,000 members;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the impact of cancer on our Nation cannot be underestimated or overlooked, with 2,041,910 new cancer cases diagnosed and 618,120 cancer deaths estimated in the United States in 2025, and more than 18,000,000 Americans counting themselves among the cancer survivor community;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas cancer is a complex, multifaceted, and chronic disease, with patients being best served by a multidisciplinary health care team specialized in oncology care, including nurses who are certified in the specialty;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas oncology nurses are involved in the care of a cancer patient from diagnosis through the end of treatment, being the front-line providers administering chemotherapy and other novel anticancer treatments, managing patient therapies and side effects, working with insurance companies to ensure that patients receive appropriate treatment, providing education and counseling to patients and family members, performing other daily acts of care on behalf of cancer patients, and conducting research that expands the evidence for standards of care and validating oncology nursing practice outcomes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for five decades, ONS has honored and maintained nursing’s historical and essential commitment to advocacy for the public good by providing oncology nurses with access to the highest quality educational programs, cancer-care resources, research opportunities, and networks for peer support; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 50th anniversary of ONS marks a significant milestone in the organization’s history and provides an opportunity to celebrate its achievements and contributions to the field of oncology nursing; Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H9F4CA41BB8794DF18222224457D56E91"><section id="HAA169CD819A44E79A7002F5FCFF5B5C9" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H0BE8B5573CF344E08A1C502FAFF21702"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the Oncology Nursing Society on the occasion of its 50th anniversary;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H179028FD692E4D3FBD8E02427D11C62F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the integral role oncology nurses play in our Nation’s cancer-care delivery system, and the invaluable contributions of the Oncology Nursing Society to patient care, teaching, research, administration, and education in the field of oncology;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H858DBF988DCB490BA306A93CD11EF89F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commends the dedication of Oncology Nursing Society members to our Nation’s cancer patients and their ongoing commitment to improving and ensuring access to quality cancer care for all cancer patients and their families; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77C82D9CE75C4EF0804444F6E7BE1594"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages continued support for the Oncology Nursing Society in its important endeavor to promote excellence in oncology nursing and quality cancer care.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

