<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA7D2D73732A7474C9853B713D7BC37F2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2995 IH: Protection from Cumulative Emissions and Underenforcement of Environmental Law Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2995</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250424">April 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To advance environmental justice by addressing cumulative impacts and underenforcement, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDBD4E44001A04CAFB93FF372F2E62A9A" style="OLC"><section id="HEF36CFE63B074070829D85C6DA37EF5A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protection from Cumulative Emissions and Underenforcement of Environmental Law Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H89577E69DB32446EA3E5ECABD3E479AC" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Public health risks associated with cumulative environmental stressors</header><subsection id="H9D52BAE88FCA4020B6EB8CF352F3E6B4" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Proposed protocol</header><paragraph id="H36A79CE72B044FE09166AD4BAFBA507E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall publish a proposal for a protocol for assessing and addressing the cumulative public health risks associated with multiple environmental stressors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H138F148B93384FF5B771D8F7BD3DE151"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Environmental stressors</header><text>The environmental stressors addressed under the proposed protocol published under paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HE06925277E97416494B7B1BC0630DE7D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>impacts associated with global climate change, including extreme heat, extremes in temperature change, drought, wildfires, sea level rise, flooding, storms, water shortage, food shortage, ecosystem disruption, and the spread of infectious disease;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A9E2B7164194525B015982004358B51" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>exposure to pollutants, emissions, discharges, waste, chemicals, or other materials subject to regulation under the Clean Air Act, the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, the Safe Drinking Water Act, the Toxic Substances Control Act, the Solid Waste Disposal Act, the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980, the Emergency Planning and Community Right-to-Know Act of 1986, and other laws administered by the Administrator; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBD9C5967A654A5CADFA2030F1900B6F" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other environmental stressors determined by the Administrator to impact public health.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85C052FC78B04AEF803E3D56767FA212"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public comment and hearings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 90 days following publication of the proposed protocol under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall—</text><subparagraph id="HD1C49977AA594DE4AEBAEAE9B44ABDA3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>allow for public comment on such proposed protocol; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA409612DE6CB4B70A89A55A908D3A12C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>hold at least 4 public hearings on such proposed protocol at times and in locations intended to maximize public input.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6ABB8752D28C4BE9B1E220CBA1A163EA" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Final protocol</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="H0973CFCE40C043A99AF5FAECF5CD1AF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">finalize the proposed protocol published under subsection (a) by revising such proposed protocol as the Administrator determines necessary based on public comments received in writing and during the public hearings held pursuant to such subsection; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90389E9B868247EFB206F179102A21DF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publish in the Federal Register the final protocol for assessing and addressing the cumulative public health risks associated with multiple environmental stressors.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD1268CA8CE0D44578144D68038DBAB0C" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall implement the final protocol described in subsection (b).</text></subsection></section><section id="HF777D4D8147E49958FCCE11DB9E79789" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Environmental justice for communities overburdened by environmental violations</header><subsection id="HECEA7887E8F842208B3E42D08793ABF9" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification of communities</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall, in consultation with co-regulators in State and local agencies, identify at least 100 communities—</text><paragraph id="H96A1F42F80D241A8B7FDCE82DED49982" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that are environmental justice communities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC5709E2B9E14D60AB1991FB60814528" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in which there have been, over the previous 5 years, a number of violations of environmental law that the Administrator determines to be greater than the national average of such violations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFAD0690D57FF4FD7A273EE6C99EF9FC0" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Analysis and recommendations</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, with respect to each community identified under subsection (a), the Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="H9368755021AE43FEB6845EE80D6E5E33" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">undertake an analysis of the conditions that have led to the number of violations described in subsection (a)(2), including through engagement with the residents of each such community;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63361712F8E544409E772F93FE67384C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify the root cause of the number of violations described in subsection (a)(2); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD686A0E8C9C43A5944C1ABA19CA0E1E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify measures that the Administrator shall take, in coordination with co-regulators in State and local agencies, to reduce the number of violations of environmental law to a number that the Administrator determines to be significantly below the national average.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCBBFE36D5791444E92771DBB6BC9EEB7" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall complete the implementation of the measures identified under subsection (b)(3).</text></subsection></section><section id="H87CD3334AF744F818EE55C7F16D1098C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HE7D57B3495104E25934D5AFDF0E95B41"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA46724576F6642FB8A7A230A134F36DE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community of color</header><text>The term <term>community of color</term> means a geographically distinct area in which the population of any of the following categories of individuals is higher than the average population of that category for the State in which the community is located:</text><subparagraph id="HBBCD8C96604942A9BC77BC5411AEB541"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Black.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0BD514D96F147B697729C2BD4385CF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>African American.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEA451B0C8E54D45BB90ECF318E7ECDD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Asian.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC3C0E89FC124437BA03B8DB75FB9A4F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Pacific Islander.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H609CA312E151438C89091E4071D8BB4D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Other non-White race.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D3B800379104428BD0AEF70613FB078"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Hispanic.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB50BD62413345A7A9652A61CDFB58BB"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Latino.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C356F7237AC41DDAFDEC0C6D55BB214"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Linguistically isolated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8104BCFF246543B5B4A6A471D83B45C9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Environmental justice community</header><text>The term <term>environmental justice community</term> means a community with significant representation of communities of color, low-income communities, or Tribal and indigenous communities, that experiences, or is at risk of experiencing higher or more adverse human health or environmental effects.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D880057BAC545B381E36E788998B30B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Low-income community</header><text>The term <term>low-income community</term> means any census block group in which 30 percent or more of the population are individuals with an annual household income equal to, or less than, the greater of—</text><subparagraph id="HE91B76ACF39C4463A8D73A4E8C8B7350"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an amount equal to 80 percent of the median income of the area in which the household is located, as reported by the Department of Housing and Urban Development; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0C65525D4054EFDA2D5B4D7EB6E1B09"><enum>(B)</enum><text>200 percent of the Federal poverty line.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2493D6CA061B453F873E0394D3E5525B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Tribal and indigenous community</header><text>The term <term>Tribal and indigenous community</term> means a population of people who are members of—</text><subparagraph id="HEF7C72B324444F398C09AAFD96C735E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a federally recognized Indian Tribe;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B4AD6760800477C99C2B455E15CF691"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State-recognized Indian Tribe;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAED87EB2BCC24A8986D767AF474BD46D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an Alaska Native or Native Hawaiian community or organization; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC375CB33D89D410BA55E7AE50EEFF6B3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other community of indigenous people located in a State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

