<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ALL25576-HN2-K9-NKX"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1914 IS: Andrew Kearse Accountability for Denial of Medical Care Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1914</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250522">May 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require Federal law enforcement and prison officials to obtain or provide
            immediate medical attention to individuals in custody who display medical
 distress.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Andrew Kearse Accountability for Denial of Medical Care Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idE3916A78403A4493BCBEAE8E7718D843"><enum>2.</enum><header>Medical attention for individuals in Federal custody displaying medical
 distress</header><subsection id="idCDAEEEAAF41D4AEBA55C679694CC6117"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/13">Chapter 13</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE08CBF8BDF3942B486A734BE5BA333BF"><section id="id878588FB9E2942ADAC3235BEB1750ECA"><enum>251.</enum><header>Medical attention for individuals in Federal custody displaying
 medical distress</header><subsection id="idA561E084B60D4DAC86E2F4BD0522334B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="idC56E21B338AD4BA8B6285D2876B2A9FC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>appropriate Inspector General</term>, with respect to a covered official, means—</text><subparagraph id="idACDEA737718045DE9541BBA94BC1D155"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Inspector General of the Federal agency that employs the covered official; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCB3FE819D21E47CEAF8D20C3B2F96EEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a covered official employed by a Federal agency that does not have an Inspector General, the Inspector General of the Department of Justice;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idC8D5D8FDF48D401CBBE5BF443D293979"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>covered official</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id9009890A50424A1FB6A9EE5749335835"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Federal law enforcement officer (as defined in section 115);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCE1EE737AB9C48A8811920498B14728E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an officer or employee of the Bureau of Prisons; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id68FAC140F93A41CAB0AD66CBE940108C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an officer or employee of the United States Marshals Service; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id85EC19C5ABBB40E09F0AECE5DA4F37CF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>medical distress</term> includes breathing difficulties.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7F8E026CC97E4CC6AE0AE5283037DA8C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement</header><paragraph id="id11867D0E0B3949549F1038EE6215EF22"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Offense</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a covered official to negligently fail to obtain or provide immediate medical attention to an individual in Federal custody who displays medical distress in the presence of the covered official if the individual suffers unnecessary pain, injury, or death as a result of that failure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idF751210F5C9A452A93EADB71D704EFE2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>A covered official who violates paragraph (1) shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6247B9342CF0427A9ECB2B1E7C5967EB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State civil enforcement</header><text>Whenever an attorney general of a State has reasonable cause to believe that a resident of the State has been aggrieved by a violation of paragraph (1) by a covered official, the attorney general or another official, agency, or entity designated by the State may bring a civil action in any appropriate district court of the United States to obtain appropriate equitable and declaratory relief.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id46806D465EE44AFA8E14F80CD72B5086"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inspector General investigation</header><paragraph id="id2D81BC8AFD94469B9E22E5E833F60C0E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The appropriate Inspector General shall investigate any instance in which—</text><subparagraph id="id5FECD7FF1AD5489088137451C9262350"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a covered official fails to obtain or provide immediate medical attention to an individual in Federal custody who displays medical distress in the presence of the covered official; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id606500536D164884887471138F815598"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the individual suffers unnecessary pain, injury, or death as a result of the failure to obtain or provide immediate medical attention.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id35F127B221E8468B88775EF54CA7DB8B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Referral for prosecution</header><text>If an appropriate Inspector General, in conducting an investigation under paragraph (1), concludes that a covered official acted negligently in failing to obtain or provide immediate medical attention to an individual in Federal custody, the appropriate Inspector General shall refer the case to the Attorney General for prosecution under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idADC6B3DCFB244AD598CEB05A02C9CF2C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Confidential complaint process</header><text>The Inspector General of a Federal agency that employs covered officials shall establish a process under which an individual may confidentially submit a complaint to the Inspector General regarding an incident described in paragraph (1) involving a covered official employed by the Federal agency (or, in the case of the Inspector General of the Department of Justice, involving a covered official employed by a Federal agency that does not have an Inspector General).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5F86564B4B8B4377AD78B3171CBB28FE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Training</header><text>The head of an agency that employs covered officials shall provide training to each covered official on obtaining or providing medical assistance to individuals in medical distress.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id2B746EFDD1E0498CB917F5E677E82FB3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/13">chapter 13</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2AB9886128C9426097A6C39F7E158BC2"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">251. Medical attention for individuals
                            in Federal custody displaying medical distress.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

