<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HD63D04EC7FB64EE984FEC269FE9B6441" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 28 EH: Protection of Women and Girls in Sports Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 28</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Education Amendments of 1972 to provide that for purposes of determining compliance with title IX of such Act in athletics, sex shall be recognized based solely on a person’s reproductive biology and genetics at birth.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H29A5BC833B084BF6BB67E7997B417931" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H843B24F4B3B646A5BF0E99BDB9CA5C58" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protection of Women and Girls in Sports Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H387C2783F72D4874B5E411C76FA36BAB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 901 of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA16139460AB941EFA6696BB34F44ED9D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H6A366C9ED8FA45BF96B7477CD2838768"><enum>(d)</enum> 
<paragraph id="HB7CB0DAD8F8E4A6C8080FD7476D302FB" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>It shall be a violation of subsection (a) for a recipient of Federal financial assistance who operates, sponsors, or facilitates athletic programs or activities to permit a person whose sex is male to participate in an athletic program or activity that is designated for women or girls.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC7832C7F5CE04DB5A51F7317D903A572" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For the purposes of this subsection, sex shall be recognized based solely on a person’s reproductive biology and genetics at birth. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC01A42D901F3470BB0B6AE57C94342AE" indent="up1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>athletic programs and activities</quote> includes, but is not limited to, all programs or activities that are provided conditional upon participation with any athletic team.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF60B88AC04674756B7C388156430B6A7" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prohibit a recipient from permitting males to train or practice with an athletic program or activity that is designated for women or girls so long as no female is deprived of a roster spot on a team or sport, opportunity to participate in a practice or competition, scholarship, admission to an educational institution, or any other benefit that accompanies participating in the athletic program or activity. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6FF8DC9BEF4F4242952815FA992B726C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General shall carry out a study to determine the meaning of the phrase ‘any other benefit’ as used in subsection (d)(4) by looking at benefits to women or girls of participating in single sex sports that would be lost by allowing males to participate. The study shall document the adverse psychological, developmental, participatory, and sociological results to girls of allowing males to compete, be members of a sports team, or participants in athletic programs, that are designed for girls, including displacement or discouragement from sports participation, deprivation of a roster spot on a team or sport, loss of the opportunity to participate in a practice or competition, loss of a scholarship or scholarship opportunities, loss or displacement of admission to an educational institution, deprivation of the benefit of an environment free of hostility based on sexual assault or harassment, or any other benefit that accompanies participating in the athletics program or activity. Further, the Comptroller General shall submit to the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report that contains the results of such study.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250114" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives January 14, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

