<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5C3122761D044EE09C5FE637678D3D6E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4496 IH: Restore and Modernize Our National Laboratories Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4496</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Energy to fund projects to restore and modernize National Laboratories, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3C495065FF5A44BC9194F20B78E21851" style="OLC"><section id="HCA44BA5EA3DD411583C64EBBEDAB2389" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Restore and Modernize Our National Laboratories Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFD0D1F35488D44258500BB1D55F48B80"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Laboratories restoration and modernization</header><subsection id="HCB7B123C80F74F3FAF6DBAFB9444D391"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Restoration and modernization</header><paragraph id="H2D71EA3B4D364B049B6C01C809376482"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="HB388535DE4D5414BB40D03A1DFE68FA2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>National laboratory</header><text>The term <term>National Laboratory</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE148D08962141D5938D2B7CC695327A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEE56AADCE60404E8C2EFD06BE1C24B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Restoration And Modernization Projects</header><text>The Secretary shall fund projects described in paragraph (3) as needed to address the deferred maintenance, critical infrastructure needs, and modernization of National Laboratories.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA88ECBF6231A4B67B886C025BE47B5FD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Projects described</header><text>Projects described in this paragraph are the following:</text><subparagraph id="HEE6C8D7521C848D4B4F42D52462B7192"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Priority deferred maintenance projects at National Laboratories, including facilities sustainment for, upgrade of, and construction of research laboratories, administrative and support buildings, utilities, roads, power plants, and any other critical infrastructure.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF1439BCEC6D4F3B93481D89D84A26A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Lab modernization projects at National Laboratories, including lab modernization projects relating to core infrastructure needed to carry out the following:</text><clause id="H2E03769C34E343BCB9ED02F8EE37E56F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Support existing and emerging science missions with new and specialized requirements for world-leading scientific user facilities and computing capabilities.</text></clause><clause id="H0B29981A620F4E7AB3511FFACAA89803"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Maintain safe, efficient, reliable, and environmentally sustainable and responsible operations.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4678F16EE44C4E20BD26892ABC4EF6AD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text>For each fiscal year through fiscal year 2030, at the same time as the annual budget submission of the President, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a list of projects for which the Secretary will provide funding under this section, including a description of each project and the funding profile for each such project.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97CF8E8BAAC74F9F926F8CCA6775631D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subparagraph id="H0A5440624CA246BD895AA23EFD49C4F9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this subsection $5,000,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CD1475E43254837AEF1B794BC8C4A55"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Office of Science</header><text>Not less than one-third of the amounts made available to carry out this section each fiscal year shall be managed by the Office of Science of the Department of Energy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F0266D9D335430FA4FAC1550EB1458D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy for facilities and infrastructure</header><text>Section 993 the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16357">42 U.S.C. 16357</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H79E64D46032A4836BCC1255FA7A5AF6D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H20642285AD5345B79CDB66FC3C8ECB7E"><enum>993.</enum><header>Strategy for facilities and infrastructure</header><subsection id="H5C6F870B01824BD78E6F5A2F03B472DB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Facility and infrastructure policy</header><paragraph id="H6726B83299184E3B9764C87AAA408B11"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall implement a strategy for facilities and infrastructure supported by the Office of Science, the Office of Environmental Management, the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, the Office of Fossil Energy and Carbon Management, the Office of Nuclear Energy, and the National Nuclear Security Administration Science and Technology Programs at all National Laboratories and single-purpose research facilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DA3D5CB43244530B89B85FF7E6AF674"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Strategy</header><text>The strategy shall provide cost-effective means for ensuring enabling infrastructure can support current and future science and energy mission needs by carrying out the following:</text><subparagraph id="H75CCD4A37CA1445C95494B8B65DDB073"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Maintaining existing facilities and infrastructure.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53FEA5F1B5954312A7CF0ABD6183561A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Closing unneeded facilities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B6716F509FE4A8D8715F42F661980A3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Making facility modifications.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H580C64FEFC4B41A6B4788E3CDC9EC11D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Building new facilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H904F6F57C0424BAE88BE2245F09E0933"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="H67646D0B87384584BE536EF44E718EAF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report describing the strategy under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE91F84B9CEE9443D85CC2884C85641C1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>For each National Laboratory and single-purpose research facility that is primarily used for science and energy research and across each Office that manages National Laboratories, the report under paragraph (1) shall contain the following:</text><subparagraph id="HF32CCC1321564AD0860E35C0E631F0E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The current priority list of each proposed National Laboratory and single-purpose research facility and infrastructure project, including cost and schedule requirements, and proposed funding source.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7C568C91A044920B620A9429C76BB5F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A current 10-year plan that demonstrates the reconfiguration of each such National Laboratory and single-purpose research facility and infrastructure to meet respective missions and to address respective long-term operational costs and return on investment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2ACAEF513870436C97816412C5FDE3DB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A preliminary estimate of funding and resources required to fulfill such 10-year plan, and a description of how investments will be allocated among budgetary sources.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BBC19EF31124006B264DEE2E5FD6999"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A description of facilities and infrastructure planning processes, including data and metrics relied upon, project prioritization criteria, and stakeholder engagement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

