<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF52DF28810134870B3CFF12A14DF9A25" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 483 IH: Health Care Efficiency Through Flexibility Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 483</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250116">January 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to delay the implementation of electronic clinical quality metrics for accountable care organizations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCDE18DA5E2C14A689801DC03DEAF0C38" style="OLC"><section id="HBD3CE332669143BFAA56D716C45A4759" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Health Care Efficiency Through Flexibility Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HF00EEE27761448C0ADAAE7A42996D997" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Delay in implementation of eCQMs for ACOs</header><subsection id="H3657087FA224462AA1E82490220D9BD3" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Delay of eCQM implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall delay the implementation of the requirement for ACOs to transition from reporting quality measures via the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicare Services Web Interface portal to electronic Clinical Quality Metrics (eCQMs), as described in the rule titled <quote>Medicare and Medicaid Programs; CY 2025 Payment Policies under the Physician Fee Schedule and Other Changes to Part B Payment and Coverage Policies; Medicare Shared Savings Program Requirements; Medicare Prescription Drug Inflation Rebate Program; and Medicare Overpayments</quote> (89 Fed. Reg. 97710 (December 9, 2024)), until January 1, 2030.</text></subsection><subsection id="H80715D65ACCA450B9618842F9509C75D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pilot program for digital reporting methods</header><paragraph id="H859F6A25C82A433E930819CB824A95F0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2026, the Secretary shall establish and commence a pilot program to test digital reporting methods for quality measures on a subset of ACOs and ACO participants that submit an application to participate in such pilot program at such time and in such form as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADECEB471921453AB31D6042FA574E53" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Temporary exemption from eCQM requirements</header><text>An ACO or an ACO participant participating in the pilot program shall be exempt from mandatory eCQM reporting requirements during the duration of the pilot program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DA9C02AF5004F7AAF4EB9F01976C849" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No effect on payment incentives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Participation in the pilot program shall have no effect on the eligibility of an ACO or an ACO participant to qualify for or earn an incentive payment under section 1833(z) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(z)</external-xref>) or a payment adjustment under section 1848(q) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(q)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24C8707770674E109E17B8755A74B33D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary shall provide technical assistance, including waivers from any applicable quality reporting requirements, to ACOs and providers participating in the pilot program to incentivize their participation and to evaluate the efficacy of digital reporting methods.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F8A438A160C4DEC89316C2B71C38B42"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2028, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="HBEA212E9D5C741BEBC44A41DC31A3FCC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the findings and results of the pilot program carried out under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACE7EC78080F47C69745DA6D19CD59A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any recommendations for increasing the adoption by additional ACOs of the digital reporting methods tested under such pilot program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B712C8AFE2047DBB66051A7A070369C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Development of long-Term digital quality reporting standards</header><paragraph id="HC39664BE6BC240AF88107FD7C373B4A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2030, the Secretary shall implement standards for digital quality reporting metrics and formats. Such standards shall ensure that all EHR systems used by an ACO are capable of supporting digital reporting methods across a diverse range of practice sizes, specialties, and geographic locations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE47D7566F56242D6B3297EB820660A7D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the standards described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall collaborate with relevant stakeholders, including representatives of the National Committee for Quality Assurance, EHR vendors, ACOs, payers, and national medical and specialty physician groups.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC9FB13BF4CD34C3184F85DE56FEE312C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Continued use of existing reporting methods</header><paragraph id="HBAB2052F54564BD5975F7E5E5AED19DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An ACO or ACO participant may use the CMS Web Interface portal, MIPS CQMs, Medicare CQMs, eCQMs, or any other previously established quality reporting methods, for the purpose of meeting such requirements until the date on which the Secretary promulgates the standardized digital quality reporting methods under subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB8F2A66D73046AF80D489C4BA86E99F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>No penalties shall be imposed on ACOs or ACO participants for failure to comply with eCQM requirements during the period prior to January 1, 2030, provided they are in compliance with existing reporting methods. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7B553A11E9944833BE13647CFD1F9341"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HF186A5DB78BB40098267FE9DBD7B1F4D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ACO</header><text>The term <term>ACO</term> has the meaning given the term <term>accountable care organization</term> in section 425.20 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF513EA66116B47819CB66C42DABD6600" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>ACO participant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>ACO participant</term> has the meaning given such term in section 425.20 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H897A0C7C9BB64B739E06467E6F4BB01B" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>EHR</header><text>The term <term>EHR</term> has the meaning given the term <term>certified EHR technology</term> in section 1848(o) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(o)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

