<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FLO25780-JJ6-YV-CV6"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2801 IS: Canterbury Shaker Village National Heritage Area Study Authorization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2801</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250915">September 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a study to assess the suitability and feasibility of designating the Canterbury Shaker Village National Heritage Area, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Canterbury Shaker Village National Heritage Area Study Authorization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="iddc553fc20b094e659153724f07da8d05"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="id488f5fca64e2469bb1878c8ad4e9a72b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Canterbury Shaker Village, which was established in 1792, has played a prominent role in the history of the United Society of Believers, commonly known as the <quote>Shakers</quote>, which was the longest-lived and most successful of the several utopian experiments of the 19th century in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfe0767ef45424f1caa33968ce94b3447"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the advent and growth of the Shaker movement was a significant component of a transformational religious and social fervor in the United States—</text><subparagraph id="id8A26EE923A044E0880AC113591301FFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which is known as the <quote>Second Great Awakening</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD3291FA0953348E999CB0170D7C92776"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that led to the development of a number of churches and sects that diversified and enriched the society of the United States;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3e31ded138e04c01b0d4620713904e61"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Shakers—</text><subparagraph id="id7F23992E685E460C81100DC074F74B29"><enum>(A)</enum><text>were a communal and celibate religious group that saw work, music, and dance as worship;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id890A5CD32BE2491F8D9EC8783ADFCB90"><enum>(B)</enum><text>practiced equality of the sexes, pacifism, and technological invention; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB70F23689E684166AD534D5B98FE6D81"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by withdrawing from the larger society, developed a refined and aesthetically significant expression of architecture, decorative arts, and utilitarian objects that are now known and studied throughout the world;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3eee9055f7f24be5b0ae32bd7ca888e6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Canterbury Shaker Village played an increasingly important role in the Shaker movement, eventually becoming the home of the Shaker Central Ministry, which supervised the consolidation at Canterbury Shaker Village of other Shaker settlements as the other settlements declined and closed during the 20th century, preserving and distilling remnants of the societies at a single site;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf0828fb6e34941aab05afd591b6b9126"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Canterbury Shaker Village was the only Shaker community to deliberately transform the community from a religious society to a nonprofit museum, Canterbury Shaker Village, Inc., to which, in 1969, Canterbury Shaker Village conveyed the land, buildings, furnishings, and archives of Canterbury Shaker Village as an intact legacy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id397e29625222406cbac3b0dfec51bfc3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in 1992, in recognition of the historical significance and physical integrity of Canterbury Shaker Village, Canterbury Shaker Village was designated as a National Historic Landmark;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfc8813ba9fde449abdff433105d7aa52"><enum>(7)</enum><text>as of the date of enactment of this Act, Canterbury Shaker Village includes—</text><subparagraph id="id86D289D985864E3A99C4B1E85224F34A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>approximately 700 acres of land;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFF6EA95D35394B93868CFBDDC168AFD1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>25 buildings; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id218DC134D63E4E049FF6A2362B33D2F7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>extensive and verified archaeological resources, gardens, orchards, a community cemetery, miles of roadways, stone culverts and walls, and a chain of manmade ponds that have powered a range of industries, including some industries that derived from the inventions of the Shakers; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id339f02bb6c12446b83fd7f1df3ea4c2f"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Canterbury Shaker Village has been the beneficiary of years of concentrated surveying, mapping, photographic recordation, archaeological investigation, and documentary research and writing that—</text><subparagraph id="id1901A14049CA44F9BC29EC9C1A9AD6E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reflect a fascination on the part of the outside world with Canterbury Shaker Village that began in the early 1800s; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEF76E9125F55476583B3CB56C4982048"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are scholarly and popular in nature; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0B8B2AE6C8614133872D89D9BDE5A9FF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>have defined a cultural landscape and a historical legacy that is of national significance and high educational and aesthetic value to the people of the United States. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="idcfab4289103e4ae3af650cfb13b73af2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id9513D97D91EC4F7A9F1D6075AF99AF3F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaa4338a6dd3b477a89d9dfee205cd9f1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of New Hampshire.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idca86223d20bc4268a25dd41b542dc633"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Study area</header><text>The term <term>study area</term> means the geographic boundaries of the Canterbury Shaker Village National Historic Landmark located in Merrimack County, New Hampshire.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id7cd69fe7471b42aa81b84bc9bdca3a9e"><enum>4.</enum><header>Canterbury Shaker Village National Heritage Area study</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with State and local historic preservation officers, State and local historical societies, State and local tourism offices, and other appropriate organizations and governmental agencies and in accordance with section 120103(a) of title 54, United States Code, shall conduct a study to assess the suitability and feasibility of designating the study area as a National Heritage Area, to be known as the <quote>Canterbury Shaker Village National Heritage Area</quote>.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

