<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-REI25131-4WM-KS-VJV"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 349 ATS: Designating the week of August 3 through August 9, 2025, as “National Farmers Market Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 349</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250730">July 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating the week of August 3 through August 9, 2025, as <quote>National Farmers Market Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas farmers markets accounted for $1,700,000,000 in income for farmers of the United States in 2020, demonstrating the crucial role of farmers markets in local economies;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Agricultural Marketing Service of the Department of Agriculture, the number of farmers markets in the United States rose from 1,755 in 1994 to 8,771 in 2019, an average growth of nearly 7 percent per year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas farmers markets serve as significant educational sites and as bridges between urban and rural communities, contributing to a better public understanding of farming and ranching;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the adoption of more sustainable farming practices is closely associated with farmer-to-consumer interactions facilitated by farmers markets;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas farmers markets and direct marketing farmers help improve the health and wellness of low-income people in the United States who receive Federal nutrition benefits; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas National Farmers Market Week is a time to recognize the unique and indispensable role farmers markets play in supporting food access, bolstering local economies, promoting healthy communities, and fostering sustainable farming: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id1d478dd116404f3ebad89f287e82b6c4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates the week of August 3 through August 9, 2025, as <quote>National Farmers Market Week</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd4d20596513649c2bb052ac036a2bc86"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the vital role that farmers markets play in bringing communities together and in supporting the livelihoods of millions of people in the United States, from farmers and food producers to consumers. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

