<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4951547D6C1941718CAA27D63A8DD6F6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3566 IH: Assuring Navigation of Compact Help for Ongoing Relocation for Military Families Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3566</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250521">May 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Defense to provide information on relocation assistance programs when a member of the Armed Forces receives orders for a change of permanent station, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE10AE1096D7E47A6839C60A272328B36" style="OLC">
<section id="HEDE06727747C44AEADA05543E6E7EC98" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Assuring Navigation of Compact Help for Ongoing Relocation for Military Families Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ANCHOR for Military Families Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5D47A4C9314B4AF4B1C3F646C32D8ACA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Provision of Information Regarding Relocation Assistance Programs for Members Receiving Orders for a Change of Permanent Station</header> <subsection id="HCB4E108D8973479FA88DE267EE29215E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1056 of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAF14FCC1F761422EA0C07624F58FD993"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)—</text> <subparagraph id="HE628CDFF1C5A4660A624CAA84715A9EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and community orientation</quote> and inserting <quote>community orientation, education systems, school enrollment procedures, and State-specific provisions under the Interstate Compact on Educational Opportunity for Military Children</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5CDF839EE0F04992B13FD4F2C3FF1145"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>and community orientation</quote> and inserting <quote>community orientation, and educational resources for dependent children, including school transition assistance, academic continuity, and special education services</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H487FD898BCC14FEF9F4DFA35EE8334E0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HC1220CF9294A4304AE6A6C596A5BAB24" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="HFD8AC7DB49CB4B7B80522DA32649A2AE" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Educational planning and support services for dependent children with disabilities, including procedures for transferring individualized education programs and coordinating with the Exceptional Family Member Program.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6B9F4A8C34549D1800D37931AFD1505"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (e) and (f) as subsections (f) and (g), respectively; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H558147FAA4844C758FDBDC5C556E7454"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (d) the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H8FEF62127BE64B0DA19CB94C2773A0AE" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H8FDB27FA3EA44A829C6B70B49EADDBB2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Provision of Information on Program</header> <paragraph id="H1289AC8971F04C1CA325E6981D41AE49" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that members of the armed forces and the families of those members are provided information regarding available assistance under this section and any other assistance relating to a change of permanent station available under any other provision of law.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDA13CE139211430B99C1ECC4B92D4BF7" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall ensure that information required to be provided under this subsection is provided to a member of the armed forces and the family of that member not later than 45 days before the date on which a change of permanent station takes effect for that member.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H03118EC1D90F41DF97489F4B7178083C" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The information provided under this subsection shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9401177E3A2F4A7F927A1C6234853590"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information on family assistance programs authorized under section 1788 of this title, including financial planning resources, spouse employment support, and community integration services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE48C30B0963C4D018671505B5766CAD3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>guidance on available housing assistance, including on-base housing options, rental protections, and resources for off-base relocation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB0530B50C3E6484A902687A9173BEA67"><enum>(C)</enum><text>mental health and well-being support services, including those accessible during the period of transition for a change of permanent station;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDDE3B25962C44020998B4A6249AE1160"><enum>(D)</enum><text>educational resources for dependent children, including school transition assistance and special education services;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HACCEEECB6D3D468988631D794DAD6DA3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>information on available legal and financial counseling programs; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA7FD8421214C4BF89F070525FB9548CA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other assistance programs that support members of the armed forces and their families during relocation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H456E311916FE48129B9E3211E36C6D6B" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H4C669417C9C14CD4828A67624944771F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>incorporate the information required to be provided under this subsection into accessible materials and briefings provided to members of the armed forces relating to a change of permanent station;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1187E32CE05746B6881B970BA732423A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that the program under this section provides accessible materials and briefings at military installations and through online resources; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBF1C0AFCF801496BB32433F4C6A0AF44"><enum>(C)</enum><text>develop a communication strategy, including digital outreach and printed materials, to increase awareness of the program under this section and assistance available under other provisions of law relating to a change of permanent station; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9F37EA3C1AF742378617038777392C70"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assess the satisfaction of members of the armed forces and their families with the information provided under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE1E7881B240A406C86D3675F8C76AC66"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for three years, the Secretary of Defense shall provide to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a briefing on the implementation of the amendments made by this section. Such briefing shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0B1749BA3CFD443E8217451A53E880B5">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the status of efforts to integrate information required to be provided by subsection (e) of section 1056 of title 10, United States Code, as added by subsection (a) of this section, into accessible materials and briefings provided to members of the Armed Forces and their families relating to a change of permanent station;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA2D5BD780DBC44F8973E2DD1672122BB">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>an assessment of the awareness by members of the Armed Forces and their families of available programs in support of a change of permanent station; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H62A885E0BA474FBB8BBCA587D0F84A82"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any recommendations of the Secretary for improving the dissemination of information related to relocation and family assistance programs.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

