<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H87A7C86A14CF47AC84C27359E31879AF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4940 IH: Accommodating Individuals Requesting Familial Assistance in Riding Efficiently Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4940</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250808">August 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a system to expedite gate passes and flight access procedures at domestic airports to allow caregivers, parents, and guardians to accompany minors and passengers needing assistance to their flights, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H748248B38BBD44E88A9661FF6B30EDC9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H490969D435C64A99B42D4F7CBC199D49" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Accommodating Individuals Requesting Familial Assistance in Riding Efficiently Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>AIRFARE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H34F9CF06662B4537A703C6295D894302"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of system to expedite gate passes and flight access procedures to allow caregivers, parents, and guardians to accompany minors and passengers needing assistance to their flights</header> 
<subsection id="H6EE04855448E4EA1937AA8CED6A5892D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H196FFCAA9D8741609DF773C0532DC02A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Caregivers</header><text>The term <quote>caregivers</quote> means individuals responsible for the care of minors or passengers needing assistance.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8C91C5762EB44131AF8B5829DB97888C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minors</header><text>The term <quote>minors</quote> means individuals under the age of 18.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H12FB59A6607941BBBA0EA6C8E8112625"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Passengers needing assistance</header><text>The term <quote>passengers needing assistance</quote> means individuals requiring special assistance related to their health or mobility, such as wheelchair users.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3F2A9444F4D647D3A9E66EBF1FE8E3BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) shall establish a system at domestic airports to expedite gate passes and flight access procedures. The system shall ensure the following:</text> <paragraph id="H6EB746C22AA3492C9F4C5ABB1768F20B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Air carriers may offer up to two gate passes to caregivers, parents, and guardians who are accompanying a minor or a passenger needing assistance to a departing flight.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H008856452E5A48B58747446DF899C815"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If applicable, caregivers, parents, and guardians may apply their existing TSA Pre-Check privileges to such gate passes via their Known Traveler Numbers, and such gate passes shall note such status in the same manner and to the same extent as such status would be noted on a ticket issued to such caregivers, parents, and guardians.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2F2DA52481504333B02C441701C91448"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>In the case of a passenger needing assistance who makes use of a wheelchair, a gate pass may be issued to a caregiver of such passenger pursuant to subsection (b) only if such caregiver is the individual pushing such wheelchair.</text> </subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

