<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H31D07238B9B44707B09C026489BA4B07" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 746 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives condemning all forms of political violence and rejecting rhetoric that dehumanizes or demonizes political opponents.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 746</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250918">September 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000635">Ms. Dexter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Vicente Gonzalez of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001231">Mr. Mannion</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000136">Mr. Vasquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000621">Ms. Pou</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001136">Mr. Conaway</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001094">Ms. Hoyle of Oregon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001234">Ms. Morrison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives condemning all forms of political violence and rejecting rhetoric that dehumanizes or demonizes political opponents.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas democracy depends upon the peaceful contest of ideas, not intimidation, violence, or assassination;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas acts of political violence and threats against elected officials, candidates, and public figures undermine the safety of those who serve, the trust of the governed, and the integrity of democratic institutions;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, in September 2025, conservative activist Charlie Kirk was assassinated by gunfire during a speaking event in Orem, Utah, in a horrifying attack authorities have described as politically motivated;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in June 2025, multiple Minnesota legislators and their families were targeted in coordinated shootings, including the assassination of Minnesota House Speaker Melissa Hortman and her husband Mark Hortman, and the attempted assassinations of Senator John Hoffman and his wife Yvette Hoffman;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, in April 2025, arsonist Cody Balmer threw Molotov cocktails into the Pennsylvania Governor’s Residence, setting fire to the building;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in July 2024, an armed individual attempted the assassination of President Donald J. Trump at a campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, resulting in death and injury, followed by a second attempt in 2025 at his golf club in Florida;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, in October 2022, Paul Pelosi, husband of then-Speaker Nancy Pelosi, was brutally attacked in his home by an assailant seeking to harm the Speaker;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on June 8, 2022, an armed individual was arrested near the Maryland home of Supreme Court Justice Brett Kavanaugh after traveling from California with the stated intent to assassinate him;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, on January 6, 2021, the United States Capitol was attacked by a violent mob seeking to disrupt the certification of the Presidential election, resulting in deaths, injuries, and threats to the safety of Members of Congress, staff, and law enforcement officers;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 2020, members of a paramilitary militia group plotted to kidnap and assassinate Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas such events demonstrate an escalating pattern of politically motivated violence across the country, targeting leaders and public figures across the political spectrum;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Members of Congress and other public officials have increasingly faced death threats, harassment, and intimidation aimed at silencing them or deterring them from fulfilling their representative responsibilities; and</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas such violence or threats, whether carried out or attempted, strike at the heart of representative democracy, impede free speech, chill civic engagement, and endanger the legitimacy and functioning of government, including the House of Representatives: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H12B94091194F4C9983E10A1877553A9B"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H196F223E8A664F88B4C278769E829C91"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="HA3AD371C661A4D79AC0CFA91DEE58852"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">condemns all forms of political violence, including assassination and attempted assassination of public officials, candidates, and public figures, regardless of political party or ideology;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4EA4E45E998C4C2FB99C72224D6DEDBB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affirms that violence and threats have no place in the political arena and that all political disputes must be resolved through lawful, peaceful, democratic means;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H13DDD4F3252241289A7D5DA2D3ED7908"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reaffirms its commitment to ensuring the safety, dignity, and respect for all Members of Congress, State legislators, elected officials, and other public servants;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBCB590BEBC064C9F9BDA803CAADA1A99"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">urges law enforcement authorities at all levels to thoroughly investigate, prosecute, and hold accountable those who commit or incite political violence;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5CFD8202C6C54F4086F2AA5C59D1E5ED"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commends law enforcement and all public officials who work to respond to such violence;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87404067179B42F88DBF54308B8BAF25"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls on all public officials, community leaders, and media to reject rhetoric that dehumanizes or demonizes opponents and to foster civil discourse; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H67466FCAA3444B70A787E7A23B10DCF2"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">declares that threats or acts of violence against officials or public figures degrade the dignity, safety, and integrity of the House of Representatives and of democratic institutions more broadly.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

