<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL25A39-P8S-R5-PV3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2557 IS: Epstein Files Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2557</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250730">July 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Attorney General to make publicly available documents related
 to Jeffrey Epstein, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Epstein Files Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="ide6d4b5d208c74599bcec8da6fa9ab19d"><enum>2.</enum><header>Release of documents relating to Jeffrey Epstein</header><subsection id="id219c60ec444f47559a747cc6d741342a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsection (c), not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall make publicly available in a searchable and downloadable format all unclassified records, documents, communications, and investigative materials in the possession of the Department of Justice, including the Federal Bureau of Investigation and each United States Attorney's Office, that relate to—</text><paragraph id="id36f99c9e6c6f4ab7b8b51321ee07662f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Jeffrey Epstein, including all investigations, prosecutions, or custodial matters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7bec3f673f1d46239f86341257830a0d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Ghislaine Maxwell;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2647c7d3de764bfc91fa1e9dc2659252"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any flight logs or travel records, including manifests, itineraries, pilot records, and customs or immigration documentation, for any aircraft, vessel, or vehicle owned, operated, or used by Jeffrey Epstein or any related entity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id84ff48b2b4034b76abda0878443426a3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any individuals, including government officials, named or referenced in connection with the criminal activities, civil settlements, immunity or plea agreements, or investigatory proceedings of Jeffrey Epstein;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb3a43ac88b3248359afb340a5fa1627b"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any corporate, nonprofit, academic, or governmental entities with known or alleged ties to the trafficking or financial networks of Jeffrey Epstein;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id74cbabf91c6149b39bc27682b94bbf09"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any immunity deals, non-prosecution agreements, plea bargains, or sealed settlements involving Jeffrey Epstein or his associates;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida6e9a1290af041d3baf59d9d2024a176"><enum>(7)</enum><text>any internal Department of Justice communications, including emails, memoranda, and meeting notes, concerning decisions to charge, not charge, investigate, or decline to investigate Jeffrey Epstein or his associates;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id927e0e7364a44fdf9af6a0229eed9197"><enum>(8)</enum><text>any communications, memoranda, directives, logs, or metadata concerning the destruction, deletion, alteration, misplacement, or concealment of documents, recordings, or electronic data related to Jeffrey Epstein, his associates, his detention and death, or any investigative files; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id355cf30831524e01bcdfa13777c86732"><enum>(9)</enum><text>any documentation of the detention or death of Jeffrey Epstein, including incident reports, witness interviews, medical examiner files, autopsy reports, and written records detailing the circumstances and cause of death.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0bf1becf29e84d089937577042328d21" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibited grounds for withholding</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Attorney General may not withhold from publication, delay the publication of, or redact any record, document, communication, or investigative material on the basis of embarrassment, reputational harm, or political sensitivity, including to any government official, public figure, or foreign dignitary.</text></subsection><subsection id="idf48d741b450644b0a9bffc0d5c114c52"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Permitted withholdings</header><paragraph id="id9f188706d73844669a6ca56a02a49582"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Attorney General may withhold from publication any record, document, communication, or investigative material, or redact any segregable portion of any record, document, communication, or investigative material, that—</text><subparagraph id="id01bc8f37e2c9467488892321a9ef59fa"><enum>(A)</enum><text>contains personally identifiable information from the personal or medical file of a victim or child witness, including information the publication of which would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec654b4768b64acf85c2382f28028da5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>depicts or contains child pornography, as defined in section 2256 of title 18, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8e6128c075f04c4d9f686a00b6187ad6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>would jeopardize an active Federal investigation or ongoing Federal prosecution, if the withholding or redaction is narrowly tailored and temporary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id30dc8927e6de406cacbcd1614a4b937c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>depicts or contains any image of the death, physical abuse, or injury of any person; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfa643e397f8d49b0b4dc3184d1992860"><enum>(E)</enum><text>contains information that is specifically authorized under criteria established by an Executive order to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or foreign policy and is properly classified pursuant to that Executive order.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddb99284ccb3c4da2a74094ce420c733a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Redactions</header><text>The Attorney General shall publish in the Federal Register and submit to Congress a written justification for each redaction under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id95af0e89705844869f0c09387f46c7b9" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Declassification to the maximum extent possible</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd458225d213744e0b8734bfba096e72f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall declassify, to the maximum extent possible, any information that the Attorney General would otherwise withhold or redact as classified information under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc7eabf2074d44d229ee86e7293e96b37"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Unclassified summary</header><text>If the Attorney General determines that information described in subparagraph (A) may not be declassified and made available in a manner that protects the national security of the United States, including methods or sources related to national security, the Attorney General shall make publicly available an unclassified summary of the information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc61b883c0d1142fbaf743617d3c03c94"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Classification of covered information</header><text>The Attorney General shall publish in the Federal Register and submit to Congress each decision made after July 1, 2025, to classify any information that would otherwise be required to be made publicly available under subsection (a), including the date of classification, the identity of the classifying authority, and an unclassified summary of the justification for classification.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id91e5ad0395ba4d8595bc3b497c3672cc"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 15 days after making publicly available all records, documents, communications, and investigative materials under section 2(a), the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report containing—</text><paragraph id="id2d860784c972475380f0f47949043ddd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of each category of records, documents, communications, and investigative materials made publicly available or withheld;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcbf55320642d4047b91dd0afd82897b8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a summary of the redactions made, including the legal basis upon which the redactions were made; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id96d826ba64c648eb84a180b2719f4a59"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a list of each government official, public figure, or foreign dignitary named or referenced in the records, documents, communications, and investigative materials made publicly available, without redaction in accordance with section 2(b).</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

