<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MUR25613-KG6-HY-2GP">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2266 IS: Consumer Online Payment Transparency and Integrity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2266</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250714">July 14, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr.
                    Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr.
                    Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms.
                    Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, and
                    <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>) introduced the following
                bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and
                Transportation</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To provide for automatic renewal protections, and for other
            purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="S1">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Consumer Online Payment Transparency and Integrity Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="idd30c0172e997486d8b49449b7152bd17">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Automatic renewal protections</header>
            <subsection id="id5e537f9d8eaf43ca9e9bb1aff75fbf57">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>A person who sells a good or service to a consumer pursuant to a contract that includes a free-to-pay conversion or negative option feature or any other automatic renewal provision shall disclose such feature or provision and the cancellation procedure clearly and conspicuously in the contract.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id1220ca8335b24d68a63c1f487b901093">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Automatic renewal</header>
 <text>A person who sells a good or service to a consumer pursuant to a contract that will automatically renew unless the consumer cancels the contract shall—</text>
                <paragraph id="id2CF773E1E01E4F4DA924E42F55A21B43">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>notify, in the same manner as the consumer entered into the contract, the consumer of—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="id423C8F8F2A6749158F30B50EDAF60FA2">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the first automatic renewal (and of each automatic renewal thereafter) not less than 7 days (or a longer time period as determined appropriate by the Commission) before the commencement of the renewal period; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id66B5F4636CD54BFF8AD1FE9AD0D2EB2D">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>how the consumer may simply cancel the contract, which shall include—</text>
                        <clause id="id39E73948BC5942EBA75565B09F3ED82E">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>an online mechanism for cancellation provided by the person; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id39C0AD5E6D664F62A597A13368DA9B3D">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>a toll-free telephone number, email address, postal mail address, or other cost-effective, timely, and easy-to-use mechanism for cancellation provided by the person;</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCFA70EFA8B984B2C90425ABB7C476BE5">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>on an annual basis and notwithstanding the consumer’s consent to the initial term (or any subsequent term), obtain the consumer’s express informed consent to renew the contract before charging the consumer for the automatic renewal; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE6BDD33B6E5540B484EED6CFC8788CDB">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>notwithstanding the consumer's consent to the initial term (or any subsequent term), in the event that the person has actual knowledge that the consumer has not used the good or service provided under the contract for a period of 6 consecutive months since the consumer's most recent express informed consent—</text>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4AC66A2ADC0D4B03AB2B4F3524EC0D8F">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>obtain the consumer's express informed consent to the automatic renewal before charging the consumer for the automatic renewal; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55BD24BCE9684083AC5F777E619795F4">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>notify the consumer that the consumer has a right to terminate the contract and receive a prorated refund for the remaining portion of the contract.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id1df7fa9f7fb346829d06d23749e6369e">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Free trial</header>
 <text>A person who sells a good or service to a consumer pursuant to a contract that includes a free-to-pay conversion feature with a free trial period, shall—</text>
                <paragraph id="id8985a3c061fe4923a738af5f39919ea3">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>notify, in the same manner as the consumer entered into the contract, the consumer—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="id8167E5F834AE417D80219FF21B08033B">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>that the consumer will be charged for the good or service not less than 7 days (or a longer time period as determined appropriate by the Commission) before the expiration of the free trial period; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id8E479159B8C74B80A872DCCB259DE8D2">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>of how the consumer may simply cancel the contract, which shall include—</text>
                        <clause id="id0B5CC4068D1A455D88A2D33921298130">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>an online mechanism for cancellation provided by the person; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8F80C84C0D11499AB71ADF80035CEB19">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>a toll-free telephone number, email address, postal mail address, or other cost-effective, timely, and easy-to-use mechanism for cancellation provided by the person; and</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idf77ca47153ca49eb8a38d80370e5d2c7">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>notwithstanding the consumer’s consent to the free trial, obtain the consumer’s express informed consent to the applicable charge for the good or service not less than 7 days (or a longer time period as determined appropriate by the Commission) before the expiration of the free trial period and before charging the consumer for the automatic renewal.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idA558CFF557A345A0AD4DFD37312B187C">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Automatic renewal void</header>
 <text>In the case of a violation of subsection (a), (b), or (c)—</text> <paragraph id="idADB8631408A04BEB98A955A195616A37"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>the applicable automatic renewal provision shall be void, and the contract shall terminate upon the occurrence of such violation; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idB963012EB3A04BFD819F5844BA6B577C">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the person who violated subsection (a), (b), or (c) shall provide the consumer with a refund for all amounts paid by the consumer due to such violation.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id7F7965688AD3434E9C18875CB6F22DA5">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Dark patterns</header>
 <text>With respect to a contract that includes a free-to-pay conversion or negative option feature or any other automatic renewal provision, a consumer's consent obtained through the use of dark patterns shall not be considered express informed consent.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idadd840f4b3df438c8c57d93ddfba1f40">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Exemptions</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements under subsections (a), (b), (c), and (d) shall not apply to a service contract or any other person or contract determined appropriate by the Commission.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idFEC0546B9B0149FA8C5ED7815C140759">
                <enum>(g)</enum>
                <header>Effective date</header>
 <text>The requirements under this section shall take effect on the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBD523FE7819F44339590DBB1E7CAB7A4">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enforcement by the Commission</header>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id36BBA901AC8640109F2758660EB8DD94">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unfair or deceptive acts or
                    practices</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation of section 2 or a rule promulgated under this Act shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or a deceptive act or practice under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC954758C13184A1AB6E4DE192C043D92">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Powers of the Commission</header>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id224BEC3D18C741EA9E5A84E5FA7184EE">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall enforce this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8E03175E660C40B8B5BF01F42BF6023D">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Privileges and immunities</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who violates section 2 or a rule promulgated under this Act shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4DECE15CEE5F4F1A9E5EC9BF6D68BAC2">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Authority preserved</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id28470e5fe9e24a39b4077f367a996e6c">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
                    <header>Rulemaking</header>
 <text>The Commission shall promulgate in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, such rules as may be necessary to carry out this Act, or to prevent unfair or deceptive acts or practices regarding free trials, automatic renewals, or other contracts under which a consumer's silence or failure to take an affirmative action to reject goods or services or to cancel an agreement is interpreted by the seller as acceptance of the offer.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="idF3A902F7A43A442CA403FC6E31736E82">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2b1138b3-caa2-453e-b9a4-8ffe6f375274"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Commission</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1FE9F2BBE5E040CB94505A05B1612A1B">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Consumer</header>
 <text>The term <term>consumer</term> means any person who seeks or acquires, by purchase or lease, any goods or services.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2AE4C1E2B6264905A5DD84A18A410215">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Dark patterns</header>
 <text>The term <term>dark patterns</term> means a user interface that has the substantial effect of subverting or impairing user autonomy, decision making, or choice.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB9E14A489A1D4743A2925F52A93E454D">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Free-to-pay conversion</header>
 <text>The term <term>free-to-pay conversion</term> has the meaning given that term in section 310.2 of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id039588CAE13840A9B7CA224983FB97C8">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Negative option feature</header>
 <text>The term <term>negative option feature</term> has the meaning given that term in section 310.2 of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47EB6D2FB1F44AA58D7693AE68392A42">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <header>Service contract</header>
 <text>The term <term>service contract</term> means a contract or agreement for a separately stated consideration for any duration—</text>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5C88EBB1A17041D8B5C33873DE5E1A04">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>to perform the repair, replacement, or maintenance of property or indemnification for service repair, replacement, or maintenance for the operational or structural failure of any motor vehicle or residential or other property due to a defect in materials, workmanship, accidental damage from handling, or normal wear and tear; or</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id38B03247401149FAB1285BEB3970373A">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>to indemnify for the same, including towing, rental, or emergency road service or road hazard protection, and which may provide for the service repair, replacement, or maintenance of property for damage resulting from power surges or interruption.</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id54c0874a4f784ebbb64f0645af5f3542">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
                <header>Simply cancel</header>
 <text>The term <term>simply cancel</term>, with respect to a contract, means the mechanism for cancellation of such contract is at least as easy to use as the mechanism the consumer used to consent to such contract.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

