<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCE61909601784C72B45950CD6A0F83A4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2912 IH: Oligarch Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2912</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250414">April 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish a wealth tax, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H16DF1E057A5A4B619D36FC70D883F3BD" style="OLC"><section id="HA4A77121DCA54AEA8489D0D67FA9B8AD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Oligarch Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1F7164CF4E5640EDAFA554270EC320FB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Imposition of wealth tax</header><subsection id="H0A1523CC22964C899F395128EA0D181F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after subtitle B the following new subtitle:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H601E49BEFCAF4F0D8265751DBC9C3051"><subtitle id="H5F2CA135C3664F73882CDC0A3789915C" style="OLC"><enum>B–1</enum><header>Wealth tax</header><toc><toc-entry level="chapter" idref="HB1DEA328FAEE47E096529417C6660645">Chapter 18—Determination of wealth tax </toc-entry></toc><chapter commented="no" level-type="subsequent" style="OLC" id="HB1DEA328FAEE47E096529417C6660645"><enum>18</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Determination of wealth tax</header><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H89C5D722063C4E05AD7C7FFC49CBF89D">Sec. 2901. Imposition of tax. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H01C2F76B4F774068B98E8162BE7F0EC8">Sec. 2902. Net value of taxable assets. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HE14F7F8A180C405587B1E1ECE8E27A99">Sec. 2903. Special rules. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H824053C1699646A0B757C3CB04F5EFC5">Sec. 2904. Information reporting. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H11C78C8081E2441AB0CE369CFCCD4E29">Sec. 2905. Enforcement. </toc-entry></toc><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H89C5D722063C4E05AD7C7FFC49CBF89D"><enum>2901.</enum><header>Imposition of tax</header><subsection id="HD0C5DE0B08BD42F79EAEBE9F4361D649"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any applicable taxpayer, a tax is hereby imposed on the net value of all taxable assets of the taxpayer on the last day of any calendar year.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7FE110E4950F4615AD93011E6968FAFB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Computation of tax</header><paragraph id="HD6C8D3B386F544E7954A2746379FBC2B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Individuals</header><text>In the case of an individual, the tax imposed by this section shall be equal to the sum of—</text><subparagraph id="H6A02A98C73BD4E29AB4E1B6261034636"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 percent of so much of the net value of all taxable assets of the taxpayer as exceed the threshold amount but do not exceed the product of 10 multiplied by threshold amount,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9717B9D9175E40BF8DCFD39A931BAD5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">4 percent of so much of the net value of all taxable assets of the taxpayer as exceed the product of 10 multiplied by the threshold amount but do not exceed the product of 100 multiplied by the threshold amount,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4613EBC3B5FB45188C53562996BEF47D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">6 percent of so much of the net value of all taxable assets of the taxpayer as exceed the product of 100 multiplied by the threshold amount but do not exceed the product of 1,000 multiplied by the threshold amount, plus</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8225A1AB32F247E48C92BE999CD49CEF"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">8 percent of so much of the net value of all taxable assets of the taxpayer as exceed the product of 1,000 multiplied by the threshold amount.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H628BD4E079144C23853EDFB2E19E1BFF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Trusts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a trust, the tax imposed by this section shall be equal to 8 percent of so much of the net value of all taxable assets of the taxpayer as exceed the threshold amount.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H43D531F80C7E4AE0A7F3B153953D9D51"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicable taxpayer</header><paragraph id="H7AA246D6D8F54D208916537BC5324609"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>applicable taxpayer</term> means any individual or any trust (other than a trust described in section 401(a) and exempt from tax under section 501(a)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC40ADC8C73E4906BB81A84CE4738A53"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of married individuals</header><text>For purposes of this section, individuals who are married (as defined in section 7703) shall be treated as one applicable taxpayer.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB4F91B04E3F14988B9A34FD58ED7BE5C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Threshold amount</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>threshold amount</quote> means the amount that is the product of 1,000 multiplied by the greater of—</text><paragraph id="H3295B5BB769E4DD8AF86BAB3AD59C967"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$50,000, or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC90F35598DFA4A5985DFBB69A7F8E311"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the applicable median household wealth.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA00E50C4FC35447AB013A60D2DC8DEAE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applicable median household wealth</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall annually determine the median household wealth with respect to the United States for purposes of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD6CD57D126BA48979B2BE66E617DD077"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Application to trusts</header><paragraph id="H53B1AC168C864AF3AD46016604FB54CC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Attribution of assets in trust</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining the assets of a taxpayer for purposes of subsection (a):</text><subparagraph id="HF1BA791413E74EE9BD4B47DFC9B5A57B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Grantor trust</header><text>In the case of a grantor trust, the grantor shall be treated as holding all the assets of the trust.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAB05B9E2300462CB21947C93598F31D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Beneficiary trust</header><text>In the case of a beneficiary trust, each beneficiary of the trust shall be treated as holding a fraction of the assets of the trust in proportion to such beneficiary’s interest in such trust.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD14D2E28C0A444B0AE2A95D5D6576816" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Property of trusts</header><text>Any asset treated as held by a grantor or beneficiary under paragraph (1) shall not be treated as held by the trust for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA24F26E3D3B741459171706141B83CED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Trusts relating to common beneficiaries</header><text>Trusts benefitting substantially the same beneficiaries shall be treated as a single applicable taxpayer for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15BA6DA567F742B3B891C779DD76714E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section:</text><subparagraph id="H0330191D86A04D3BBBD5961714292C97"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Grantor trust</header><text>The term <quote>grantor trust</quote> means a trust in which a taxpayer is treated as owning an asset of the trust under subpart E of part I of subchapter J of chapter 1.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE15F19BDB6614842BCD7F1E1C9512846"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Beneficiary trust</header><text>The term <quote>beneficiary trust</quote> means any trust that is not a grantor trust.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6880A223153A49EAA664BB8BB976D5DF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including—</text><paragraph id="H6403E5323AD84213A303AA590289D69C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>regulations establishing a process by which a beneficiary may demonstrate the portion of such beneficiary’s interest in a trust, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4343103E7B064DEF9E5C5CB157ECE592"><enum>(2)</enum><text>regulations for determining the appropriate attribution of assets in a trust for purposes of subsection (e)(1) in the case of a trust with multiple grantors.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H01C2F76B4F774068B98E8162BE7F0EC8"><enum>2902.</enum><header>Net value of taxable assets</header><subsection id="H514D388909E34DC69518542E79E87C7A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this subtitle, the term <term>net value of all taxable assets</term> means, as of any date, the excess of—</text><paragraph id="H12BBA535A059449DBBF24217C3B41D69"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the value of all property of the taxpayer (other than property excluded under subsection (b)), real or personal, tangible or intangible, wherever situated, over</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64230E232CFB4540A1B46C9BB98BB8EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any debts (including any debts secured by property excluded under subsection (b)) owed by the taxpayer.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C989E34F4E94F618D2B67922AEFF255" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exclusion for certain assets under $50,000</header><text>Property of the taxpayer shall not be taken into account under subsection (a) if such property—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H4977D763312244B8B17F815728E9AFCE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has a value of $50,000 or less (determined without regard to any debt owed by the taxpayer with respect to such property),</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEAEED761A143434BB210EDF9042E1351"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is tangible personal property, and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H36FC27222A224DF99DA127E59E2E8025"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is not property—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC7B52F7427C841938A1983C9D228C0A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which is used in a trade or business of the taxpayer,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1E02919D640145B0AD0F4E3845D6662D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in connection with which a deduction is allowable under section 212, or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H189E5AEC6062410EA895BF2C14A96871"><enum>(C)</enum><text>which is a collectible as defined in section 408(m), a boat, an aircraft, a mobile home, a trailer, a vehicle, or an antique or other asset that maintains or increases its value over time (within the meaning of section 5.02(2) of Revenue Procedure 2018–08).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H95F7A6B2FD654BAEBC258246427F022A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rules for determining property of the taxpayer</header><text>For purposes of this subtitle:</text><paragraph id="H2D0AFE2658FC44728CC789E116897432"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Property included in estate</header><text>Any property that would be included in the estate of the taxpayer if the taxpayer died shall be treated as property of the taxpayer.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8E01E336599A4698AA8A498DE06404C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion of certain gifts</header><text>Any property transferred by the taxpayer after the date of the enactment of this chapter, to an individual who is a member of the family of the taxpayer (as determined under section 267(c)(4)) and has not attained the age of 18 shall be treated as property of the taxpayer for any calendar year before the year in which such individual attains the age of 18.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD13187FEBE4B4E5796E2E64DAB445C6F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Establishment of valuation rules</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall establish rules and methods for determining the value of any asset for purposes of this subtitle, including rules for the valuation of assets that are not publicly traded or that do not have a readily ascertainable value. Such rules and methods—</text><paragraph id="HF7E67FAA09524BC09492A207716C389F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may utilize retrospective and prospective formulaic valuation methods not currently in use by the Secretary, </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2731C859891F44F686CE8E7214FA8135"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may require the use of formulaic valuation approaches for designated assets, including formulaic approaches based on proxies for determining presumptive valuations, formulaic approaches based on prospective adjustments from purchase prices or other prior events, or formulaic approaches based on retrospectively adding deferral charges based on eventual sale prices or other specified later events indicative of valuation, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AE995AA607F4B5B85245050B4DFEB21"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may address the use of valuation discounts.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE14F7F8A180C405587B1E1ECE8E27A99"><enum>2903.</enum><header>Special rules</header><subsection id="H79AA1933DC824F00AB58C5FEF459F432"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deceased individuals</header><paragraph id="H5C5BEDEA4D3944138B4DF62F345A8AB7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any individual who dies during a calendar year and who is not married on the date of such individual's death—</text><subparagraph id="HA23C72EC2C094065B6FCF3D419F91D8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 2901 shall be applied by substituting <quote>the date of the applicable taxpayer's death</quote> for <quote>the last day of any calendar year</quote>, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDCABAB835974B80B9FF9667F8E0B9FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount of the tax imposed under such section shall be reduced by an amount which bears the same ratio to such amount (determined without regard to this subsection) as—</text><clause id="HBA1DD17F94F046F19AFF44CDD9BDD343"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of days in the calendar year after the date of the individual's death, bears to</text></clause><clause id="H75C74E2C1813470D867C6364C933ECB1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>365.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8ADBED5C3CE440C8879208F9DE05560"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination with estate tax</header><text>For purposes of section 2053, the tax imposed by this section for the year of the decedent's death shall be considered to have been imposed before such death.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC8E3CE05E0F943C6B4C2784B39387BE9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application to non-Residents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any nonresident alien individual, this subtitle shall apply only to the property of such individual which is situated in the United States (determined under rules similar to the rules under subchapter B of chapter 11).</text></subsection><subsection id="H8D69B4EF659E4BF3B5B710D45FE3C11C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application to covered expatriates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual who is a covered expatriate (as defined in section 877A), section 2901(a) shall be applied as if the calendar year ended on the day before the expatriation.</text></subsection></section><section id="H824053C1699646A0B757C3CB04F5EFC5"><enum>2904.</enum><header>Information reporting</header><subsection id="HF5FC2AD4AAEC42029C5076A479F81BD7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall by regulation require the reporting of any information concerning the net value of assets appropriate to enforce the tax imposed by this chapter.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1B4BF43C7A2148DAB0F2A163BF36B3C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Method of reporting</header><text>The Secretary shall, where appropriate, require the reporting made under subsection (a) to be made as a part of existing income reporting requirements (including requirements under chapter 4 (relating to taxes to enforce reporting on certain foreign accounts)).</text></subsection><subsection id="H677A644DB5AF4543B2A44E0F1ACB90E3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibility for reporting</header><text>The Secretary may impose reporting obligations by reference to the ownership, control, management, claim to income from, or other relationship to assets and liabilities for purposes of administering the tax imposed by this section and may impose such obligations on financial institutions, business entities, or other persons, including requiring business entities to provide estimates of the value of the entity itself. </text></subsection></section><section id="H11C78C8081E2441AB0CE369CFCCD4E29"><enum>2905.</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall annually audit not less than 30 percent of taxpayers required to pay the tax imposed under this chapter.</text></section></chapter></subtitle><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H20FD686CE21348FC9B604FED5F1FABBE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No deduction from income taxes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 275 of such Code is amended by inserting after paragraph (6) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99C3105028814ED4A52DB3D81D54D456"><paragraph commented="no" id="HD7076617B1104C1396727F6B5E4401B8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Taxes imposed by chapter 18.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H23EE5E8EB40A4A7DBBA68CF00AEE542F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Extension of time for payment of tax</header><paragraph id="H864CA216890B484AB03AFD5725CD5C33"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6161(a) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="HE7469A7AD5FD4E828EBD68EA58C37C3A" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HBDE26B0FD44842F099C9F6A48A9B9F02"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Wealth tax</header><subparagraph id="H4EF94FB6F01F4398B4BFA54E4B0BA319"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an applicable taxpayer described in subparagraph (B), the Secretary may extend the time for payment of the tax imposed under chapter 18 for a reasonable period not to exceed 5 years from the date fixed for the payment thereof.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDACBF8E4A7F49F6A8F7947730E5D3F2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Taxpayers described</header><text>An applicable taxpayer is described in this subparagraph if such the Secretary determines—</text><clause id="HE57413B7CEF7420F84EC71E34451798B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the applicable taxpayer has severe liquidity constraints, or </text></clause><clause id="H45706D24AB94469F848E457DAD534CCE" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>immediate payment would cause undue hardship on an ongoing enterprise.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2DDFE9FA3BDD46C8858752F7997419A3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Applicable taxpayer</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>applicable taxpayer</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2901.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H24D0FC9AC66A43C8BEB99A93ED8897DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rules</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary's delegate) shall establish rules for the application of the amendments made by paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8CA68F0247B74020AFA43CEB45BD3C1A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application of accuracy related penalties</header><paragraph id="H8BFC4CCB091F4F2EB4380BBE80CD411A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6662(b) of such Code is amended by inserting after paragraph (10) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H42671CF1D17B4CD2B807355D43BE28A2"><paragraph id="HBA7C698A582D4ED6808B24CD45238341"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Any substantial wealth tax valuation understatement.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D9D4ADB122E40D1A65CBA9DBEC535A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Substantial wealth tax understatement</header><text>Section 6662 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33797222AB494EB18C267880872EE87D"><subsection id="H13FDBCF7080648998E4F4C061D275248"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Application to substantial wealth tax valuation understatement</header><paragraph id="H6F684E37A4D943A8A60A391A652960D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Substantial wealth tax valuation understatement defined</header><subparagraph id="H3BAF726538874FD4B35E5BEDA635FF02"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, there is a substantial wealth tax valuation understatement if the value of any property claimed on any return of tax is 65 percent or less of the amount determined to be the correct amount of such valuation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FAC487CF7844865A17D444252AB9A93"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>No penalty shall be imposed by reason of subsection (b)(11) unless the portion of the underpayment attributable to substantial wealth tax valuation understatements for the calendar year exceeds $5,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BE9A2C0C0394E86A32A4D358A734D8A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Increased penalty</header><subparagraph id="H876D96AA67A640B7AA8E2697458C9F72"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any portion of an underpayment which is attributable to one or more substantial wealth tax valuation understatement, subsection (a) shall be applied—</text><clause id="H0B10D75B5FB444289483ECFC5C745D38"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a substantial wealth tax valuation understatement which is a gross wealth tax valuation misstatement, by substituting <quote>50 percent</quote> for <quote>20 percent</quote>, and</text></clause><clause id="H53B60E228C2C44B0B6229C57F0748114"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in any other case, by substituting <quote>30 percent</quote> for <quote>20 percent</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6A0B171DA764130A0CB63D2CE515349"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Gross wealth tax valuation misstatement</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <term>gross wealth tax valuation misstatement</term> means a substantial wealth tax valuation understatement, as determined under paragraph (1) by substituting <quote>40 percent</quote> for <quote>65 percent</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0FA3E852DEC24D6989FE3F685F23C64D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exemption of tax-Exempt entities</header><text>Section 501(a) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>and subtitle B–1</quote> after <quote>this subtitle</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H24DF36F88A264528900F1E1BDB10CE97"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of subtitles of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to subtitle B the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD7C26C5DA9024707A869A71284F7D9E7"><toc><toc-entry level="subtitle">Subtitle B–1—Wealth tax</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H5C563572F7F94555A2FF0E3F4DD4F28E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to calendar years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

