<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELT25812-CVL-R8-SLJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2395 IS: Mid-South Oilseed Double Cropping Study Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2395</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Federal Crop Insurance Act to require the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation to conduct research and development on the inclusion of certain oilseed crops in double cropping policies, and for other purposes. </official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mid-South Oilseed Double Cropping Study Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id15df4222629a4b62b725ee0d2f838cb0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on inclusion of certain oilseed crops under double and rotational cropping policies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 522(c) of the Federal Crop Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1522">7 U.S.C. 1522(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf0edde173247482eaf759fd959217aa7"><paragraph id="ide0fb53748f564bc0ae2015520635f500"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Double cropping and rotational cropping of certain oilseed crops</header><subparagraph id="id8ad725485b8c49e2a8ce3d003f5a9b4a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definition of covered oilseed crops</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>covered oilseed crops</term> means rapeseed and canola crops that—</text><clause id="idc4caabe7497140d5bc201bef2d62fe9f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>require a period of cold temperature (vernalization) before the crops will produce flowers and seeds; and</text></clause><clause id="id36d0d24328964c13adfb40a4fb8f0fb7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are planted and harvested on land that would otherwise be idle in a rotation pattern.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id55bd3c7eae354fd48244d04d5a9caf57"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Research and development</header><text>The Corporation shall carry out research and development, or offer to enter into 1 or more contracts with 1 or more qualified persons to carry out research and development, with respect to the inclusion of covered oilseed crops under double cropping and rotational cropping policies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfde52701cbc746e1a4502d62e7c0e3c8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The research and development carried out pursuant to subparagraph (B) shall be conducted in consultation with stakeholders to evaluate—</text><clause id="id764c03accd5444a6b7cbc0345dd4b5e9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the factors impacting availability and cost of crop insurance when incorporating covered oilseed crops into double cropping and rotational cropping policies; and</text></clause><clause id="idba53ce77149346958074acf90fb7cede"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the potential risk management benefits associated with incorporating covered oilseed crops into double cropping and rotational cropping policies, including risk management benefits to soil health, biodiversity, and the profitability of farming operations.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id29f23dbc61414bda81b0d59a7ac909e5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Emphasis</header><text>In awarding contracts under subparagraph (B), the Corporation may place emphasis on qualified persons and institutions that—</text><clause id="id3e6d0288ad2441c6b95ab59f25ff91fb"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have previous research experience with covered oilseed crops; and</text></clause><clause id="idfada9ae37e134192af0f2bac27ef349b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have access to a facility with the capacity to carry out the applicable research.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd2366c24abe94e068aafb5244bea557a"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 13 months after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Corporation shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives a report that describes—</text><clause id="id2e4187773ed14c7791695e8e5e915e2b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the results of the research and development carried out under subparagraph (B); and</text></clause><clause id="id43b1353e0247457e8a139b8fdced1486"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any recommendations with respect to those results.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

