<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6EB40F617D3C4296B68428093B3C30A5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 971 IH: Reducing Accidents In Locomotives Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 971</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250204">February 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="R000619">Mr. Rulli</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enhance safety requirements for trains transporting hazardous materials, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H972E1D64EDAF42A0988B64B45ACD3718" style="OLC"><section id="H70D37A577DC84F0191619591E6336CBE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H5C5EB64F9CEB4352BC2918C3B9006B35"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reducing Accidents In Locomotives Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RAIL Act</short-title></quote>. </text></subsection><subsection id="H447E8EA3C8934DB18A3CD277F3F8ADB7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H70D37A577DC84F0191619591E6336CBE" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5E4DE177B8D54EF5A6C2E21AAD7F2BB4" level="section">Sec. 2. Defined term.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HCF57A492D7BD49929547838CB6DD3016" level="section">Sec. 3. Recommendations for safety.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H8442E4B167B04A869A4E87EDDE7D5109" level="section">Sec. 4. Inspections.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HCF4483B0356E449789DD8976CD94F735" level="section">Sec. 5. Defect detectors.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HFA4D89874CDA4A6291171149286D3945" level="section">Sec. 6. Increasing maximum civil penalties for violations of rail safety regulations.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HDAC6467F04234D6592F14D45508A5D76" level="section">Sec. 7. Safer tank cars.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HBE33E52CDBCD490492193A92D989797C" level="section">Sec. 8. Hazardous materials training for first responders.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H264CBC62C1EB4814B7A76A0074A2ED40" level="section">Sec. 9. Freight train crew size safety standards.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="H5E4DE177B8D54EF5A6C2E21AAD7F2BB4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Defined term</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text></section><section id="HCF57A492D7BD49929547838CB6DD3016"><enum>3.</enum><header>Recommendations for safety</header><subsection id="HCEC3FDDC08C74A0095DF3C8610A67C8D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the National Transportation Safety Board issues the report on the East Palestine, Ohio crash, the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration, shall issue regulations, or modify existing regulations, based on such report establishing safety requirements, in accordance with subsection (b), with which a rail carrier operating a train transporting hazardous materials that is not subject to the requirements for a high-hazard flammable train under section 174.310 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, shall comply with respect to the operation of each such train and the maintenance of specification tank cars.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4355C053551A42F9A2C1ECDAA48C8FF5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The regulations issued pursuant to subsection (a) shall require rail carriers—</text><paragraph id="H37479E5D555E4059971BF51FBE1CB14C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide advance notification and information regarding the transportation of hazardous materials described in subsection (a) to each State emergency response commissioner, the tribal emergency response commission, or any other State or tribal agency responsible for receiving the information notification for emergency response planning information;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14B80B2518A543D08A637103015DD954"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to include, in the notification provided pursuant to paragraph (1), a written gas discharge plan with respect to the applicable hazardous materials being transported; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H269A8F8F5A39412A9E776BA14AF80A9E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to reduce or eliminate blocked crossings resulting from delays in train movements.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H313F4E7721794F2287E36D9B4C10040A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the regulations required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall include requirements regarding—</text><paragraph id="H19729B378D384E5F9EDE616B8A799FCC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>train length and weight;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC161AB4BB056443F977E6E34A1D82EBA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>train consist;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76F72D611D834C9485C5E67E4CC5715E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>route analysis and selection;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H437D844A35434E5BAD7FF3C5ED7C7B82"><enum>(4)</enum><text>speed restrictions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB1133EDE8CD462693BE07F22ACC81B0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>track standards;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H886CEF826E34485E92A1F837DF54FCD6"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">track, bridge, and rail car maintenance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F6563B62FB44130A3B589E0D2F45BEE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>signaling and train control; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47A2879170FD40EA97E58FD053EBAA69"><enum>(8)</enum><text>response plans.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8442E4B167B04A869A4E87EDDE7D5109"><enum>4.</enum><header>Inspections</header><subsection id="H922D50A440E745728A1287B796E06395"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Time available for inspection</header><paragraph id="H12145FCDEE5E4075B387AB7154AA7841"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H3AEA492AE5B84C838A6C1B986C404E00" style="USC"><section id="HCB7E5B9C0C5F40C08FC29E99E28C9B19"><enum>20172.</enum><header>Time available for inspection</header><subsection id="H23164E9022E3466A8B11F73C41D4D8B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No railroad may limit the time required for an employee to complete a railcar, locomotive, or brake inspection to ensure that each railcar, locomotive, and brake system complies with safety laws and regulations.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7545273891294D4B8054D25B1F147249"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Employees shall perform their inspection duties promptly and shall not delay other than for reasons related to safety.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BA730F8682F4A77A455E848B7423244"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H96FA68C4CE284F92B2A92705541CAB78" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">20172. Time available for inspection.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA1CA4E24BF0D44EDA9C48D364EA4A484"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pre-Departure railcar inspections</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall amend the pre-departure inspection requirements for Class I railroads under part 215 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (as written on such date of enactment)—</text><paragraph id="H658FEA33A1494554AD39F2D91B66FF32"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to ensure that after initial consultation with the Federal Railroad Administration, and after each subsequent annual consultation, each railroad identifies inspection locations and, at such locations, has inspectors designated under part 215 available for the purpose of inspecting freight cars;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13AA1F08FC414BC2B4F5A85D647E33BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to ensure that all freight cars are inspected by an inspector designated under part 215 at a designated inspection location in the direction of travel as soon as practicable; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE8C7A13F14C46DC82DA60F464B1B658"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to require each railroad that operates railroad freight cars to which such part 215 applies to designate persons qualified to inspect railroad freight rail cars, subject to any existing collective bargaining agreement, for compliance and determinations required under such part.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1E9C35A42FA9423EA768E7648A8026E5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified locomotive inspections</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall review and amend, as necessary, regulations under chapters 229 and 243 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations—</text><paragraph id="HDBE8087A317A497CB72A1A6965A1C1C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to ensure appropriate training qualifications and proficiency of employees, including qualified mechanical inspectors, performing locomotive inspections; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF5D402C60A9461AAD56D66D163FC0FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for locomotives in service on a Class I railroad, to require an additional daily inspection to be performed by a qualified mechanical inspector between the current intervals under section 229.23(b)(2) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBC5BDDC98481468094D0E7ECBF04B101"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Audits</header><paragraph id="H836414E5400C4C41851B185C34A47BF6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall initiate audits of Federal railcar, locomotive, and train brake system inspection compliance with chapter II of subtitle B of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, which—</text><subparagraph id="H4FADAD09747B412CB40D563F9A3CA52C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider whether the railroad has in place procedures necessary for railcar, locomotive, and train brake system inspection compliance under such chapter;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2255E25877604F4C90F7823674C19DA8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assess the type, content, and adequacy of training and performance metrics the railroad provides employees who perform railcar, locomotive, and train brake system inspections, including the qualifications specified for such employees;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAF3DC5BB8B44162A446EE3201612FB9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>determine whether the railroad has practices that would interfere with an employee’s responsibility to perform an inspection safely;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C2AC1D3F3F24FD08E31603EFB30BCFA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>determine whether railcars, locomotives, and train brake systems are inspected on the railroad’s network in accordance with such chapter;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE97F1E88CA2C41D7A4817062F8AFFBCF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>involve proper communication of identified defects to railroad personnel and make appropriate use of remedial action reports to verify that repairs are made;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00356B66B25B4042A9B46F801E5E9271"><enum>(F)</enum><text>determine whether managers coerce employees to sign off on any documents verifying an inspection or repair of a railcar, locomotive, or train brake system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9F496C2AD444955BD81EE40DA5EE471"><enum>(G)</enum><text>determine whether the railroad’s inspection procedures reflect the current operating practices of the railroad carrier; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72CCEAD30A424C239B0BC6D6D465BEE4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>ensure that railroad inspection procedures only provide for the use of persons permitted to perform each relevant inspection under such chapter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B024A6AC42247A7AD633013B8F734CA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Audit scheduling</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H86B32A08A54840719B521F6F45BB2665"><enum>(A)</enum><text>schedule the audits required under paragraph (1) to ensure that—</text><clause id="HE91F090063F743D1BCC571DFC0F29E93"><enum>(i)</enum><text>every Class I railroad is audited not less frequently than once every 5 years; and</text></clause><clause id="H31F9A1093D5F415F8EF90EB3FAD33D5A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a limited number, as determined by the Secretary, of Class II and Class III railroads are audited annually, provided that—</text><subclause id="H88C44071078547F38593266BEE075B61"><enum>(I)</enum><text>no audit of a tourist, scenic, historic, or excursion operation may be required under this subsection; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H5AE59085CC844F678EF2675E6F6DBC42"><enum>(II)</enum><text>no other Class II or III railroad may be audited more frequently than once every 5 years; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA2BB6F45D8F4E9DB626ACB035D61824"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conduct the audits described in subparagraph (A)(ii) in accordance with—</text><clause id="HD32AEE06E06B4020BEAA59B389C3EB00"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Small Business Regulatory Enforcement Fairness Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note); and</text></clause><clause id="HD20D858563E24B34A6C2535C5303576D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>appendix C of part 209 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AD7BE7BF407451EB1C2A89FD88E709A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Updates to inspection program and procedures</header><text>If, during an audit required under this subsection, the auditor identifies a deficiency in a railroad’s procedures or practices necessary to ensure compliance with chapter II of subtitle B of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, the railroad shall eliminate such deficiency, after first being provided the opportunity to address whether such a deficiency exists.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0FFC47E3E8A4645A85C74BF35EA8EFC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation and cooperation</header><subparagraph id="HFF1ADFEA93534472B11552BCE4F838EB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In conducting any audit required under this subsection, the Secretary shall consult with the railroad being audited and its employees, including any nonprofit employee labor organization representing the employees of the railroad that conduct railcar, locomotive, or train brake system inspections.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEEBA92C02914698B99967D50285ECB2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Cooperation</header><text>The railroad being audited and its employees, including any nonprofit employee labor organization representing mechanical employees, shall fully cooperate with any audit conducted pursuant to this subsection—</text><clause id="H28ACD17003834DA78355B17AB2340FA3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by providing any relevant documents requested; and</text></clause><clause id="H63B0D510BCDD4560B076125140225F73"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by making available any employees for interview without undue delay or obstruction.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC679F06E5104F5AACEF79E80DE428E3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Failure to cooperate</header><text>If the Secretary determines that a railroad or any of its employees, including any nonprofit employee labor organization representing mechanical employees of the railroad is not fully cooperating with an audit conducted pursuant to this subsection, the Secretary shall electronically notify the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives of such noncooperation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0F981ABC920A4F198A9CE034EEC2C1B0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Review of regulations</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and periodically thereafter, the Secretary shall determine whether any update to chapters I and II of subtitle B of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, is necessary to ensure the adequacy of railcar, locomotive, and train brake system inspections.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAB271F71C8C246D38F9A477DB61F2885"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The Secretary shall publish an annual report on the public website of the Federal Railroad Administration that—</text><paragraph id="HE8628532598E49969947B9EB56079529"><enum>(1)</enum><text>summarizes the findings of the audits conducted pursuant to subsection (c) during the most recently concluded fiscal year;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C70AB7FCCF44E68B5948CDDE65C9AD1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>summarizes any updates made to chapter I or II of subtitle B of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, pursuant to this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DE51F914C374729969D071DF5A59523"><enum>(3)</enum><text>excludes any confidential business information or sensitive security information.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFDA93CEA4B754DC4B2EA6D2D33DF1B0F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed—</text><paragraph id="H048D11B94A6D432A82ECFF8114D88AA1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide the Secretary with any authority to interpret, revise, alter, or apply a collectively bargained agreement, nor any authority over collective bargaining, collectively bargained agreements, or any aspect of the Railway Labor Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/151">45 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85EB718E2AF5472FAB700CB3A540B524"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to alter the terms or interpretations of existing collective bargaining agreements; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F9058C6274C45CE9EF2DDA3567D90C6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to abridge any procedural rights or remedies provided under a collectively bargained agreement.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCF4483B0356E449789DD8976CD94F735"><enum>5.</enum><header>Defect detectors</header><subsection id="H58AEFBA74E1349778312C0C267ECDDE2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue regulations establishing requirements for the installation, repair, testing, maintenance, and operation of wayside defect detectors for each rail carrier operating a train consist carrying hazardous materials.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCE36529364624B2184169A665E867B97"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The regulations issued pursuant to subsection (a) shall include requirements regarding—</text><paragraph id="H4FD4A8D4A65E458BB16A160186B9E8C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the frequency of the placement of wayside defect detectors, including a requirement that all Class I railroads install a hotbox detector along every 10-mile segment of rail track over which trains carrying hazardous materials operate; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H796B3B30E11E45EE8BBEF654DFCD5EEC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>performance standards for such detectors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F0356E8A2CF46E39D917EEC1F055B39"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the maintenance and repair requirements for such detectors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51C0BD41DB274AD498D874A10F0F1E91"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reporting data and maintenance records of such detectors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D5479017321414D8CE24EFD5BD41D32"><enum>(5)</enum><text>appropriate steps the rail carrier must take when receiving an alert of a defect or failure from or regarding a wayside defect detector; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93F850149BA44590911A1DA37C95DD37"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the use of hotbox detectors to prevent derailments from wheel bearing failures, including—</text><subparagraph id="H85109B791F7E40BC89CBF932EA808071"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the temperatures, to be specified by the Secretary, at which an alert from a hotbox detector is triggered to warn of a potential wheel bearing failure; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5F71FAC51F845D1B16C7EACEC885815"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any actions that shall be taken by a rail carrier upon receiving an alert from a hotbox detector of a potential wheel bearing failure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB52A9AFA939D483F98E183B35241344E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Defect and failure identification</header><text>The Secretary shall specify the categories of defects and failures that wayside defect detectors covered by regulations issued pursuant to subsection (a) shall address, including—</text><paragraph id="H897028B05FE5437490EB5B609B8EF992"><enum>(1)</enum><text>axles;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D14622942CA4F1FB0AB3FF845C33F3B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>wheel bearings;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA46601812C15418F997CF88FF65F425A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>brakes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD27ABA4E666D4C7487462A5D91A06B5B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>signals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7A5B577B2544880ADE55573A2E7E55B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>wheel impacts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94F45975DB1240A79F7019080F858C25"><enum>(6)</enum><text>other defects or failures specified by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED6791AE60514516A12681A3B6F2103D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Safety placards</header><paragraph id="HBF834122D26F4614B1A0ABB1F2B7963D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In issuing regulations under subsection (a), the Secretary shall require that placards covered under section 172.519 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, be able to withstand heat in excess of 180 degrees. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DBF637639954331A7FE417CB11D97BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Update based on recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may, upon recommendation from the National Transportation Safety Board, issue such regulations as are necessary to increase the heat threshold described in paragraph (1). </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA4D89874CDA4A6291171149286D3945"><enum>6.</enum><header>Increasing maximum civil penalties for violations of rail safety regulations</header><subsection id="H8DD7EC8CDF9C442C849071A98E044FA5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Civil penalties related to transporting hazardous materials</header><text>Section 5123(a) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HA6FDE5B2D8834BF096C37252D432EADD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>$75,000</quote> and inserting <quote>the greater of 0.5 percent of the person's annual income or annual operating income or $750,000</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H230973B469A5413B83B5ED6ED259C8F2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>$175,000</quote> and inserting <quote>the greater of 1 percent of the person's annual income or annual operating income or $1,750,000</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBD4963115AF14AEBB63604B0820A3F34"><enum>(b)</enum><header>General violations of chapter 201</header><text>Section 21301(a)(2) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H05927A03FFC6427D813B4421AA29BB5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$25,000.</quote> and inserting <quote>the greater of 0.5 percent of the person's annual income or annual operating income or $250,000</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B4802653D0545B2B444C03FACBE8B6D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$100,000.</quote> and inserting <quote>the greater of 1 percent of the person's annual income or annual operating income or $1,000,000</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H91AE9F4EC3014FE8A5865ACC03E3B9A2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Accident and incident violations of chapter 201; violations of chapters 203 through 209</header><text>Section 21302(a) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H62438864F2D2400F8E45EC2539901DA0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>203–209</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>203 through 209</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC916AE0CCF084C9188118708DBAF1CCD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1EE115610C224FC88CF7F9011DC04358"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>$25,000</quote> and inserting <quote>the greater of 0.5 percent of the person's annual income or annual operating income or $250,000</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36419834D8E5436E807DD10F736E1F7C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$100,000</quote> and inserting <quote>the greater of 1 percent of the person's annual income or annual operating income or $1,000,000</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H43D6587BE08B4968B391525B1D763E38"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Violations of chapter 211</header><text>Section 21303(a)(2) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H470333C6CE2043368DAD1B6362DCCDA0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$25,000.</quote> and inserting <quote>the greater of 0.5 percent of the person's annual income or annual operating income or $250,000</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02C00760AF314190845E1E28D252AC73"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$100,000.</quote> and inserting <quote>the greater of 1 percent of the person's annual income or annual operating income or $1,000,000</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDAC6467F04234D6592F14D45508A5D76" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header>Safer tank cars</header><subsection id="HFA9762CF8AF043B9BE452F1728E85000"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Phase-Out schedule</header><text>Beginning on May 1, 2030, a rail carrier may not use DOT–111 specification railroad tank cars that do not comply with DOT–117, DOT–117P, or DOT–117R specification requirements, as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act, to transport Class 3 flammable liquids regardless of the composition of the train consist.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4F2283DAA0AB4EAE9F2DA98A850C942D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming regulatory amendments</header><paragraph id="H59DFBF79E5104554BAB484BF8839256B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="H4A22CDC66A43477EAC561553E7972142"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall immediately remove or revise the date-specific deadlines in any applicable regulations or orders to the extent necessary to conform with the requirement under subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC3325BB91054D00B6AB852E6BD68B8D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not enforce any date-specific deadlines or requirements that are inconsistent with the requirement under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H006FD581C06941B4B514474CDBC54ADE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Except as required under paragraph (1), nothing in this section may be construed to require the Secretary to issue regulations to implement this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBE33E52CDBCD490492193A92D989797C"><enum>8.</enum><header>Hazardous materials training for first responders</header><subsection id="HCEB4473FC78A4A3F8D174C59E989CC20"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual registration fee</header><text>Section 5108(g) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4CA2849236E54961AA72B54719831346"><paragraph id="HBC699706C85B4860AE62FD77D201BFEA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Additional fee for class I rail carriers</header><text>In addition to the fees collected pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2), the Secretary shall establish and annually impose and collect from each Class I rail carrier a fee in an amount equal to $1,000,000.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H59B61CD4D70743CE8A0A0C15F598E492"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assistance for local emergency response training</header><text>Section 5116(j)(1)(A) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC42C7DBF424342AC960F71F8228ACC95"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>liquids</quote> and inserting <quote>materials</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H130C0521E90D4C02B0F6578DBD2E1AD4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3), by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H817DB60551D24FD7855DCC687A1F38A8"><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E873A7A72B240F1976D84D4821DF873"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out the grant program established pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary may expend, during each fiscal year—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCAD1FDDF6CDA402CA61DAF98591D5428"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amounts collected pursuant to section 5108(g)(4); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE3EC53D8BA444F5BE9BEEFDCB8EC7AC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any amounts recovered during such fiscal year from grants awarded under this section during a prior fiscal year.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF17BB731B5304745BDAB12D98335BD09"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Supplemental training grants</header><text>Section 5128(b)(4) of title 49, United States Code is amended by striking <quote>$2,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$4,000,000</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="H264CBC62C1EB4814B7A76A0074A2ED40"><enum>9.</enum><header>Freight train crew size safety standards</header><subsection id="H2B278A58F9244A86A9C221C484CA61C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Freight train crew size</header><text>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/20153">section 20153</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block id="H9DDC0BEFF3A64E5DA607E4EABAC8D63A" style="USC"><section id="H0F9266EDCDA14F759C96C85AB28B2372"><enum>20154.</enum><header>Freight train crew size safety standards</header><subsection id="HB17275A82B65403B835EE693D6CA5221"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Minimum crew size</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), no Class I railroad carrier may operate a freight train without a 2-person crew consisting of at least 1 appropriately qualified and certified conductor and 1 appropriately qualified and certified locomotive engineer.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE6FAC085B6C648CA80B1CCC04D8E035C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="H459BE477DBBD4A3FA7B97EF0D0F6FC03"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the requirement under subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="H9C4885632D774C17A8C692F71D616964"><enum>(A)</enum><text>train operations on track that is not main line track;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E644DED123B453D90CEEF53549CA75C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>locomotives performing assistance to a train that has incurred mechanical failure or lacks the power to traverse difficult terrain, including traveling to or from the location where assistance is provided;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D019F6025E64EC98DD45D0B620201F2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>locomotives that—</text><clause id="H36230423E40F4DA495E3B47400E61C11"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are not attached to any equipment or are attached only to a caboose; and</text></clause><clause id="H9A127D6218D748DE81D0965D229C9F8D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>travel not farther than 50 miles from the point of origin of such locomotive; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE16A15E175854DD184567BFDBE2F5564"><enum>(D)</enum><text>train operations staffed with fewer than a 2-person crew at least 1 year before the date of the enactment of the Safe Freight Act of 2024, except if the Secretary determines that such operations do not achieve an equivalent level of safety as would result from compliance with the requirement under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF9FC6A2A1AB4AD8B8AA6485271D1C9B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Trains ineligible for exception</header><text>The exceptions under paragraph (2) shall not apply with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="H39DA1DE279F841BBBCEDF08935AE34B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a high-hazard train; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CC5C5D333ED4094AFE5F2FEFA51921E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a train with a total length of at least 7,500 feet.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0652749BB6504C7D9CC974EC939777E9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>A railroad carrier may seek a waiver of the requirements under subsection (a) in accordance with section 20103(d).</text></subsection><subsection id="H23CBCCF6496F4DD9AC22AF6E04AD8780"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H3319EF4CC44E44CE9885EC4205B1A7A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>High-hazard train</header><text>The term <quote>high-hazard train</quote> means a single train transporting, throughout the train consist—</text><subparagraph id="H986AEA9C641C4E9A97E850E5FE714296"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not fewer than 20 tank cars loaded with a flammable liquid (Class 3) (as such term is defined in section 173.120 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulations);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1A79DC6CB8546809575AA77F52ED391"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not fewer than 1 tank car or intermodal portable tank load with a material poisonous by inhalation or a material toxic by inhalation (as such term is defined in section 171.8 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulations);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFD3EFF96533449B9541A9358F423133"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not fewer than 1 car loaded with a type B package or a fissile material package (as such terms are defined in section 173.403 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulations);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89F93CBD2F994F29951AD900F853D4E8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>not fewer than 10 cars loaded with Class 1 explosives categorized under section 173.50 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations) as being in division 1.1, 1.2, or 1.3;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDCF7342C09E45D7BA04A010EF103CD1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>not fewer than 5 tank cars loaded with a flammable gas (as such term is defined in section 173.115(a) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulations); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD32070AACD104AB1830CC8ED54BB88C7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>not fewer than 20 cars loaded with any combination of flammable liquids, flammable gases, or explosives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5644D1D20D99483FAAA7D015A23BD309"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Main line track</header><text>The term <quote>main line track</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H36E88953E90646938F5F9841D34823E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a segment or route of railroad tracks—</text><clause id="HABC3FE7DF35649C294DACC2919596B7D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>over which 5,000,000 or more gross tons of railroad traffic is transported annually; and</text></clause><clause id="H9C39B6966ED0479DAE28F2D5CD497001"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that has a maximum authorized speed for freight trains in excess of 25 miles per hours; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H027090888C434E0D9B5B4BDF9062A5F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>intercity rail passenger transportation or commuter rail passenger transportation routes or segments over which high-hazard trains operate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC4C2F26A81934953A28DEA084E8CA1CE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/20153">section 20153</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block id="H11869B1B70FB47DA9E7C6737E0E3CE16" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">20154. Freight train crew size safety standards.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H570EEA5188414A9E8C03327AD4A54D98"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Preservation of authority of secretary</header><text>Nothing in section 20154 of title 49, United States Code, as added by this section, shall be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary under any other provision of law.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

