<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA25417-CFW-TR-L0Y"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 253 ATS: Congratulating His Holiness Pope Leo XIV on his election to the papacy.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 253</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250522">May 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating His Holiness Pope Leo XIV on his election to the papacy.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Senate recognizes the historic and spiritual significance of the election of His Holiness Pope Leo XIV as the Bishop of Rome and leader of the worldwide Catholic Church;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the Senate recognizes the historic and spiritual significance of the first Pope from the United States ever elected to the papacy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Pope serves as a global symbol of peace, compassion, humility, and the pursuit of justice; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the election of the new Pope marks a moment of profound importance for over 1,000,000,000 Catholics worldwide, including millions in the United States, and for people of all faiths who are inspired by his message and ministry: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id6d3e71af681d4ed1a82fc25383f17fb8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>acknowledges the commitment of His Holiness Pope Leo XIV to promoting human dignity, defending the poor and marginalized, advancing interfaith dialogue, and fostering reconciliation and peace throughout the world; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id445f8f4bcf34482b8df954abb71c6a66"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses the hope that the strong relationship between the United States and The Holy See will continue to deepen, reflecting shared values of human rights, religious freedom, and global cooperation;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96bbe0a9010f486aa4873d08cd041eac"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the significance of the Catholic Church in promoting justice, humanitarian assistance, and moral leadership in the world; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id66f3342e9724462e82a9b97e3a6bd001"><enum>(4)</enum><text>extends its best wishes for a successful and inspiring pontificate.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

