<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7D384FF9252E49BA82DFDDCC96251D46" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3887 IH: SNAP Anti-Theft and Victim Compensation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3887</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250610">June 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 relating to punishment and compensation for the theft of supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits; and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H488A134F2CCD48EAAD9BE4A299ED09B1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H980C7F236C3D4602BB5D44C24FCDA03C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>SNAP Anti-Theft and Victim Compensation Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5888E2CA01FE404AABA6E7F9BDB92292" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expanded investigative authority of the Department of Agriculture Inspector General</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 16 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2025">7 U.S.C. 2025</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8F9CC113DFB049439E84ABF307ADBB27" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H051EB76B5C0A456799DC2B703E646474"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Office of Inspector General coordination authority</header> 
<paragraph id="H11C805A2EC2B42078A537300D697DDCA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General of the Department of Agriculture shall have full authority to investigate and coordinate multi-jurisdictional efforts to prevent, detect, and prosecute theft, misuse, or fraudulent accessing of supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HF39BE2C878A046D8BA8D60EAC96D78E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">investigation of cyber-enabled benefit theft, including skimming, cloning, phishing, spoofing, and unauthorized access to EBT systems; Issuing subpoenas, executing warrants, and initiating civil or criminal referrals;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFEEC45D2E69C4016B76C7FFBF8B434FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issuance of subpoenas, executing warrants, and initiating civil or criminal referrals;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB8D9BB7CDC464A45A24FC501BEAF022E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>coordination with the Department of Justice, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Department of Homeland Security, the Secret Service, State and local law enforcement, and financial institutions;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4E9503E27DFA43B4A0EAF1B9916FCBFE"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requesting and receiving data from State EBT processors and contracted vendors for investigative purposes; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5122F1BDFBAB4196AB045D7EB2A9A77C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>participation in interagency cyber task forces or fraud detection initiatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H91B3D6FAE6374B8987CE6CCB0A8FFAE8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture may issue rules, and allocate funds, necessary to support the activities of the Inspector General under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H4954A1CA86EA40058CEEB3A4D4F19183"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authority to reimburse stolen SNAP benefits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 11 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2020">7 U.S.C. 2020</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H15DC7C99866D438BB0B4B2C475A675A6" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HA56F6E8CE9394DC58C952B2E64B966CD"><enum>(y)</enum><header>Reimbursement for stolen benefits</header><text>.</text> <paragraph id="H553CE02CE6494CEAB6208298C69FB516"><enum>(1)</enum><text>States are authorized to use supplemental nutrition assistance program benefit funds to reimburse households whose benefits are stolen due to no fault of their own, including via skimming, cloning, or other unauthorized electronic transfers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD6216F616F6D4A99A69F5BB7474ADCAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Reimbursement shall be made in accordance with guidance from the Secretary and shall not affect the household’s monthly allotment or ongoing eligibility.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2358932191F24580B40CED4A5F91FE07"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H90926FE05B8040149197360F5B1F5DBD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to States for fraud detection and claims validation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA0C106D7F9314701BAD4E11A7F81EA92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintain a centralized reporting database for benefit theft incidents;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8D3C9D90B52F498AAABE510A402FF2AA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>require States to submit annual data on benefit theft and reimbursements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8EE7ABEC357D4C35BDD84C283F08D6CD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary shall promulgate regulations as necessary to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68AD4BA6EAA24C6CA968DF8ADF4C9F37"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Secretary shall review the necessity of this authority once all States have successfully upgraded to secure payment technologies.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H5801D782D7FF4D1FB493F294AC7769CC"><enum>4.</enum><header>. Civil penalty for theft of SNAP benefits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 15 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2024">7 U.S.C. 2024</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB29D3293AC1B49CAAE6FE43C7925EC51" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HDBF31072B18744F48A2A18F025AD1F3F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Civil penalty for theft of supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits</header><text>.</text> <paragraph id="H2F5FD08B3F384A428EC4EC6EF04D5A78"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any person who knowingly accesses, uses, or transfers supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits issued to household without authorization shall be liable to the United States for a civil penalty in an amount equal to twice the value of the benefits stolen.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA01BEA4587C748898686017D0E08054C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary may assess and enforce this penalty through an administrative proceeding under section 14 or through a civil action in a district court of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H244BDBE4E8394EC0BC966F58E2EFF5FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Funds recovered under this subsection shall be used, as determined by the Secretary, to offset the cost of reimbursing victims of benefit theft and the cost of the enhanced investigatory authority of the Inspector General of the Department of Agriculture.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8F0E2C7C50704133A40BFDAD3FF9DD2E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A civil penalty imposed under this subsection shall be in addition to any other civil or criminal penalty imposed under any other provision of this Act or under any other provision of law.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> </legis-body></bill>

