<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCC01AA44F6DA460EB59F078795E3DCE1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3902 IH: Restoring Federalism in Clean Water Permitting Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3902</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250611">June 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000622">Mr. Patronis</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to review the regulations applicable to the approval of State permit programs under section 404 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H36CAD0988569415FB51CABEEF9CAC16B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAD813F5B756A416FB8669309D73DCB10" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Restoring Federalism in Clean Water Permitting Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7706612A046F4B84981D6CBC2E3309B3"><enum>2.</enum><header>State assumption of section 404 permit program regulation review</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall complete a review of the regulations applicable to the approval of State permit programs under section 404 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>) in order to identify revisions to such regulations necessary to streamline the approval process, reduce administrative burdens, and encourage additional States to administer a permit program under such section, and the Administrator shall implement any such revisions as appropriate.</text></section> 
<section id="H7D5F1BBBED2D4D28B04F9194621CD63B" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Judicial review timeline clarity</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 404 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H535F176C89594885B0954619604E9C50"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (t) as subsection (u);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9146C908FD9846C892281EA1A4734D3E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (u), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>Nothing in the section</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Savings provision.—</header-in-text>Nothing in this section</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC1E9B3D945E4CBD8CDC21D82A02BFF6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (s) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H3B076A2DAD1244A2A7BC7438E377A454" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HDB5BE94308394E2D84A46691CC64A9E5"><enum>(t)</enum><header>Judicial review</header> 
<paragraph id="H3018CF3D67AB4113A8267E76EDC170D9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Statute of limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any applicable provision of law relating to statutes of limitations, an action seeking judicial review of the approval by the Administrator of a State permit program pursuant to this section shall be filed not later than the date that is 60 days after the date on which the approval was issued.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H67409EBAF87E4CAC8E237DF3EEA1DCD2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on commencement of certain actions</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no action described in paragraph (1) may be commenced unless the action—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF7E50DF9B3AD4A6B92A5206B61C4FEFB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is filed by a party that submitted a comment—</text> <clause id="HEA1D81A6AD9C44D08E00D4F749585CCA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>during the public comment period for the administrative proceedings related to such action; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H530194C97DBB4B429456D513871C71F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which was sufficiently detailed to put the Administrator on notice of the issue upon which the party seeks judicial review; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDA57DC70CDA14B32B945636A014A9E9E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is related to such comment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H979B2E1098AB423D83819C4B736E4144"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Remedy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a court determines that the Administrator did not comply with the requirements of this section in issuing an approval of a State permit program pursuant to this section—</text> <subparagraph id="HC027B67A4B4048D1817E9B67AE2EDB63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the court shall remand the matter to the Administrator for further proceedings consistent with the determination of the court; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF127F0F2F2A54CA69232FA529D744834" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the court may not vacate, revoke, enjoin, or otherwise limit the authority of the State to issue permits under such State permit program, unless the court finds that activities authorized under any permit issued under the program would present an imminent and substantial danger to human health or the environment for which there is no other equitable remedy available under the law.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1EFA060C2674861A1ECF9E3571EFBA9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Timeline to act on court order</header><text>If a court remands a matter under paragraph (2), the court shall set and enforce a reasonable schedule and deadline, which may not exceed 180 days from the date on which the court remands such matter, except as otherwise required by law, for the Administrator to take such actions as the court may order.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

