<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF6B12D064AD445B980D3012634B829BE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2788 IH: End Driving While Intoxicated Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2788</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 23, United States Code, to provide for a national standard to prevent driving while intoxicated by requiring ignition interlocks for DWI offenders, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA6639BAA776945C0B0C029A0B18D8012" style="OLC"><section id="H9F54CFE4F18449F4B51AEED43B1F36F5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>End Driving While Intoxicated Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>End DWI Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H94F8FEF709BF411EB2155D9B94F06AE1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HD6A0FAE2E24041B6822E6B4637A61C14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>According to Mothers Against Drunk Driving, there has been a historic increase in alcohol-impaired driving fatalities since 2019 resulting in one person dying in a driving while intoxicated crash in the United States every 39 minutes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H526F7BA6C47B4B79AD6773E164F3041C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>According to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, between 2020 and 2021, driving while intoxicated deaths increased 14 percent and 13,384 people were killed, a level not seen since 2006.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5990AF625C274107856A8DF30B1C7897"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Studies show that ignition interlocks reduce recidivism, by up to 70 percent, among first-time, repeat and high-risk driving while intoxicated offenders while they are installed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0D46CFD69204023B2158ADF56197E51"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Ignition interlocks are required for people who have been convicted for driving while intoxicated in 31 States and the District of Columbia, according to the National Conference of State Legislators.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF74D6071151425FBC9BD285225C8F0A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The rise in polysubstance impaired driving significantly increases the crash risk on our nation’s roads.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF195459D4484430BA129B8CB349EA6AE"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One 2018 study from Washington State revealed that polysubstance impairment was the most common type of impairment found among drivers involved in fatal crashes between 2008 and 2016 and among drivers involved in fatal crashes during this timeframe, 44 percent tested positive for 2 or more substances with alcohol and THC being the most common combination.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5688CA4BDCB647668717FF329AB84A86"><enum>3.</enum><header>National standard for ignition interlocks for DWI offenders</header><subsection id="H74AC266DE0CE4129B4A43AC9B9CC2EBD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/23/1">Chapter 1</external-xref> of title 23, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H9FBBCB97B8DD4A1F903F8B03C0FDC262" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H92246B206CEA420087F66B5C2AFE15CE"><enum>180.</enum><header>National standard for ignition interlocks for DWI offenders</header><subsection id="H3E9C579896C6453F83FD3F2EF47A7A5F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Withholding of apportionments for non-Compliance</header><paragraph id="H2DEDC96E01594247A413D6E439321957"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Fiscal year 2027</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall withhold 3 percent of the amount required to be apportioned to any State under each of paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 104(b) on October 1, 2026, if the State does not meet the requirements of paragraph (3) on such date.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3B84FA1A3974280A02C18B872DF310D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent fiscal years</header><text>The Secretary shall withhold 5 percent of the amount required to be apportioned to any State under each of paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 104(b) on October 1, 2027, and on October 1 of each fiscal year thereafter, if the State does not meet the requirements of paragraph (3) on such date.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H472C2A53EBFA4BB3A8E5ADF01F034C87"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements</header><subparagraph id="H6EADE9009A674CBFA1E2E2F25715886B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State meets the requirements of this paragraph if the State has enacted and is enforcing a law mandating a restriction on driving privileges for a driving while intoxicated offender that limits the individual to operating only motor vehicles with an ignition interlock device installed, unless a special exception applies (as determined by the respective State), for a minimum period of 180 days and remain without a violation for a minimum period (as determined by the respective State) that precedes the date of the removal of the restriction.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53AF118756614F21A16F0EA25E525338"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Interlock period</header><text>The interlock period described in subparagraph (A) may be served by the individual during an administrative license suspension period, post-conviction, or a combination of both, as determined by the respective State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEE6BCC6B6AF84D26AFB72DC816810164"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Period of availability; effect of compliance and non-Compliance</header><paragraph id="H32194A379262473189485924F8654E00"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Period of availability of withheld funds</header><subparagraph id="HC3BB0A67DB2B4449A49D041E9B732703"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Funds withheld on or before September 30, 2028</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any funds withheld under subsection (a) from apportionment to any State on or before September 30, 2028, shall remain available until the end of the third fiscal year following the fiscal year for which the funds are authorized to be appropriated.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA59D54DA6BD34E45B151CCBF105EEE52"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Funds withheld after September 30, 2028</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds withheld under this section from apportionment to any State after September 30, 2028, shall be available for apportionment to the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H75B41A38DEEF40719EE801384C57B72C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Apportionment of withheld funds after compliance</header><text>If, before the last day of the period for which funds withheld under subsection (a) from apportionment are to remain available for apportionment to a State under paragraph (1)(A), the State meets the requirements of subsection (a)(3), the Secretary shall, on the first day on which the State meets the requirements, apportion to the State the funds withheld under subsection (a) that remain available for apportionment to the State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43D2F4D45746450283D11F2BEBBFD535"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Period of availability of subsequently apportioned funds</header><subparagraph id="HE30974E8CFA64E33B6884D76C25638AF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any funds apportioned under paragraph (2) shall remain available for obligation until the end of the third fiscal year following the fiscal year in which the funds are so apportioned.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD859EC28CEE241BDA675CE78FE47B32A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of certain funds</header><text>Sums not obligated at the end of the period referred to in subparagraph (A) shall lapse.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF01976E3874417FBF4D3EB485C25794"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Effect of non-compliance</header><text>If, at the end of the period for which funds withheld under subsection (a) from apportionment are available for apportionment to a State under paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection, the State does not meet the requirements of subsection (a)(3), the funds shall lapse.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H61313C0F4757438FBE8E5D16ADC0B680"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HC00BA9607CC1429CBEB628F8C5518EB1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Driving while intoxicated</header><text>The term <quote>driving while intoxicated</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 164 and section 405.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5019B998FB3544C1ACE989FEFC049DC2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ignition interlock</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>ignition interlock</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>ignition interlock system</quote> in section 1275.3 of title 23, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EC4BAA47F0D485F990A502A6762F7C0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Motor vehicle</header><text>The term <quote>motor vehicle</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 32101 of title 49.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1B7EC12FC244572A525A66280E6005B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Special exception</header><text>The term <quote>special exception</quote> has the meaning defined by a State in law or regulation with respect to an ignition interlock device that may include that the individual is required to operate an employer’s motor vehicle in the course and scope of employment and the business entity that owns the vehicle is not owned by the individual. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D388561F1C845B6A26086E9359EA643"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Violation</header><text>The term <quote>violation</quote> has the meaning defined by a State in law or regulation with respect to an ignition interlock device that may include failing a breath test, failing to take or pass a re-test, circumventing an ignition interlock, tampering with an ignition interlock, or a combinations of the actions described in this paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H95D7B20A138E4E72826FED67CFD28F58"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/23/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of title 23, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/23/179">section 179</external-xref> the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HE95385BE3DC84B9181A7D6FC3F9CAA08" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">180. National standard for ignition interlocks for DWI offenders. </toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H414845CCCA2C4CB5B2CB66E97F9FD5E1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="HA2F89AADF1C142ACA4CC55AF8177CC5E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Minimum penalties for repeat offenders</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 164(a)(6) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>or controlled</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE4F1471114B4D019F669C03039BF7B1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National priority safety programs</header><text>Section 405(d)(6) of title 23, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HC26BC34495A145B0AC3C25EC383AC31F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(ii) by striking <quote>registered, owned, or leased for operation</quote> and inserting <quote>operated</quote>; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEB6BBEF4575492B9E003F936344690A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F)(i) by striking <quote>or controlled</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

