<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-DAV25246-VMT-CD-YW1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 91 IS: Acknowledging the third anniversary of Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine and expressing support for the people of Ukraine.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 91</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250224">February 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Acknowledging the third anniversary of Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine and expressing support for the people of Ukraine.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on February 24, 2022, Russia launched a full-scale, unprovoked, and illegal invasion of Ukraine, which followed Russia’s illegal annexation of Crimea in 2014 and its illegal occupation of parts of the Donbas region in 2014;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the international community recognizes the sovereignty and full territorial integrity of Ukraine within the 1991 borders; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Ukrainian Armed Forces and the people of Ukraine have demonstrated a determined resistance that has prevented Russia from taking control of their country: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id56ceaee93c964bd1adad61f4c37244f4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses continued solidarity with the people of Ukraine and condolences for the loss of tens of thousands of Ukrainian people to Russian aggression;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id02c37bab8ca24f1da0be7c894c4ed82f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>rejects Russia’s attempts to militarily seize sovereign territory in Ukraine and elsewhere in Europe;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id355a2254ec244438921dca3feb9211e4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirms the support of the United States for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id271285ef5bff4ae9b009a43b528f2460"><enum>(4)</enum><text>commends NATO, the Ukraine Defense Contact Group, and the international community for their continued efforts to support Ukraine’s defense and the protection of human rights on its territory;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id82ee89b4743f4c63b0319dca85d54cc6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supports Ukraine’s aspirations to integrate into Euro-Atlantic structures;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5ad0fc4d9b574660b9751126efdcb789"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes Ukraine's efforts to strengthen its democracy during wartime; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc4098107b3874718863e128e03152ccf"><enum>(7)</enum><text>encourages the transatlantic community to continue to denounce Russia’s illegal and unprovoked war in Ukraine and counter Russian aggression; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc3989d7d70dd480cb36f49f6de9a4b7a"><enum>(8)</enum><text>emphasizes that Ukraine must be a participant in discussions with the Russian Federation about Ukraine’s future. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

