<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD0F2E1E789A7434187D4B3C7F2E84E59" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 295 IH: Expressing Support for the President’s Actions to Safeguard National Security and Eliminate Threats from Foreign Terrorist Organizations.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 295</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250407">April 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001137">Mr. Crank</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing Support for the President’s Actions to Safeguard National Security and Eliminate Threats from Foreign Terrorist Organizations.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on January 20, 2025, President Trump issued Executive Order 14157, designating cartels and other organizations as Foreign Terrorist Organizations (FTOs) and Specially Designated Global Terrorists (SDGTs);</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tren de Aragua (TdA), who has been directed to attack U.S. law enforcement officers, was specifically named as a FTO under this Executive order;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in early February 2025, President Bukele met with Secretary of State Marco Rubio and agreed to imprison members of Tren de Aragua of behalf of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on March 15, 2025, President Trump invoked the Alien Enemies Act in response to the infiltration of the United States by Tren de Aragua;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on March 15, 2025, two flights carrying noncitizen members of Tren de Aragua and the Salvadoran gang MS–13 departed U.S. airspace;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on March 16, 2025, El Salvador President Nayib Bukele received these two flights and immediately transferred the SDGTs into El Salvador’s Terrorism Confinement Center (CECOT) for detention.</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HAFA9787A70274B66BF306A00C7CB4A82"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H29CA5DE7F0D64010BD0E88B6EDDB89B1"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HDF0BC06D9D1A4263943D18B6BAF84BE3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the President’s Action to remove foreign terrorists under the Alien Enemies Act, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/21">50 U.S.C. 21 et seq.</external-xref>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB623828CE16849CC92EE82C82C1A8D7E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affirms that, as Commander in Chief, the President has executive authority to detain, deport, or restrict non-citizens from a Foreign Terrorist Organization; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A5DDF6D8A7C41BB9655F2D8935BB293"><enum>(3)</enum><text>endorses the complete elimination of these organizations from the United States to protect the nation’s territory, safety, and security.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

