<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD065810F81B44C9CB87FF0BBF2BA05EC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 348 IH: Stop Corrupt Iranian Oligarchs and Entities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 348</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250113">January 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000392">Mr. Kustoff</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a report on oligarchs and parastatal entities of Iran, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9702788A7A874D108AD0DE72B3160AEB" style="OLC"><section id="H758F7DB4E2E6447591C545A0E57C5CE7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Corrupt Iranian Oligarchs and Entities Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H85A1C74D1F5F49959C5CEE33AA7AF891"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on oligarchs and parastatal entities of Iran</header><subsection id="HC8FDF4E8BFCD46B5BC8AB672061D9259"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence and the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a detailed report on the following:</text><paragraph id="HD2B6B27D25ED43FDA7289DA13901EF76"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Senior foreign political figures and oligarchs in Iran, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="HFF026F7BCBA54E16B412E6C4E270B25F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An identification of the most significant senior foreign political figures and oligarchs in Iran, as determined by the closeness to the Iranian Government of each such figure and oligarch, and the estimated net worth of each such figure and oligarch.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C739051A57E480DA7B1256D7EBD9196"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the relationship between the individuals identified under subparagraph (A) and President Masoud Pezeshkian or other members of the Iranian ruling elite.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H799287633F1748D5824025CC293A665E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An identification of any indices of corruption with respect to such individuals.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6715A2971DA64EC79545CBE8717CCDE3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Known sources of income of such individuals and their family members (including spouses, children, parents, and siblings), including relevant beneficial ownership information.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77E7E1E87D0342F7B4DCEC16997FD33C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An identification of the non-Iranian business affiliations of such individuals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0316AFE847446959BF9D97891233F49"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Iranian parastatal entities, including an assessment of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HCB115D8B29AD445A973C0597F510859C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The emergence of Iranian parastatal entities and their role in the economy of Iran.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0B624133C444B9F93A699D90DE40B70"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The leadership structures and beneficial ownership of such entities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65E74BD03CE6457DBE7667820A92D550"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An identification of the non-Iranian business affiliations of such entities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4C7D32D633A4257BAF4C89B0CC82761"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information relating to the exposure of key economic sectors of the United States, including, at minimum, the banking, securities, insurance, and real estate sectors, to Iranian politically affiliated persons, Iranian parastatal entities, and Iranian State-owned enterprises.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E2E10186757471F9BDBC1F232586935"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Information relating to the likely effects of imposing debt and equity restrictions on Iranian parastatal entities, as well as the anticipated effects of adding Iranian parastatal entities to the list of Specially Designated Nationals maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDADD7372D12242C6938CDF3BBAA08B86"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Information relating to the potential impacts of imposing sanctions or debt and equity restrictions in addition to any such sanctions or restrictions in existence as of the date of the enactment of this Act on Iranian oligarchs, Iranian parastatal entities, or Iranian State-owned enterprises, including impacts on such oligarchs, entities, and enterprises and on the economy of Iran, as well as on the economies of the United States and United States allies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H15E03D04430A4EE7A33B192DAE7BE5E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in an unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6397FD2DBCF34916AFDFF1AE4FB568FE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="HDC0C7F5EEDE14E86B847C631F71194CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H1C38D28813FE4CC4A8F77AB40A1D40E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57E564F08515406C979980019F706EF9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HABAE128BDFEF4910804F3A8BA049AC89"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Iranian parastatal entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Iranian parastatal entities</term> means entities—</text><subparagraph id="H0D9A805F2A944BE9A6CE837DEF490561"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in which Iranian State ownership is at least 25 percent; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CEC156344614A8386529B5D5BC5EE66"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that had 2016 revenues of approximately $2,000,000,000 or more.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C8D84BC7B764D9A9324C792C6D82F63"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Senior foreign political figure</header><text>The term <term>senior foreign political figure</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1010.605 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (or any corresponding similar regulation or ruling).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

