<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9D16FF934D144F619060A6BAC59D39B5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3536 IH: Countering Russian Innovation and Safeguarding Individual Scientists Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3536</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250521">May 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security to provide certain nationals of Russia with special immigrant status, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFFA2B599457F41B98C63DBCB2B04DC15" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1C90D64B715343C4A8A2D3BF89FF2028" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Countering Russian Innovation and Safeguarding Individual Scientists Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CRISIS Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H78ACC79E4AA3459CA2A462DBAE693AA3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Special immigrant status for certain Russian nationals</header> <subsection id="HE95EBDD0A54649ADB3609456EDD940D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (e), the Secretary of Homeland Security, or, notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of State in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, may provide an alien described in subsection (b) with the status of a special immigrant under section 101(a)(27) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(27)</external-xref>) if the alien—</text>
<paragraph id="HCB52EE8DEE784D389808D45E4246C2B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submits a classification petition under section 204(a)(1)(G)(i) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1154">8 U.S.C. 1154(a)(1)(G)(i)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFEBD9CBA536E4A45AFE5D95356207795" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is otherwise eligible to receive and immigrant visa;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4251098E73C24F21A2F186FE4789FB63"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is otherwise admissible to the United States for permanent residence; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73C848A77129478AB18247EF1795C4ED"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">clears a background check and appropriate screening, as determined by the Secretary of Homeland Security and in accordance with subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB2BCF978A24B4E458C5053F8F0AC791F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Aliens described</header>
<paragraph id="H48AFC5D77A244F2CB0239877A1AFC834"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Principal alien</header><text>An alien is described in this subsection if the alien—</text> <subparagraph id="H64725CCE1DE44EFB844468FA1A2F284C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a national of Russia;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H652656ECE8C9485E940FC5EA9CD01FE6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has earned a doctoral degree in the United States or an equivalent foreign degree in a field involving science, technology, engineering, or mathematics; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H062D48E1BDAD45FE881140538ADA8A82"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is seeking admission to engage in work in the United States in such a field.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1B3D5DB788DC475282A782E3FB141898"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Spouse or child</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An alien is described in this subparagraph if the alien—</text> <subparagraph id="HBE40AC8902D34120854758EF8CA16216"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is the spouse or child of the a principal alien described in paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFD0EE819BF554EB682470519D3EC366B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is accompanying or following to join the principal alien in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2DA82CC71FF948B1ADB76BFB0B8AB67C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Processing and numerical limitations</header> <paragraph id="HCF617A91117441EE928F24D36A715CEC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total number of aliens described under subsection (b) who may be provided special immigrant status under this section may not exceed 3,000 per year for each of the fiscal years 2026, 2027, 2028, and 2029.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA925191BD0E643CF917042B6522E2CF6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Processing</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall, to the extent practicable, process petitions described in subsection (a) not later than 90 days after the date on which the Secretary of Homeland Security receives all required documentation and information to render a decision on such petition.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H149F423659F24F1687AD181743B8B6CD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Numerical limitations</header><text>Aliens admitted to the United States pursuant to subsection (a) shall be exempt from the numerical limitations described in sections 201, 202, and 203 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151</external-xref>, 1152, and 1153).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H17B859DC8BC54C728125B6647A7C9BB7" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Interview and vetting requirements</header>
<paragraph id="H11A661A389CB48EBA3459C9287715E2C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Vetting requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish vetting requirements for applicants seeking special immigrant status under this section that are equivalent to the vetting requirements for refugees admitted to the United States through the United States Refugee Admissions Program, including an interview.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6D20162C247F437A95DDC88AEE89FCA9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Record requirements</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall maintain records that contain, for each applicant under this section for the duration of the pendency of their application for special immigrant status—</text>
<subparagraph id="H7E5F2DD193A242EBA17D30BFC4F5E92D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>personal biographic information, including name and date of birth;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8BF0C5043B244F3C9B526D8F9AD1C56A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>biometric information;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H31A617B0779C411D917DBD46DF06A36D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any criminal conviction occurring after the date on which the applicant entered the United States; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6B242603C5EB4FB4ABF5503C57DFF204" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the history of the United States Government vetting to which the applicant has submitted, including whether the individual has undergone in-person vetting.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD6706C05DD834420BDDF60F615C8B8AB" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of Construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security to maintain records in accordance with any other provision of law.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8FF74CCD43284D0D8561E9D80728D47D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security to admit aliens to the United States pursuant to subsection (a) shall terminate on the date that is the last day of the fourth full fiscal year after the date of enactment of this Act, except that petitions under subsection (a) that are approved on or before such date continue to form the basis for an application for an immigrant visa under section 221 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201</external-xref>) or an application for adjustment of status under section 245 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1255">8 U.S.C. 1255</external-xref>) after such date.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H86E6BF17F182460B8DA14B955DB2366F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>The term <term>field involving science, technology, engineering, and mathematics</term> includes advanced computing, advanced engineering materials, advanced gas turbine engine technologies, advanced manufacturing, advanced and networked sensing and signature management, advanced nuclear energy technologies, advanced particle accelerator and detector technologies, artificial intelligence, autonomous systems and robotics, biotechnologies, communication and networking technologies, cybersecurity, directed energy, financial technologies, human-machine interfaces, hypersonics, advanced missile propulsion technologies, networked sensors and sensing, quantum information technologies, renewable energy generation and storage, semiconductors and microelectronics, and space technologies and systems.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H10D7DFBB83C84CE2AD3E1005DCC4FDC9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to require an alien described in subsection (b) to have an offer of employment from a United States employer to be eligible to be admitted as a special immigrant pursuant to subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

