<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFD3177963D11477B893A9F4F8AE7209F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2148 IH: Veteran Caregiver Reeducation, Reemployment, and Retirement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2148</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To expand medical, employment, and other benefits for individuals serving as family caregivers for certain veterans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4059CD7E77234885B5BECEA7B2445F74" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA92F1B011F41422F81AE34531F9CD8F9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veteran Caregiver Reeducation, Reemployment, and Retirement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H75E198284384470E8997415EF91DF1D8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extension of period of medical care coverage for caregivers designated as primary providers of personal care services for veterans</header> <subsection id="HC24973A946C448C08D5312848E013801"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a)(4) of section 1781 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting before the comma at the end the following: <quote>, including during the 180-day period following the removal of such designation unless the individual was dismissed from the program under section 1720G(a) of this title for fraud, abuse, or mistreatment</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9A29B493C3BC469480DDFCBEBE0100BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on eligibility for caregivers entitled to Medicare</header><text>Subsection (d) of such section is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1D7DF04E53E1487F94B15100D0CAE124"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (5); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6CD2DD4D4A0F44D5A54826E7FBB95E63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H17F5E1DA4A314AF3A1BB9FA64510F712"> <paragraph id="HFE4D27F3ECC8414CBCA410B190D3F7ED" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, an individual is not eligible for medical care under this section during the 180-day period specified under subsection (a)(4) if the individual is entitled to hospital insurance benefits under part A of the medicare program during such period.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H4F8BE426F9804F1C8F88D3B3370EC61B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Employment and other benefits for caregivers designated as primary providers of personal care services for veterans</header> 
<subsection id="H9E12AB8B84FD47DAAE5FCEB6488E7663"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Employment assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1720G of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB2018779B7E42CF845A87AEBAC72F10"> <subsection id="H574FF0D4986C4FF9B8642E6B44D043E4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Employment assistance</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFEC6551862D54923BB59855AA1253914"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide to an individual designated as a primary provider of personal care services under subsection (a)(7)(A) employment assistance as follows:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD96DBB02436A453EAA9E1879FE4765F2" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reimbursement of fees associated with certifications or relicensure necessary for such employment.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8A68911939784CF6AD1A6EC9D44CE03E" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For purposes of gaining credit for continuing professional education requirements, access to training modules of the Department at no cost.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph indent="up1" id="H70B63AC187B94E88800F41C1E347C7F7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Labor, access to employment assistance under—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1B175CAC91504CD0A88AC6E12F70A7B8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Military OneSource program of the Department of Defense; </text></clause> 
<clause id="H94E56D54625C44CABA0569F16760EE6D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Veterans’ Employment and Training Service of the Department of Labor; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7FD6674FE88844278B32C953489E9733"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such programs of the Department of Veterans Affairs as the Secretary of Veterans Affairs determines appropriate. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph indent="up1" id="H051657D999514910B3BDBF7BB9329A53"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual described in paragraph (1) shall have access to assistance described in such paragraph—</text> <subparagraph id="H3751B3DCA76B41118EFB2D0D11EF4286"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">while participating in the program established under subsection (a)(1); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H547D34A16B6341EB962D680E743F24F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">during the 180-day period following the date on which the individual is no longer participating in such program unless the individual was dismissed from the program for fraud, abuse, or mistreatment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph indent="up1" id="H4FEAA360AF0F459BA17638CBA841DC93"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The maximum lifetime amount that may be reimbursed for an individual under paragraph (1)(A) is $1,000.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1105CA5207DD412E9369047A9C0222FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expansion of available services</header><text>Subsection (a)(3)(A)(ii) of such section is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE5C9B825D3F949A6B804DF77C0772363"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subclause (V), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA5CD43EEB6AC4B21AC48678CE43288F7" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subclause (VI)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6CA39D3C48124D16BFB5F53334FE293D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding item (aa), by inserting <quote>or agreements</quote> after <quote>contracts</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9C7533F08AC24893915C76E4B400B3D4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in item (aa), by inserting <quote>, including retirement planning services,</quote> after <quote>services</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1FFEBCC6B99645B0BCED89604EDD15DA"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in item (bb), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H006BCCB013FF40AEA8F26CCDD4599A1C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD6DEBB8A08F04E908E3AF1B35135232D"> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7C987131975045F5AC991620B52FE743" indent="up2"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">during the 180-day period following the date on which the family caregiver is no longer participating in the program required by paragraph (1), unless the family caregiver was dismissed from the program for fraud, abuse, or mistreatment, such instruction, preparation, training, and support as the Secretary considers appropriate to assist the family caregiver in transitioning away from caregiving.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1893270D17B94EEA8BC8A717393D0D72"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assistance returning to workforce</header><text>Subclause (VI) of such subsection is further amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFEC1F77ACFB64C7388B57C9D32A754C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in item (aa), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6025C852BD8C41C2BBE39EDCD237AFDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in item (bb), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4EDDD7638169488C84E046A81EEED7BA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H260553BB1FB4496BBE31BB72AA2B5328"> 
<item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1B82374004EE4309BF1357CD34C4DE05" indent="up2"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>assistance returning to the workforce upon discharge or dismissal from the program required by paragraph (1) unless the family caregiver was dismissed from the program for fraud, abuse, or mistreatment.</text></item><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3E75180B7F044148B087841331DE32A9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Bereavement counseling and support</header><text>Subsection (a)(3)(A)(i)(III) of such section is amended by inserting before the semicolon the following: <quote>, including bereavement counseling and support following the death of the eligible veteran</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3E9B1B17F42846CB9641E13A705008B3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Study on provision of returnship program</header> 
<paragraph id="HF1EA8F805CFF4C65A0EC295F769E2704"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in partnership with the Secretary of Labor, shall complete a study on the feasibility and advisability of conducting a returnship program for individuals who are or were designated as a primary provider of personal care services under section 1720G(a)(7)(A) of title 38, United States Code, to assist such individuals in returning to the workforce.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6C328731DB4B40578F3DD71C21785A57"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after completion of the study under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the study.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H163D34DF77904B68ACA1CB843A4D9106"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Study on incorporating former caregivers into workforce of Department of Veterans Affairs</header> 
<paragraph id="H6436D78907DC428CB91B3E250472311F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall complete a study on barriers and incentives to hiring individuals who were designated as a primary provider of personal care services under section 1720G(a)(7)(A) of title 38, United States Code, at facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs to address staffing needs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E5D9A4E7628477892AE10A9CCE5EF74"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after completion of the study under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the study, which shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFDA36A8AFBF34A3DBCB36821D60922F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan for increasing employment opportunities at facilities of the Department for individuals who were designated as a primary provider of personal care services under section 1720G(a)(7)(A) of title 38, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB6885A1F0B434C5FAD7F9B462CCA23F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such recommendations for legislative or administrative action as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H60DAD9E4D32945DBA2E578565F95D4D8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Comptroller General report on efforts of Department of Veterans Affairs in supporting family caregivers transitioning away from caregiving</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report assessing the efforts of the Department of Veterans Affairs in supporting individuals serving as family caregivers under section 1720G(a) of title 38, United States Code, in transitioning away from caregiving, either by assisting those individuals with retirement planning or returning to work.</text></section> <section id="H10EFBF5A644B4410B015C61C03A0BA2D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report on feasibility and advisability of establishing a retirement plan or retirement savings for family caregivers of certain veterans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the heads of such other relevant entities as the Secretary of Veterans Affairs determines necessary, shall submit to Congress a report on the feasibility and advisability of, for individuals serving as family caregivers under section 1720G(a) of title 38, United States Code—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H53DB449268954E1190294A174C383CBB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing an individual retirement plan (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7701">section 7701(a)(37)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) or similar retirement plan; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H20BB7BFFA3FE48919408265B43BC3E8D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">permitting such individuals to join an already established pathway to retirement savings. </text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

