<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2B7ADE7AC6774A9880C2775F093C3EBA" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 357 IH: Of inquiry requesting the President and directing the Secretary of State to transmit to the House of Representatives any record created on or after January 20, 2025, under the control of the President or the Secretary, respectively, relating to international agreements between the United States of America and El Salvador and the removal of individuals from the United States to El Salvador and subsequent detentions of such individuals.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 357</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250429">April 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Of inquiry requesting the President and directing the Secretary of State to transmit to the House of Representatives any record created on or after January 20, 2025, under the control of the President or the Secretary, respectively, relating to international agreements between the United States of America and El Salvador and the removal of individuals from the United States to El Salvador and subsequent detentions of such individuals.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H75C6AC5A5A1F4AA39C4FA92B7068C2D3"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H59FF660F96524CEEACC117383D6C451B"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the President is requested, and the Secretary of State is directed, to transmit, respectively, to the House of Representatives, not later than 14 days after the date of the adoption of this resolution, copies of all documents, charts, or tables, including notes from meetings, audio recordings, records (including telephone and email records), correspondence, artificial intelligence large language model conversation transcripts, and any other communications created on or after January 20, 2025, under the control of the President or the Secretary, respectively, that refer or relate to any of the following:</text><paragraph id="H584650FEB3894CA7A55E08063100C40C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any agreements, including nonbinding instruments, or arrangements made with the Government of El Salvador.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H094CEFCBF4894831B7E98F18928564EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>All information pertaining to Secretary of State Marco Rubio’s trip to El Salvador in February 2025, including preparation materials, transcripts, and notes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8EEE25B90B948C09518FDAA1376DADC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>All information pertaining to President Bukele’s April 14, 2025, visit to the White House, including preparation materials, transcripts, and notes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52E7A1E31AB8425592721A3011435073"><enum>(4)</enum><text>All information regarding the removal of individuals from the United States to El Salvador and the detention of those individuals by the Government of El Salvador, including on behalf of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C5D4DA369AF4861AED3D1C1E66DC0E5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>All information pertaining to any funding provided by the United States to the Government of El Salvador to support the detention of individuals, including information pertaining to the accounts from which those funds are or will be drawn, amounts already transferred, and amounts obligated or committed to be transferred.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB463FF4A99FF41D2B0EF366A09AA87D5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Legal analysis of or legal justifications for any agreements, including nonbinding instruments with the Government of El Salvador, including any and all analysis of whether such agreements are subject to the requirements set forth in the Case-Zablocki Act and amendments thereto included in PL 117–263.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H166729084C1B45598F20A7593A27DB52"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Legal analysis of or legal justifications for any funding provided by the United States to the Government of El Salvador to support the detention of individuals, including any and all analysis of whether such obligations of funding require notification to Congress.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

