<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3554741EF7B743C78587CFFA9621B6F9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5725 IH: Mental Health Crisis Response Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5725</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251008">October 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Attorney General to establish a grant to support communities transitioning to health-centered responses for mental health-related emergencies.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF5B1666A49964672A961DC47972EC5B8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H03EC649FAE00474294B55A5ED3E9A8DD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mental Health Crisis Response Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HF28CA396F9AC4E32BE4A930A213EF3BC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program for crisis response alternatives</header> 
<subsection id="H2E44322B6BDF4BE39AA9D506DE653000">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Establishment</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, in partnership with the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, shall establish a grant program, to award, on a competitive basis, grants to eligible jurisdictions for the purposes of implementing or expanding health-centered crisis response strategies for individuals experiencing behavioral health emergencies.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H90FF78B9A45C4ACE90C6ADFDB94FCC76">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Eligible jurisdictions</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A jurisdiction shall be eligible for a grant under subsection (a) if the State, Tribal, or local government manages emergency services in response to any incident, including law enforcement and emergency medical services.</text>
            </subsection>
<subsection id="HB80C05B423314EEA87A1AB449E5B0B5A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible jurisdiction seeking a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Attorney General at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H091FAE8FEB8B487C9ECFC2FB4D2D8A08"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A grant awarded under subsection (a) may be used by an eligible jurisdiction to:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF3B5C6EB369E4655BA18CE91B94241B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Embed mental health professionals into 911 dispatch and call triage systems.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02319BCDCA914143974E27B291507271"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Develop alternative 911 call routing to 988 or other mental health or substance abuse crisis hotline service.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB708E2B97CB1439EA35BB356B93B2EE3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Form partnerships between State or local emergency services and State or local 911 dispatch centers to ensure a streamlined handoff without requiring the caller to hangup and dial 988 or other mental health or substance abuse crisis hotline service.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE230DDD7F4F34B4485D42736599EF2BF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H98C9A24E4ED446E08557E8C478EF725C">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>require a State, Tribe, or local government to remove law enforcement from an emergency response model; or</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H02BD4696CC5A4F068DA156286F6705E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preempt a State law regarding involuntary psychiatric holds, involuntary treatment, or any emergency authority that would hinder public safety.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H843726BF7A1942B9A49677FDF2BA00F1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>An eligible jurisdiction awarded a grant under this section shall submit an annual report on—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAF3DF72A98884CFF83539214F50A160C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of time it takes for a response to an incident;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE78FADD594AE434D9E8888062483E993"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use of force by law enforcement or any other individual responding to an incident where an individual requires assistance;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBACED68920974E02A51B99AB89325E7B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>diversion rates; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3569D54FA9CE4EFD93EA3830A0C28BBE"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other information requested by the Attorney General or Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H58F95DC1E3AB419894486443C14127A4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031 to carry out this section.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

