<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H86B17EBB8AFB404690753AD2AE64B31E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2551 IH: Military Installation Retail Security Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2551</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250401">April 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to establish requirements relating to long-term concessions agreements between the Secretary of Defense and certain retailers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA5EC0C81CF264681822636B88B918997" style="OLC"><section id="HD90243E92F394695B32F607AB2701E30" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military Installation Retail Security Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1303E4EFA469461E98F9F906D785BB48" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirements relating to long-term concessions agreements with certain retailers</header><subsection id="H61503B7672764AA1B12BB18C887036B3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/363">Chapter 363</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H237535B60BF745AE954CEE125D6A9E02" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H0819DD0F552842F9B1AABC5A9D362859"><enum>4664.</enum><header>Requirements relating to long-term concessions agreements with certain retailers</header><subsection id="H2F57C514323D4E4B909A48EDEA7D2B94"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on contracting with certain retailers</header><paragraph id="H514F6D668691479E8F53AEFBF1814184"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense may not renew, extend, or enter into a long-term concessions agreement with a retailer that is controlled by a covered nation to permit such retailer to operate or conduct business through a physical location on a covered military installation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5ECAEA42C8C04C0D9A26CB7C6FC08948" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary may waive the requirements of paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines that—</text><subparagraph id="H0E3E6A59B34C4AD1864C515AC615E40E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the goods or services to be provided by the retailer are vital for the welfare and morale of members of the Armed Forces and no reasonable alternatives exist; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B3774F59CFC4884B86C25F0A4BAC664"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary has implemented adequate measures to mitigate any potential national security risks of the retailer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E0B81C6669A4C348C46AFDB25CBC8FB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 30 days after each use of the waiver authority under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and Senate a report including a justification for the use of such authority and a description of any risk mitigation strategies described in paragraph (2)(B).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBDA70902F634A3E9CEA0073E13667B0" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a retailer that has misrepresented the ownership and control of such retailer for the award of a long-term concessions agreement, the Secretary of Defense may terminate such agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC94E7A5E7DD3472F97ABC0AD90C91182"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall apply with respect to a long-term concessions agreement entered into on or after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H612EE7EC16AD41FA9A4D5665AE185EA2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered retailers</header><paragraph id="H4A5F3043F5CC4034B915A956AC443D8D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense may not permit a covered retailer controlled by a covered nation to operate or conduct business through a physical location on a covered military installation, unless such covered retailer has received an approval determination under paragraph (4).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61B6422D89F9408A90BCC4D3FAB81A21"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this section, a covered retailer—</text><subparagraph id="HD12DA94788FF48798FCBD9C22A3383BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (in this section referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>) a notice that includes any direct or indirect relationships between the covered retailer (including any subsidiaries or parent companies of such covered retailer) and any covered nation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5674D63F1FBB463C86F5F70BF5082E2A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not operate or conduct business through a physical location on a covered military installation unless the Committee submits a determination approving such notice in accordance with paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAD07C1BA5544F848B6236720517BC1F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Investigation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall conduct an investigation of the effects of a notice submitted under paragraph (2) on the national security of the United States, including an assessment of any direct or indirect relationships between the covered retailer (including any subsidiaries or parent companies of such covered retailer) and any covered nation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H792347CC0E484455BFEB265EDEA87DAC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after completing an investigation under paragraph (3), the Committee shall submit to the Secretary of Defense a determination approving or disapproving the notice submitted under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EB2AB09053849F1A341B32A4298C5B1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Compliance</header><subparagraph id="H7D71FF40E1984F1C80C9C707C3E270F7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered retailer that receives an approval under paragraph (4) shall submit annually to the Committee disclosures regarding any change in the ownership structure that may affect whether or not the covered retailer is controlled by a covered nation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0458C805CD004751B96C94C47EE289BA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Failure to comply</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall immediately terminate a long-term concession agreement with a covered retailer if the Secretary determines such covered retailer has failed to comply with the requirements of this subsection. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H171A054DEE0F490E9856593C1815A4FF" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assessment of covered retailers</header><paragraph id="HE4B16075504E47179E4DD23F7CAA0C66" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Defense shall review each long-term concessions agreement with a covered retailer that permits the covered retailer to operate or conduct business through a physical location on a covered military installation to assess any direct or indirect relationships between the retailer (including any subsidiaries or parent companies of such covered retailer) and any covered nation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06A94A3442584E36A8567EAAEECE06D8" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after making a determination that a covered retailer is controlled by a covered nation based on an assessment described in subsection (a) or a determination made under subsection (b), the Secretary of Defense shall terminate any long-term concessions agreement with the covered retailer.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H07BAA6DFC20A43E294736EC6974687EF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H668D46BD3AAD44C8A364A749F572CE87"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>controlled by a covered nation</term> means, with respect to a retailer—</text><subparagraph id="H337CC56611BC407ABB84AD8CA16FEE03"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the retailer is organized under the laws of a covered nation or any jurisdiction within a covered nation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF940CBC6525747289B666368E970CA34"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that a covered nation owns 20 percent or more of the shares of the retailer; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B62BADCF08D4BBCA5546845CAC514FC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that the retailer is subject to the direct or control of a covered nation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BC9AF04B9B143A891CE4952E2410F6A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>covered military installation</term> means a military installation (as defined in section 2801 of this title) located in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1298EFFB081145F2B3281A2DF3E8FCD9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered nation</term> has the meaning given in section 4872 of this title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6004A92543FE49E7A389A867A8219E22"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered retailer</term> means a retailer that is performing a long-term concessions agreement on or before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71F50DC1D552431B8F47D18E4A79C0BA"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>long-term concessions agreement</term> means a contract, subcontract (at any tier), or other agreement, including a lease agreement or licensing agreement, to operate a business through a physical location on a covered military installation entered into by—</text><subparagraph id="H175B3D5C0F474B70BFCCDF5A0859CE12"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Defense or a Secretary of a military department and a person, including a nonappropriated fund instrumentality; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2323228A0BA542F7865972E17D77450C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person and a nonappropriated fund instrumentality.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC80D4FA39068459990A6E1AB0E580C9F" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>retailer</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H33AECD7053F042AF8BEAC9FED6A03AB0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a nonappropriated fund instrumentality that operates or seeks to operate a business through a physical location on a covered military installation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D3A63E3D20943CF999AA07516CF92B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other person that operates or seeks to operate a business on a covered military installation under a contract, subcontract (at any tier), or other agreement, including a lease agreement or licensing agreement, with—</text><clause id="H626C6281139C49FDA67A9AF811B1E567"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a nonappropriated fund instrumentality;</text></clause><clause id="H5CC61DD7145B4DC5BAA3A387016D15D6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Secretary of Defense; or</text></clause><clause id="HD0E6F3C046A04F02991B89EB1FF674FF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a Secretary of a military department.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HBAAE4FE64E6849728D3FC9A4AC8465C9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assessment of covered retailers</header><paragraph id="HAD18D738D88347578B52E218CA162CD2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall review each long-term concessions agreement with a covered retailer that permits the covered retailer to operate or conduct business through a physical location on a covered military installation to assess any direct or indirect relationships between the retailer (including any subsidiaries or parent companies of such covered retailer) and any covered nation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD7CDB1BBDD74D85BAC80B19EA4D449D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after making a determination that a covered retailer is controlled by a covered nation based on an assessment described in subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall terminate any long-term concessions agreement with the covered retailer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B2D7C2057754ED8B65ED929E970895B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the terms <term>covered nation</term>, <term>covered retailer</term>, and <term>long-term concessions agreement</term> have the meanings given in section 4664 of title 10, United States Code, as added by this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

