<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0CC96102880A42ADB5CB1BB40C7747F9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5239 IH: Endometrial Cancer Research and Education Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5239</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250909">September 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000299">Mr. Johnson of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to expand research and education with respect to endometrial cancer, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD17524B9AFB140BBADFDBF26E07A14D9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE4A8AFFAE5CF400F9C270F2D89D9C813" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Endometrial Cancer Research and Education Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6D5D0BABCFD84D0F9105D9CFA7DA5CEF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBA1B7ADE1B254BB9823AD005846B2874"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Endometrial cancer is cancer of the lining of the uterus (or endometrium) and is the most common form of uterine cancer.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFD941DAD1D92478CAC71D48ED647ABF7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Endometrial cancer is the fourth most common cancer diagnosed in women, after breast, lung, and colon cancer.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB4AC0A3A33AD465E99292D29BAE1B843"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Endometrial cancer mainly affects postmenopausal women, with most women diagnosed between age 55 and 64.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65CC698FC834462FBD11E2DF8517B3B1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Women with polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS) and uterine leiomyoma have an increased risk of developing endometrial cancer.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA610B5FCFD2C4BC8A55322449876DA6B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Unlike most other types of cancer, the incidence of endometrial cancer, particularly aggressive subtypes of such cancer, has been increasing in the United States among all women, particularly among African-American and Asian women, with a 2.5 annual percent change for both groups.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC145BAEE763249508DBC17C99B15F37F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In comparison to non-Hispanic White women, African-American women have significantly higher incidence rates of aggressive endometrial cancers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8BAD24F4AB184C87974AE26BA9E7D4B8"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such incidence rates for Hispanic and Asian women are equal to or lower than such incidence rates for non-Hispanic White women.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4888825E1DA74C93B28E29CC561CC409"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Although non-Hispanic White women are more likely to be diagnosed with endometrial cancer in comparison to African-American women, the rate of mortality is higher for African-American women.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC00C993635B24D80A2867307C3B23362"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Currently, the cause of such disparity is unknown. Researchers are proposing investigative studies that link this disparity to the relationship between delays in care, aggressive late-stage diagnosis, and the time between diagnosis and beginning treatment protocol for their cancer type. These factors are often exacerbated by socioeconomic conditions that affect access to innovative treatment, treatment completion, patient-reported outcomes, and overall quality of life.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HF977763065CE4651BC5065325183DCA6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Expanding research and education with respect to endometrial cancer</header> <subsection id="HAB01361FCC8741C880737A1EBDBDE123"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National Institutes of Health</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part B of title IV of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/284">42 U.S.C. 284 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3933DA1E8BA043C7A76CF25CAA6271A9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE14FF30FB85742A09912F0F088745EC6"><enum>409K.</enum><header>Endometrial cancer</header> 
<subsection id="HEEB3C3E447C84267ACBDF3112B23E6E1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of NIH shall—</text> <paragraph id="H715330D84D9740E887B338AD705DF50F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expand, intensify, and coordinate programs to conduct and support research with respect to endometrial cancer;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF5BBF418768E4F84A516DBF03229BE0D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>communicate to medical professionals and researchers, including through the endometrial cancer public education program established under section 399V–8, the disparity in the diagnosis of endometrial cancer between African-American women and non-Hispanic White women and any new research relating to endometrial cancer; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D6A2C73203047F9999614933A30E468"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that African-American women are represented in clinical trials conducted or supported by the National Institutes of Health with respect to endometrial cancer in appropriate proportion to incidence rates of such cancer for African-American women.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6D21CCA94382461EA08EEE275E469155"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination with other institutes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of NIH shall coordinate activities carried out by the Director pursuant to subsection (a) with similar activities carried out by—</text> <paragraph id="H5E17CB33B7C54EA085DB4343409CB878"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Director of the Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5BE2735E11FA49C9AF40507321DAA5DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Director of the National Institute on Minority Health and Health Disparities; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF835603DAEB44DB0B9D22FD3DCFA5500"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Director of the Office of Research on Women’s Health.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H89682EC82E024889BF0D00D07C11E4EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>For purposes of carrying out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2028.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H998C6E05DA3C4E8EB7D0D705DD8A87D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part P of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g">42 U.S.C. 280g et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33AB2B2034284AB8B7E648E7E13A7678" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H20C051AD6EC84F2BAB4797163E075366"><enum>399V–8.</enum><header>Endometrial Cancer Public Education Program</header> 
<subsection id="H745B285C40CE4DF99EF4B8168CE2C167"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall develop and disseminate to the public informational materials on endometrial cancer, including the incidence rate of such cancer, the risk factors for developing such cancer, the increased risk for ethnic minority women to develop such cancer, and the range of available treatments for such cancer. Any informational material developed pursuant to the previous sentence may be transmitted to a nonprofit organization; institution of higher education; Federal, State, or local agency; or media entity for purposes of disseminating such material to the public.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1995DE76CF9C42E9B67D86CFD8DABFB7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>The informational materials under subsection (a) shall include materials targeted toward African-American women.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H09DD3EB2F0D84F24830675491B9B9120"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing and disseminating informational materials under subsection (a), the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall consult with the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H70B30226A2B44863AB03D9971F465F22"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>For purposes of carrying out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2028.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

