<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H992600BF496A409181D44DBADED2AB69" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3812 IH: Stop Troubling Retroactive Invoices for Veteran Expenses Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3812</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250606">June 6, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000605">Mr. Gray</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to prohibit the collection of a health care copayment by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs from a veteran under certain conditions attributable to a failure of the Department of Veterans Affairs to process certain information within applicable timeliness standards, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HCA12CC7B8BF8495F8719D6EC484FB8E9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H317770C3536B444CB8FB5D0427BBDAE5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Troubling Retroactive Invoices for Veteran Expenses Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STRIVE Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H09C7A7F3135A4F56A4483F2B21DB9596"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on collection of health care copayments by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under certain conditions; authority of the Secretary to waive health care copayments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1730A of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9E8CB959FCD247F8888FC4B2AD642D3B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the heading and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">Prohibitions on collection of copayments under certain conditions</header-in-text> </quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HADFE1B8D692246EC96D4675FB26DF0F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9C53A9494DAA42B59C2AFD44129669E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC">Prohibition</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC">Prohibitions</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF4D867450C3E4BE28D4F41D69267C628"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the Secretary may not require</quote> and all that follows through the end of the subsection and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H2CB29D28D3394E519AE35D93501DE0FB" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary may not require—</text> <paragraph id="H8158384496754D1684AB2C1B2568529D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a covered veteran to make any copayment for the receipt of hospital care or medical services under the laws administered by the Secretary;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8758AA123E954E60B7AECCC7350CA449"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any veteran to make any copayment for the receipt of such hospital care or medical services after the end of the two-year period beginning on the date such veteran received such hospital care or medical services if the failure of the veteran to make such copayment during such period is attributable to the failure of an employee, official, or information system of the Department to process information provided by or on behalf of the veteran within applicable timeliness standards established by the Secretary; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6CCA748FF8B4B19B27D3ADE691C6179" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any veteran to make a copayment in an amount that exceeds $2,000 for the receipt of such hospital care or medical services if the amount of such copayment is attributable to an error on the part of an employee, official, or information system of the Department. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCE80B75C149F4730BD6F38935491B848"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (b) as subsection (c); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H463BFACA83D84A4C9B3CF404D842181C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H2FC3246490104BB597AF71EEC4CEDA08" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HB516ABAC44004C98B78CA1915937E350"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may waive the requirement for a veteran to make any copayment for the receipt of such hospital care or medical services in any case in which the Secretary determines such a waiver would be appropriate, without regard to whether the veteran submits to the Secretary a request for such waiver.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

