<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7D6D3FF134A7486CB2C3DDED03A14296" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4018 IH: To unleash America’s offshore critical minerals and resources.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4018</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250617">June 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000235">Mr. Ezell</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To unleash America’s offshore critical minerals and resources.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC576824DC3DC4985A9DAFB5543FB8A23" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2FF37BDEDBEB4CF48F2093BB42E90DB2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HEC59B31C72634A46B81DE58427989F4C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States has a core national security and economic interest in maintaining leadership in deep sea science and technology and seabed mineral resources.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H561B47F2333E4C3DA516B9BB2AD4C32D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The United States faces unprecedented economic and national security challenges in securing reliable supplies of critical minerals independent of foreign adversary control.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8135745A9E25478C999390A8771093DB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Vast offshore seabed areas hold critical minerals and energy resources.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H04C2E6CE4A0D481A93916F1EA2069EE9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>These resources are key to strengthening our economy, securing our energy future, and reducing dependence on foreign suppliers for critical minerals.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA0DE45C14F1844569288E9A1BB2F72AC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The United States also controls seabed mineral resources in one of the largest ocean areas of the world.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H56D9D225B70D47B7AB2FBBAFF36C3B63"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Our Nation can, through the exercise of existing authorities and by establishing international partnerships, access potentially vast resources in seabed polymetallic nodules, other subsea geologic structures, and coastal deposits containing strategic minerals such as nickel, cobalt, copper, manganese, titanium, and rare earth elements, which are vital to our national security and economic prosperity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H41D8AB2E764B4B13849C484ADDBB2458"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Our Nation must take immediate action to accelerate the responsible development of seabed mineral resources, quantify the Nation’s endowment of seabed minerals, reinvigorate American leadership in associated extraction and processing technologies, and ensure secure supply chains for our defense, infrastructure, and energy sectors.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF0919E73B28F4C45880DE18509809794"><enum>(8)</enum><text>It is the policy of the United States to advance United States leadership in seabed mineral development by—</text> <subparagraph id="HC10B3539788F4BC89F22953BCCA67DC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rapidly developing domestic capabilities for the exploration, characterization, collection, and processing of seabed mineral resources through streamlined permitting without compromising environmental and transparency standards;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6D33ADA6897740F4A3E4543ECFD9071C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supporting investment in deep sea science, mapping, and technology;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H242E85518B6342BB919A0F8E6035816D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enhancing coordination among executive departments and agencies with respect to seabed mineral development activities described in this Act;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H942CC0579A0749E0834B07403FEEBD37"><enum>(D)</enum><text>establishing the United States as a global leader in responsible seabed mineral exploration, development technologies, and practices, and as a partner for countries developing seabed mineral resources in areas within their national jurisdictions, including their exclusive economic zones;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H56F654C652F14D929B2C2555381853FE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>creating a robust domestic supply chain for critical minerals derived from seabed mineral resources to support economic growth, reindustrialization, and military preparedness, including through new processing capabilities; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H78BA0C7DB773407E91A9E9C98DA57ED9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>strengthening partnerships with allies and industry to counter China’s growing influence over seabed mineral resources and to ensure United States companies are well-positioned to support allies and partners interested in developing seabed minerals responsibly in areas within their national jurisdictions, including their exclusive economic zones.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H537397C903DE40AD9E7C973E4DE44BFF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Strategic seabed critical mineral access</header> <subsection id="H6907F17342014892A0BB315BABD73E0E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expediting issuance of certain authorizations under Deep Seabed Hard Mineral Resources Act</header> <paragraph id="H581394E2B5DF4425B9E400F36142089A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and in consultation with the Secretary of State and Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management, shall expedite the process for reviewing and issuing licenses for exploration and permits for commercial recovery under the Deep Seabed Hard Mineral Resources Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1401">30 U.S.C. 1401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H000D95D7255C4B228D6AAD13D21E76B1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In expediting the process described in paragraph (1), the entities described in that paragraph shall ensure efficiency, predictability, and competitiveness for United States companies.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H903E5261689D42648628D57C8A6958EE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expediting issuance of certain authorizations under Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act</header> <paragraph id="H7693779864DC478484A5E52B59591C8F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior shall establish an expedited process for reviewing and approving permits for prospecting and granting leases under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331 et seq.</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA76DFFA3F9C04AA387CB2EB057D05212"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The expedited process established under paragraph (1) shall ensure efficiency, predictability, and competitiveness for United States companies.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBEB763F5F3A840F4955898B4B0A89EBB"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Seabed mapping plan</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Secretary of State, Secretary of Commerce, and heads of other relevant Federal agencies, and in cooperation with commercial and other nongovernmental organizations, shall develop a plan to map priority areas of the seabed United States outer Continental Shelf, to include extended areas of the outer Continental Shelf, such as those with abundant or accessible seabed mineral resources, to accelerate data collection and characterization.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3F3F958C383D4A46B9E612D33140AA77"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Identification of certain critical minerals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior—</text> <paragraph id="H66D25CDA4DC140AC9829112DBAEAA518"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall identify which critical minerals may be derived from seabed mineral resources; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEB0D77725DF34CE7B6DDDB89925507F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and Secretary of Energy, determine which critical minerals derived from seabed mineral resources are essential for applications such as defense infrastructure, manufacturing, and energy.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H468A4ACB895D4E67842BADBD7765E935" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Engagement with key partners and allies</header> <paragraph id="HDDEFC5AA1A5B4254ADD308D6875DD3D8" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce, in coordination with the Secretary of State, Secretary of the Interior, and Secretary of Energy, shall engage with key partners and allies to offer support for seabed mineral resource exploration, extraction, processing, and environmental monitoring in areas within the jurisdictions of such key partners and allies, including by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4C780C30EA334214921BC8B64FA07F99" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seeking scientific collaboration and commercial development opportunities for United States companies; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC2E6BD94B4634B0AA4DD31985B59C7CF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>developing a prioritized list of foreign countries for engagement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCD2524E0DBC34E44A65D8FDC5B6D62A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Key partner or ally determination</header> 
<subparagraph id="H9CAC02E886564269A2C7FA0D8CA45B70"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State shall determine whether an entity is a key partner or ally for the purposes of this Act, based on factors such as—</text> <clause id="H37B32EC71CC645C3863D98B31AE0FBEE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>existing agreements with the United States;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD30BDFB1C41D45989BAECB54B8907452"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>alignment with strategic interests of the United States; and</text></clause> <clause id="H233D901F13674B9FB1CB91CE01D06EA5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>participation in joint initiatives.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA1569258624E4E519B5E38F75294260A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>The Secretary of State shall notify the Secretary of Commerce, Secretary of the Interior, and Secretary of Energy of any determination made under subparagraph (A).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H28B8F8A5971545E1B4274649C4DC346F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1ADAA9D967A5421D8F9E81C33BD3E7D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior, in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce and Secretary of Energy, and in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Energy and Natural Resources and Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report that identifies private sector interest in and opportunities for seabed mineral resource exploration and mining on the outer Continental Shelf, in areas beyond national jurisdiction, and in areas within the jurisdiction of a foreign country that expresses interest in partnering with United States companies with respect to seabed mineral resource development; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H43ECB01D1BCC4D92A95E327FA680F389"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of the Interior, jointly with the Secretary of State, Secretary of Commerce, and Secretary of Energy, shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Energy and Natural Resources and Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report regarding the feasibility of an international benefit-sharing mechanism for seabed mineral resource extraction and development that occurs in an area beyond the jurisdiction of any country.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
<section id="HBCD4486B4894428C879CD04940C8A1E3"><enum>3.</enum><header>General provisions</header> 
<subsection id="H88B8D5E5D9EC489C9D7CB92775159BF0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H185C8AAC0F2A4C46B7FACA38F7E0A083"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No creation of right or benefit</header><text>This Act does not create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, entities, officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD49859829A8E496D86E3D7F0398E1DE1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HD6921B3005EE40D6B6CA91BA05BB77E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commercial recovery</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>commercial recovery</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Deep Seabed Hard Mineral Resources Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1403">30 U.S.C. 1403</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFB3E28CFFDF7478B9167751EC7CEC2D1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Critical mineral</header><text>The term <term>critical mineral</term> has the meaning given the term in section 7002(a)(3) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(a)(3)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBCA57D0A1F0F4807B860FFF692762A8C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exploration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>exploration</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Deep Seabed Hard Mineral Resources Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1403">30 U.S.C. 1403</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD11E855DBAFA4CA59BE80C78D61B871F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Lease</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>lease</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C35C9EA428F4FDD858D83DB31D6426C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Mineral</header><text>The term <term>mineral</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8738470E3F094A268DC2B7392BFCC1A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a critical mineral;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7479FB7FEFFA4B1EB080DAB1D642270B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>uranium;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6370401B1A7B4FDC92C54933AD6F1338"><enum>(C)</enum><text>copper;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H700057DE089C48488DB840303BB1B972"><enum>(D)</enum><text>potash;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA102F1E21CE6453BAD0D957AF7931EE6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>gold; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H119AAB304B2449B58EF6806E01526B51"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other element or compound the Chair of the National Energy Dominance Council determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF50800B216534B8F8021E75F9C8C0798"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Outer Continental Shelf</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>outer Continental Shelf</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D9F1A993ADA4B46970B568EB6389B70"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Processing</header><text>The term <term>processing</term> includes the concentration, separation, refinement, alloying, and conversion of minerals into usable forms.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA8005DDCF488436D83640AA2CE50F5E0"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Prospecting</header><text>The term <term>prospecting</term> has the meaning given the term <term>geological and geophysical (G&amp;G) prospecting activities</term> in section 580.1 of title 30, Code of Federal Regulations (or a similar successor regulation).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H22917A2EB88E4F71BA276EB97E6A6061"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Seabed mineral resource</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>seabed mineral resource</term> means a mineral-bearing material located in the seabed of the outer Continental Shelf, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H81BF08877FBD443D999F42F5ECF55C1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a polymetallic nodule;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H10C97CFBE75B4706A6FA29547FD8B7E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a cobalt-rich ferromanganese crust;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H270BDFBE42304AD9BAA9F27E752585A5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a polymetallic sulfide;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H34B4DBC059DB437BA557908A2B3E4663"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a heavy mineral sand; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC48D73A257954FA1A61EBAC981D87312"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a phosphorite.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31E95092FF454F019253A2847D97CE7E"><enum>(10)</enum><header>United States company</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>United States company</term> has the meaning given the term <term>United States citizen</term> in section 4 of the Deep Seabed Hard Mineral Resources Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1403">30 U.S.C. 1403</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

