<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H113A4F8E0E2D40718C5C7CA7B283D338" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 588 IH: Condemning the slogan “Globalize the Intifada” as a call to violence against Israeli and Jewish people across the world and urging United States national, State, and local leaders to condemn it as such.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 588</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000067">Mr. Yakym</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000300">Mr. Evans of Colorado</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris of Maryland</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning the slogan <quote>Globalize the Intifada</quote> as a call to violence against Israeli and Jewish people across the world and urging United States national, State, and local leaders to condemn it as such.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Arabic word <quote>intifada</quote> means <quote>uprising</quote> or <quote>shaking off</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas <quote>Intifada</quote> is commonly used to describe two periods of violent terrorism launched against Israel and Israeli citizens, with the First Intifada from 1987 to 1990 and the Second Intifada from 2000 to 2005;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the First Intifada and Second Intifada killed thousands of Israelis in terrorist attacks that included suicide bombings, shootings, stabbings, and other violence in passenger buses, restaurants, nightclubs, and other civilian areas;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on October 7, 2023, Hamas committed a barbaric terror attack on Israel and the Israeli people, killing and torturing civilians indiscriminately in their homes, as well as at a music festival and other civilian areas;</text></whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas, in the wake of the October 7, 2023 massacre, scores of pro-Hamas protests broke out worldwide, including in American cities and college campuses;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas many of these protests have prominently featured calls to <quote>Globalize the Intifada</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Anti-Defamation League characterizes the slogan <quote>Globalize the Intifada</quote> as <quote>generally understood as a call for indiscriminate violence against Israel, and potentially against Jews and Jewish institutions worldwide</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the American Jewish Committee characterizes the slogan <quote>Globalize the Intifada</quote> as <quote>often understood by those saying and hearing it as encouraging violence against Israelis, Jews, and institutions supporting Israel</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 2024, the Anti-Defamation League found 9,354 antisemitic incidents in the United States, which represents <quote>a 344-percent increase over the past five years and an 893-percent increase over the past ten years</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the American Jewish Committee defines anti-Zionism as a form of antisemitism <quote>when Jews are verbally or physically harassed or Jewish institutions and houses of worship are vandalized in response to actions of the State of Israel</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on April 13, 2025, an individual set multiple fires at the Pennsylvania Governor’s Residence while Governor Josh Shapiro and his family were inside following a Passover Seder;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the suspect admitted intent to cause harm motivated by hostility toward the Governor’s support for Israel and now faces charges including attempted murder, terrorism, and arson;</text></whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas, on May 21, 2025, two staff members at the Israeli Embassy, Yaron Lischinsky and Sarah Lynn Milgrim, were fatally shot outside the Capital Jewish Museum in Washington, DC;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas in announcing charges against the alleged perpetrator, the Department of Justice called this a <quote>targeted, antisemitic attack</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on June 1, 2025, in Boulder, Colorado, an antisemitic terrorist attack on a peaceful gathering supporting the return of hostages held by Hamas in Gaza resulted in the death of 82-year-old Karen Diamond and injuries to 12 others;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas charging documents indicate the alleged perpetrator targeted the peaceful gathering due to its connection to Israel, calling the organizers a <quote>Zionist Group</quote> and saying that he wanted to <quote>kill all the Zionist people</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States Holocaust Memorial Museum called it <quote>outrageous</quote> to link the slogan <quote>Globalize the Intifada</quote> with the 1943 Warsaw Ghetto Uprising; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas efforts have been made to downplay the slogan <quote>Globalize the Intifada</quote> as a call for Palestinian human rights: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HCE01097DF0564D05A27191D5AD3E80B7"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HB3A94F1CA8EA480A86A2D5B968179FD8"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA4E920D696234E248B6EFF3649D23B8E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the slogan, <quote>Globalize the Intifada</quote>, is a call for violence against Israeli and Jewish people across the world;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H311AC100376B458E8A36A4E9A163CA90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the slogan undermines the safety and security of Israeli and Jewish people in their communities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDDEF7216460B4F9F820D91AADE8F6C28"><enum>(3)</enum><text>those truly committed to Middle East peace should refrain from affirming, chanting, or displaying the slogan;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA60FCAD3CE3A42E387885C650E92DEF9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>organizers of demonstrations truly committed to Middle East peace should denounce participants that affirm, chant, or display the slogan; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2FFC3DC53A754338AFB286B5B07766CD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the slogan must be strongly and unequivocally condemned by national, State, and local leaders.</text></paragraph> </section> </resolution-body></resolution>

