<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3867223E77184DC5BFF3C24AB37887A2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3047 IH: To require the Director of the Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency for the District of Columbia and the Director of the Pretrial Services Agency for the District of Columbia to reside in the District of Columbia.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3047</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250428">April 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Director of the Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency for the District of Columbia and the Director of the Pretrial Services Agency for the District of Columbia to reside in the District of Columbia.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4477FF09834246DB9E9AF2FAAC141218" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H59C18A7FB76748278A466BFE016D03E3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>District of Columbia residency requirement for Director of Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency and Director of Pretrial Services Agency</header> 
<subsection id="HCBFE6092432D4A02B4EBCA91CDECE52A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Director of CSOSA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The second sentence of section 11233(b)(1) of the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997 (sec. 24–133(b)(1), D.C. Official Code) is amended by striking <quote>shall be compensated</quote> and inserting <quote>shall be a resident of the District of Columbia, shall be compensated</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF80EE1D4963C413B83DBC13F6CA0ED7D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Director of Pretrial Services Agency</header><text>Section 23–1304(b), District of Columbia Official Code, is amended by striking <quote>Columbia.</quote> and inserting <quote>Columbia and who shall be a resident of the District of Columbia.</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0CFF60F2FCFB4353850A5F464388BE63"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to each individual who is first appointed to serve as the Director of the Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency for the District of Columbia or the Director of the Pretrial Services Agency for the District of Columbia (as the case may be) on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

