<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EHF25608-PKL-MF-YF3"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1561 IS: Securing and Enabling Commerce Using Remote and Electronic Notarization Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code> 
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>S. 1561</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20250501">May 1, 2025</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To authorize notaries public to perform, and to establish minimum standards for, electronic notarizations and remote notarizations that occur in or affect interstate commerce, to require any Federal court to recognize notarizations performed by a notarial officer of any State, to require any State to recognize notarizations performed by a notarial officer of any other State when the notarization was performed under or relates to a public Act, record, or judicial proceeding of the notarial officer’s State or when the notarization occurs in or affects interstate commerce, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H967A2E40D9FF40E88DC570EA0B2734F9"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HD66D8FBCD2FB4E94AEBE72F226367E83"> <enum>1.</enum> <header>Short title</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing and Enabling Commerce Using Remote and Electronic Notarization Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SECURE Notarization Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H8FA71845A0ED46A68DCE3F6A3F0244EA"> <enum>2.</enum> <header>Definitions</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H48FE3B0F46684511B77C9B56031AFE57"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Communication technology</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>communication technology</term>, with respect to a notarization, means an electronic device or process that allows the notary public performing the notarization, a remotely located individual, and (if applicable) a credible witness to communicate with each other simultaneously by sight and sound during the notarization.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HEDB8BAF048064686B5E79672078AF878"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Electronic; electronic record; electronic signature; information; person; record</header> <text>The terms <term>electronic</term>, <term>electronic record</term>, <term>electronic signature</term>, <term>information</term>, <term>person</term>, and <term>record</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 106 of the Electronic Signatures in Global and National Commerce Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/7006">15 U.S.C. 7006</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4110BAA5597146FD8613CFBC5BF1B885"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Law</header> <text>The term <term>law</term> includes any statute, regulation, rule, or rule of law.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HA31EE6D5777740CABF69E6BBDE08E21F"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Notarial officer</header> <text>The term <term>notarial officer</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H26C2EDF28F2344E6A252BD040AB9E46D"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>a notary public; or</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD5F454E45FEC41BDA13ABFBDA43AB82C"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>any other individual authorized to perform a notarization under the laws of a State without a commission or appointment as a notary public.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H101022BD7D8F400BA7B12DD5320E7B3F"> <enum>(5)</enum> <header>Notarial officer’s State; notary public’s State</header> <text>The term <term>notarial officer’s State</term> or <term>notary public’s State</term> means the State in which a notarial officer, or a notary public, as applicable, is authorized to perform a notarization.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H59B363C408E340E2AA536684C8DF395A"> <enum>(6)</enum> <header>Notarization</header> <text>The term <term>notarization</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBDE8D4AD37C049BA9230B910AB95B1F6"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>means any act that a notarial officer may perform under—</text> <clause id="H8958B83ABACB4A528A5A42BBC3B65090"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>Federal law, including this Act; or</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H88C5FAA032C84C8CA4423D14049EACB2"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>the laws of the notarial officer's State; and</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE3554A8F45744B5B88EEBCDD7D23833B"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>includes any act described in subparagraph (A) and performed by a notarial officer—</text> 
<clause id="HD95EB272616A4B5490E3F6D37E267FAC"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>with respect to—</text> <subclause id="H56324207E4BE4A31B2F639E59D68B2DA"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>a tangible record; or</text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="HB9B499FDD9C2496288A428C1FD90D0BD"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text>an electronic record; and</text> </subclause> </clause> <clause id="H1A3CAA57807A482396B6D9FE257AE2CF"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>for—</text> 
<subclause id="HC23A9A62D01143FCBE3B3E3E6E8EF4DC"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>an individual in the physical presence of the notarial officer; or</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H8E292281C92045BE8D2D61A78A1BE005"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text>a remotely located individual.</text> </subclause> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H654C3030C0BE4DB2B0077268BF082BB7"> <enum>(7)</enum> <header>Notary public</header> <text>The term <term>notary public</term> means an individual commissioned or appointed as a notary public to perform a notarization under the laws of a State.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C9D7AF1BE514341A6ECDDF8A1CF18BE"> <enum>(8)</enum> <header>Personal knowledge</header> <text>The term <term>personal knowledge</term>, with respect to the identity of an individual, means knowledge of the identity of the individual through dealings sufficient to provide reasonable certainty that the individual has the identity claimed.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D67AED4601047B690CDED2CC61818D0"> <enum>(9)</enum> <header>Remotely located individual</header> <text>The term <term>remotely located individual</term>, with respect to a notarization, means an individual who is not in the physical presence of the notarial officer performing the notarization.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H9BFEDD862451452FB55963866C807F3A"> <enum>(10)</enum> <header>Requirement</header> <text>The term <term>requirement</term> includes a duty, a standard of care, and a prohibition.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H54B8BB7FF39E43A8A14DFCDFE463B2D4"> <enum>(11)</enum> <header>Signature</header> <text>The term <term>signature</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HAD2A80CB27224F08A93EF129B71883CF"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>an electronic signature; or</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD481988F86FC4655BBB7B6B0FE003685"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>a tangible symbol executed or adopted by a person and evidencing the present intent to authenticate or adopt a record.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HE211D539EF114621A6120A404B6052C0"> <enum>(12)</enum> <header>Simultaneously</header> <text>The term <term>simultaneously</term>, with respect to a communication between parties—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H204D37DFEFA94E6085AF1921D8682006"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>means that each party communicates substantially simultaneously and without unreasonable interruption or disconnection; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5D921586F9684C9B873E9F6A4DCF7255"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>includes any reasonably short delay that is inherent in, or common with respect to, the method used for the communication.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H006FA82074EE4A17B3F7FDFD0A18FAB0"> <enum>(13)</enum> <header>State</header> <text>The term <term>State</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H1C2DB8672FC14818939859F4D38C3FE0"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>means—</text> 
<clause id="HC2D7048DCEE54E6BBEB4E4E93A85C9F1"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>any State of the United States;</text> </clause> <clause id="H29184FECD22640F0A47A13D665B663DE"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>the District of Columbia;</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H85D59652F39F4672A019F123042E1720"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <text>the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico;</text> </clause> <clause id="H14F0BC9D253D4592B6945689E0E38927"> <enum>(iv)</enum> <text>any territory or possession of the United States; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H5A52371C71DD46739CE48F6A19BCAD89"> <enum>(v)</enum> <text>any federally recognized Indian Tribe; and</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H95711B126088410789FC5CFA7DAF05B7"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>includes any executive, legislative, or judicial agency, court, department, board, office, clerk, recorder, register, registrar, commission, authority, institution, instrumentality, county, municipality, or other political subdivision of an entity described in any of clauses (i) through (v) of subparagraph (A).</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </section> 
<section id="HBC24CCE6EA534ABABD41484C1731EBE5"> <enum>3.</enum> <header>Authorization to perform and minimum standards for electronic notarization</header> 
<subsection id="HC8D31E154B3D4B818943004609D13649"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Authorization</header> <text>Unless prohibited under section 10, and subject to subsection (b), a notary public may perform a notarization that occurs in or affects interstate commerce with respect to an electronic record.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H7ACF49C2707D453AB8C9C7489A6264F4"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Requirements of electronic notarization</header> <text>If a notary public performs a notarization under subsection (a), the following requirements shall apply with respect to the notarization:</text> 
<paragraph id="H63D8B8DCEADF41F28AEF17FEB722D1C3"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>The electronic signature of the notary public, and all other information required to be included under other applicable law, shall be attached to or logically associated with the electronic record.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H839B1E606C77484687487E885BFD80C6"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>The electronic signature and other information described in paragraph (1) shall be bound to the electronic record in a manner that renders any subsequent change or modification to the electronic record evident.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> </section> 
<section id="HBD704033DAFC458C9ACBC13696418BAB"> <enum>4.</enum> <header>Authorization to perform and minimum standards for remote notarization</header> 
<subsection id="HE90F9999CB864E7991D97FCFC7C71E42"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Authorization</header> <text>Unless prohibited under section 10, and subject to subsection (b), a notary public may perform a notarization that occurs in or affects interstate commerce for a remotely located individual.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HFFE8347A8D12440AA58F46AC5384E095"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Requirements of remote notarization</header> <text>If a notary public performs a notarization under subsection (a), the following requirements shall apply with respect to the notarization:</text> 
<paragraph id="H293C1CD7557742B090A790585488D31D"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>The remotely located individual shall appear personally before the notary public at the time of the notarization by using communication technology.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H761F8FA93AE74BB8884015DAF0B5BC2D"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>The notary public shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H52E3C069BFCD42FAB18B389937A77894"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>reasonably identify the remotely located individual—</text> <clause id="HF7639EF5D0DC437E86162E17709F4BFB"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>through personal knowledge of the identity of the remotely located individual; or</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H01CE1E3E677C4EB281BA412179FCC3A3"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>by obtaining satisfactory evidence of the identity of the remotely located individual by—</text> <subclause id="HB8EA253773D84958877077336E998FA8"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>using not fewer than 2 distinct types of processes or services through which a third person provides a means to verify the identity of the remotely located individual through a review of public or private data sources; or</text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="H1C6782ED022C45DF8FD56DE1833E6B68"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text>oath or affirmation of a credible witness who—</text> <item id="HD1999E80C98D4EF48AE7DE02F922ADB9"> <enum>(aa)</enum> <subitem commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H87D93921D1704E1C91609F3429B9646F"> <enum>(AA)</enum> <text>is in the physical presence of the notary public or the remotely located individual; or</text> </subitem> 
<subitem id="H8045911D58A047FABB6EBCBC4B3F5872" indent="up1"> <enum>(BB)</enum> <text>appears personally before the notary public and the remotely located individual by using communication technology;</text> </subitem> </item> <item id="HA74D571F4A8C4BF6899A72E2726DFFF8"> <enum>(bb)</enum> <text>has personal knowledge of the identity of the remotely located individual; and</text> </item> 
<item id="H7E2CA0CDEDCB4B46BF6A0CD849E6F998"> <enum>(cc)</enum> <text>has been identified by the notary public in the same manner as specified for identification of a remotely located individual under clause (i) or subclause (I) of this clause;</text> </item> </subclause> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H417EF785EE6049BFB625E444742FDC65"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>either directly or through an agent—</text> 
<clause id="H92BA1CA493104113992A62598C994510"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>create an audio and visual recording of the performance of the notarization; and</text> </clause> <clause id="H951992E2625E4847B55B355535F0702A"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>notwithstanding any resignation from, or revocation, suspension, or termination of, the notary public’s commission or appointment, retain the recording created under clause (i) as a notarial record—</text> 
<subclause id="HF3517658B6084E96B1C4F8F7D6C79CF0"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>for a period of not less than—</text> <item id="HE4D1DAE3A2754D2A8AB3994B65046C28"> <enum>(aa)</enum> <text>if an applicable law of the notary public’s State specifies a period of retention, the greater of—</text> 
<subitem id="H0ACDDEBF703D413394257D8A8EE64AFC"> <enum>(AA)</enum> <text>that specified period; or</text> </subitem> <subitem id="HD45F3FD9F8E2418780B846411A924C03"> <enum>(BB)</enum> <text>5 years after the date on which the recording is created; or</text> </subitem> </item> 
<item id="H692B8188E916468EADC194910CDD64A0"> <enum>(bb)</enum> <text>if no applicable law of the notary public’s State specifies a period of retention, 10 years after the date on which the recording is created; and</text> </item> </subclause> <subclause id="HBE4C65E1D66B4F02B2FC0AC809818C84"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text>if any applicable law of the notary public’s State governs the content, manner or place of retention, security, use, effect, or disclosure of the recording or any information contained in the recording, in accordance with that law; and</text> </subclause> </clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFAC6A5E3707A48508B0117F07F8A7B54"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>if the notarization is performed with respect to a tangible or electronic record, take reasonable steps to confirm that the record before the notary public is the same record with respect to which the remotely located individual made a statement or on which the individual executed a signature.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H4650E242196445939635F4ECEAE19806"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>If a guardian, conservator, executor, personal representative, administrator, or similar fiduciary or successor is appointed for or on behalf of a notary public or a deceased notary public under applicable law, that person shall retain the recording under paragraph (2)(B)(ii), unless—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC0619523E0E845D28969EDC3107E53EB"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>another person is obligated to retain the recording under applicable law of the notary public’s State; or</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAAFE6045C5B442BB8DD2AE346CB18818"> <enum>(B)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0D4F29BB702741D989AF6138E58A0E7D"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under applicable law of the notary public’s State, that person may transmit the recording to an office, archive, or repository approved or designated by the State; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H8CEF69CD7F63400A821A442974773549" indent="up1"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that person transmits the recording to the office, archive, or repository described in clause (i) in accordance with applicable law of the notary public’s State.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HC125689DE5194B798C41054298816252"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>If the remotely located individual is physically located outside the geographic boundaries of a State, or is otherwise physically located in a location that is not subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, at the time of the notarization—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H5136469B0587485EA1771ABA13719034"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the record shall—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H3A4E4FC1FAF0473292E4F9F9DABC851D"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>be intended for filing with, or relate to a matter before, a court, governmental entity, public official, or other entity that is subject to the jurisdiction of the United States; or</text> </clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H536786BD4FA447DABD6691A5A5740A6E"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>involve property located in the territorial jurisdiction of the United States or a transaction substantially connected to the United States; and</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H906CD821F2A6437CB48A2D25B1AF87CA"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>the act of making the statement or signing the record may not be prohibited by a law of the jurisdiction in which the individual is physically located.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H415B89C50DE349EBB02C2F149C6D0FB6"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Personal appearance satisfied</header> <text>If a State or Federal law requires an individual to appear personally before or be in the physical presence of a notary public at the time of a notarization, that requirement shall be considered to be satisfied if—</text> <paragraph id="H5096C7561E994FDEBC0337E5A89C4582"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>the individual—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAA5FA469EFF9456EAA0935A36BDEF07A"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>is a remotely located individual; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF50B108BA90948C7A2FE41D006421609"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>appears personally before the notary public at the time of the notarization by using communication technology; and</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD89A7A5468CE49CCA7E4F044375000F5"> <enum>(2)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3E106FE473A44620B00A7F396AEB22CF"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the notarization was performed under or relates to a public act, record, or judicial proceeding of the notary public’s State; or</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE78F0FFF4593490096D7C88DCB13ADE7" indent="up1"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>the notarization occurs in or affects interstate commerce.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> </section> 
<section id="HD630AD027AFA48FA9D8DC11154B7CE10"> <enum>5.</enum> <header>Recognition of notarizations in Federal court</header> 
<subsection id="HD66D89930B1E48D29298805D0A04A07E"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Recognition of validity</header> <text>Each court of the United States shall recognize as valid under the State or Federal law applicable in a judicial proceeding before the court any notarization performed by a notarial officer of any State if the notarization is valid under the laws of the notarial officer’s State or under this Act.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H80CD5E9999A64DC5A020B0869AC60604"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Legal effect of recognized notarization</header> <text>A notarization recognized under subsection (a) shall have the same effect under the State or Federal law applicable in the applicable judicial proceeding as if that notarization was validly performed—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD9CABD6B0258426599414EAE7457D1F2"> <enum>(1)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0AF917A8450045088241F4FCA7AA2075"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>by a notarial officer of the State, the law of which is applicable in the proceeding; or</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4FFCD61DE6714F26910EF6842B9ED493" indent="up1"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>under this Act or other Federal law; and</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37D03D3FD0714FC0837281AF0670FFD5"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>without regard to whether the notarization was performed—</text> <subparagraph id="HB13B359CE0E745BC8E0615738E5B81FC"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>with respect to—</text> 
<clause id="HE5AAB71235A84303ABA35C6A809F6924"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>a tangible record; or</text> </clause> <clause id="HE310876923844435883F74E7C9AF70A1"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>an electronic record; or</text> </clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6F52C7DB357843FE9F493D258EDFC339"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>for—</text> <clause id="H1A04D06A20814155AD9529D95280859C"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>an individual in the physical presence of the notarial officer; or</text> </clause> 
<clause id="HAF306462DF704E39B4F2546D62239F3A"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>a remotely located individual.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HD8BE6AC24E9544868C02DDF3247977B2"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Presumption of genuineness</header> <text>In a determination of the validity of a notarization for the purposes of subsection (a), the signature and title of an individual performing the notarization shall be prima facie evidence in any court of the United States that the signature of the individual is genuine and that the individual holds the designated title.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H13CCBFB7D4EA46B3AFF4A50ED9976377"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Conclusive evidence of authority</header> <text>In a determination of the validity of a notarization for the purposes of subsection (a), the signature and title of the following notarial officers of a State shall conclusively establish the authority of the officer to perform the notarization:</text> <paragraph id="HE41968C79DC24744B22DFF4680A16138"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>A notary public of that State.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H45D9F1E5DFB549929C29FA00C7E2D3C3"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>A judge, clerk, or deputy clerk of a court of that State.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> </section> <section id="HD0B34C31E03A493CB740EDCEF5DA5479"> <enum>6.</enum> <header>Recognition by State of notarizations performed under authority of another State</header> <subsection id="HCB44865A69DA446FB63F963E05C54AE7"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Recognition of validity</header> <text>Each State shall recognize as valid under the laws of that State any notarization performed by a notarial officer of any other State if—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA74C295A79AD43518E514E7AA0DC4BAB"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>the notarization is valid under the laws of the notarial officer’s State or under this Act; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A7148A573B4401E80A28DBAC7457215"> <enum>(2)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC6955DD6B9D140BFAE8B4EE65FD4BA7D"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the notarization was performed under or relates to a public act, record, or judicial proceeding of the notarial officer’s State; or</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5F51B60DF5DC4FE290FD7FEA8E431682" indent="up1"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>the notarization occurs in or affects interstate commerce.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HB89FCFA3FA9A4480B0C32C52E923DE36"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Legal effect of recognized notarization</header> <text>A notarization recognized under subsection (a) shall have the same effect under the laws of the recognizing State as if that notarization was validly performed by a notarial officer of the recognizing State, without regard to whether the notarization was performed—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC874D98197C64F7C8960973648D3B211"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>with respect to—</text> <subparagraph id="HB01013E6455E433EACE5B3FAE7C2BF2E"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>a tangible record; or</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7FD5C67D3BD54484800DC8278E8F44E3"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>an electronic record; or</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A834BC7E7D242C582E39D5F77A1AF26"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>for—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H842D3A19098643239CBB674B7517B644"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>an individual in the physical presence of the notarial officer; or</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5523EBBFA84948CF80139738243AB94F"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>a remotely located individual.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0014C2F279824C11995D2BE88F46CCB8"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Presumption of genuineness</header> <text>In a determination of the validity of a notarization for the purposes of subsection (a), the signature and title of an individual performing a notarization shall be prima facie evidence in any State court or judicial proceeding that the signature is genuine and that the individual holds the designated title.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HA3A8BEDDB3B64BC7992DBD1ADE203A86"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Conclusive evidence of authority</header> <text>In a determination of the validity of a notarization for the purposes of subsection (a), the signature and title of the following notarial officers of a State shall conclusively establish the authority of the officer to perform the notarization:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF40EA61B28F44CF1B2571AC5C3DE8A72"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>A notary public of that State.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H23651CCA689648BC8BBEF2DD36BD4863"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>A judge, clerk, or deputy clerk of a court of that State.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> </section> 
<section id="H15E778003CB449C6B2BBB25D1848312B"> <enum>7.</enum> <header>Electronic and remote notarization not required</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to require a notary public to perform a notarization—</text> <paragraph id="HD86B159C9514421D8A5F246A0F4411CF"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>with respect to an electronic record;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H16C1B16F6F674FA0A7EE46A8B2F9614A"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>for a remotely located individual; or</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H786D9CC0FA284901A922400AE36BC98B"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>using a technology that the notary public has not selected.</text> </paragraph> </section> 
<section id="H9BFE37748FE04A9680CE6369CECC075D"> <enum>8.</enum> <header>Validity of notarizations; rights of aggrieved persons not affected; State laws on the practice of law not affected</header> 
<subsection id="HB481E7BC929B4F6C9FEBCDD7BAD106FD"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Validity not affected</header> <text>The failure of a notary public to meet a requirement under section 3 or 4 in the performance of a notarization, or the failure of a notarization to conform to a requirement under section 3 or 4, shall not invalidate or impair the validity or recognition of the notarization.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HAF79C87F2AC64DEB82C46630B904F6DB"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Rights of aggrieved persons</header> <text>The validity and recognition of a notarization under this Act may not be construed to prevent an aggrieved person from seeking to invalidate a record or transaction that is the subject of a notarization or from seeking other remedies based on State or Federal law other than this Act for any reason not specified in this Act, including on the basis—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8ECDB5A6A5F6471E88E066070BE64DD6"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>that a person did not, with present intent to authenticate or adopt a record, execute a signature on the record;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HEBAF4CA68CB942CC88BD7242770D7DA5"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>that an individual was incompetent, lacked authority or capacity to authenticate or adopt a record, or did not knowingly and voluntarily authenticate or adopt a record; or</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9801CB43A27B4D5C8353FE40286D9786"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>of fraud, forgery, mistake, misrepresentation, impersonation, duress, undue influence, or other invalidating cause.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H1F93A8AAD74C4B5087FB93F62AF4F220"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Rule of construction</header> <text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to affect a State law governing, authorizing, or prohibiting the practice of law.</text> </subsection> </section> 
<section id="HBEC1918F1EE94186AD4AD6773A59B9DE"> <enum>9.</enum> <header>Exception to preemption</header> 
<subsection id="H4B205206C2334AA09C26B6751498BA8F"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>A State law may modify, limit, or supersede the provisions of section 3, or subsection (a) or (b) of section 4, with respect to State law only if that State law—</text> <paragraph id="HCDE26C12B68E4BE4AD4A4D1B2CCDAEA5"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>either—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9A90297A2F004FEFB3E0E64C5D8C64AF"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">constitutes an enactment or adoption of the Revised Uniform Law on Notarial Acts, as approved and recommended for enactment in all the States by the National Conference of Commissioners on Uniform State Laws in 2018 or the Revised Uniform Law on Notarial Acts, as approved and recommended for enactment in all the States by the National Conference of Commissioners on Uniform State Laws in 2021, except that a modification to such Law enacted or adopted by a State shall be preempted to the extent such modification—</text> <clause id="HDE0DA20D15574B46BBDAF04DA915B994"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>is inconsistent with a provision of section 3 or subsection (a) or (b) of section 4, as applicable; or</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H1E1E118A606D4C63AF04422DFF1EF269"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>would not be permitted under subparagraph (B); or</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H823C2F463FA549A7A057E9E131DFF6F6"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>specifies additional or alternative procedures or requirements for the performance of notarizations with respect to electronic records or for remotely located individuals, if those additional or alternative procedures or requirements—</text> 
<clause id="HD7DE6E657E56406B8EE4236D94E6C392"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>are consistent with section 3 and subsections (a) and (b) of section 4; and</text> </clause> <clause id="H65D6B8A9088F464EAFBFFF7A58840793"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>do not accord greater legal effect to the implementation or application of a specific technology or technical specification for performing those notarizations; and</text> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H47435C56B0F340ED87DF3478D0D66FAA"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>requires the retention of an audio and visual recording of the performance of a notarization for a remotely located individual for a period of not less than 5 years after the recording is created.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H352B0C24EE3C4FC4BA0A3806BE04F889"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Rule of construction</header> <text>Nothing in section 5 or 6 may be construed to preclude the recognition of a notarization under applicable State law, regardless of whether such State law is consistent with section 5 or 6.</text> </subsection> </section> 
<section id="H9D86E80B26B8478D97B02B7D9F028419"> <enum>10.</enum> <header>Standard of care; special notarial commissions; false advertising</header> 
<subsection id="H71A90D8CB0524A0AA52FE3DF5FA2A00D"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>State standards of care; authority of State regulatory officials</header> <text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to prevent a State, or a notarial regulatory official of a State, from—</text> <paragraph id="HE9BB75882C254F2E9709E5A406C53704"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>adopting a requirement in this Act as a duty or standard of care under the laws of that State or sanctioning a notary public for breach of such a duty or standard of care;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H41A8CB024C494EF1A2A25BEAF3ED8119"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>establishing requirements and qualifications for, or denying, refusing to renew, revoking, suspending, or imposing a condition on, a commission or appointment as a notary public;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF67483EA19384E6ABBB8F4CFC37D747E"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>creating or designating a class or type of commission or appointment, or requiring an endorsement or other authorization to be received by a notary public, as a condition on the authority to perform notarizations with respect to electronic records or for remotely located individuals; or</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H51E0691CC42047EAA8C044F7A986E73E"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>prohibiting a notary public from performing a notarization under section 3 or 4 as a sanction for a breach of duty or standard of care or for official misconduct.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H43D56C2CA5DE4850BD6325618F461BBC"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Special commissions or authorizations created by a State; sanction for breach or official misconduct; false advertising</header> <text>A notary public may not perform a notarization under section 3 or 4 if any of the following applies:</text> 
<paragraph id="H307A910F42034D1BB6EFBEDB41AB9DF3"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>The notary public’s State has enacted a law that creates or designates a class or type of commission or appointment, or requires an endorsement or other authorization to be received by a notary public, as a condition on the authority to perform notarizations with respect to electronic records or for remotely located individuals, and—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB31BB49D3D374CC3805A2F184963FB30"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the commission or appointment of the notary public is not of that class or type; or</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H22DBF88168F2401AAFEA5201B4F06035"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the notary public has not received the endorsement or other authorization.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCDA237458B3D43BDA9456A0B12B48CB0"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>The notarial regulatory official of the notary public’s State has prohibited the notary public from performing the notarization as a sanction for a breach of duty or standard of care or for official misconduct.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9CF2748619B7422DAEE04619023A3B77"> <enum>(3)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H56D8D66C4E8842D3AB9864B81468AAA3"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>The notary public has engaged in false or deceptive advertising.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H05AB2EF4695D4BC3B2A87491DD46E96D"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>For the purposes of subparagraph (A), a notary public shall be considered to have engaged in false or deceptive advertising if the notary public (unless the notary public is an attorney licensed to practice law in a State)—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE59F85A9015D4EBDB038A88755ACAFF6"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>uses the term <quote>notario</quote> or <quote>notario publico</quote>; or</text> </clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEDCAA5FEF3B641518D8F93FC83B5DD57"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>states or represents in a record offering commercial notarial services that the notary public is authorized to—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F7ADAC2A9E04465A3E007973B337C65"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>assist in drafting legal records, give legal advice, or otherwise practice law;</text> </subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H38C04D130B324CEE8F2F9ABFFB264BED"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text>act as an immigration consultant or an expert on matters pertaining to immigration;</text> </subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB40A1819837747B18742A2E31195A268"> <enum>(III)</enum> <text>represent a person in a judicial or administrative proceeding relating to immigration to the United States, United States citizenship, or related matters; or</text> </subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7CEF7A27E1D645A58C261886009E1906"> <enum>(IV)</enum> <text>receive compensation for performing any activity described in this subparagraph.</text> </subclause> </clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="HBB6C9A9F71034AD9B2691316C60FEC5F"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>For the purposes of a notarization performed by a notary public under section 4 for a remotely located individual, if a record executed by the remotely located individual attests that the notary public disclosed to the individual the prohibitions under this paragraph, and that the notary public did not make any statement or representation in violation of this paragraph, that record shall conclusively establish compliance by the notary public with the requirements of this paragraph, as of the date on which the individual executes that record.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> </section> <section commented="no" id="H18CA04793A8047968DA3167A1B0CB094"> <enum>11.</enum> <header>Severability</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance is held to be invalid or unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act and the application of the provisions thereof to other persons or circumstances shall not be affected by that holding.</text> </section> 
</legis-body>
</bill>


