<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H01E63E39F0564253A761022C80D290A5" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 393 IH: Providing for consideration of the joint resolution (H. J. Res. 73) relating to a national emergency by the President on February 1, 2025.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 393</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250506">May 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing for consideration of the joint resolution (H. J. Res. 73) relating to a national emergency by the President on February 1, 2025.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H0DF6506D3FBF4E6C87022356C9DF5ACA"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H9B619CF32F084632B49129A800B7EB7D"><text>That immediately upon adoption of this resolution, the House shall proceed to the consideration in the House of the joint resolution (H. J. Res. 73) relating to a national emergency by the President on February 1, 2025. All points of order against consideration of the joint resolution are waived. The joint resolution shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the joint resolution are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the joint resolution and on any amendment thereto to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Foreign Affairs or their respective designees; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text></section> <section id="HBA1BD77B436445719902828176844BE1"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clause 1(c) of rule XIX and clause 8 of rule XX shall not apply to the consideration of H. J. Res. 73.</text></section> 
<section id="H19EC5EB2E85F4D79A40A63F39E2C03CD"><enum>3.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Clerk shall transmit to the Senate a message that the House has passed H. J. Res. 73 no later than one week after passage.</text></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

