<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP25828-PPT-52-S5F"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2585 IS: Modernization, Accountability, and Planning for Broadband Funding Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2585</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250731">July 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To modernize and improve the Broadband Funding Map in order to promote the most efficient use of Federal funds for broadband deployment, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Modernization, Accountability, and Planning for Broadband Funding Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>MAP for Broadband Funding Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idd86060ea76d44b46b0b39e8bd5482593"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idae2fe2a7b2a448158e28768f89b022b5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id612424534eb54b2690678c3466afebf7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate</committee-name>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id309438494fa941e6b3bfcbb8a3ee8ab8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id26569e0ea7394b1f8000e2e397de66cb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Broadband Funding Map</header><text>The term <term>Broadband Funding Map</term> means the Deployment Locations Map, as defined in section 60105(a) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1704">47 U.S.C. 1704(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0fd3120dbbc8413e8df2a34851213f28"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Broadband infrastructure</header><text>The term <term>broadband infrastructure</term> has the meaning given that term in section 60105(a) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1704">47 U.S.C. 1704(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idae27cae7f7fa4b92b578626de8fe0671"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Communications Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9a33efccae5b4d48b05a933183e4ed52"><enum>(5)</enum><header>NTIA</header><text>The term <term>NTIA</term> means the National Telecommunications and Information Administration.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id7247f1e5d97041289a15ae6095a49028"><enum>3.</enum><header>Broadband Funding Map modernization</header><subsection id="id2db0cf32357942ea83cd1b7ea2671d53"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission, in coordination with NTIA, shall collect data submitted for the Broadband Funding Map by relevant Federal agencies on a reasonable and timely basis pursuant to section 60105(d) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1704">47 U.S.C. 1704</external-xref>), in order to promote the most efficient use of Federal funds for broadband deployment and prevent redundant overbuilding of broadband infrastructure with Federal funding.</text></subsection><subsection id="idcfd1f793944a4518982910e97fc122c6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inquiry</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id29e1c7b825ef466f85fd1ef6f2f3b0d1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice of inquiry</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall initiate a notice of inquiry concerning the optimum functionality and transparency of the Broadband Funding Map, including the quality and completeness of the data populated to the Broadband Funding Map.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id72d0704b86e04ca9bb5c8820ee136eac"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluation considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the inquiry, the Commission shall include evaluation of the following considerations:</text><subparagraph id="ida993b59954104d31878ab4777de5254c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The adequacy with which Federal agencies have been able to collect and submit the required categories of data pursuant to section 60105(d) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1704">47 U.S.C. 1704</external-xref>) to date.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbd5231b28ab94ba1a324029f667eb19c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The usability of such existing categories of data described in subparagraph (A) to the public, and whether any category should be added, eliminated, or otherwise altered for improved user experience.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2e1b144aae444ff99800e9209c8b275b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The timeliness of periodic updates from Federal agencies to the Broadband Funding Map described in subparagraph (A) pursuant to section 60105(e) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1704">47 U.S.C. 1704</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc7799a1c230e47838e52080863abc975"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Whether the scope of programmatic data to be reported to the Broadband Funding Map pursuant to section 60105(d)(1) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1704">47 U.S.C. 1704</external-xref>) should be expanded.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc02c8a54524d4c159f8bd726896eb966"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any manners in which the Commission should potentially augment or streamline the Broadband Funding Map with existing Commission mapping tools.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1150a76bff6f4f928cc804128209e3c4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Completion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the initiation of the inquiry under paragraph (1), the Commission shall complete the inquiry.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id4ee3025de00f44868baef69d7edb2a52"><enum>4.</enum><header>GAO Study and Report</header><subsection id="id543fa0c20bea4be398cfc794db799f3b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller of the United States shall—</text><paragraph id="id8dcfd5f7f1ee4442a9ea25b14e3d9ad0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a study on the roles, responsibilities, and progress to date of Federal agencies to maintain the Broadband Funding Map and ensure the completeness and continued relevance of the Broadband Funding Map; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5a63248253554ab082f0b455bf5e3afd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the study under paragraph (1) that includes the findings and conclusions of the Comptroller General.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id76c6e91cccee44abae7458bcc8f7c8f9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In conducting the study required under subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall review the following:</text><paragraph id="id1550c82edbb74a2594a898cdd94f1677"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The extent to which each eligible Federal agency is submitting programmatic data to the Broadband Funding Map adequately and in compliance with section 60105 of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1704">47 U.S.C. 1704</external-xref>), including identification of any—</text><subparagraph id="ide654ed0218c943cf9bed000247147070"><enum>(A)</enum><text>successful best practices in submitting such data to the Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6c07bc6e2b3d4f39a054a62db346ca07"><enum>(B)</enum><text>challenges resulting in incomplete data submissions from an agency or individual program to the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6d1b8923f21e4f92977d82fa0cd9aab4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The proficiency of the Commission’s management of the Broadband Funding Map and related interagency collaboration.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddcd63e7bc0c94c95a8da1173e6693ba6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Whether the Commission has sufficient authority to collect the necessary data from Federal agencies to populate the Broadband Funding Map.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2247daf8192b47f590ecfb4a62d950fe"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The respective data collection efforts of NTIA pursuant to the ACCESS BROADBAND Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1307">47 U.S.C. 1307</external-xref>) and section 60105 of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1704">47 U.S.C. 1704</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd2aebb80e0804e98a25b101fd92a309e"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The effectiveness of coordination among the Commission, NTIA, and other relevant Federal agencies that provide funding for broadband infrastructure deployment, including the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and the Institute of Museum and Library Sciences, pursuant to section 60105(g) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1704">47 U.S.C. 1704</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc34aa9a7d86a4cb38c46e5b652b23454"><enum>(6)</enum><text>How enhanced use of the Broadband Funding Map across relevant Federal agencies could improve taxpayer savings.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

