<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H70224982C5E64A6A967C05AA097D6F14" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 512 IH: Expressing support for the designation of Sunday, June 15, 2025, as “Father’s Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 512</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of Sunday, June 15, 2025, as <quote>Father&#8217;s Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Father’s Day recognizes and raises awareness of the importance of fathers in the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Father’s Day was established in 1966 by then-President Lyndon Johnson issuing a proclamation setting aside the third Sunday in June to honor fathers;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Father’s Day has been celebrated annually since 1972, when then-President Richard Nixon signed a law making it a permanent national holiday;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, throughout the history of the United States, whether in their homes, workplaces, schools, and communities, fathers have fought for themselves, their families, and all people of the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 6 in 10 adult men in the United States are fathers;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas 29,000,000 of these fathers are also grandfathers;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas fathers are just as likely as mothers to say that parenting is extremely important to their identity;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, since 1965, fathers in the United States have nearly tripled the time they spend caring for children;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas there are 3,050,000 men who are <quote>solo</quote> fathers to a minor;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas children with involved loving fathers are significantly more likely to do well in school, and exhibit greater emotional security, curiosity, and math and verbal skills;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas toddlers with involved fathers go to school with higher levels of academic readiness, and they are more patient when handling stress associated with attending school;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the positive impacts of having an engaged father persist into adolescence and adulthood, resulting in higher intellectual functioning, better verbal skills, and higher academic achievement;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas children with involved fathers have higher self-esteem and fewer behavioral problems at school;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas fathers who take 2 or more weeks off after the birth of a child are more involved in that child’s direct care 9 months after birth than fathers who take no leave;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas a father’s involvement in his newborn’s care in the first 6 months can mean both mother and baby sleep better;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas a mother’s income rises 7 percent for each month of leave their child’s father takes;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas policies that provide support to fathers ensure that families and children thrive while also benefiting fathers’ physical and mental health;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas universal paid family and medical leave will give fathers the freedom to care for themselves and their loved ones;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas affordable, accessible, high-quality child care with family sustaining wages for early educators will help fathers support their children’s healthy development;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas a permanent, fully inclusive, monthly child tax credit will put consistent resources into the hands of fathers caring for children; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Sunday, June 15, 2025, will be widely celebrated across the United States as <quote>Father’s Day</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="HBDF9AFDA1F7748869D5F732023FD99E3"> <section id="H83B09BEAE1AB4AE4947B998BFB78F7C6" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="H967E8097FA4F40848FD0BCC786486BB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the role of fathers in the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF71D98F1C0C471F8A5A4457F0EE853B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>urges support for universal paid family and medical leave, affordable, accessible, high-quality child care, and a permanent, fully inclusive, monthly child tax credit;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5AAE81050BDD48FD967F7B24052651C0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>acknowledges that fathers can, and should, be celebrated and supported as an integral part of families, communities, workplaces, and society; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71825F6B56134278973D346CBD8DC8B6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports the designation of a <quote>Father’s Day</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

