<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA2A1CBA239564EC3991CFB02C30C0A9C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4791 IH: Keep USGS Strong Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4791</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250729">July 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To exempt the United States Geological Survey from hiring freezes or reductions in force, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H76A394CC3FAF4C0E9B4253CB80207E6C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H13FAADB53906450B9858B0F5DB660C55" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Keep USGS Strong Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1B95F1412CD640F0BB50C038C9B8D05C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H0EE892E06FEA48F0A801B52ADCB8AD4E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>United States Geological Survey (USGS) plays a critical role in advancing our understanding of the natural environment through its extensive research and data collection efforts.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H584EDF8ED53E4448BB809C1B499AB7CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The USGS plays a vital role in studying the Great Lakes, which contain 20 percent of the world’s freshwater. Through monitoring water quality, invasive species, and ecosystem health, USGS research informs efforts to protect and restore these critical resources. Their work supports fisheries management, pollution control, and the mitigation of threats such as harmful algal blooms, ensuring the long-term sustainability of the Great Lakes for millions of residents.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H62A6647BF8554214B4DB3D70B3E90230"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The USGS operates a comprehensive nationwide seismic network that continuously monitors earthquake activity. This data is essential for assessing seismic hazards, informing building codes, and enhancing public safety through early warning systems.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H76C826365760470BA7D2CCE8D056BC6F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Through detailed monitoring of surface water and groundwater resources, the USGS provides vital information on water availability, quality, and trends. This supports water resource planning and sustainable management across diverse regions, especially in drought-prone and rapidly urbanizing areas.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3A553719783B4C0FB2093D7CAA25812A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The USGS’s topographic and thematic maps, along with its geospatial datasets, are fundamental tools used by government agencies, researchers, and the public. These resources support land use planning, environmental conservation, and disaster response.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H64309784B62E4F4494D0A99F137FC9C3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Beyond earthquakes, the USGS conducts extensive research on other natural hazards such as volcanoes, landslides, and floods. Their work helps predict and mitigate the impacts of these events, thereby reducing risks to communities.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H55283ACBF62640BC85057F4C5F9DD394"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The USGS leads long-term monitoring of ecosystems, wildlife habitats, and environmental health. This research informs conservation efforts and policies aimed at protecting biodiversity and natural resources.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6EEA6FD5A6EA49089A0E996B34042DFC"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The USGS assesses the availability and environmental impact of mineral and energy resources, contributing to the sustainable development of these critical materials.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H18C19F1AB8C945B18D0831007D31251B"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The USGS serves everyday Americans by providing essential scientific information that directly impacts their safety, health, and quality of life. From monitoring earthquakes and floods to ensure timely warnings and disaster preparedness, to tracking water quality and availability that affects drinking water and agriculture, the USGS’s work touches many aspects of daily life.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F38384CE68B4515B55672C6BC9447D3"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Their mapping and geospatial data help communities plan infrastructure and manage natural resources effectively, while their research on ecosystems supports conservation efforts that preserve recreational areas and wildlife. By making this data openly accessible, the USGS empowers individuals, local governments, and businesses to make informed decisions that promote resilience and sustainability across the country.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6271CFA024D947CFB54EA0903D82B877"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The USGS’s multidisciplinary approach and commitment to open data ensure that policymakers, scientists, and the public have access to reliable, up-to-date information crucial for informed decision-making and risk management.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H69648F50FA154EB68AE1B4A4A0977B27"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exempting USGS from hiring freeze or reduction in force</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the United States Geological Survey (in this section referred to as <quote>USGS</quote>) shall not be subject to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEFF9B8A5081E483A9F575F9A12EADF55"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Presidential Memorandum issued on January 20, 2025, titled <quote>Hiring Freeze</quote> or any extension of such Memorandum;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA9B8BE1AD324FBB96BC6D862BEEA4A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any reduction in force of employees of USGS, or any other significant reduction of such employees, if Congress has enacted a law appropriating funds for the salary and expenses of such employees; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8C0E36B935514D19A5F3CF157D6DEA49"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any cancellation, without approval of the Director of USGS, of a lease of real property entered into by USGS.</text> </paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

