<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H849D10B3F9AA43ACA1E7563B8895C3F4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4042 IH: States Taking Accountability for Troops Engaged in Safety Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4042</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250617">June 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000829">Mr. Wied</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001098">Mr. Hamadeh of Arizona</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a State to reimburse the Federal Government for the deployment of the National Guard to such State.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4E88ECD9DC84422BB8D449C78A9788F3" style="OLC"><section id="HB3974BC983BC46149951FA170BF59172" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>States Taking Accountability for Troops Engaged in Safety Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STATES Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H112DC758CCD64463AF2629EBDC9E1AC5"><enum>2.</enum><header>National guard in Federal service</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12406 of title 10, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="HD4CC0CF29627459280BBCB23D5FDA84E" style="USC"><section id="H129D562336CE4FAC9514BC264AF3CA3F"><enum>12406.</enum><header>National guard in Federal service: call</header><subsection id="H792C921D13A34DE79D997FBC662889FF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Whenever—</text><paragraph id="HC0F8DF68EE1343649E2048090456674E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States, or any of the Commonwealths or possessions, is invaded or is in danger of invasion by a foreign nation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H816E60E5C1DB4E818AB067730CBB32AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>there is a rebellion or danger of a rebellion against the authority of the Government of the United States; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5384752E6E24172B02A9F6CF0047071"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the President is unable with the regular forces to execute the laws of the United States;</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">the President may call into Federal service members and units of the National Guard of any State in such numbers as he considers necessary to repel the invasion, suppress the rebellion, or execute those laws. Orders for these purposes shall be issued through the governors of the States or, in the case of the District of Columbia, through the commanding general of the National Guard of the District of Columbia.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="HA8D75F38D1014D4090E799C587597949"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adjustment of disbursements in certain circumstances</header><text>If the President—</text><paragraph id="HE394FF21BA4B46399F26385557A664D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>calls into Federal service members and units of the National Guard of any State in such numbers as he considers necessary to repel the invasion, suppress the rebellion, or execute those laws pursuant to subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D92B95626BB4F3FA0A01A12A1FFFC54"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">within 30 days of the conclusion of an action described in subsection (a), provides a determination to the Governor of the State in which the National Guard was called into Federal Service that the calling into service was the result of an action or act of negligence carried out by the State government;</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">the President shall direct the Secretary of Defense to coordinate with the Secretary of the Treasury, and any other appropriate officials or agencies, to determine the cost incurred to the Federal Government as a result of calling the National Guard into service, and shall, after notifying the Governor of the State, reduce funds made available to such State equal to 100 percent of the costs incurred by the Federal Government.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="H7AA1496215C04E6A8903ECA23FC7A15D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the reimbursement requirement under this section in cases of extreme financial hardship to the State or when the deployment is primarily to protect Federal property or enforce Federal law, as determined by the President.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0C6CC7FC69A0439DA8F5697E872A358A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary of Defense may prescribe regulations to implement this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H92449769C18542889EEC254B2EAB687E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect retroactively on June 1, 2025, and apply to all National Guard deployments required thereafter.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

