<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE08579B3AF294C1EB873416903F3E1B4" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 359 IH: Supporting the mission and goals of National Fentanyl Awareness Day in 2025, including increasing individual and public awareness of the impact of fake or counterfeit fentanyl pills on families and young people.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 359</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250429">April 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001136">Mrs. McClain</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the mission and goals of National Fentanyl Awareness Day in 2025, including increasing individual and public awareness of the impact of fake or counterfeit fentanyl pills on families and young people.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas drug traffickers are mass-producing fake or counterfeit pills and falsely marketing them as legitimate prescription pills to deceive the people of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many fake or counterfeit pills are made to look like prescription name-brand opioids, stimulants, or anxiety medications;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas drug traffickers are using fake or counterfeit pills to exploit prescription drug misuse and the opioid crisis;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Drug Enforcement Administration (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>DEA</quote>) has observed a dramatic rise in the number of counterfeit pills containing not less than 2 milligrams of fentanyl, which is considered a deadly dose;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 5 out of every 10 pills with fentanyl tested by the DEA contain a potentially lethal dose;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas counterfeit pills may also contain fentanyl-related substances and methamphetamine;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the number of counterfeit pills with fentanyl seized by law enforcement agencies in 2024 was 60,000,000;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, including the nearly 8,000 pounds of fentanyl powder seized in 2024, total fentanyl seizures are equivalent to more than 377,000,000 lethal doses of fentanyl;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas fake or counterfeit pills have been identified in all 50 States and the District of Columbia;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas illicit fentanyl has also been detected in illicit drugs such as heroin, cocaine, MDMA (ecstasy and molly), and methamphetamine;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for the 12-month period ending in October 2024, more than 84,000 individuals in the United States died of drug-induced deaths, and more than 58,000 of those deaths involved illicit fentanyl and other synthetic opioids;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, over the last 20 years, drug-induced deaths among individuals 15 to 35 years of age have increased 5-fold, largely driven by the increase in illicit fentanyl drugs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for the 12-month period ending in June 2023, illicit fentanyl was involved in more deaths of individuals 55 years of age and under than any single other cause;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas fake counterfeit pills are easily accessible and often sold on social media and e-commerce platforms, making them accessible to teens and youth;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas illicit fentanyl is involved in more deaths of youths than all other drug types combined;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, between 2019 and 2021, drug overdose and poisoning deaths for individuals 14 to 18 years of age increased by 128 percent, a rate of increase which was 77 percentage points higher than the national rate and higher than the rate for any other 5-year age group;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, between 2019 and 2021, the number of deaths involving illicit fentanyl in drug overdose and poisoning deaths for individuals 14 to 18 years of age increased by 236 percent, a rate of increase which was 141 percentage points higher than the national rate and higher than the rate for any other 5-year age group over the age of 15;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since 2021, the annual number of drug overdose and poisoning deaths and those deaths involving illicit fentanyl in drug overdose and poisoning deaths for individuals 14 to 18 years of age has increased;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the 12-month period ending June 2023, illicit fentanyl was involved in 81 percent of drug-induced deaths of individuals between 14 and 23 years of age, compared to 70 percent of drug-induced deaths of individuals of all ages;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2024, only 65 percent of youth and 55 percent of teens in the United States were aware that fentanyl is being used to create counterfeit pills;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2024, only 55 percent of youth and 50 percent of teens considered themselves knowledgeable about fentanyl; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2024, there were 51,010 reported overdose deaths involving illicit fentanyl and other synthetic opioids: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HF61961A3A53C42048469F1D0ECE7B163"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H4A80560BBB10440E9B15F037751C5071"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HE1FCD4483B57464CB89A257F3316CBE1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the recognition and goals of National Fentanyl Awareness Day, which include increasing individual and public awareness of the impact of fake or counterfeit fentanyl pills on families and young people;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC829C663C734B358BC5540A4A6B657F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>applauds the work of Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies that work to combat the proliferation of counterfeit pills;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD4E0FD1A6254F3B97ADC5F88513B400"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages the use of existing authorities to proactively stop and prevent the spread of illicit counterfeit pills; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H570158680FCD46C8986D21DB813EE6BE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National Fentanyl Awareness Day</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

