<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL25853-H68-KD-DJV"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2429 IS: Stop the Scammers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2429</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250724">July 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr.
                    Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van
                    Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms.
                    Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr.
                    Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, and
                    <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>) introduced the following
                bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to ensure the Bureau
            of Consumer Financial Protection retains adequate resources to ensure fair, transparent,
            and competitive markets for financial products and services for consumers and to provide
 for whistleblower incentives and protection.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id5CA43C5AB5F44C2193759C9AE3A84344"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop the Scammers Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="id6209ae3081fe416bbb7935eaefcac16a"><enum>2.</enum><header>Bureau whistleblower incentives and protection</header><subsection id="idD1AE21647F3140DEAD944E3296026AFC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5481">12 U.S.C. 5481 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 1017 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEB1223196ABA49749A0BAC82E6343041"><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="idB7695F9EC7B94E2F8B594A21848AD35F"><enum>1017A.</enum><header>Whistleblower incentives and protection</header><subsection id="id813e1e225d4548a0bd2ee859a042215b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id05ddbada00bf47f189d2877ba12681ef"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrative proceeding or court action</header><text>The term <term>administrative proceeding or court action</term> means any judicial or administrative action brought by the Bureau that results in monetary sanctions exceeding $1,000,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb25fa1d5832e4cc9ad6ab7d22900d2b2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fund</header><text>The term <term>Fund</term> means the Consumer Financial Civil Penalty Fund established under section 1017(d)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9d7c44f2cd8a4d7eb3449e14d2c9990b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Monetary sanctions</header><text>The term <term>monetary sanctions</term> means, with respect to any administrative proceeding or court action, any monies, including penalties, disgorgement, restitution, interest, ordered to be paid or other amounts of relief obtained under section 1055(a)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b22dbef513a4e40b3fe840998739e6c"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Original information</header><text>The term <term>original information</term> means information that—</text><subparagraph id="ide083b3b04bdd43709cca91363450868b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is derived from the independent knowledge or analysis of a whistleblower;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id88633c8e841e400dbe569a9e2379df6c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not known to the Bureau from any other source, unless the whistleblower is the original source of the information;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id731aa9825bae49e49ee62e8e20fd2aed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not exclusively derived from an allegation made in a judicial or administrative hearing, in a governmental report, hearing, or from the news media, unless the whistleblower is a source of the information; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id55395daa516b45b2896be19db5ba6447"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is not exclusively derived from an allegation made in an audit, examination, or investigation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id45f8d873aa46415d87d70bbc4241d4ce"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Successful enforcement</header><text>The term <term>successful enforcement</term> includes, with respect to any administrative proceeding or court action brought by the Bureau, any settlement of such proceeding or action.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1d527971087b488f80b475392b94360f"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Whistleblower</header><text>The term <term>whistleblower</term> means any individual who provides, or 2 or more individuals acting jointly who provide, original information relating to a violation of Federal consumer financial law, consistent with any rule or regulation issued by the Bureau under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idcc4c523fa567488d8b3d7b18d735d3f3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Awards</header><paragraph id="id80c674f24b004059a7404b1ab48f23a0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any administrative proceeding or court action the Bureau, subject to regulations prescribed by the Bureau and subject to subsection (c), shall pay an award or awards to 1 or more whistleblowers who voluntarily provided original information that led to the successful enforcement of the covered administrative proceeding or court action in an aggregate amount equal to—</text><subparagraph id="id4e6e963bcf1847bb92248025186115d2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not less than 10 percent, in total, of the civil money penalties collected by the Bureau in the action; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb31a9298ed574573b500b2cc0b6e3f2d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not more than 30 percent, in total, of the civil money penalties collected by the Bureau in the action.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbaf96d6c201947aebdc9ca5ac2f3620a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payment of awards</header><text>Any amount paid under paragraph (1) shall be paid from the Fund.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd434e80b7e8841ce8165a0ea27197a5e"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Award minimum</header><text>If the Bureau collects less than $1,000,000 in civil money penalties in the action, the Bureau shall provide for an award to any single whistleblower equal to the greater of—</text><subparagraph id="idD66282CC13034BACA451BD5F9AEDE989"><enum>(A)</enum><text>10 percent of the civil money penalties collected; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id768D3F1CFB1449648722E10F6AE76EBA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$50,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4515837d247e490b920fecd1271653da"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determination of amount of award; denial of award</header><paragraph id="idaed761619755433aaabe464022c2964b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination of amount of award</header><subparagraph id="idd47754f7822c4f2e8cda3fbf91974938"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Discretion</header><text>The determination of the percentage amount of an award made under subsection (b) shall be in the discretion of the Bureau.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc9d849aad2da45dfb6e2b3242a3cdfd3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>In determining the percentage amount of an award made under subsection (b), the Bureau shall take into consideration—</text><clause id="id4a49bb6b50d44693a1ce47b83db86ab9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the significance of the information provided by the whistleblower to the successful enforcement of the administrative proceeding or court action;</text></clause><clause id="id58eac706340749a989e7313e935e50ce"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the degree of assistance provided by the whistleblower and any legal representative of the whistleblower in an administrative proceeding or court action;</text></clause><clause id="idefb3f14ec2a64098bef0589a9df14327"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the programmatic interest of the Bureau in deterring violations of Federal consumer financial law (including applicable regulations) by making awards to whistleblowers who provide information that leads to the successful enforcement of such laws; and</text></clause><clause id="ide9eae26e7e25425fb2704a2287267fba"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>such additional relevant factors as the Bureau may establish by rule or regulation, including the amount available in the Fund.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6982ede3bb7e4a489b684f59b8ad2e15"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Denial of award</header><text>No award under subsection (b) shall be made—</text><subparagraph id="idffbe34d8a25743369eea2676585cea90"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to any whistleblower who is, or was at the time the whistleblower acquired the original information submitted to the Bureau, a member, officer, or employee of an entity described in subclauses (I) through (V) of subsection (h)(1)(C)(i);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id34c0b02128da4be882dbe30671a8c4fd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to any whistleblower who is convicted of a criminal violation related to the administrative proceeding or court action for which the whistleblower otherwise could receive an award under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id51319ab9ba4b4eb59875d8419495a1a0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to any whistleblower who is found to be liable for the conduct in the administrative proceeding or court action, or a related action, for which the whistleblower otherwise could receive an award under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id679199846da745a588ef24f215cf55ca"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to any whistleblower who planned and initiated the conduct at issue in the administrative proceeding or court action for which the whistleblower otherwise could receive an award under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idda14989fb6b64caba4e10e21e92f5011"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to any whistleblower who submits information to the Bureau that is based on the facts underlying the administrative proceeding or court action previously submitted by another whistleblower; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id259066dd0cc046a0817cfa8a0fc6b799"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to any whistleblower who fails to submit information to the Bureau in such form as the Bureau may, by rule or regulation, require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id71eb4a8dc6c341f685bdbef64d9f7bcd"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Representation</header><paragraph id="id4ea7d8eaa5a045529e2c1cd0c1d9a02d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Permitted representation</header><text>Any whistleblower who makes a claim for an award under subsection (b) may be represented by counsel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id36ab7731cd5e4ff4a432cc49c3562994"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required representation</header><subparagraph id="id4305567d6a4c4583817a0c9a2ed127fa"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any whistleblower who anonymously makes a claim for an award under subsection (b) shall be represented by counsel if the whistleblower submits the information upon which the claim is based.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id92e1bcd0b05147cf830974307cdcc7d1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disclosure of identity</header><text>Prior to the payment of an award, a whistleblower shall disclose the identity of the whistleblower and provide such other information as the Bureau may require, directly or through counsel of the whistleblower.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc0d2cb73d8304b09b1d7a2ddcda76f14"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No contract necessary</header><text>No contract or other agreement with the Bureau is necessary for any whistleblower to receive an award under subsection (b), unless otherwise required by the Bureau by rule or regulation.</text></subsection><subsection id="idbde63edeb769456b99f0182254e68531"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Appeals</header><paragraph id="id22FFE9C7B5CF4F8981DF87269F123502"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any determination made under this section, including whether, to whom, or in what amount to make awards, shall be in the discretion of the Bureau. Any such determination, except the determination of the amount of an award if the award was made in accordance with subsection (b), may be appealed to the appropriate court of appeals of the United States not more than 30 days after the determination is issued by the Bureau.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB9A678D019374BC3A2079A67B89F10F2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scope of review</header><text>The court shall review the determination made by the Bureau in accordance with section 706 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc336ee93c11745ada6ffe2dff7116659"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than December 31 of each year, the Bureau shall transmit to the House Committee on Financial Services and the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs a report on the Bureau’s whistleblower award program under this section, including a description of the number of awards granted and the types of cases in which awards were granted during the preceding fiscal year.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc7a6162f7fbd48ed93fe0ab9afe81a5e"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Protection of whistleblowers</header><paragraph id="idf1f4cd943f2e4621b93da5b2061b63a8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><subparagraph id="id08eea4217356483391c463b57d4a93b2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C), the Bureau and any officer or employee of the Bureau, shall not disclose any information, including information provided by a whistleblower to the Bureau, which could reasonably be expected to reveal the identity of a whistleblower, except in accordance with the provisions of section 552a of title 5, United States Code, unless and until required to be disclosed to a defendant or respondent in connection with a public proceeding instituted by the Bureau or any entity described in subparagraph (C). For purposes of section 552 of title 5, United States Code, this paragraph shall be considered a statute described in subsection (b)(3)(B) of such section 552.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id750b0c6ca280498b990bc245ebc91799"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph is intended to limit the ability of the Attorney General to present such evidence to a grand jury or to share such evidence with potential witnesses or defendants in the course of an ongoing criminal investigation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfab2ebfbfa3c4805953d34d9236610a3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Availability to government agencies</header><clause id="idb4c3c4a274964c03b3559ff8ded2b3ab"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Without the loss of its status as confidential in the hands of the Bureau, all information referred to in subparagraph (A) may, in the discretion of the Bureau, when determined by the Bureau to be necessary or appropriate, be made available to—</text><subclause id="id4fa4376d8393439293aa66126c68d8d5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Department of Justice;</text></subclause><subclause id="id69c15bee02fd43cc87e4d8577a7c6ea2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an appropriate department or agency of the Federal Government, acting within the scope of its jurisdiction;</text></subclause><subclause id="id0169d302dba44845ba270e8dfa0bcfa9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a State attorney general in connection with any criminal investigation;</text></subclause><subclause id="idf9927a93f7a94ce0aace39882c02a12f"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>an appropriate department or agency of any State, acting within the scope of its jurisdiction; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idab3baf093fb74f0099c4142cbfa78a86"><enum>(V)</enum><text>a foreign regulatory authority.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idfb357a171e104f759113bc9421332e9d"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Maintenance of information</header><text>Each of the entities, agencies, or persons described in clause (i) shall maintain information described in that clause as confidential, in accordance with the requirements in subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5675c7a2e4a9466ca6e07ba1e155c48c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rights retained</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be deemed to diminish the rights, privileges, or remedies of any whistleblower under section 1057, any other Federal or State law, or under any collective bargaining agreement.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7d41952bba3a4579a95593d84dfcab9c"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rulemaking authority</header><text>The Bureau shall have the authority to issue such rules and regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to implement the provisions of this section consistent with the purposes of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="idf757d63dd0d04314be0ec490b58e0751"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Original information</header><text>Information submitted to the Bureau by a whistleblower in accordance with rules or regulations implementing this section shall not lose its status as original information solely because the whistleblower submitted such information prior to the effective date of such rules or regulations, provided such information was submitted after the date of enactment of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="id0afd0238dea845d6b0a3037593f2dabb"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Provision of false information</header><text>A whistleblower who knowingly and willfully makes any false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation, or who makes or uses any false writing or document knowing the same to contain any false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or entry, shall not be entitled to an award under this section and shall be subject to prosecution under section 1001 of title 18, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida3d30978a0d54c0a89aee655046f2efa"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Unenforceability of certain agreements</header><paragraph id="ide6eff181bc7e4bdabd27dc1324238dec"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No waiver of rights and remedies</header><text>Except as provided under paragraph (3), and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the rights and remedies provided for in this section may not be waived by any agreement, policy, form, or condition of employment, including by any predispute arbitration agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc7abc51a5bec4dd7a9985229e3f4063e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No predispute arbitration agreements</header><text>Except as provided under paragraph (3), and notwithstanding any other provision of law, no predispute arbitration agreement shall be valid or enforceable to the extent that the agreement requires arbitration of a dispute arising under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbac9643343aa486aad9afa8ad8bba32a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2), an arbitration provision in a collective bargaining agreement shall be enforceable as to disputes arising under this section, unless the Bureau determines, by rule, that such provision is inconsistent with the purposes of this title.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id8838d07dd7ac49f280fedddc40175ef8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consumer Financial Civil Penalty Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1017(d)(2) of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5497">12 U.S.C. 5497(d)(2)</external-xref>) is amended, in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>and for awards authorized under section 1017A</quote> before the period at the end.</text></subsection></section><section id="idac13bd03713743fc854ec22b4e45b1e9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Funding cap for the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1017(a)(2)(A)(iii) of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5497">12 U.S.C. 5497(a)(2)(A)(iii)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>6.5</quote> and inserting <quote>12</quote>.</text></section></legis-body></bill>


