<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB500600EE25744BDB3D74FD916C951C6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 420 IH: Federal Grant Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 420</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250115">January 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose limitations on the amount of indirect costs allowable under Federal research awards to institutions of higher education, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF415A59E3C3645DA9F99B3E9C69FC940" style="OLC"><section id="H8F52393A46CF423D9E7DBFC0F285C0C8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Grant Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9E12EF370DDB4907929CD7244B6C752B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitations on indirect costs allowable under Federal research awards</header><subsection id="H07F29C72CE36455E945C24831EA92A91"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="HF89F64293383437D904B0B092DA3F15E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limit on indirect costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total amount of indirect costs allowable under a Federal research award to an institution of higher education may not exceed the total amount of indirect costs allowable under private research awards, as calculated using the average indirect cost rate applicable to such awards.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9825ADCCE43348EDBB927EA9EBEE225E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Private research award rate</header><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall determine, not less frequently than annually, the average indirect cost rate applicable to private research awards for purposes of paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BC64E65FE7B4510A56A6141E1B19701"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Determination of indirect costs</header><text>In determining <quote>indirect costs</quote> for purposes of this subsection, the guidelines under subpart E of title 2, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations) for determining indirect costs charged to Federal awards shall be used.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1B8C14B0418442ACA997AA3C21177C56"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Comptroller General study on indirect costs under Federal and private research awards</header><paragraph id="H001CB268680144C188E721D4A6481BA7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on—</text><subparagraph id="H2E71FD7AAC2346E6BE49277337702FD0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the indirect cost rates allowable under Federal research awards to institutions of higher education, including awards made by the National Institutes of Health, the National Science Foundation, and other such organizations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BABAFC4DCD74F1E8151E6C47B323D3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the indirect cost rates allowable under private research awards to institutions of higher education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DC80F804E7E495B878E0B3A3BC2495E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The study under paragraph (1) shall include an assessment of—</text><subparagraph id="H610F91F5F3044902BA78D1B4A334B99E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the average indirect cost rates allowable under Federal and private research awards, respectively;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FD513C31C3C4921A8626DAD3F505EA7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the research fields that receive the highest levels of funding from Federal and private research awards, respectively;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB643F65D05D43F18FA7DC40BB3EEE6B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the average amount of indirect costs allowable under Federal and private research awards that are used to fund administrative staff, including administrative staff with responsibilities relating to diversity, equity, and inclusion; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA883AE9160A4D5EA3F19DEB8518ED00"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the measures implemented by organizations that make Federal research awards, including the National Institutes of Health and the National Science Foundation, to ensure such organizations are implementing indirect cost rate-setting guidance in a consistent manner.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H25D831FB7DE4423FB6E431A4893F247F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1). The report shall include such recommendations as the Comptroller General considers appropriate to improve the system for determining indirect cost rates and tracking reimbursements for indirect costs under Federal research awards.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H76EC3AD2653B46AE9FB5093041990B7E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HC46C6CF4D65449B5A508D42FF517329E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal research award</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal research award</term> means support provided to an individual or entity by a department or agency of the Federal Government to carry out research activities, which may include support in the form of a grant, contract, cooperative agreement, or other such transaction.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9998E06397D044259045AC2708E747F0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5741F8C2B7C14D0D9EE63C449873EC74"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Private research award</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>private research award</term> means an award made by a private sector organization to support research activities at an institution of higher education.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

