<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEN25318-34P-HY-NPY"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1409 IS: Public Safety Officer Concussion and Traumatic Brain Injury Health Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1409</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to collect and disseminate information on concussion and traumatic brain injury among public safety officers.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Safety Officer Concussion and Traumatic Brain Injury Health Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idA1DE2429F6AB417FACFE35674749A5A5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Information on concussion and traumatic brain injury among public safety officers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part J of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280b">42 U.S.C. 280b et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 393D of such Act the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDDFEBD489C1141D29818D40E596BC138"><section id="id5FF92FDBC80F4A3AAA94CA4F32006584"><enum>393E.</enum><header>Information on concussion and traumatic brain injury among public safety officers</header><subsection id="id0297A4C3F17B4C92ABEBAF20BA1D6F0C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall collect and make publicly available information on concussion and traumatic brain injury among public safety officers, including research related to evidence-based practices and personal protective equipment recommendations, and medical information related to diagnosing, protocols for identifying and treating, and measures for reducing the incidence of concussion and traumatic brain injury among public safety officers.</text></subsection><subsection id="id21ac34c16cb541f696dc105defa9ed8f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Dissemination of information</header><paragraph id="idEB38008B5CD341E9AB62079E150E9B40"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of making information available under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide3b8b8290c44494da23dfee085ce8512"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">update the website of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention with respect to traumatic brain injury; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef698d4da5a94c0585668bb3d77b8797"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop other means to disseminate such information to—</text><clause id="idff3bdb8563da44b78a1e9109778844e5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>medical professionals and public health professionals, to improve care and treatment services provided to public safety officers suffering from concussion or traumatic brain injury;</text></clause><clause id="id2bba70289c0f4ed0aab39c531c9b2224"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>public safety employers and employee representatives, to improve strategies and practices to reduce the incidence of concussion and traumatic brain injury resulting from firefighting, fire protection, law enforcement, and other public safety activities;</text></clause><clause id="id7d4c943425624f8c8ab1d7234dad9c1c"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>mental health professionals, to develop a better understanding of the link between concussion and traumatic brain injury and conditions such as trauma and stress related disorders, mood disorders, and suicidal ideations; </text></clause><clause id="idd09da025d72248789ca2c34742218982"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>patients and their families, to improve awareness of health care specialists in the area of concussion and traumatic brain injury, and to improve patient understanding of the effects of concussion and traumatic brain injury; and</text></clause><clause id="idbc9caa66607a467fae3f1ebe7414ab71"><enum>(v)</enum><text>institutions of higher education, including medical schools and schools of public health, and other researchers.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id01ee2df117d84bd0a0ec657183f4d956"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing the website under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consult with the individuals and entities described in clauses (i) through (v) of paragraph (1)(B) to ensure that information collected and disseminated best meets the needs of the public safety community in terms of content, quality, and utility.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2B3B4E2E14A2444EB56195B8ABFC8A64"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional dissemination activities</header><text>The Secretary may disseminate information described in subsection (a) through arrangements with nonprofit organizations, labor organizations and employee representatives, other governmental organizations or entities, and the media.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc09349b063ac42c09473033ca23c16d6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorized activities</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary may support public and private efforts to identify and create model guidelines, protocols, and evidence-based practices to treat concussion and traumatic brain injury in public safety officers, including through grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements. </text></subsection><subsection id="idfb9e238d27e54444af9a1c6776db15c4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>public safety officer</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1204 of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

