<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD06F133DE6E24A768C070A063412E800" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4408 IH: Understanding Noncontiguous Infrastructure and Threats Year-round Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4408</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250715">July 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000404">Ms. King-Hinds</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To study the effectiveness of disaster response and recovery in noncontiguous communities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB8C01209E9CE4111BC074CAB9F885880" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA5CA2936982148769AD43682A8D07D3E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Understanding Noncontiguous Infrastructure and Threats Year-round Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>UNITY Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section>
<section id="H4F08B1BB72604B09AD58CD9474F6F4F4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improving disaster workforce retention in noncontiguous communities</header> 
<subsection id="HDEE6239E772B43CB897FF5437D3588C9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall conduct a study on the effectiveness of practices of the Agency relating to hiring, recruitment, and retention in noncontiguous communities by soliciting feedback from staff in such communities.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HD183F3AA5C6C45E5BD136FCF7E090C51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the study under subsection (a), the Administrator shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4A674A3DE7C447B38851E309900BE3C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate the recruitment strategies of the Agency and efforts of the Agency to broaden the pool of qualified local candidates;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF9D491303679405EAC3CC425A9E1387B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prioritize input from communities in which there are the most severe staffing shortages; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1B64BF81DACC4EAA92E8F1F395561F5B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify specific steps that the Agency can take to improve opportunities for staff in noncontiguous communities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5B0C868E236C40F6B63C41A532CE6B19"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall brief the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate on the results of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0134808C825B44889F8B96FCEEB38D32"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Policies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall take such actions as are necessary to revise any policies, guidance, or regulations of the Agency to address the disaster workforce challenges in noncontiguous communities identified in the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> <section id="HC2D81B7F06C3447285E410F3F5B33607"><enum>3.</enum><header>GAO review of disaster response and recovery in noncontiguous communities</header> <subsection id="H2291F40474CF419E9916CC11D551D663"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the effectiveness of disaster response and recovery practices in noncontiguous communities, with a particular focus on recovery efforts relating to damage caused by Super Typhoon Yutu, and compare such practices with the disaster response and recovery practices in contiguous communities.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEBD13ED94991458182930ACAEAAC8417"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the study under subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall—</text> <paragraph id="H961F9E5A571B4E4B86F02373D1576F35"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analyze ongoing recovery efforts from disasters that have impacted noncontiguous communities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6FB05795F1D44E1B87660D6D1115A030"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analyze the level of coordination between the Federal Departments and Agencies tasked with disaster response and recovery;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H315B03DECA804EC1A6F43863E4F23C31"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess how effectively Federal agencies coordinate with State emergency management offices;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFAC311647907407BA9B41D6C2BA2CA5A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess the effectiveness of the Area offices and Regional Advisory Councils of the Agency in assisting noncontiguous communities; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEFBDC9A28DAE4386B0F3A2E1B8D703AC"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make recommendations on how to improve the disaster response and recovery outcomes in noncontiguous communities.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H84DC38CB846444CD9893B810B70A5863"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H1CC7AD07DB344EB6B83C9ED711F16EED"><enum>4.</enum><header>Preliminary damage assessment pilot program</header> <subsection id="HACACB154515448D6AEFD486A80BB4171"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall establish a pilot program to implement new technology in carrying out a preliminary damage assessment in a noncontiguous community in which a major disaster has been declared under section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>).</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H58C162D480C5457D86DC0D2B2AD94C98"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program established under subsection (a), the Administrator shall ensure that the most geographically remote noncontiguous communities are prioritized.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H67384E0278B441148FFB5681182568C1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall brief the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate on the implementation of the pilot program established under subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB265C75B46794D3889DA3C6D88C42393"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The pilot program established under subsection (a) shall terminate on September 30, 2030.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

