<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL25460-J2X-1D-T78"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1299 IS: Housing Supply Frameworks Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1299</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250403">April 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Policy Development and Research, to publish guidelines and best practices for State zoning and local zoning frameworks, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H6DE5561CA46F4E40BCDCC269916171A5"><section id="idcf1d44ac662f4edc8ff99da94e5994a4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Housing Supply Frameworks Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id12256386e3f14dac90ddab6319e8cfc3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id7eb8754c44164c5f82a0475e1ea1182c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>As of 2022 in the United States, there was an estimated housing shortage of 3,850,000 homes. This housing supply shortage has resulted in a record number of cost-burdened households across regions and spanning the large and small cities, towns, and coastal and rural communities of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id113ac79e6a4f454cbc82948ae62deb85"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Several factors contribute to the undersupply of housing in the United States, particularly workforce housing, including rising costs of construction, a shortage of labor, supply chain disruptions, and a lack of reliable funding sources.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id655d22212122446e800b9d99af8ee2c3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Regulatory barriers at the State and local levels, such as zoning and land use regulations, also inhibit the creation of new housing to meet local and regional housing needs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id74df04842c4449e28550ede7ef9860d2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>State and local governments are proactively exploring solutions for reforming regulatory barriers, but additional resources, data, and models can help adequately address these challenges.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4b92272c4c8048e19403169b036f7448"><enum>(5)</enum><text>While land use regulation is the responsibility of State and local governments, there is Federal support for necessary reforms, and there is an opportunity for the Federal Government to provide support and assistance to State and local governments that wish to undertake necessary reforms in a manner that fits their communities’ needs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6a995931b30b420a85b0201cf5990251"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Therefore, zoning ordinances or systems of land use regulation that have the intent or effect of restricting housing opportunities based on economic status or income without interests that are substantial, legitimate, nondiscriminatory and that outweigh the regional need for housing are contrary to the regional and national interest.</text></paragraph></section><section id="ida2b0253a338e4ced8c5b69fd6cb169cb"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idc883a8290f104100a0b16efdd877a23a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affordable housing</header><text>The term <term>affordable housing</term> means housing for which the monthly payment is not more than 30 percent of the monthly income of the household.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0d7dcce85712418bb980f07709175892"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Assistant Secretary</term> means the Assistant Secretary for Policy Development and Research of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id313957ec75284385817c0f6ddc2b4bad"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Local zoning framework</header><text>The term <term>local zoning framework</term> means the local zoning codes and other ordinances, procedures, and policies governing zoning and land-use at the local level.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id565bb9c9a98b4120a8210c45099764bb"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id47a836b315e14d73ab74252993b67080"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State zoning framework</header><text>The term <term>State zoning framework</term> means the State legislation or State agency and department procedures, or such legislation or procedures in an insular area of the United States, enabling local planning and zoning authorities and establishing and guiding related policies and programs.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idefb38ac816d84e75b6d39d9f34ae6ab2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Guidelines on State and local zoning frameworks</header><subsection id="idbe342bad3a624eacbda52671fc3a5626"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Assistant Secretary shall publish documents outlining guidelines and best practices to support production of adequate housing to meet the needs of communities and provide housing opportunities for individuals at every income level across communities with respect to—</text><paragraph id="idac5257974dc8435f9feadae29d08318f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>State zoning frameworks; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd9dca057b235415dbfdf5cab6063e1a5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>local zoning frameworks.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddf3962f9cf934575b2b752b1c5b7cdf0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation; public comment</header><text>During the 2 year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, in developing the guidelines and best practices required under subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="idd283b7e7f38346409872287d036eb8a3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>publish draft guidelines in the Federal Register for public comment; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1a1476bce6b846249f3e18819757c03c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish a task force for the purpose of providing consultation to draft guidelines published under paragraph (1), the members of which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="id2ba54adffb8d4b31a880a0d605884da0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>planners and architects;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4f2409fd3c504043955d37b31f68467f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>advocates with experience in affordable housing, community development efforts, and fair housing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id04f7537936974e35889d00f96b385adc"><enum>(C)</enum><text>housing developers, including affordable and market-rate housing developers, manufactured housing developers, and other business interests;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9a8900cebced4fd393083423bf96c8df"><enum>(D)</enum><text>community engagement experts and community members impacted by zoning decisions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida4a67c6e77174b4fb1e0a7ffeecedfdc"><enum>(E)</enum><text>public housing authorities and transit authorities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2653b848e4f7471383c277c90a905e49"><enum>(F)</enum><text>members of local zoning and planning boards and local and regional transportation planning organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id88da9b791a4443e085a066da7db89f9c"><enum>(G)</enum><text>State officials responsible for housing or land use, including members of State zoning boards of appeals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ided5d0b96ca484f869c6f2ca298ac3185"><enum>(H)</enum><text>academic researchers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc478004998f84fdd876eb61ce33e1a6a"><enum>(I)</enum><text>home builders.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id061db22b2e4d4af88daa161fb665f76d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The guidelines and best practices required under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="id08e37b755ee14586b607aff3080d60f0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>with respect to State zoning frameworks, outline potential models for updated State enabling legislation or State agency and department procedures;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3dcce0ddbbf849a1b3fc91a43a3c2000"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include recommendations regarding—</text><subparagraph id="ida40f09bf53dd40e78ce5ac8c312c917a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the reduction or elimination of parking minimums;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf6623fc84e03427d8139171c0b4587f2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the increase in maximum floor area ratio requirements and maximum building heights and the reduction in minimum lot sizes and set-back requirements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id98094ea8c92b4e208f1011671027b18f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the elimination of restrictions against accessory dwelling units;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idab03b1bebcb34528a168c1ab12e23bcc"><enum>(D)</enum><text>increasing by-right uses, including duplex, triplex, or quadplex buildings, across cities or metropolitan areas;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc3a56ebde62d4964a2356bb8cf74b65c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>mechanisms, including proximity to transit, to determine the appropriate scope for rezoning and ensure development that does not disproportionately burden residents of economically distressed areas;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0f93b9498845414eb65f6c562eef408f"><enum>(F)</enum><text>provisions regarding review of by-right development proposals to streamline review and reduce uncertainty, including—</text><clause id="ide44a49c952ed4eb493cc15cdb1ec8c9a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>nondiscretionary, ministerial review; and</text></clause><clause id="id69f8425af8224a48bc33d4ea93d94062"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>entitlement and design review processes;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id174f1f123d31470bbbf5143a44eb4bc2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the reduction of obstacles to a range of housing types at all levels of affordability, including manufactured and modular housing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id141323c0eb734e0192ddce1eb48c7d7d"><enum>(H)</enum><text>State model zoning regulations for directing local reforms, including mechanisms to encourage adoption;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id67033d2c387b444f98b0a34995d2aac4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provisions to encourage transit-oriented development, including increased permissible units per structure and reduced minimum lot sizes near existing or planned public transit stations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcc43e73967de4bf6a9e4445cb6cc9d2c"><enum>(J)</enum><text>potential reforms to the public engagement process, including—</text><clause id="idb634b7cdbecd445598c03416d86c5493"><enum>(i)</enum><text>meaningful access for persons with limited English proficiency and effective communication improvements for persons with disabilities;</text></clause><clause id="idff77010c76994d1a963697a93886aa8d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>leveraging of virtual meeting technologies; and</text></clause><clause id="id29a262f77fdb48c5a823570583066982"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>proactive outreach in communities;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc4756333feb747cd917db7f9aabf1a68"><enum>(K)</enum><text>reforms to protest petition statutes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb76fa30ae243468992c8400fb41d132d"><enum>(L)</enum><text>the standardization, reduction, or elimination of impact fees;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddac1b58199ef45c7af5a648eb7a24ca3"><enum>(M)</enum><text>cost effective and appropriate building codes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfedaa050c2ad429ba6168c558eb460e1"><enum>(N)</enum><text>models for community benefit agreements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id62f831ed98f84b3ca6019fefb4d77c71"><enum>(O)</enum><text>mechanisms to preserve affordability, limit disruption of low-income communities, and prevent displacement of existing residents;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id40be1fbce0c64addbb0943c0ece703fc"><enum>(P)</enum><text>with respect to State zoning frameworks—</text><clause id="idabf402fc70c74f61ad49ddfc0e37f24f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>State model codes for directing local reforms, including mechanisms to encourage adoption;</text></clause><clause id="ida2ab95e01d804c629c2d410f527e814f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a model for a State zoning appeals process, which would—</text><subclause id="id77dc1258182744ba8bcdb7530edb7b51"><enum>(I)</enum><text>create a process for developers or builders requesting a variance, conditional use, special permit, zoning district change, similar discretionary permit, or otherwise petitioning a local zoning or planning board for a project including a State-defined amount of affordable housing to appeal a rejection to a State body or regional body empowered by the State;</text></subclause><subclause id="iddf3025703d944c2a9c6072bfea96a91b"><enum>(II)</enum><text>establish qualifications for communities to be exempted from the appeals process based on their available stock of affordable housing; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idf1feeccbe45547ebb4ff6c47ee559520"><enum>(III)</enum><text>establish a State zoning appeals board to consider appeals to a discretionary permit rejection and objectively evaluate petitions based on the potential for environmental damage and infrastructural capacity; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id9782b12c81354d79bdbbdbc9213e13c1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>best practices on the disposition of land owned by State governments for affordable housing development;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3853b3dbb25448fea8b6a4e75f9f8ba9"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>with respect to local zoning frameworks—</text><clause id="id8789ce4963e1489399af70b280f9df0d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the simplification and standardization of existing zoning codes;</text></clause><clause id="idcba0a17f50eb4544a75ba54c0229ff1e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>maximum review timelines;</text></clause><clause id="idbe68c875e3214db5ae549772ca2edbe6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>best practices for the disposition of land owned by local governments for affordable housing development; and</text></clause><clause id="ida4227c7e3db240139968e1a20b2f668b"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>differentiations between best practices for rural, suburban, and urban communities, and communities with different levels of density or population distribution; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf4467e6579394765a989ae791fb89f3d"><enum>(R)</enum><text>other land use measures that promote access to new housing opportunities identified by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf5e9582ebc094bfb81cbd67252343d96"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consider—</text><subparagraph id="id5d850f28c35448ab90b67e1939152548"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consistency with respect to fair housing and civil rights requirements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3ca21037136f415aa32bb25758049407"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the effects of adopting any recommendation on eligibility for Federal discretionary grants provided by the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the Department of Transportation, and the Department of Agriculture, and tax credits for the purpose of housing or community development;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0a6edf4cbe1d482a8e102cd62e5757ce"><enum>(C)</enum><text>coordination between infrastructure investments and housing planning;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id912e87c703d14e768552176d5027d77b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>local housing needs, including ways to set and measure housing goals and targets;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idad260431138c4afc8b8f3040a1b8a8ee"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a range of affordability for rental units, with a prioritization of units attainable to extremely low-income, low-income, and moderate-income residents;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd5e5bb23441d4e4eac4274ab4f226659"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a range of affordability for homeownership units attainable to low-income and moderate-income residents;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idce97c39688a8456080dba648e838e48a"><enum>(G)</enum><text>accountability measures;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide94031d960e0444281fbc404e40a43d3"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the long-term cost to residents and businesses if more housing is not constructed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5dfd0d13290d4e7b8793a8fe4120a0ae"><enum>(I)</enum><text>barriers to individuals seeking to access affordable housing in growing communities and communities with economic opportunity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd2a16ab8b3aa4f5897e0ce39d7f4c038"><enum>(J)</enum><text>with respect to State zoning frameworks—</text><clause id="idddce6f126f52495cac5b667bc3fe1f21"><enum>(i)</enum><text>distinctions between States providing constitutional or statutory home rule authority to municipalities and States operating under the Dillon Rule, as articulated in Hunter v. Pittsburgh, 207 U.S. 161 (1907);</text></clause><clause id="id0adca83b974540c8a57a157de1896537"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>statewide mechanisms to preserve existing affordability over the long term, including support for land banks and community land trusts; and</text></clause><clause id="id309314fed00b42f1892958313b4e3de6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>guidance to States on collecting and maintaining proactive data on the current rental housing market and rental registries;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6e6432d09d624f1095135e118d4f5ddf"><enum>(K)</enum><text>public comments described in subsection (b)(1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3e98f9b228e84cbba50787d335be90ce"><enum>(L)</enum><text>other considerations, as identified by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idb3f403cdb28f4e71b4130d6ebd229d4e"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date on which the Assistant Secretary publishes the guidelines and best practices for State and local zoning frameworks, the Assistant Secretary shall submit to Congress a report describing—</text><paragraph id="idc02bac0a3a37460bbfaa187ccb7b53a9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the States that have adopted recommendations from the guidelines and best practices, pursuant to section 4 of this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id97283fb144934ae4972ab53b9142097b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a summary of the localities that have adopted recommendations from the guidelines and best practices, pursuant to Section 4 of this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id68c103cc92dc496e8029a6d1a19b0d8b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a list of States that adopted a State zoning framework;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id324b810c6df4404193af23a29533880c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a summary of the modifications that each State has made in their State zoning framework;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id40fd247edaba4a218dea8d8947043906"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a general summary of the types of updates localities have made to their local zoning framework; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddacec76c040a420386a6c93ac0a38c43"><enum>(6)</enum><text>of the States that have adopted a State zoning framework or recommendations from the guidelines and best practices, the effect of such adoptions on the number of building permits issued.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id7419155a225e4b01a21ea8eb46929df3"><enum>6.</enum><header>Abolishment of regulatory barriers clearinghouse</header><subsection id="id1f5e07bb541d419c924ef27f12705353"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Regulatory Barriers Clearinghouse established pursuant to section 1205 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12705d">42 U.S.C. 12705d</external-xref>) is abolished.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb31fcfa2eb744271a187922fd4b0bbdf"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text>Section 1205 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12705d">42 U.S.C. 12705d</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></subsection></section><section id="idaaca7f01a160450aae0e7b812fb59b9c"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this Act $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

