<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H99DB5064BF814C589B04E02616D24D34" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3390 RH: Bringing the Discount Window into the 21st Century Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 191</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3390</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–234]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250514">May 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000594">Ms. De La Cruz</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000491">Mr. Lucas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250904">September 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on May 14, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Reserve Act to require the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to carry out a review of discount window operations and to implement improvements to such operations, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HBA00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H0934F984B1184A8B999D8B993A1CC8D4"><section id="H7AC076BC49CC4FA68A4DB4E095C86C3B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bringing the Discount Window into the 21st Century Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HA3C44D2E4FCA4ED6A3BD019B33D59E34" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Review of discount window operations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 10 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/241">12 U.S.C. 241 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H0A772724B14D499AA14DF95404AAD4B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (12) as paragraph (11); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FB4526FB4ED481E8281A5112B7DC54E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H51142F7F0B4B4FDC8BA1C19CB188EA62" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00"><paragraph id="H6C255C119ADE4FF7B1746DA67746387F"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Review of discount window operations</header><subparagraph id="H4ECACE3B7CFA4618AF42F553A19D1FF4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Board of Governors shall commence a review of the discount window lending programs of the Federal reserve banks (the <quote>discount window</quote>), and shall complete such review not later than 240 days after the date of enactment of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B1DD4CC0B8E40028CBF899D23A2A99D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The review required by subparagraph (A) shall include a consideration of—</text><clause id="HD6F53BD8D27B40C6871217842AAA39A4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effectiveness of the discount window in providing liquidity to financial institutions, including in times of financial stress;</text></clause><clause id="H9B316D821F124D459CA725970DF09979"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether the technology infrastructure, including means of communications, are sufficient to support the timely provision of liquidity, including in times of financial stress;</text></clause><clause id="H5499A267509947F4A9A89F98806CE40A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effectiveness of cybersecurity measures implemented with respect to discount window operations;</text></clause><clause id="H78919D609BE245A19A9F2D044EC70EDF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effectiveness of communications between Federal reserve banks, financial institutions, the Board of Governors, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Comptroller of the Currency, and the Secretary of the Treasury regarding discount window operations;</text></clause><clause id="HAA03A081303547E096AD8ED82E38328D"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effectiveness of the Board of Governors in providing oversight of the discount window and in ensuring consistent access to the discount window across the Federal Reserve System;</text></clause><clause id="HE2E564C2437A4C38A01FB250996208D2"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the discount window interacts with other providers of liquidity, including the Federal Home Loan Banks, during both normal operations and times of financial distress;</text></clause><clause id="HBD30E6CFEA824914A5475A010E950BF1"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effectiveness of existing discount window operating hours and whether such hours should be expanded, taking into account the interaction between discount window operating hours and the operating hours of payment systems of the Federal reserve banks, such as the Fedwire Funds Service and FedNow Service;</text></clause><clause id="HAD063F287C9146A4A267B132902AA556"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of mobile banking and instant communications technology on depositor behavior and liquidity risk posed to financial institutions, including how the discount window can—</text><subclause id="H191F3719C69C4D5694DE6CBE3133F787"><enum>(I)</enum><text>help financial institutions better respond to rapid liquidity shortfalls; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HE5A518213DBB433B841C2A0FFC452E07"><enum>(II)</enum><text>prevent broader financial instability; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H1CCDF989514044B8920FAC2EA67D878C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effectiveness of the discount window in light of the stigma associated with its usage, ways to reduce such stigma, and ways to improve access, operational efficiency, transparency, and timeliness of the process for financial institutions seeking advances, including on the pricing and other terms of such advances.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H505D951896364E4DA2B831A4044EA7CA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Remediation plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the Board of Governors completes the review required by subparagraph (A), the Board of Governors, in consultation with the Federal reserve banks, shall—</text><clause id="H8BB5A414C4204ABE8EC323D253626EC0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identify deficiencies with the discount window and areas for enhancing discount window effectiveness; and</text></clause><clause id="HC7B1CA8DCBAA431A9A123A43002DB1F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop a written plan to remediate the identified deficiencies and implement the identified enhancements, which shall include—</text><subclause id="HD5038D4DFEAE4C36B8AEA5E9D387EDE6"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification of actions that will be taken to enhance discount window effectiveness and remediate identified deficiencies;</text></subclause><subclause id="H8F0DB48509B644E6BD677147F9004376"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">timelines and milestones for implementing the plan and measures to demonstrate how the implemented improvements will be maintained on an ongoing basis; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HE13CB8C01F284BC6ACC0D86D7A2DF982"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">measures of managing and controlling any deficiencies and current operations until the plan is implemented in full.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1C8CFBBDEB04E93B1D5499F228A283B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Report to Congress on review and plan</header><clause id="H1D77E164E8BB473D88A59445735958E8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 365 days after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Board of Governors shall submit a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate containing—</text><subclause id="H30B58DBCE17D46F3A49412D0C0F07062"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the findings of the review required by subparagraph (A); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H480E3EC05A3743C7A6491E46928ECA18"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the remediation plan required by subparagraph (C).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF35AB720C6C24EF485870AAC8CB758B1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before submitting the report required by clause (i), the Board of Governors shall—</text><subclause id="HB602C0FCD8A14D80AA38A61DBA618550"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide a copy of the proposed report to the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the Secretary of the Treasury; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HFC11FA290F9D46EF90506B4B8367A3E6"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the Secretary of the Treasury with an opportunity to provide feedback on the report.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HA4AC3D0AB05D4E9999D794C7422D7175"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Testimony</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairman of the Board of Governors shall, at the semi-annual hearing required under section 2B, testify with respect to the contents of the report required under this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56408D22CA7E42589772BCB7D1C52507"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Annual reports to Congress</header><clause id="H38933390BBA54359BE03D79FA7C40452"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reports by the Board</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board of Governors shall submit an annual report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate containing a review of the effectiveness of discount window operations and a progress report on the actions taken to implement the identified enhancements described in subparagraph (C).</text></clause><clause id="H598CFA9866D0465D98AB6CA72DF81C0C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reports by the Inspector General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection shall submit an annual report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate containing a report on the progress of the Board of Governors in implementing the remediation plan required by subparagraph (C).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17EE358D25E343D9A92B789F7757CDC9"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Confidential report information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any report required under this paragraph may contain a confidential annex containing information that, if made public, could—</text><clause id="HFF6A6CA4AC3C421D94C983C94A621937"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">impact monetary policy, financial stability, or cybersecurity; or</text></clause><clause id="HCE4FD40182314EABB82068CABF05F6BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>significantly endanger the financial stability of any financial institution.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EB9BB8222F648919340F59497675D90" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This paragraph shall be repealed on the date on which the Board of Governors notifies the Congress and publishes on a public website of the Board of Governors that the remediation plan required under subparagraph (C) has been fully implemented. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20250904">September 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

