<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H99DB5064BF814C589B04E02616D24D34" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3390 IH: Bringing the Discount Window into the 21st Century Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3390</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250514">May 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000594">Ms. De La Cruz</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000491">Mr. Lucas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Reserve Act to require the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to carry out a review of discount window operations and to implement improvements to such operations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAF5B6E5AD2BA4C458E982F17CEB4EFAD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H256368AF48CE49709417546FBE4C07A0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bringing the Discount Window into the 21st Century Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> 
<section id="H3261946CBC094C0FB8F52736E3A13FC4" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Review of discount window operations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 10 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/241">12 U.S.C. 241 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H791AD28330904C0DB9B550540B9E7C77"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (12) as paragraph (11); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFEDE4867947D48DC9D2698F36C21F17A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6FB97B4312564D1286FDF5D06DABB802" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H80BE90FADF00464EAB87F71027B1CD69"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Review of discount window operations</header> <subparagraph id="HA2BA055FA6A84E81AB56A6F15CF0D131"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Board of Governors shall commence a review of the discount window lending programs of the Federal reserve banks (the <quote>discount window</quote>), and shall complete such review not later than 240 days after the date of enactment of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H53626CD95FF3455984F906CCE5D107B2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The review required by subparagraph (A) shall include a consideration of—</text> <clause id="HA083B69A92D34BD5918253E96BBA3727"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effectiveness of the discount window in providing liquidity to financial institutions, including in times of financial stress;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5450998334E14F42B5200CC9AAAA0936"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether the technology infrastructure, including means of communications, are sufficient to support the timely provision of liquidity, including in times of financial stress;</text></clause> <clause id="H6767263C6D1B415F9E6C10C93F7B7D4D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the effectiveness of cybersecurity measures;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H044B366AE07F4D0190D14B5122553FC2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the effectiveness of communications between Federal reserve banks regarding discount window operations;</text></clause> <clause id="H4E1E1F3EAC884D53B7C4B4AE21B2CAEE"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effectiveness of the Board of Governors in providing oversight of the discount window;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB0AD3543C18E4EC58527BF305981F66B"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the discount window interacts with other providers of liquidity, including the Federal Home Loan Banks, during both normal operations and times of financial distress; and</text></clause> <clause id="H29C9F746B20D4B55BC4F91B7FB82765D"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effectiveness of existing discount window operating hours and whether such hours should be expanded, taking into account the interaction between discount window operating hours and the operating hours of payment systems of the Board of Governors and Federal reserve banks, such as FedWire and FedNow.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H40E7BDF9E8C64CA9B8D2CAB8AE065415"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public comment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the review required by subparagraph (A), the Board of Governors shall provide the public with an opportunity to comment on the effectiveness of discount window operations and to offer suggestions for improving operations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3253646FE5644F3C84B7498B368CC9A9"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Remediation plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After completing the review required by subparagraph (A) and considering any public comments received pursuant to subparagraph (C), the Board of Governors shall develop, and approve by a vote of the Board of Governors, a written plan to remediate any identified deficiencies or areas for enhancing effectiveness of the discount window, which shall include—</text> 
<clause id="HF6BA7794580B44928E2FDDAD01CFC353"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an identification of actions that the Board of Governors will take to remediate those deficiencies;</text></clause> <clause id="HA6EFA3B36A4E40B7923E9F860F450745"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">timelines and milestones for implementing the plan and measures to demonstrate how the Board of Governors will maintain implemented improvements on an ongoing basis; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H413A77D06379408C8BB7FE56A40052B8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">measures of managing and controlling deficiencies until the plan is implemented in full.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2A9C3F90AD574C1DA41061CCE61DF941"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Report to Congress on review and plan</header> <clause id="H5B9638D2F57F442D9739057F3F3D1C2F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 365 days after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Board of Governors shall, after approval by a vote of the Board of Governors, submit a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate containing—</text> 
<subclause id="H4EF56EC620D4472B99A257C2171778A0"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the findings of the review required by subparagraph (A); and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE6BEB64FB388467CB313117E67E6172F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the remediation plan required by subparagraph (D).</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H7FF488ACB16E42E28F222F0A4872CD1C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before submitting the report required by clause (i), the Board of Governors shall—</text> <subclause id="HF5AF22DE712E42459654800AF6387488"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provide a copy of the proposed report to the Comptroller General of the United States and the Inspector General of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA0B37116B2CE44AFAD4F50D2E74BA738"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provide the Comptroller General and Inspector General with an opportunity to provide feedback on the report.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H61883D8A69614A48BB1C0BF9D17E03D2"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Testimony</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairman of the Board of Governors shall testify before the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate with respect to the contents of the report required under this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5448E020697D42F99087C988C25D62E3"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Annual reports to Congress</header> 
<clause id="HE746FC47FB174275921DFDC20638EB93"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reports by the Board</header><text>The Board of Governors shall submit an annual report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate containing a review of the effectiveness of discount window operations.</text></clause> <clause id="H814664DFF49A45EC86BCFD5CFE6C8D41"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reports by the Inspector General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection shall submit an annual report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate containing a report on the progress of the Board of Governors in implementing the remediation plan required by subparagraph (D).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE9BED842620249718E555C83CDE03CC5"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Confidential report information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any report required under this paragraph may contain a confidential annex containing information that details any cybersecurity deficiencies or any deficiencies which, if made public, could cause financial instability.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

