<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H700A08F04EF54ED39C3312D434BA0B8F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3479 IH: Safeguarding Essential Cables through Undersea Risk Elimination American Telecommunications Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3479</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250519">May 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000067">Mr. Yakym</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve the licensing and security of submarine and cross-border terrestrial telecommunications cables, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB6BA70A4E0734B6883A83D818C87408B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5E2EC24992204AE29227ABDFCED73533" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="H61FC6DCBD5654911A9C679C8999FB67D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safeguarding Essential Cables through Undersea Risk Elimination American Telecommunications Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SECURE American Telecommunications Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE8F69AC5A2164EF5A0246A0BB95C5202"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="H5E2EC24992204AE29227ABDFCED73533" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H9E93BBA187404923B34BF3FD869EF40A" level="section">Sec. 2. Submarine cable licensing.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H903678797FB0410FA7235DD45AF3DFEE" level="section">Sec. 3. Cross-border terrestrial telecommunications cable licensing.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC0E780B136544FC7BE41352AA8804ED6" level="section">Sec. 4. Permit process and exemption from certain requirements.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H9A011E5062E3470F8BCA3AD20D5F40A3" level="section">Sec. 5. Repair reports.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H1AEAC4CB36744A53A656CA6BBD9D27E3" level="section">Sec. 6. Protection zone study.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HA4976EE0DA6C48BAA7C9F52F6A90F7C6" level="section">Sec. 7. Incidents report.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H3A72BC5BDE6D4ECB9C37F9A12D09D9A8" level="section">Sec. 8. International security agreement.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H83FC5ACA03C34782B60192F6BE9B13AB" level="section">Sec. 9. Penalties for injury to submarine cables.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H7DD9A7596681467A9C295CA2C8752055" level="section">Sec. 10. International Cable Protection Committee membership.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB56906E681FB4083BE5D2B68A07910DB" level="section">Sec. 11. Definitions.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="H9E93BBA187404923B34BF3FD869EF40A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Submarine cable licensing</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Act of May 27, 1921 (Chapter 12; 42 Stat. 8; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/34">47 U.S.C. 34 et seq.</external-xref>), is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9FC90B57E8014FCEBE682DC87EDEF61F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the first section—</text> <subparagraph id="H1056B68016CF4A238FC1EBBC3038E128"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>President of the United States</quote> and inserting <quote>Federal Communications Commission</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H15F6C0CEC5434ACFA6A948D0010E83DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>That any such cable now laid within the United States without a license granted by the President may continue to operate without such license for a period of ninety days from the date this Act takes effect: <italic>And provided further,</italic></quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5443E476EFA94134AA117A38F8A28999" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 2—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC23441EEF6474343AEAD0E9274A44F67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>President may withhold or revoke such license when he shall be</quote> and inserting <quote>Federal Communications Commission may withhold and the Federal Communications Commission or the President may revoke such license when</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7FE9D7123AB74E0E8CBE8C557C0E933A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or may</quote> and inserting <quote>and the Commission may</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F356B39685242768341D04FD8F02156" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 3, by striking <quote>President</quote> and inserting <quote>Federal Communications Commission</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4F61D3B7BC2545EE93A6C95E713B3D93"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="traditional" id="HC99565A4D9374091ABB4A509FCE0E71D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HC67E2B21CDFE4E79B693A64F5B56B0BD"><enum>7.</enum> 
<subsection id="H5E26A7EF5B534CF5BE45FC8069D01FED" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text>No license may be issued under this Act for a submarine cable directly connecting the United States with—</text> <paragraph id="H0D49C0FFCD6C430B94E9AFF6FB47E88C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an area controlled (as determined by the Secretary of State) by a foreign adversary of the United States; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCD87432A1FE84485A4A0D44E658A1736"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a facility that contains any communications equipment, or uses any service, that is on the list published by the Federal Communications Commission under section 2(a) of the Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1601">47 U.S.C. 1601(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H53709D1BD5F4412CAFF04A67B911A371" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>foreign adversary of the United States</term> means a foreign government or foreign non-government person specified in section 791.4(a) of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H841DCAFE4E7940DB84B0676D0F3B9BD1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>8.</enum> 
<subsection id="HFFA2018B301E4BF58FE61DEA8A74A6E7" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A license for a submarine cable under this Act shall be issued to an individual or entity subject to the following conditions:</text> <paragraph id="H5DFB8D5CB39A44F4A0342288864328BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the event of an incident that creates or is the consequence of a cybersecurity risk (as defined in section 11 of the <short-title>Safeguarding Essential Cables through Undersea Risk Elimination American Telecommunications Act</short-title>) involving such submarine cable, such individual or entity shall submit to the Federal Communications Commission and the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency a report on the nature of such incident not later than 24 hours after the date on which such individual or entity learns of such incident.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4B81110AB3C942E4B74B294C54B990C8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such individual or entity shall follow the minimum physical security and cybersecurity standards established under subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2A3C74B04E0F42A3BC599BBA98F960D9" indent="up1"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Federal Communications Commission shall promulgate regulations establishing minimum standards for the physical security and cybersecurity of submarine cables and the landing stations of such cables, including a standard for the minimum distance between submarine cables on the seabed.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFB2B419CD529429CB31232F22F14F9C5" indent="up1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less frequently than every 2 years, the Federal Communications Commission shall review the regulations promulgated under subsection (b) and update such regulations if necessary.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H0160DCD8C4AB45689F246305AB1B5349"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receipt of a report under subsection (a)(1), the Federal Communications Commission shall provide notice of such report to relevant entities, including cable operators and data centers, as the Federal Communications Commission determines appropriate.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEEF0C3686AF04DA4BB5A680548045DF3"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In promulgating and reviewing the regulations promulgated under subsections (b) and (c), the Federal Communications Commission shall consult with—</text> <paragraph id="HB9071CC0D7A64F148332FE9DC254D72A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Attorney General;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H563A0F25DCB4429C9B77F48730700B70"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Director of National Intelligence;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89E984AB619D4689B0D785F789529A6E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Secretary of Defense;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H672EF5B1688848CB8D55D277EAAF90A8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Secretary of Homeland Security; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD23900A764BF495DADCB570C02BA3A98"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other Federal entity that the Commission determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H32DE903B24754F78B2A29423B7328E28" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>9.</enum> 
<subsection id="HE047538FFDC5424B94B48BC183D595D4" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Communications Commission shall make a final determination with respect to the issuance of a license under this Act not later than the date that is 540 days after the date on which an application for such license, filed in accordance with all applicable regulations, is received by the Federal Communications Commission.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H40EACC42C16145FFB5C978028742EEB8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Federal Communications Commission does not make a final determination with respect to the issuance of a license under this Act within the period required by subsection (a), such license shall be deemed granted on the day after the last day of such period.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H903678797FB0410FA7235DD45AF3DFEE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Cross-border terrestrial telecommunications cable licensing</header> 
<subsection id="H5F818A9FF28E47198A16F9CA5805BE01"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No person may construct, connect, operate, or maintain in the United States a terrestrial telecommunications cable directly connecting the United States with a foreign country unless a written license to construct, connect, operate, or maintain such cable has been issued by the Commission.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7DDBD98E3C5940E8B38FBD6AE6BC6674"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A terrestrial telecommunications cable for which a license is required under subsection (a) shall be subject to the same requirements under the Act of May 27, 1921, as amended by this Act, as a submarine cable for which a submarine cable license is required, to the maximum extent practicable (as determined by the Commission).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB77A4213DC0348DBB72CB7F7F8E72421"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Relationship to certain other requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 13867 (84 Fed. Reg. 15491; relating to issuance of permits with respect to facilities and land transportation crossings at the international boundaries of the United States) does not apply with respect to a terrestrial telecommunications cable for which a license is required under subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H33B095E81FCE497082EBB0B8F1DF0760"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application process</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall promulgate regulations to establish a single application for—</text> 
<paragraph id="H14059708D2A9429581FF8495ACB17AEA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a license under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA54E4AEEF404D2492C00BCCD27EF95E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other Federal authorization required with respect to a terrestrial telecommunications cable for which a license is required under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCD01A532F643445C8CA1A80E58A22C6C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsections (a), (b), and (c) shall apply with respect to a terrestrial telecommunications cable that is constructed after the date on which the Commission promulgates regulations under subsection (d).</text></subsection> </section> <section id="HC0E780B136544FC7BE41352AA8804ED6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Permit process and exemption from certain requirements</header> <subsection id="H10A31BACEFB84A269A552471A174D5B8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Permit process</header> <paragraph id="H4D832EF345034045827A23D3C61355A2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>General permit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Army (acting through the Chief of Engineers) shall issue a general permit on a nationwide basis under section 404(e) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344(e)</external-xref>) for the construction, repair, and maintenance of submarine cables and landing stations of such cables.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H253EA0CA09F74131A776FCA467FE2030"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The general permit described in paragraph (1) shall incorporate the standard for the minimum distance between submarine cables on the seabed promulgated under section 8(b) of the Act of May 27, 1921, as amended by this Act.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HB8445A8899484F298C470FE75B16360E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal authorization prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no Federal authorization (other than a submarine cable license, a certificate required by section 214 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/214">47 U.S.C. 214</external-xref>), or the general permit described in subsection (a)(1)) may be required with respect to the construction, repair, or maintenance of a submarine cable or a landing station of such a cable, including with respect to a submarine cable or a landing station of such a cable that runs or is proposed to run through a national marine sanctuary designated under the National Marine Sanctuaries Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1431">16 U.S.C. 1431 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H971F22DD1D114DB89739EF7B8C32FF88"><enum>(c)</enum><header>NEPA categorical exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may not remove the construction of new submarine cable systems from actions that are categorically excluded from environmental processing under section 1.1306 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDD4209AC87D2484A8CA573B0615D8C0F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Preemption of State and local authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No State or local government or instrumentality thereof may regulate the placement, construction, modification, or repair of a submarine cable with respect to which the Commission has issued a submarine cable license, or a landing station of such a cable, on the basis of the environmental effects of such cable or landing station.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H9A011E5062E3470F8BCA3AD20D5F40A3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Repair reports</header> 
<subsection id="HFC45296AAC514B5EBD2806B0631894B3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any individual or entity that repairs damage to a submarine cable, a landing station of such a cable, or a terrestrial telecommunications cable, such individual or entity shall, not later than 7 days after the date on which such repair is commenced, submit to the Commission through the Network Outage Reporting System of the Commission a report on the nature of such damage (which shall include information known with respect to the cause of such damage).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0389457FA5974FEBB06B56F49D389A05"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information sharing</header><text>Not later than 7 days after the date on which a report required by subsection (a) is received by the Commission, the Commission shall transmit such report—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB833C804FFCE47D4B06651FDD348DDC7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8BEFA7F3467547C38981499FE00D9600"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of a report relating to a submarine cable or a landing station of such a cable, to the Department of the Navy and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H51E2E50766EF4C5AA22C4CA74795F8E5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Format</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by subsection (a) may be submitted in classified form.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H1AEAC4CB36744A53A656CA6BBD9D27E3"><enum>6.</enum><header>Protection zone study</header> <subsection id="H8126AAABDDD14619B8EAB700F658AE99"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission, the Secretary of the Army (acting through the Chief of Engineers), and the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall jointly conduct a study on the benefits, costs, and feasibility of the establishment by the United States of submarine cable protection zones.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6901813CD84243BCA514A4CCF59A2137"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the study under subsection (a), the Commission, the Secretary of the Army (acting through the Chief of Engineers), and the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall consult with the Secretary of State on information with respect to submarine cable protection zones established by countries other than the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC08080919D9F4234B7984373DEBC52AF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Matters for analysis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The study conducted under subsection (a) shall include an analysis of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H202FD968A13F4ECF96682F47416A2C76"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the submarine environment of the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H56CA101D7CCD4B218C67B866E1460D94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the commercial environment of the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCFCB91C3793C4FD2BA15B6CD79631F7F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the regulatory environment of the United States; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4754366E097D45948E740742FF5778C4"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">benefits, costs, and obstacles associated with the establishment by the United States of submarine cable protection zones.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB8E919E6431E4A1ABCA0ED3B928B1172" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 540 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission, the Secretary of the Army (acting through the Chief of Engineers), and the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report containing the results of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> <section id="HA4976EE0DA6C48BAA7C9F52F6A90F7C6"><enum>7.</enum><header>Incidents report</header> <subsection id="HBB91A8951871465B9977AE0B0356B715"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Commission shall submit to the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate a report describing any incident that creates or is the consequence of a cybersecurity risk that was caused by a foreign country or a non-state actor during the preceding year and that targeted—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1B6FBE7C369E499097BE76E5432BE39D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a submarine cable with respect to which the Commission has issued a submarine cable license;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEAEF6478DFC248B0BB70E0A83107EECF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a submarine cable of an ally (as determined by the Secretary of State) of the United States; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2D91CB52C26F42DDAFB9D6C0BCB44BD5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a landing station of a cable described in paragraph (1) or (2).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE25848239FF34F498EFDA3A8517AFA11"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H3A72BC5BDE6D4ECB9C37F9A12D09D9A8"><enum>8.</enum><header>International security agreement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall seek to enter into an agreement with the covered countries to establish a common set of minimum security standards with respect to submarine cables, the landing stations of such cables, and licenses to land and operate such cables.</text></section> <section id="H83FC5ACA03C34782B60192F6BE9B13AB"><enum>9.</enum><header>Penalties for injury to submarine cables</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Act of February 29, 1888 (Chapter 17; 25 Stat. 41; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/21">47 U.S.C. 21 et seq.</external-xref>), is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5704F16917844C99AE10C37AC7F77D3E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the first section, by striking <quote>shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and, on conviction thereof, shall be liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding two years, or to a fine not exceeding five thousand dollars, or to both fine and imprisonment, at the discretion of the court</quote> and inserting <quote>shall be imprisoned for not more than 25 years or fined under title 18, United States Code, or both</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H09DB2F5B833340529E248CAA7418A253" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 2, by striking <quote>shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and, on conviction thereof, shall be liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding three months, or to a fine not exceeding five hundred dollars, or to both fine and imprisonment, at the discretion of the court</quote> and inserting <quote>shall be imprisoned for not more than 1 year or fined under title 18, United States Code, or both</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H7DD9A7596681467A9C295CA2C8752055"><enum>10.</enum><header>International Cable Protection Committee membership</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall take such actions as are necessary to become a member of the International Cable Protection Committee.</text></section> <section id="HB56906E681FB4083BE5D2B68A07910DB"><enum>11.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HFDDBB6245F2D44009293B6F729F64161"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Communications Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6EA5297C49434814BF8C70643D165A66"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered countries</header><text>The term <term>covered countries</term> means the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H03165C6E8F9247DE8838CBE067D62F9D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Australia.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE840866D6284D9F893698BA897AA03C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Canada.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB0BF8FEFD9144C3698A10170B8D4F7A5" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>New Zealand.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEB5AAF26B63048A1A77AD3DE0A9CC38D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The United Kingdom.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3912F27FFC794838A06CDDCB99B97D2C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cybersecurity risk</header><text>The term <quote>cybersecurity risk</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="HD10239D75181405BA5DD21A296F5E7F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a threat to or vulnerability of information or an information system, including through—</text> 
<clause id="HDE358E069E784BCE8B7AF77934A27B33"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">unauthorized access to such information or information system;</text></clause> <clause id="HF748D6614BF946189276EEF1A55C7356"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>unauthorized use of such information or information system;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4831DD7A7FC64A528704C2BE49FC826F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>unauthorized disclosure of such information or information with respect to such information system;</text></clause> <clause id="H021F36C1C1E04822AF0D723A68A73617"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>unauthorized degradation of such information or information system;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA5DCB465B5AB4F94B5C3671E6762B765"><enum>(v)</enum><text>unauthorized disruption of such information or information system;</text></clause> <clause id="H3FB14AE531FE4108A23E459DFB89E31A"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>unauthorized modification of such information or information system;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H44754500466C4827B9F08420B4DCBF36"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>unauthorized destruction of such information or information system; and</text></clause> <clause id="H733445D76FBF46498F5C7A73D2902130"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>an act of terrorism; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H74660B2D81C0455FBB384A3C0D8A2E00" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include any action that solely involves a violation of a consumer term of service or a consumer licensing agreement.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC596C82664540279EBCDD4FAA377BDC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal authorization</header><text>The term <quote>Federal authorization</quote>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF57929778E2746FBB000508E1DE932DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any authorization required under Federal law with respect to a submarine cable or a terrestrial telecommunications cable, including any authorization with respect to the construction, repair, or maintenance of such a cable or a landing station of such a cable; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1934D19B037E4D74AC7C9471B2BCE326"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes any licenses, permits, special use authorizations, certifications, opinions, or other approvals as may be required under Federal law with respect to such a cable or a landing station of such a cable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE1633C0FE8414D0487434FEBD4BC8CBE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/153">47 U.S.C. 153</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H27F11F6E71BA4945888D0DBD487392C0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Submarine cable license</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>submarine cable license</term> means a license to land or operate a submarine cable required by the first section of the Act of May 27, 1921 (Chapter 12; 42 Stat. 8; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/34">47 U.S.C. 34</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF0E516AA208B4B869A00D00CF4FF5D17" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Submarine cable protection zone</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>submarine cable protection zone</term> means a maritime geographic zone in which marine activity may be restricted to protect a submarine cable from accidental or intentional damage.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H625631D23AE74488996A51806A26C190" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Terrestrial telecommunications cable</header><text>The term <quote>terrestrial telecommunications cable</quote> means any terrestrial cable used for a telecommunications purpose, including any infrastructure associated with such cable.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

