<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA076761A02C242C3BCEDD516FF5C274B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2935 IH: Preparing Regulators Effectively for a Post-prohibition Adult-use Regulated Environment Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2935</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250417">April 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001222">Mr. Miller of Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a Commission on the Federal Regulation of Cannabis to study a prompt and plausible pathway to the Federal regulation of cannabis, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAFD3CC08A10147BAA05733A039D1205F" style="OLC"><section id="H6AC52AD393564EE281D1B9311FD78F47" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preparing Regulators Effectively for a Post-prohibition Adult-use Regulated Environment Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PREPARE Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H30ED6C6E188544F1BD777847C3B7956B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H31F48461509C48C6A49ADA497903BB77"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Cannabis was federally legal in the United States until 1937.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E9AFA127CB240659290523238EDF3F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Cannabis was federally prohibited to codify discriminatory practices against minority communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02FE4663888147FFAB451F642AF314A9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Medical cannabis prohibition was established despite objection from the American Medical Association.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE25456FBD67E4008BF145889F31D9FDD"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">38 States and the District of Columbia have legalized cannabis for medical purposes. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AD23C15FBC345D3BF6D79A4F5E60B46"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">21 States and the District of Columbia have legalized cannabis for adult use.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAB3DDE67D504159A31FA47F723C6E56"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Despite the Federal Government collecting revenue from the sale of cannabis, individuals are still criminally persecuted for its use.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE486A04257AD4C518903361A067A97F2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Cannabis research, including research on medical uses, product safety, and impairment standards, is severely hindered and made nearly impossible by its schedule 1 classification.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FA6B715921C411A9521E040C17FEB71"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Cannabis should remain an adult product aside from the physician prescribed treatment of minors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39D9B2D3FCF64838A00D6A1A9E1FE353"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Cannabis has proven medically beneficial for patients suffering from pain, cancer, post-traumatic stress disorder, seizure disorders, and multiple sclerosis, among other diseases.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53165AF21D964AE7B61C9599E7412286"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Since 2003, the United States Government by way of the Department of Health and Human Services has held a patent for medical cannabis as an antioxidant and neuroprotectant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C998D74B1F6487B87364A13E032B4F0"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">While the United States remains trapped in antiquated cannabis regulations, other nations and scientific competitors, including the United Kingdom, Canada, South Korea, Germany, and Israel have modified their laws to allow for varying degrees of cannabis legality and medical research. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H366DFF05A3B24467AFE088F30E355BD4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President and Congress shall prepare the Federal Government for an inevitable and prompt end to Federal marihuana prohibition by establishing a commission to advise on the development of a regulatory framework with respect to marihuana regulation, including accounting for the different characteristics of communities, agencies, and industries impacted by Federal marihuana prohibition. Such regulatory framework shall be modeled after Federal and State regulatory frameworks with respect to alcohol.</text></section><section id="HC938600852E948909E3CFF73DBE08E38"><enum>4.</enum><header>Commission establishment and membership</header><subsection id="H2B5E6DAF20C649D28B8166FE402A4667"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall establish a commission to be known as the <quote>Commission on the Federal Regulation of Cannabis</quote> (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>) to study a plausible and prompt pathway to cannabis regulation. </text></subsection><subsection id="H6BB7D3F7D81B499AAA307B1323E7D305"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties of Commission</header><paragraph id="H070E6CA0BE6C4D038DF59AF2E2E0960E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Proposal of measures</header><text>The Commission shall propose measures to alleviate and remedy—</text><subparagraph id="H0C556FB6D8D6480C81CD172412E790F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the impact of cannabis criminalization, particularly on minority, low income, and veteran communities; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C42020E9F584A458319BD6DC8B7C71B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the lack of access to the financial service sector for cannabis entrepreneurs and their affiliated industries; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CF3868D0B5542FBAAB1AA54D2452A2B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the lack of access to cannabis related research, including research on medical uses and the effects of impairment; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H014478669C9340419421501E94CF8683"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the lack of access to medical cannabis and research, particularly with respect to Federal agencies; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H620736862ECE4A1FB5C259E6A13E3122"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the lack of medical cannabis training at publicly funded medical training centers; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFD41A83BC9A4A9890268639E129B548" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the lack of consistent regulations for cannabis product and safety, use, and labeling requirements, including requirements to protect youth and reduce harms to youth; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82ADF23EA5AD444AA90072A5BD315C13"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the lack of efficient cannabis revenue reporting and collecting, including efficient and tenable Federal revenue frameworks;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BB2DEED634D4D8BA6197F31AF4571EB"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the lack of guidance for cannabis crop production, sale, intrastate, interstate, and international trade; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE2746CD02F34B4C953B6A688499880B"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the lack of guidance regarding the successful coexistence of individual hemp and cannabis industries, including prevention of cross pollination of cannabis and hemp products; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H797795D1E4AA4AD6BE971E936CF0A7FE"><enum>(J)</enum><text>any other barriers to Federal cannabis legalization identified by the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5139867890D436898BF585596A3B290"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public comment; public witness; reports</header><subparagraph id="HBEB08B8A9CB44FE6BAA272704DD9DD31"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Comment period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall solicit comment with respect to the regulation of cannabis from industry stakeholders, criminal justice reform advocates, substance use advocates, healthcare experts, State cannabis regulators, the Department of Justice of each State or Tribal government, and the public.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC21638AAE03D4905A4F75163338C5A29"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public witness hearing</header><clause id="HCF2D4725DCCA4AAF9767971320D0F052"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall convene a witness hearings and solicit written or verbal testimony from participants in the cannabis industry. Such hearings shall include—</text><subclause id="HA870EC9EF6B74FE7896E0E1DA2C01CE9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not less than two unique individuals or entities, who are not employed by the Federal Government, and represent a State legal operation that is licensed by a single State to sell, manufacture, produce, possess, distribute, administer, or deliver cannabis; </text></subclause><subclause id="HB3B30C5188AF44CB93DABB221EBC7C4F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not less than two unique individuals or entities, who are not employed by the Federal Government, and represent a State legal operation with a multi-State presence that is licensed by such States to sell, manufacture, produce, possess, distribute, administer, or deliver cannabis; </text></subclause><subclause id="H1444130F4F704E7E84FB725859950990"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an individual who was convicted and incarcerated by the Federal Government for a non-violent offense with respect to cannabis; and </text></subclause><subclause id="H32E03ACE2154414B8D51CC8EEFF8787A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individual who was convicted and incarcerated by a State for a non-violent offense with respect to cannabis.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HCFD0FF7C8DFC4B02B05784944E53FC92" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the Commission’s authority to include additional participants at the public witness hearing. if the participants referred to under clause (i) are included. </text></clause><clause id="HFE95552592B542ABB40DA2E40EAACEC7"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>Written and verbal testimony under clause (i) shall be made publicly available in the final recommendations published under paragraph (5).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC336E149FCEA40FD9A7162499256096C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Initial report and recommendations</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall publish initial findings and recommendations pursuant to subsection (b), including an identification of barriers to and suggestions for regulating cannabis in a way that is similar to the regulation of alcohol with respect to the rights of States, Tribal Governments, and the Federal Government, on the internet website of the Department of Justice. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B8F0F7304254233B56683781DD8532D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Additional public comment period</header><text>Beginning 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall solicit additional public comment from stakeholders identified pursuant to paragraph (2)(A) with respect to the initial recommendations published pursuant to paragraph (3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A02001EEBDD4C7CBB8780B23AB99EE3" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Final recommendations</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall publish a report including findings and recommendations pursuant to subsection (b), including an identification of barriers to and suggestions for regulating cannabis in a way that is similar to the regulation of alcohol, on the internet website of the Department of Justice. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C32D5C386C34B8885E1688F32D90E3A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall be composed of the following members:</text><paragraph id="HABCCC6A9C93A41A899BE0E30AD6A0AC7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The majority leader of the Senate shall appoint one member who is not employed by the Federal Government and was formerly incarcerated for a non-violent crime with respect to cannabis use or possession.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6E8FA95C6B94EFBA5E2092179D1419A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The minority leader of the Senate shall appoint one member who is not employed by the Federal Government and is an expert in substance abuse prevention.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE27B3A7740E34D9EAE4DFAC14AC5331D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The minority leader of the House of Representatives shall appoint one member who is not employed by the Federal Government and is an expert in the history of cannabis criminalization and the impact of criminalization on various communities, particularly minorities, medical patients, and veterans. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8585163649C74D4AA5DBD8327E02A08E" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The majority leader of the House of Representatives shall appoint one member who is not employed by the Federal Government and who is medically licensed with substantial knowledge and demonstrated research into cannabis use and medical treatments. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5CB65C268D34126828638F96FA0E615"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Attorney General shall appoint one member from the Department of Justice, who is an expert in the history of cannabis criminalization and the impact of criminalization on various communities, particularly minorities, medical patients, and veterans. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFB7AE2B1A0141B6833CDF0661A6CC1B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0831EF9617DF4A09B2A24D5A7E2AED11"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Director of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A107235D03F4A5EAC8F36813AC47014"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Secretary of Education shall appoint one member from the Department of Education who is an expert in prevention of youth access to alcohol and tobacco.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5F7BB5C4E64418D917CCFA6D2A5F5C8"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Director of Occupational Safety and Health Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F68B8DB9D8642E4BC9FC7C195FB8898"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall appoint one member from the Department of Agriculture who is an expert on cannabis and hemp cultivation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22500BAA0F2E4D5DA7696FA1F13A8AF9"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Commissioner of the Food and Drug Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8153BE21A61045D2A1C72B2A5D7D99F4"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The Director of the Alcohol and Tobacco Tax and Trade Bureau.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D07EFD59B8C401D8BC82C2E5C97290E"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The Commissioner of the Internal Revenue Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC12D2A3CE48D4E35B55EAE4A4E0A1738"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The United States Trade Representative.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBBA47410B7D4F7E81D534743618BE20"><enum>(15)</enum><text>The Secretary of Commerce shall appoint one member from the Department of Commerce who is an expert on regulated goods in interstate commerce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D4CE96C5B8540F2B35C70DC141B94E3"><enum>(16)</enum><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall appoint one member from the Department of Health and Human Services who is an expert on medical cannabis use and access.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCC8DEC501044BF1BB79861EAA1FDC0C"><enum>(17)</enum><text>The Director of the National Institutes of Health.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35BAB6EA0B874822B347222ADDDDA541"><enum>(18)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Veterans Affairs shall appoint one member from the Department of Veterans Affairs with knowledge of treatments for pain management and post-traumatic stress disorder and for providing patients with affordable treatment options.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD3114C48B694BC19DEAB7AB7F135822"><enum>(19)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Deputy Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC67DC7E53BD4914A8654E7B4DE3BCA5"><enum>(20)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall appoint one member from the Small Business Administration who is an expert in creating industry access for historically marginalized communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2ABB97F6A8845B48E49358733AE23ED" commented="no"><enum>(21)</enum><text>The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD947EAADEBDE44F283B9EB3DF83F6722" commented="no"><enum>(22)</enum><text>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CA71DCCAC7443B28E726385997858CE" commented="no"><enum>(23)</enum><text>The Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE88D63CF34E49C7BC043FDFE55F45D7" commented="no"><enum>(24)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C254BAE85D24D238A32DAE5B88E10F5" commented="no"><enum>(25)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5A1265F07C742529B2ED7C80C2DFCFC" commented="no"><enum>(26)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Minority Health.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB31A001D869D434D96DB21482D687347" commented="no"><enum>(27)</enum><text>The Director of Indian Health Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7993E7CAA0C48C6B3E7BC246EDD36F4"><enum>(28)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One representative from a trade organization or other non-profit entity with members from multiple, highly regulated adult goods and consumer package goods, appointed by the Attorney General.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64766759A8FC4FDE80EB0E9F109259E2" commented="no"><enum>(29)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two representatives who have worked on a State cannabis control commission to develop two successful, separate, and unique State-level regulatory systems, appointed by the Attorney General. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H444F4D023F4742DB92FEC5F040DC7178"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Leadership</header><paragraph id="H9D399B9220BD4C118CD7DE468AA3ED0D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Chairperson shall be elected by the members of the Commission at the first meeting of the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BD3DB1971C641989F2EEC2E69E3E3E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall be elected by the members of the Commission at the first meeting of the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A8BFDBBCD374E73AEC39F9E721D809B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A vacancy in the Chairperson or Secretary position shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made by the remaining members of the Commission. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1440F89731BE4FEFA3A1586027E2CB79"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Membership by political party</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If after the Commission is appointed there is a partisan imbalance of Commission members, the congressional leaders of the political party with fewer members on the Commission shall jointly name additional members to create partisan parity on the Commission. </text></subsection><subsection id="HBFF1309E7C584E5DA05B9B0ED83D7952"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Appointments; removals; vacancies</header><paragraph id="HDB34DC03D7914E09B68A83E51816BC46"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Timing of appointments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each initial appointment to the Commission shall be made no later than 30 days after the Commission is established. If any appointing authorities fail to appoint a member to the Commission, their appointment shall be made by the Attorney General. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40447BB7F56A43B396D272DC88C6A985"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A member of the Commission may be removed from the Commission at any time by the appointing authority should the member fail to meet Commission attendance requirement pursuant to subsection (g).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF080B40BF59A4A8B89842AD5AA870B20"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A vacancy in the Commission shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made prior to the date of the Commission’s next meeting.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H041FD2A7790047D6A4FC43D63F98F293"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Meeting requirements</header><paragraph id="HFC335828FAE7464697A44D60FE37E43D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>First meeting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall have its first meeting no later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H097847B4ACE04641835432434FE69E35"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Quarterly meetings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall meet quarterly. In addition to all quarterly meetings, the Commission shall meet at other times at the call of the Chairperson or as determined by a majority of Commission members.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9030F1445A55413E87A37FD720CAEBB6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Quorum; rule for voting on final actions</header><text>A majority of the members of the Commission constitute a quorum, and an affirmative vote of a majority of the members present is required to issue recommendations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66EF9522F5A24387968468C87624543A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Attendance by members</header><text>Members are expected to attend all Commission meetings. In the case of an absence, members are expected to report to the Chairperson prior to the meeting and allowance may be made for an absent member to participate remotely. Members are responsible for fulfilling prior commitments, regardless of attendance status. If a member is absent two times in a given year, he or she will be reviewed by the Chairperson and appointing authority and further action will be considered, including removal and replacement on the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H80DE8E6F0AEF4D008313EDF0711A365A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Minutes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Minutes shall be taken at each meeting by the Secretary, or in that individual’s absence, the Chairperson shall select another Commission member to take minutes during that absence.</text></subsection><subsection id="H15EF4449D3A646988EB30C092B6E55FB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Administrative requirements</header><text>The Attorney General shall provide staff and administrative support to the Commission. All entities of the United States Government shall provide information that is otherwise a public record at the request of the Commission.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBF9E13C8154D4E788DCC3892FB58528A"><enum>(j)</enum><header>No rulemaking authority</header><text>The Commission shall not have rulemaking authority. </text></subsection><subsection id="H361197C4780347CD8F0EEFBF7833899F"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Prohibition of compensation</header><paragraph id="H73A1C737EC054867AC2DE398D874DE7F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal employees</header><text>Members of the Commission who are full-time officers or employees of the United States may not receive additional pay, allowances, or benefits by reason of their service on the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H474FA75DAD004FC88F45AC2A1E961FB8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other members</header><text>Members of the Commission who are not full-time officers or employees of the United States may not receive additional pay, allowances, or benefits by reason of their service on the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC79E8FDFFF554CD191785D743884D320"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HBECB8910B654432FACE75889841195BD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cannabis</header><text>The term <term>cannabis</term> has the meaning given the term <term>marihuana</term> in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9B4EC816DD24D7A8B784DD2B05D9AA3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H268CF34AFE7648CD99FFCE0076C807CF" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State cannabis control commission</header><text>The term <term>State cannabis control commission</term> means any State commission, bureau, board, department, office, agency, division, or authority responsible for the regulation of the State’s legal medical and recreational cannabis program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB80D9C927AC445094FCF7E3B0B97BE2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Tribal government</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Tribal government</term> means the recognized governing body of any Indian or Alaska Native tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, community, component band, or component reservation, individually identified (including parenthetically) in the list published most recently as of the date of enactment of this paragraph pursuant to section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5131">25 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

