<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H920443E4E30242798171553B9992D4C4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1508 IH: DHS Special Events Program and Support Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1508</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250221">February 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000621">Ms. Pou</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize a program to assess the threat, vulnerability, and consequences of terrorism or other security threats, as appropriate, to certain events, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9C2B945FBD26431F8B7C3B1E78023F31" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF95562FE22FD4887B0ABB2845611A098" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DHS Special Events Program and Support Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFAB7E502E32A45F4A236C647FF71ED7B"><enum>2.</enum><header>DHS special events program</header> <subsection id="H8ECB23E31F0441CF8538FDDCBC316462"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle H of title VIII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/451">6 U.S.C. 451 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDF82381354DE4D25B259225D4C164A42" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<section id="H7D01A5ACA75C4064B486DB776977965E"><enum>890E.</enum><header>Special events program</header>
<subsection id="HD85842DC6DF64B758C528C7E87AC7B1D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized within the Department a program to assess the threat, vulnerability, and consequences of terrorism or other security threats, as appropriate, at certain special events in accordance with subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7B1DAFFF8BB946BF8C41E93802D679FA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The program authorized under subsection (a) shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HAD0E1617231A454CA9852DE4F955543D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>apply to special events that are pre-planned and not designated as National Special Security Events by the Secretary;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0C2DC182D4B44ABACE128C0B1677548" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include a standard process for Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial officials to voluntarily submit to the Secretary requests for a special event rating that could result in direct support for security and situational awareness for such special event;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H952A088FA42A4904A52727D301C04774"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain a risk-based methodology to assess ratings requests, including requests submitted pursuant to paragraph (2), that considers the anticipated attendance by United States officials or foreign dignitaries, the size and venue of the special event, credible threats of terrorism or other security threats, and other homeland security information, as appropriate; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89D714C5D8A0489F97EE303820EC6B79" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include a process for expedited consideration and, where appropriate, a process for the reassessment, of a special event rating.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HDDB09747A78A483281A486DAFDDFE428"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Support to special events</header><text>For purposes of protecting a special event described in subsection (b), the Secretary may provide security and situational awareness support to a Federal, State, local, Tribal, or territorial official at the request of an appropriate Federal, State, local, Tribal, or territorial official.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5D3DE0045EB545ACADFF388FA00C50EA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the program authorized under subsection (a). Each such report shall include information relating to the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HF139101086DC453A96B7B94E889224CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total number of special events submitted to such program in the prior year, including the number of special events at each rating level.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H758BB3B3E8A540ACB538B8D82C15D9BD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total number of events in the prior year for which the Secretary designated a Federal coordinator or coordinated security and situational awareness support, including a summary of Federal support provided.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE5556E4BDCBF420FB945E9834A67DC7C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total number of requests for special event rating reassessment under subsection (b)(4), including the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HEC9F7551F4D2446CB71D3C73336781BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The identification of the requesting entity.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1A78AF8CB040457D82DCF64328792331"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The special event name, date, and location.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H30C9ECD60AE04FEAA777DDEB1C3D1209"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The initial and final rating determination.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAD268CCC23964FDA986928C86CA67BDD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The justification for such final rating determination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC9BCD95F2AFD4B0A83CB26A80C17E9FA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Periodic assessments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section and every five years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate an assessment of the program authorized under subsection (a).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HFCFEB369D924418B9509EB2CF273C3E6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>homeland security information</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 892.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HFA97C166579141E9A24A2F1031DCA1F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mass gathering research</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Undersecretary for Science and Technology of the Department of Homeland Security and the official responsible for carrying out section 890E of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by subsection (a), shall, to the extent practicable, carry out research and development, including operational testing, of technologies and techniques for enhancing the Department’s security and situational awareness support to Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial officials relating to mass gatherings consistent with applicable constitutional, privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties protections.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H558C1982D9E14B0886CBEB7747AE0A75"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 890D the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF2D600545360451394A12C3A319DD93B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 890E. Special events program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

