<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H39BC65016BD24215A5C9DF15F285793F" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 42 EH: Electing Members to certain standing committees of the House of Representatives.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="no">119th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="no">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. RES. 42</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20250115">January 15, 2025</action-date>
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Electing Members to certain standing committees of the House of Representatives.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="HCE733CF1D71641239D4E7CB1FB060E10"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H5D82D0086A8D4084B06D8A52503FAF74"><text>That the following named Members be, and are hereby, elected to the following standing committees of the House of Representatives: </text> <committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Agriculture:</header><text>Mr. Lucas, Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia, Mr. Crawford, Mr. DesJarlais, Mr. LaMalfa, Mr. Rouzer, Mr. Kelly of Mississippi, Mr. Bacon, Mr. Bost, Mr. Johnson of South Dakota, Mr. Baird, Mr. Mann, Mr. Feenstra, Mrs. Miller of Illinois, Mr. Moore of Alabama, Mrs. Cammack, Mr. Finstad, Mr. Rose, Mr. Jackson of Texas, Ms. De La Cruz, Mr. Nunn of Iowa, Mr. Van Orden, Mr. Newhouse, Mr. Wied, Mr. Bresnahan, Mr. Messmer, Mr. Harris of North Carolina, Mr. Taylor.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Foreign Affairs:</header><text>Mr. Smith of New Jersey, Mr. Wilson of South Carolina, Mr. McCaul, Mr. Perry, Mr. Issa, Mrs. Wagner, Mr. Burchett, Mr. Green of Tennessee, Mr. Barr, Mr. Jackson of Texas, Mrs. Kim, Ms. Salazar, Mr. Huizenga, Mrs. Radewagen, Mr. Davidson, Mr. Baird, Mr. Kean, Mr. Lawler, Mr. Mills, Mr. Self, Mr. Zinke, Mr. Moylan, Mrs. Luna, Mr. Shreve, Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina, Mr. Baumgartner, Mr. Mackenzie.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph> <committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Natural Resources:</header><text>Mr. Wittman, Mr. McClintock, Mr. Gosar, Mrs. Radewagen, Mr. LaMalfa, Mr. Webster of Florida, Mr. Fulcher, Mr. Stauber, Mr. Tiffany, Ms. Boebert, Mr. Bentz, Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia, Mr. Hunt, Mr. Collins, Ms. Hageman, Mr. Amodei of Nevada, Mr. Walberg, Mr. Ezell, Ms. Maloy, Mr. McDowell, Mr. Crank, Mr. Begich, Mr. Hurd of Colorado, Mr. Kennedy of Utah.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Science, Space, and Technology:</header><text>Mr. Weber of Texas, Mr. Baird, Mr. Webster of Florida, Mr. Obernolte, Mr. Fleischmann, Mr. Issa, Ms. Tenney, Mr. Scott Franklin of Florida, Mr. Miller of Ohio, Mr. McCormick, Mr. Collins, Mr. Fong, Mr. Rouzer, Mr. Self, Mr. Harrigan, Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina, Mr. Hurd of Colorado, Mr. Haridopolos, Mr. Kennedy of Utah, Mr. Begich.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph> </section> </resolution-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </resolution> 

