<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELL25544-8JT-GY-YVM">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2659 IS: 504 Credit Risk Management Improvement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2659</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250801">August 1, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which
                was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSSB00">Committee
                    on Small Business and Entrepreneurship</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To amend the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to enhance the Office of
            Credit Risk Management, to require the Administrator of the Small Business
            Administration to issue rules relating to environmental obligations of certified
            development companies, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section section-type="section-one" id="id4a2098f2-f923-4f7a-b5da-fc82e765a138" changed="not-changed">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>504 Credit Risk Management Improvement Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="id6b74ebd0-cbb2-4699-b07b-0429ee68118e" changed="not-changed">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Enhancements to the Office of Credit Risk Management</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title V of the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/695">15 U.S.C. 695 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
            <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id73018CC04D12400DBB8AFAC2488BF6DA" changed="not-changed">
                <section id="idfa77f39969c040a78f52334941035129" changed="not-changed">
                    <enum>511.</enum>
                    <header>Office of Credit Risk Management oversight</header>
                    <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7f65296762ae484683f860688bd71116" changed="not-changed">
                        <enum>(a)</enum>
                        <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header>
 <text>In this section—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide69092d57af442b48fbb346c7f418881" changed="not-changed"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office; and</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida56066e34fea4bd6ada41b62f5e42e7d" changed="not-changed">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>Office</term> means the Office of Credit Risk Management established under section 47 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657t">15 U.S.C. 657t</external-xref>).</text>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                    <subsection id="id13edf29a-3c1f-45df-9b3c-ed49dbda5c2d" changed="not-changed">
                        <enum>(b)</enum>
                        <header>Duties relating to 504 program</header>
 <text>The Office—</text> <paragraph id="id223e018f-7a53-40a1-bc6a-aae901a5fa2b" changed="not-changed"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>shall be responsible for—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="id22f7190f-5c36-44f3-9c65-eff6e4b60282" changed="not-changed">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>supervising any certified development company, as provided in subsection (d); and</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id43b0f935-2272-4705-bc5b-7d6698c205ae" changed="not-changed">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>conducting file reviews with respect to loan closings under the program established under this title, as provided in subsection (c); and</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="iddca497ab-2510-4185-8a86-0f238590c309" changed="not-changed">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>may—</text> <subparagraph id="iddb91a596-bcf0-4c2b-bf32-47212170d80f" changed="not-changed"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>take formal and informal enforcement actions against a certified development company, as provided in subsection (e); and</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id3a210b62-7fc9-4083-9837-0645e9929308" changed="not-changed">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>charge a certified development company a fee, as provided in subsection (g).</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                    <subsection id="idf7f6e598-9643-44da-9e28-63d0435f9395" changed="not-changed">
                        <enum>(c)</enum>
                        <header>Loan closing file reviews</header>
 <text>With respect to a loan closing under the program established under this title, the Office shall be responsible for the following:</text>
                        <paragraph id="idb80e1ec5-16ed-4ea4-8127-338437bff624" changed="not-changed">
                            <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>Conducting a complete file review of a random selection of all loan closings, the number, frequency, and conduct of which shall be at the discretion of the Office, to ensure program integrity, including a review of the items listed on the Checklist for Complete File Review contained in the appropriate form of the Administration.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="id9dadbf03-07b2-45da-967e-6d9f3e5aba41" changed="not-changed">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which each complete file review conducted under paragraph (1) is completed, preparing a written report documenting the results of that review, which the Office shall send to—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="id7d793d71-a47d-48ad-80b6-ec077e13893d" changed="not-changed">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the applicable certified development company;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id75064e1d-f932-4ba0-8536-c769d17b3364" changed="not-changed"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the designated attorney that closed the loan for the certified development company; and</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id9e892e88-a4aa-41e9-9264-1d81f5282b22" changed="not-changed">
                                <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>the Commercial Loan Service Center.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id4e69d350-309d-46f1-ad5c-d0e0fb06419b" changed="not-changed"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>If a complete file review conducted under paragraph (1) reveals a deficiency that could result in a loss to the Administration, requiring the applicable certified development company or the designated attorney to promptly correct the deficiency.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                    <subsection id="id9696aca3-0731-478b-8893-70cca0272d31" changed="not-changed">
                        <enum>(d)</enum>
                        <header>Supervision of certified development companies</header>
 <text>With respect to the supervision of certified development companies—</text>
                        <paragraph id="id8456f5dd-0cc1-4444-a24d-a19ff5396d84" changed="not-changed">
                            <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>an employee of the Office shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id54895e75-15e3-4bb1-93ca-467aa43e1660" changed="not-changed"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>be present for, and supervise, the review of any such company that is conducted by a contractor of the Office on the premises of the company; and</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id67a996f5-3d76-42bc-9ac1-8e3ce29a3f9f" changed="not-changed">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supervise the review of any such company that is conducted by a contractor of the Office that is not conducted on the premises of the company; and</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="id95c4e08d-8be9-4655-8ca2-17560d15f462" changed="not-changed">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the Administrator shall—</text> <subparagraph id="idfc90fadb-ac94-4028-b7f1-b74b5e8f8163" changed="not-changed"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>develop a timeline for the review by the Office of certified development companies and the submission of reports regarding those reviews, under which the Administrator shall—</text>
                                <clause id="id2d622122-4851-4687-8232-ae1643be126b" changed="not-changed">
                                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>submit to a certified development company a written report of any review of the company not later than 90 days after the date on which the review is concluded; or</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="id65a90a75-63e0-4700-bf34-5345201ba9a5" changed="not-changed">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>if the Administrator expects to submit the report after the end of the 90-day period described in clause (i)—</text>
                                    <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id249e0e9195df4274b12b3d582bcea78a" changed="not-changed">
                                        <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify the company of the expected date of submission of the report and the reason for the delay; and</text>
                                    </subclause>
                                    <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd3a4c0e8e2f149b299df64828eae8001" changed="not-changed">
                                        <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>submit to the company the report; and</text> </subclause> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id61f682a0-be0e-4775-b0bd-9e2a9615a7cc" changed="not-changed"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>if a response by a certified development company is requested in a report submitted under subparagraph (A), require the company to submit responses to the Administrator not later than 45 business days after the date on which the company receives the report.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                    <subsection id="idd651a10f-4183-4357-8283-84594e59150d" changed="not-changed">
                        <enum>(e)</enum>
                        <header>Enforcement authority against certified development
                            companies</header>
                        <paragraph id="ida6f994ab-c738-41eb-89be-b94efa733fa8" changed="not-changed">
                            <enum>(1)</enum>
                            <header>Informal enforcement authority</header>
 <text>The Director may take an informal enforcement action against a certified development company if the Director finds that the company has violated a statutory or regulatory requirement or any requirement in a Standard Operating Procedures Manual or Policy Notice relating to a program or function of the Office of Capital Access.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="id25855b25-1640-4d8b-9ca3-c43c04fe70fe" changed="not-changed">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
                            <header>Formal enforcement authority</header>
                            <subparagraph id="idd76634fc-f057-41b0-b15e-65070bfb6b16" changed="not-changed">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
                                <header>In general</header>
 <text>With the approval of the Lender Oversight Committee established under section 48 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657u">15 U.S.C. 657u</external-xref>), the Director may take a formal enforcement action against any certified development company if the Director finds that the company has violated—</text>
                                <clause id="ide7d203e8-2f1a-45b0-b6bd-225e4cc91878" changed="not-changed">
                                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>a statutory or regulatory requirement, including a requirement relating to the necessary funds for making loans when those funds are not made available to the company from private sources on reasonable terms; or</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="idb3edeffd-7516-41bc-abd9-1043f84311c2" changed="not-changed">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>any requirement described in a Standard Operating Procedures Manual or Policy Notice relating to a program or function of the Office of Capital Access.</text>
                                </clause>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id6480eef9-ad5e-427e-8499-263f507107e4" changed="not-changed">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
                                <header>Enforcement actions</header>
 <text>The decision to take an enforcement action against a certified development company under subparagraph (A) shall be based on the severity or frequency of the violation and may include assessing a civil monetary penalty against the company in an amount that is not greater than $250,000.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="id515285d4-2532-465f-8015-2174ee327e6b" changed="not-changed">
                            <enum>(3)</enum>
                            <header>Failure to submit annual report</header>
 <text>With respect to a certified development company that, as of the date that is 60 days after the date on which the company is required to submit any report, fails to submit that report, the Director may—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="id5a1ed0b4-4425-436d-ab42-1f9c233be4dc" changed="not-changed">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>suspend the company from participating in the program established under this title for a period that is not longer than 30 days; or</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id10862e8b-07e5-4e9e-99af-4048d749c898" changed="not-changed">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>impose a penalty on the company in an amount to be determined by the Director, except that the amount of the penalty shall be not more than $10,000.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                    <subsection id="id7826458759614df4a878be4a89602862">
                        <enum>(f)</enum>
                        <header>Portfolio risk analysis of 504 loans</header>
                        <paragraph id="id41f423ab80ab4a06990795bdc927b2e9">
                            <enum>(1)</enum>
                            <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Director shall annually conduct a risk analysis of the portfolio of the Administration with respect to all loans guaranteed under section 504.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="id8ae82e363a7e43de9a5395d37f519508">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
                            <header>Report to Congress</header>
 <text>On December 1, 2025, and every December 1 thereafter, the Director shall submit to Congress a report containing the results of each portfolio risk analysis conducted under paragraph (1) during the fiscal year preceding the submission of the report, which shall include—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="id4725553adc274643ad391e7803dd1d46">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>an analysis of the overall program risk of projects and loans approved under section 504;</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id2ddb29f994c64a009176cf9646253794">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>an analysis of the program risk, set forth separately by industry concentration;</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id7bf99dee9dcb4c1dbedbdef30d0a2113">
                                <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>without identifying individual certified development companies by name, a consolidated analysis of the risk created by the individual companies responsible for not less than 1 percent of the gross project approvals set forth separately for the year covered by the report by—</text>
                                <clause id="id17b8942c77994920abea0ecc865fc652">
                                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>the dollar value of the loans made by such companies; and</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="id0a773840ed4445ef8bf92dad1cb6d0e9">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the number of loans made by such companies;</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id96660f2daf324ddeab6bb40e0e572536"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>steps taken by the Administrator to mitigate the risks identified in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C);</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id077134eb4db5444fa0a114bb2fb92075">
                                <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>the number of certified development companies, the number of projects undertaken, the number of unique third party lenders participating in the program, and the gross and net dollar amount of debentures guaranteed and approved projects;</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id32fcbc1dd9ed4eebbe86628866322faa">
                                <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>the number and dollar amount of total losses, the number and dollar amount of total purchases, and the percentage and dollar amount of recoveries at the Administration;</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id51e8daca268e49b3ac42286fb251f605">
                                <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>the number and type of enforcement actions recommended by the Director;</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id1e2ba75384bf4a6c8fe04ee86657bce1">
                                <enum>(H)</enum>
 <text>the number and type of enforcement actions approved by the Lender Oversight Committee established under section 48 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657u">15 U.S.C. 657u</external-xref>);</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="idc9ef7f9307fa49ba8eda925865b510b7">
                                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>the number and type of enforcement actions disapproved by the Lender Oversight Committee; and</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="idabbd8686370d4c8f9ee35a402a1d84ab">
                                <enum>(J)</enum>
 <text>the number and dollar amount of civil monetary penalties assessed.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                    <subsection id="idaed80a20-f858-4dcc-b42c-10c28e15a289" changed="not-changed">
                        <enum>(g)</enum>
                        <header>Fee authority regarding certified development companies</header>
                        <paragraph id="id14c33e89-f423-4db5-b085-86593efdedfd" changed="not-changed">
                            <enum>(1)</enum>
                            <header>In general</header>
 <text>On and after the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>504 Credit Risk Management Improvement Act of 2025</short-title>, the Office may collect from each certified development company a fee as necessary to reduce to zero the cost to the Administration of examinations, reviews, rulemakings, and other lender oversight activities in this Act, the amount of which—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="idfe88709f-6c19-405f-b963-3bcd97f4a54f" changed="not-changed">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>shall be determined on a graduated scale according to the size of the portfolio of the certified development company with respect to the program carried out under this title; and</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id9960dcc1-a30c-4eb0-918b-c7a31b662d84" changed="not-changed">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>shall not exceed the amount that is 1 basis point with respect to the value of the portfolio described in subparagraph (A).</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb39cf19-33b1-4e0d-bf6c-6274fe12a08a" changed="not-changed">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
                            <header>Payment</header>
 <text>A certified development company on which a fee is imposed under paragraph (1) shall pay the fee from the servicing fees collected by the development company pursuant to regulation.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                </section>
                <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
        </section>
        <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="id6aeb1101-36bc-4666-a006-21f0dbeb6184" changed="not-changed">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Rules relating to obligations of certified development companies under the
                National Environmental Policy Act</header>
            <subsection id="id90fcba77-bc50-4e10-a706-b7b627080ab7" changed="not-changed">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Eligible certified development company defined</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>eligible certified development company</term> means a certified development company, within the meaning under title V of the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/695">15 U.S.C. 695 et seq.</external-xref>), that receives assistance pursuant to that title.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id33ff3608-820e-4b14-a344-4b0217d151f9" changed="not-changed">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Requirement To issue rules</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall issue rules to clarify the procedures necessary for an eligible certified development company to comply with the applicable requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcecdfde0-b2f7-4dbf-b52f-ce5aa6ab9fa6" changed="not-changed">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Rule of construction</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to modify the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

