<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB1818D93CA314DB99C8541C5F960DEB6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2674 IH: Department of Homeland Security Climate Change Research Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2674</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250407">April 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Under Secretary for Science and Technology of the Department of Homeland Security to research and develop approaches to mitigate identified or potential negative effects of climate change on homeland security, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H85EEDFFDC6FB409497F902657D790EC0" style="OLC"><section id="H87088017CE8E4D8885D388B4AEEB053A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Homeland Security Climate Change Research Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC9B4ADD5B57F4B308913A3AF3EA92A91"><enum>2.</enum><header>Climate change research and development</header><subsection id="H463B62545EB64DC38206962309B2414C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title III of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/181">6 U.S.C. 181 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="HA31323E7CB074805A47F0B329B23E6DB" style="OLC"><section id="HD053AEC43F6B45178DD6652996FAA46A"><enum>324.</enum><header>Climate change research and development</header><subsection id="H3A473AA95A584883AF9C2CF17F44DFB8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary for Science and Technology—</text><paragraph id="HC9A525174D6340C0AD2C1E4DDD5A3CED" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall evaluate existing Federal research regarding approaches to mitigate identified or potential negative effects of climate change on homeland security that includes consideration of—</text><subparagraph id="H86893329C5954493AD0FCA1AD2D8F372" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the degree to which such identified or potential negative effects affect preparedness and emergency planning and policies, including with respect to preparedness, response to, and recovery from natural disasters;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABC070383C45489FB2B9F1A583969253" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the degree to which the Federal funding structure to respond to major disaster declarations and emergency declarations is appropriately structured to address such identified or potential negative effects; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D344A52560043B2BF5F1B9C3C3AEA7A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such other matters as the Under Secretary determines appropriate; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE368DB8CD0454E678431AA031795DC41"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may, subject to the availability of appropriations, conduct research and development on approaches to mitigate such identified or potential negative effects of climate change on homeland security in response to the evaluation under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H232901EE956845699F4AF489B8D74389" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>The scope of the research and development under paragraph (2) of subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="HCDD264C26E7B4F3ABBCB6F39127DC5A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall prioritize mitigating identified or potential negative effects that impact the ability of the Department to carry out operations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04F96E73E0E94F01B014F2FFA98AEE03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may address the matters described in paragraph (1) of such subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H35B79BAD18EA4517AFE74B26DA260B5A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation and coordination</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Under Secretary for Science and Technology shall consult, and may, as appropriate, coordinate, with—</text><paragraph id="H647A5565A89544C6B4F79581B7E8BB9B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the heads of—</text><subparagraph id="H39DE93479DC940209AD3E8849003CF7E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>other relevant Federal agencies and departments; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83AC55F5E75E4412927F2890B5963679"><enum>(B)</enum><text>State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A5841A2878D43CB8CB4D8CCF07E866D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>relevant owners and operators of critical infrastructure.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H999734238EFB4CD9A389D09224E58FDA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Climate change defined</header><text>The term <quote>climate change</quote> refers to detectable changes in one or more climate system components that is directly or indirectly attributed to—</text><paragraph id="H7FD3047B573246F5AA2C3171772FA73B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>human activity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CF803B0563743A399FEB399E66FD60C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>altering the composition of the global atmosphere.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H50D9524C20F649AE84380E316B91ED2A" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text> Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section and annually thereafter for three years, the Under Secretary for Science and Technology of the Department of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on any research and development activities carried out pursuant to section 324 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H98C5593D8EEC487C809AF7E6FF83120F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 323 the following new item:</text><quoted-block id="H68AFDA719BF94D67945C68BEC010D06A" style="OLC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 324. Climate change research and development.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

