<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAC9A7C57C5834888865D81B995C282A7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2721 IH: Honoring Our Heroes Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2721</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish and carry out a pilot program to furnish a headstone or burial marker to veterans who died on or before November 1, 1990, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB974DB40FEF146CC85108FE1C058B57B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3F4961C2767846E3A4247B48A9433143" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Honoring Our Heroes Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HE0D58583D67C4044A4926348A5843F76"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs pilot program to furnish headstones and burial markers to covered veterans</header> <subsection id="H1BA4FCAFCC334C3F811F55F8E0E38FE5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, acting through the Under Secretary for Memorial Affairs, shall establish and carry out a pilot program under which the Secretary shall furnish, when requested, an appropriate headstone or burial marker for the purpose of commemorating a covered veteran.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2C39328B446D4FC2918FCF025069F55A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>An individual desiring to request a headstone or marker for the purpose of commemorating a covered veteran under such pilot program shall submit to the Secretary an application in such time, in such form, and containing such information and assurances as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H681A779E740445A3A25B2A497D8051C5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Update to eligibility requirements</header><text>During the period the authority to carry out the pilot program under this section is effective, the Under Secretary shall update the internet website of the National Cemetery Administration with respect to the requirements for eligibility for a headstone or burial marker under the laws administered by the Secretary.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7D8EDAF9D5304E3E83D3768D808687C4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Termination date</header><text>The authority of the Secretary to carry out the pilot program under this section shall terminate on the date that is two years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H11280286CFCC43428D9364D7CE6E26C5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Covered veteran defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered veteran</term> means a veteran (as defined in section 101 of title 38, United States Code) who died on or before November 1, 1990.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

