<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9147FD0F4ABB492FB7AE7E4FC8586A75" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3207 IH: Disabling Enemy Flight Entry and Neutralizing Suspect Equipment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3207</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250506">May 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000067">Mr. Yakym</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001216">Mr. Mills</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security or the Attorney General to deputize a State or local law enforcement officer to protect certain events with temporary flight restrictions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H358390B4B327464B85365BB60E2858D9" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HE19AB96D9B27435284BE8F8A6A7C8C99"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Disabling Enemy Flight Entry and Neutralizing Suspect Equipment Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>DEFENSE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H61412DCE5E204743865FE1245E03425C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Drone countermeasures to protect events</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 210G of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/124n">6 U.S.C. 124n</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE4D0F9344CE4CBD8178299DA1937603">
<subsection id="H6123EE8F90AE41C6878C8871F491B7D6"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Stadium security</header>
<paragraph id="H41590424E8FC4E4381D716C4F9468951"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary or the Attorney General may deputize a State or local law enforcement officer to exercise the authority granted by subsection (a), except that the authority is granted solely for the purpose of protecting—</text> <subparagraph id="HA77E4821CB854DB493A47C4C111A9D45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a site with respect to which a flight restriction is maintained pursuant to section 521 of division F of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/40103">49 U.S.C. 40103</external-xref> note);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD9B241127D3E4B98AAEA0920B546DC0C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the location of an eligible large public gathering described in section 44812(c) of title 49, United States Code; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H951A1CA617B243A5A4782F3923E7F879"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a public gathering otherwise protected by a temporary flight restriction, at the discretion of the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration under the authority of section 40103(b) of title 49, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD6D85D28606B4B189912B556D71353D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Training required</header><text>The Secretary or the Attorney General may deputize only a State or local law enforcement officer that has completed training in the use of the authority described in paragraph (1), as specified by the Secretary or Attorney General in coordination with the Secretary of Transportation and the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF8753751F7EB446EB57156632FF9F30D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Oversight</header><text>The Secretary or the Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Transportation and the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, shall exercise oversight of the use of the authority described in paragraph (1) by a deputized State or local law enforcement officer.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8A070AC049CB4A718C1CFFE03E397B98"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorized equipment</header><text>Equipment authorized for unmanned aircraft system detection, identification, monitoring, or tracking under this subsection shall be limited to systems or technologies that are included on a list of authorized equipment maintained by the Department, in coordination with the Department of Justice, the Federal Aviation Administration, the Federal Communications Commission, and the National Telecommunications and Information Administration.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

