<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE26C62328C924606A4D300D8BE216B88" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 570 IH: Commending Petty Officer 3d Class Scott Ruskan for his heroic efforts to rescue victims during the devastating flooding in central Texas.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 570</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250710">July 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000603">Mr. Luttrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000375">Mr. Arrington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000601">Mr. Goldman of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000300">Mr. Evans of Colorado</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000235">Mr. Ezell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000600">Mr. Langworthy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000594">Ms. De La Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commending Petty Officer 3d Class Scott Ruskan for his heroic efforts to rescue victims during the devastating flooding in central Texas.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, starting on July 4, 2025, catastrophic flash flooding occurred in and downstream from the Texas Hill Country, particularly in Kerr County, resulting in extensive damage and tragic loss of life;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in just a few hours, significant rainfall caused the Guadalupe River and surrounding waterways to rise rapidly and dangerously, threatening the safety and well-being of thousands of residents;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the magnitude of the flooding necessitated an immediate and extensive response by Federal, State, and local authorities, including the deployment of Coast Guard personnel, aircraft, and resources from Air Stations Corpus Christi, Houston, and Miami to support search and rescue operations;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Petty Officer Ruskan is from Oxford, New Jersey;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Petty Officer Ruskan enlisted in the Coast Guard on September 28, 2021;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Petty Officer Ruskan was the Basic Training Honor Graduate of his company;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Petty Officer Ruskan completed Aviation Survival Technician A-School in July, 2024;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Petty Officer Ruskan currently serves at Air Station Corpus Christi as an Aviation Survival Technician Third Class;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Petty Officer Ruskan, during the first rescue mission of his career, displayed exceptional courage, selflessness, and professionalism by directly saving an astonishing 165 individuals from the rising floodwaters;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Petty Officer Ruskan served as the only triage coordinator on the Camp Mystic site, ensuring that victims received timely medical care and stabilization under hazardous and rapidly changing conditions;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Petty Officer Ruskan’s actions exemplify the highest traditions of service in the Coast Guard and reflect great credit upon himself, his unit, and the Armed Forces; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the people of Texas and the entire Nation are deeply grateful for Petty Officer Ruskan’s heroic service and dedication to saving lives during this devastating natural disaster: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HE6D44CE92F0C469A81C31AAF941A20A1"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HE53A2CF0043B4F0E9DC96B3101B18DF7"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HA99E38AC655B4946B19C4982C0E1A662"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commends and congratulates Petty Officer 3d Class Scott Ruskan for his extraordinary bravery and heroic efforts to rescue 165 victims during the catastrophic flooding in central Texas; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3800CC3CE2BD441F865B598A9FC3EEF2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">extends its deepest gratitude to all members of the Coast Guard, other Federal and State agencies, first responders, and volunteers who risked their lives to protect and rescue others during one of the deadliest natural disasters in Texas in recent memory.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

