<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3B7BA248A0E94EE7BF0A215BB0F07CA5" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 825 IH: Of inquiry requesting the President to transmit certain information to the House of Representatives referring to United States Government agencies sharing certain communications with the public and Federal employees.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 825</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251021">October 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000831">Mr. Walkinshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Of inquiry requesting the President to transmit certain information to the House of Representatives referring to United States Government agencies sharing certain communications with the public and Federal employees.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HA276092CC55B44469A4152239F736204"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HDE996A4609D145CDABF3211585540A62"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the President is requested to transmit, to the extent that such documents are in the possession of the President, to the House of Representatives, not later than 14 days after the adoption of this resolution, in complete and unredacted form, a copy of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H3796E94A56514C909372D621C267001C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any and all documents and communications, including notes from meetings, audio records, telephone and electronic mail records, text and other digital messages, related to a directive from the Office of Management and Budget to Federal agencies directing them to include certain language in communications to employees regarding a potential lapse in appropriations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H00175AD3EE6940D0AECED866BA733362"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any and all documents and communications, including notes from meetings, audio records, telephone and electronic mail records, text and other digital messages, related to the Department of Housing and Urban Development posting a message on their website reading <quote>The Radical Left in Congress shut down the government. HUD will use available resources to help Americans in need.</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC9854D1101984E979A5D5DA7210804CD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any and all documents and communications, including notes from meetings, audio records, telephone and electronic mail records, text and other digital messages, related to the decision of the Department of Education to modify the out-of-office email messages of furloughed employees to read as follows: <quote>Thank you for contacting me. On September 10, 2025, the House of Representatives passed H.R. 5371, a clean continuing resolution. Unfortunately, Democrat Senators are blocking passage of H.R. 5371 in the Senate which has led to a lapse in appropriations. Due to the lapse of appropriations, I am currently in furlough status. I will respond to emails once government functions resume.</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAC319C03D4944664A944673A85619DCC"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any and all documents or communications between the Office of the President, the Office of the Vice President, the Office of Personnel Management, the Office of Management and Budget, and the Office of Special Counsel on whether any communications issued from official Federal Government sources regarding the Federal Government lapse in appropriations occurring in October 2025 constituted a violation of the sections 7323 or 7324 of title 5, United States Code, or section 1341 of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

