<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HDCA055B3EAB6459F9769A9F66E66DE46" resolution-type="house-resolution"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 439 IH: Providing for the expulsion of Representative LaMonica McIver from the United States House of Representatives.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 439</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250521">May 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSO00">Committee on Ethics</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing for the expulsion of Representative LaMonica McIver from the United States House of Representatives.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Representative LaMonica McIver is a Member of the United States House of Representatives;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on May 9, 2025, Representative LaMonica McIver arrived at Delaney Hall Federal Immigration Facility in Essex County, New Jersey, a Federal immigration detention facility operated by United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Representative LaMonica McIver entered a secure area of Delaney Hall Federal Immigration Facility without authorization;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Representative LaMonica McIver attempted to prevent Federal law enforcement officers from making a lawful arrest of another individual who entered a secure area of Delaney Hall Federal Immigration Facility without authorization;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Representative LaMonica McIver slammed her forearm into the body of a uniformed Homeland Security Investigations Special Agent and attempted to restrain the agent by forcibly grabbing the agent;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Representative LaMonica McIver pushed a United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement Deportation Officer and used each of her forearms to forcibly strike the officer;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this conduct by Representative LaMonica McIver was captured on video on body cameras worn by Federal law enforcement and is undisputable;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas clear and convincing evidence shows Representative LaMonica McIver made multiple attempts to forcibly assault, resist, oppose, impede, intimidate, and interfere with Federal law enforcement agents in violation of Title 18, United States Code, Section 111(a)(1);</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States Department of Justice has charged Representative LaMonica McIver with two violations of Title 18, United States Code, Section 111(a)(1), for forcibly assaulting, resisting, opposing, impeding, intimidating, and interfering with a person designated in Title 18, United States Code, Section 1114;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas clause 1 of Rule XXIII of the Rules of the United States House of Representatives requires Members to “behave at all times in a manner that shall reflect credibility on the House”;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, a Member forcibly assaulting, resisting, opposing, impeding, intimidating, and interfering with Federal law enforcement, in violation of Federal law, does not reflect credibility on the House;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on December 1, 2023, the House of Representatives set the precedent for the expulsion of a Member who stands charged, but not convicted, of criminal offenses by expelling former Representative George Santos prior to any criminal conviction;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas as a Member of the United States House of Representatives, Representative LaMonica McIver must be held accountable to the highest standards of conduct in order to safeguard the public’s faith in this institution;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Constitution of the United States charges the House with policing the behavior of its own Members, and the House should take action against Representative LaMonica McIver commensurate with her violations of Federal law and the Rules of the House;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas given her egregious violations, Representative LaMonica McIver is not fit to serve as a Member of the United States House of Representatives: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body id="HC02643014578485EA02437D15D0DB1EB" style="traditional"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H84CEB2D2114B49C485E49962F6CA1611" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum/><text>That pursuant to article I, section 5, clause 2 of the Constitution of the United States, Representative LaMonica McIver, be, and she hereby is, expelled from the United States House of Representatives.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

