<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5F10EEC5788E43249E4DB8D8039BD397" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 452 IH: Congratulating the Jewish War Veterans on the 129th anniversary of the organization’s founding and honoring their commitment to Jewish war veterans.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 452</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250529">May 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</sponsor> submitted the following resolution;
        which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans'
          Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the Jewish War Veterans on the 129th anniversary of the organization’s founding and honoring their commitment to Jewish war veterans.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Jewish War Veterans of the United States of America was founded on March 15, 1896, by 63 Jewish veterans of the Civil War in opposition to antisemitic comments about the lack of Jewish service in the Civil War;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Jewish War Veterans of the United States is the oldest active and one of the most distinguished veterans service organizations in the United States, providing advocacy and support for thousands of Jewish veterans and their families;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the early goals of the Jewish War Veterans included—</text> <paragraph id="HF20D63B8FE9E491EB9866B29E3C45A2B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>countering antisemitism by addressing antisemitic rhetoric that questioned the patriotism and contributions of Jewish Americans, particularly in the context of the Civil War; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H05121A9398CB4696B14CBC9CDE8AF43C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>advocacy to ensure that Jewish veterans received the same rights, benefits, and recognition as their non-Jewish counterparts;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Jewish War Veterans work tirelessly to preserve the memory and legacy of those who served in the Armed Forces, ensuring that the sacrifices of veterans are honored, including the creation of the National Museum of American Jewish Military History;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Jewish War Veterans have been an active voice in advocating for policies that benefit veterans, including support for military health care, educational benefits, and services for veterans in need;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Jewish War Veterans have consistently worked to combat antisemitism and promote tolerance as far back as the 1930s when they led protests and boycotts against Nazi Germany;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Jewish War Veterans have been instrumental in the education and remembrance of the Holocaust, ensuring that the lessons of history are passed on to future generations, and remain committed to standing against hate and prejudice in all forms;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Jewish War Veterans have a rich legacy of leadership and service, with members who have served in every major American conflict from the Spanish-American War to the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, and continue to serve as a beacon of pride and resilience in the Jewish-American community;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the impact of Jewish War Veterans extends beyond veterans’ affairs, with ongoing charitable and community programs, including initiatives to support military families, promote civic engagement, and preserve Jewish history; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Jewish War Veterans continue their legacy of combating antisemitism, hate, and bigotry, both within the Armed Forces and in society as a whole, while promoting Jewish patriotism and the rights of not only Jewish veterans, but all veterans: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H23F5396C4FC845C3A873679663D44C80"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H2AE2C14408B049A8B525DB4F18C65CE6"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H2FD2921EA1364E0E961CF8EEAE5CF4EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">congratulates the Jewish War Veterans of the United States on the 129th anniversary of its founding, and recognizes the organization for its unwavering dedication to the welfare of veterans, the Jewish community, and the Nation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H23F7A75DCE1945C882E67D2422A2473C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commends the Jewish War Veterans for its continued service to the United States, its contributions to honoring military service, and its commitment to upholding the values of justice, equality, and remembrance;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87D37768248545C796E1892792AAD003"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affirms the importance of the Jewish War Veterans' ongoing work in ensuring that the sacrifices of veterans and the lessons of history are never forgotten, and that all Americans benefit from their contributions to society; and</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA82AB9E2864D44A2B31384EB1CE701F2"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages the Jewish War Veterans to continue its vital mission and looks forward to its continued success in the years to come.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

