<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H49C25626DF8646818352C80A7AB02D28" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1451 IH: Quapaw Tribal Settlement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1451</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250221">February 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001317">Mr. Brecheen</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of the Treasury to make payments to the Quapaw Nation and certain members of the Quapaw Nation in accordance with the recommendation of the United States Court of Federal Claims, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H18659EFA9BB84D0798905E21197EB548" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HE6BE553BFD1F426384A49ACB509B3999"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Quapaw Tribal Settlement Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H757FF02A13B44DD893326CE9A422C2C2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Quapaw Tribal settlement</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H298CBC9809F947CD80D88DCDAF05CC7A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H9A3254101CE74A60BBC911AAFFA63D9C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Claimant</header><text>The term <term>Claimant</term> means each of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF44BE5DD29764904A62AC6870BAE01EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Quapaw Nation and the parties identified in paragraphs 1 through 10 of the complaint in Bear, et al. v. United States, No. 13–51X (Fed. Cl. Mar. 25, 2013); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H45EE822CE31046059561916079391EA8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the individual members of the Quapaw Nation identified in Exhibit A to the amended complaint in Bear, et al. v. United States, No. 13–51X (Fed. Cl. Mar. 25, 2013) filed on February 14, 2014.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC187B82BCF5546FAAE6B40B56053F785"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The term <term>Report</term> means the report of the Review Panel of the United States Court of Federal Claims in Congressional Reference Case No. 13–51X, Bear, et al. v. United States (Jan. 9, 2020), submitted to the House of Representatives on January 31, 2020.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8DA98E0A0AEF46C785C50F0D7BA0B0B4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior (or a designee).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBEEFA2165B044930BA0A138460BCFB38"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established a Special Deposit Account in the Department of the Interior Bureau of Trust Funds Administration, to be known as the <quote>Quapaw Bear Settlement Trust Account</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF9B900A983DA4318ADCF701A331B9E74"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior by and through the Bureau of Trust Funds Administration shall administer all funds appropriated to the Quapaw Bear Settlement Trust Account.</text></subsection><subsection id="H61740C0DD81E4861977F071BA6CE95B1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of payment</header><text>In accordance with the Report, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized and directed to pay to the Claimants $137,500,000 out of any funds in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated. The Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer the single payment to the Quapaw Bear Settlement Trust Account established in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H079739B7FB4B4A06B56B4B17A115ED42"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Payment in accordance with report</header><text>The payment under subsection (d) shall be made in accordance with the Report.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1E9343053D4D47F49F17EC5590FDB68C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>After the settlement proceeds are transferred to the Quapaw Bear Settlement Trust Account specified under subsection (b), the settlement proceeds shall be available for use, allocation, and distribution in accordance with the Claimants’ distribution plan. The Claimants shall establish a distribution plan in accordance with subsection (d) and the procedures set forth in subsection (g).</text></subsection><subsection id="H6B9429A983664CFB8A0A394626A7C43B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Distribution of Funds in the Quapaw Bear Settlement Trust Account</header><paragraph id="HF628925B8DF740728E644F70BC61AB70"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mediation</header><subparagraph id="HCCEE97A339EB4C81846A545387417B76"><enum>(A)</enum><text>No more than forty-five (45) days following enactment of the Act, the Claimants shall submit the issues of the allocation and distribution of the settlement proceeds to a mutually agreed upon third-party mediator.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7685A118C5624E678DEFCA1C10C6C356"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the event the Claimants do not submit to a mutually agreed upon third-party mediation within forty-five (45) days pursuant to the preceding subparagraph, then any Claimant may initiate Secretarial Allocation procedures under paragraph (2) below.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85EB10049FEF43DD9A47399EE7B350FD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any mediation shall be confidential and non-binding on the Claimants without the written consent of the Claimants, provided that nothing in this paragraph shall be interpreted to bar the Quapaw Nation Business Committee from consulting with the Quapaw Nation Indian Council during mediation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H006C8D9CF08A41F3821D9DFF4DCB7776"><enum>(D)</enum><text>No statements made or information exchanged during mediation shall be admissible in any future legal or dispute resolution proceedings without the written consent of the Claimants.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07CDD95BA8494C36BE03077A27923F41"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Claimants shall mutually agree to conduct mediation at a specified location. Each Claimant shall pay its own costs, plus an equal share of the costs of the mediator and the mediation facilities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H407EB9C761464DF389D1241309B0EF62"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Following successful completion of any mediation under this section, the Claimants may submit a mutually agreed upon distribution plan to the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3595B14BFEB244879BD6AC0B44B4C2A5"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Upon submission of a mutually agreed upon distribution plan to the Secretary, the Secretary shall distribute the funds in the Quapaw Bear Settlement Trust Account to the Claimants in accordance with their mutually agreed upon distribution plan.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1106F8C3358442BF8B81837C62554B4A"><enum>(H)</enum><text>In the event the Claimants do not reach a mutually agreed upon distribution plan following mediation, then any Claimant, through written notification, may submit the matter to the Secretary who shall determine a final distribution plan allocating the funds in the Quapaw Bear Settlement Trust Account in accordance with the Report based on the procedures in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A4D1CE187364F0683A10537A225BAA5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretarial Allocation</header><subparagraph id="HF7F03E1F140B4EAAB2BFE36116A5C73E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Following an unsuccessful mediation pursuant to the procedures in paragraph (1), any Claimant may petition the Secretary to determine final allocations of settlement proceeds in accordance with subsection (d).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3865F0CB77684BD1A03D2EC71E17C1F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary shall commence the Secretarial Allocation process in accordance with this paragraph (2) if the Claimants do not reach a mutually agreed upon allocation plan within 18 months following enactment of the Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FCD22C5AFEC4738ACF6656FD090958D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Upon the receipt of such a petition by a Claimant, the Secretary or the Secretary’s designee shall order an allocation of the settlement proceeds pursuant to the following steps:</text><clause id="H82A7D33ABC404ABBA57EED236C20AC87"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Within thirty (30) days following the Secretary’s receipt of a petition to allocation settlement proceeds after failed mediation, the Secretary or the Secretary’s designee shall issue a scheduling order to establish a schedule for a hearing and the issuance of a final decision by the Secretary of a final distribution plan.</text></clause><clause id="H5ED69C4CDC4A4DE4AA14922A321F7205"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Secretary’s decision determining a final distribution plan in accordance with subsection (d) shall be made following a hearing to be presided over by the Secretary or the Secretary’s designee. The hearing shall occur no less than sixty (60) days following the issuance of the scheduling order.</text></clause><clause id="H970F7D0FF43546568533508A5E882E1F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>At least fifteen (15) days prior to the hearing, each Claimant shall submit to the other Claimants and to the Secretary a copy of all exhibits on which such Claimant intends to rely at the hearing, a pre-hearing brief, and a proposed final decision by the Secretary. The proposed final decision shall include a proposed distribution plan to be submitted to the Secretary and shall be limited to proposed rulings and distributions for each Claimant.</text></clause><clause id="HB0BCE42A9B0D4EEAA446D9A60B0CC2B4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Within fourteen (14) days after the close of the hearing, each Claimant may submit a post-hearing brief to the Secretary.</text></clause><clause id="H22DD3D03436944DAA635658D0F2DF40F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Following the hearing and post-hearing brief, the Secretary shall issue a final decision determining a final distribution plan in accordance with subsection (d) within sixty (60) calendar days. The Claimants may mutually agree upon a binding distribution plan at any time before the Secretary’s decision is issued.</text></clause><clause id="HC08E4C05D4BD4B4FA1EBB23CBE6CD0AA"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Within twenty (20) calendar days after transmittal of the Secretary’s final decision to the Claimants, the Claimants may submit to the Secretary any information necessary for the implementation of the final distribution plan.</text></clause><clause id="HA9ECE42B4C114748A7C8547797F7E857"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Within sixty (60) days of the Secretary’s final decision determining a final distribution plan, the Secretary shall distribute the funds in the Quapaw Bear Settlement Trust Account to the Claimants pursuant to the terms of the final distribution plan.</text></clause><clause id="HCA5989B9C1E74FBE8C7AD3223B18B3A5"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Any deadlines established in this section may be extended by unanimous mutual agreement of the Claimants.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6EE39C19E724EC48DE8CFB5A36D2017"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal Mediation &amp; Conciliation Service</header><text>In discharging any duties under this Act, the Secretary is authorized to utilize the Federal Mediation Conciliation Service to provide technical support and dispute resolution resources, provided, however, that the Secretary or the Secretary’s designee is responsible for approving and implementing any mutually agreed-upon or binding distribution plan reached pursuant to this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

