<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4097812399EA44F3945FBEC08DFC5AF4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3634 IH: Interactive Federal Review Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3634</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250529">May 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000301">Mr. Johnson of South Dakota</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve the environmental review process for highway projects through the use of interactive, digital, cloud-based platforms and digital twins, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDEDC5B0CC00E4EF888703D9367FCD42F" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H0AA1F717B7CB4EA7AC2DEC4A179411C1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Interactive Federal Review Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HDEDEE760BC064C2EB483AAB1038A8886"><enum>2.</enum><header>Digital platforms and digital twins for NEPA reviews for highway projects</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H884B914E8870476E8D3DBD89223CC74D"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC1BD6918D50C49539D0E1098C2526C22"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered project</header><text>The term <term>covered project</term> means a highway project that received a grant under any of the following:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA71BBD766851458DAEC7D069E067E3AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The nationally significant freight and highway projects program under section 117 of title 23, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Infrastructure for Rebuilding America (INFRA) grant program</quote>).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBCD197D1FAA74FDCB750A942D9FC6E26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The national infrastructure project assistance program under section 6701 of title 49, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Mega grant program</quote>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE11230305514A609186E77163B3626B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The local and regional project assistance program under section 6702 of title 49, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Rebuilding American Infrastructure with Sustainability and Equity (RAISE) grant program</quote>).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6703CA4FEB0B43A1B83710A8CCBD85E1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The program for national infrastructure investments (commonly known as the <quote>Rebuilding American Infrastructure with Sustainability and Equity (RAISE) grant program</quote> and formerly known as the <quote>Better Utilizing Investments to Leverage Development (BUILD) grant program</quote>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H41822F0B9DD44C9C8519C67814A7330D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H927C4B74DD7B42EFBE4A4C35A9C8B4EE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this section are—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F2C120B70B44807B08E433591D86F51"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to expedite the environmental review process at Federal agencies and for the general public; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB245C3886C71464E8FE30D72136C5CB4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to facilitate interactive public stakeholder engagement and understanding of environmental impacts of projects under the Federal-aid highway system.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBCABAF256CC149548883707C348A0AAA"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Encouraged use of digital platforms and digital twins</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C138D9366C44D2BB9BE18BB916ED53A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall encourage recipients of Federal funds from the Secretary to utilize interactive, digital, cloud-based platforms and high fidelity, 3-dimensional digital models of infrastructure project elements, such as digital twins, when carrying out environmental reviews under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) by publishing the guidance described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA3989CA00D97425789BC422118989118"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall publish technology-neutral best practice guidance to encourage sponsors of projects that receive Federal funds from the Secretary to use an interactive, digital, cloud-based platform and high fidelity, 3-dimensional digital models of infrastructure project elements, such as digital twins, in carrying out the environmental impact analysis and community engagement processes required under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF915C6365417461A901DFF6078AFA255"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of digital platforms and digital twins in covered projects</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB1ECFD1954214985AFE7A7A7794AE821"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall select not less than 10 covered projects to demonstrate the use of interactive, digital, cloud-based platforms and high fidelity, 3-dimensional digital models of infrastructure project elements, such as digital twins, in carrying out the environmental impact analysis and community engagement processes required under that Act, which may include projects in States participating in the surface transportation project delivery program under section 327 of title 23, United States Code.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF3A16B8D73D14A9FA53D80870B495475"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional projects</header><text>In addition to the covered projects selected by the Secretary under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall include additional projects that utilize interactive, digital, cloud-based platforms and high fidelity, 3-dimensional digital models of infrastructure project elements, such as digital twins, in the report under subsection (e), on request of the sponsors of those projects.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H881D93562CBA4CC7915099894F1299E6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in selecting covered projects under a program described in subparagraphs (A) through (D) of subsection (a)(1), the Secretary shall give priority to applications for projects that demonstrate a plan to implement an interactive, cloud-based platform and high fidelity, 3-dimensional digital models of infrastructure project elements, such as digital twins, to carry out the environmental impact analysis and community engagement processes required under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9D515804D6A24DB6B0C08FCB5BC83C97"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header>
<paragraph id="H53FEE20A9D4F4C54AF65C5E883804F0A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report on the efficacy of using interactive, cloud-based platforms and high fidelity, 3-dimensional digital models of infrastructure project elements, such as digital twins, in carrying out environmental impact analysis and community engagement requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>), including—</text> <subparagraph id="H3010AE757D2544308ADC3776A7158537"><enum>(A)</enum><text>metrics that describe estimates of achieved efficiencies, community engagement measures, and efficiencies enjoyed across Federal agencies; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFC69FD1E7B984D74BCB3223A50D46B48"><enum>(B)</enum><text>examples of digital workflows enabled.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA8A5D08907D4859BE3A1CA8DD4FC5FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication of examples</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall publish on the website of the Department of Transportation, and submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, not less than 5 examples of an environmental impact statement, environmental assessment, or categorical exclusion document developed using an interactive, digital, cloud-based platform and high fidelity, 3-dimensional digital models of infrastructure project elements, such as digital twins.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8DABEA29299C409797FA8B596FB97B89"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this section affects or interferes with the authorities or responsibilities assumed by a State under section 327 of title 23, United States Code.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

