<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H49CE2BE9ACCD490C81442A4EA57C97CB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5075 IH: Guaranteeing Religious Accommodation in Childhood Education Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5075</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250829">August 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000634">Mr. Downing</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the award of Federal education funds to educational institutions and agencies that do not allow for religious exemptions to vaccination requirements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4368498070C5417AA91E1915950FF3C6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6B1EF5E1149547A9AC338165F32F247F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Guaranteeing Religious Accommodation in Childhood Education Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GRACE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HE879286D1DB54762AD7F3261765B0194"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on award of Federal education funds to certain educational institutions and agencies</header> 
<subsection id="HD0DB843057844F068A91CD8E289A6A26"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal education funds may be made available to an educational institution or agency that has a vaccination requirement, unless such institution or agency maintains a policy under which—</text> <paragraph id="H6021A9919F9F463B987F2904B0F5AA34"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an individual may be exempted from such requirement if such individual (or their parent or guardian, in the case of an individual who is a child) asserts that receiving the vaccination would violate a sincerely held religious belief; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE86DF1A616354EF399EEFE437D009FD1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>no documentation or other information is required to be submitted by the individual (or their parent or guardian) to support the validity of such assertion.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3DF536A96DB6456DA1808BFEE9CBC31D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF20A5489745D4A4F854B5AD9EA50E208"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Child</header><text>The term <quote>child</quote> means an individual who has not attained the age of 18 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD10B5C5A5310462B8919EC5C65D489D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Educational institution or agency</header><text>The term <term>educational institution or agency</term> means an elementary school, secondary school, local educational agency, or State educational agency (as those terms are defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H28CC474F17604A9F9E463214C7D0CBD5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Vaccination requirement</header><text>The term <term>vaccination requirement</term> means any requirement by an educational institution or agency that, as a condition for enrollment, attendance, participation in athletics or other student activities, or employment at the institution or agency, requires an individual to have received one or more vaccinations.</text></paragraph> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

