<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ERN25688-1JN-CY-X0Y"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2244 IS: Excluding Illegal Aliens from Medicaid Act </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2244</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250710">July 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require immediate changes to Medicaid relating to alien eligibility and payments to Medicaid expansion States that furnish health care to certain aliens.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="idfa3b36eb1ce847389674e1732eddb82e" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Excluding Illegal Aliens from Medicaid Act </short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF9B594FB1C5E40C5AAD7D3F7C39A6E89"><enum>2.</enum><header>Change of effective date for alien Medicaid eligibility</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id86d0046811ed434a88ddee7f0b07976a"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1903(v)(5) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(v)(5)</external-xref>), as added by section 71109(a) of an Act to provide for reconciliation pursuant to title II of H. Con. Res. 14 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/21">Public Law 119–21</external-xref>), is amended by striking <quote>October 1, 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>July 4, 2025</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="idbeed766643d244b2b3cd5b68a8854886"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect as if included in the enactment of section 71109 of an Act to provide for reconciliation pursuant to title II of H. Con. Res. 14 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/21">Public Law 119–21</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="HBC0772B493D345DB843CB3E7D3BA201A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Expansion FMAP for certain States providing payments for health care furnished to certain individuals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1905 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H52E1D75956664FA1A65753FA647A4E71"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (y)—</text><subparagraph id="H5B4D3E853AE14EDBAC57826FBDCDEF33"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(E), by inserting <quote>(or, for calendar quarters beginning on or after July 4, 2025, in the case such State is a specified State with respect to such calendar quarter, the Federal medical assistance percentage determined under subsection (b) for such State)</quote> after <quote>thereafter</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B4AB16364894A8197A326D6C31BA5AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1F4FE6655B634FE09EB31A66D4AB6EE6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HACB506ABD67D4CAD918CB16E42F01BEC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Specified State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>specified State</quote> means, with respect to a quarter, a State that—</text><clause id="H3692DAFB593847618C6AF0EEBBA2F5D2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides any form of financial assistance from a State general fund during such quarter, in whole or in part, whether or not made under a State plan (or waiver of such plan) under this title or under another program established by the State, to or on behalf of an alien who is not a qualified alien and is not a child or pregnant woman who is lawfully residing in the United States and eligible for medical assistance pursuant to section 1903(v)(4) or for child health assistance or pregnancy-related assistance pursuant to section 2107(e)(1)(Q), for the purchasing of health insurance coverage (as defined in section 2791(b)(1) of the Public Health Service Act) for an alien who is not a qualified alien and is not such a child or pregnant woman; or</text></clause><clause id="HB3775C32906043C8A8F214F273CF8510"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides any form of comprehensive health benefits coverage, except such coverage required by Federal law, during such quarter, whether or not under a State plan (or waiver of such plan) under this title or under another program established by the State, and regardless of the source of funding for such coverage, to an alien who is not a qualified alien and is not such a child or pregnant woman.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDF83706BE82499F99A6881705A13235"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Immigration terms</header><clause id="H54A5F782F316439DA907AE01AB4C4E60"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Alien</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>alien</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act.</text></clause><clause id="HE9571C7C0CF5495EA27811858EBC67C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Qualified alien</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>qualified alien</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 431 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996, except that the references to <quote>(in the opinion of the agency providing such benefits)</quote> in subsection (c) of such section 431 shall be treated as references to <quote>(in the opinion of the State in which such comprehensive health benefits coverage or such financial assistance is provided, as applicable)</quote>. </text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H740826D182684878A14934DD906A5ED1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (z)(2)—</text><subparagraph id="H64BFCFBA50F64B6C8E97B0DCB83C139C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>for such year</quote> and inserting <quote>for such quarter</quote>; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CE686F244DE45DEBEB5653C682B403B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(i)—</text><clause id="H527A5C0595CF40A6BFD2664ACC6D7C4B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subclause (I), by striking <quote>for a year</quote> and inserting <quote>for a calendar quarter in a year</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H8846C44149C74B93A76C5460D3870D78" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subclause (II), by striking <quote>for the year</quote> and inserting <quote>for the quarter for the State</quote>. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

