<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H035CAD747081475B9E107A1B78C2BBB6" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 628 IH: Recognizing the 20th anniversary of the Renewable Fuel Standard and its foundational role in strengthening United States energy security, supporting rural communities, growing the United States economy, and improving environmental performance.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 628</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250801">August 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001222">Mr. Miller of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000474">Mr. Flood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000446">Mr. Feenstra</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 20th anniversary of the Renewable Fuel Standard and its foundational role in strengthening United States energy security, supporting rural communities, growing the United States economy, and improving environmental performance.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Renewable Fuel Standard (<quote>RFS</quote>), first established by Congress in 2005 and expanded in 2007, celebrates its 20th anniversary as a key national policy for increasing the supply of domestic renewable energy and supporting families in the United States, the economy, and United States energy security;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the RFS provides for steady growth by setting forth increasing annual volumetric targets for an appropriate variety of renewable fuels;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the RFS achieves this goal by setting forth annual volumetric targets for renewable fuel, including specific pools for biodiesel, cellulosic, and advanced;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas such targets were designed to be ambitious in order to induce private sector innovation and investment, while providing ample flexibility in the law for the Environmental Protection Agency to administer the program, including the ability to adjust annual targets if necessary to reflect production volumes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the RFS drives innovation that improves environmental performance by requiring that renewable fuel achieve certain minimum thresholds of life-cycle greenhouse gas emissions reductions ranging from 20 percent to 60 percent, depending on the type of fuel;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the private sector has responded with billions of dollars of investment in the renewable fuel sector since 2007, to both expand production of first-generation renewable fuel and to develop and demonstrate advanced renewable fuel;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the RFS has driven innovation and investment in the biofuels sector, resulting in more than 2,700 renewable fuel facilities in 42 States, producing almost 28,000,000,000 gallons per year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the renewable fuels industry supports a robust bioeconomy that, in 2023, contributed $210,000,000,000 of gross domestic product and supported nearly 644,000 domestic jobs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the RFS has provided critical markets for farmers in the United States, supporting rural economies and domestic processing, and helping to drive economic growth and strengthen rural communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the RFS continues to provide an important backstop for farmers in the United States to ensure robust domestic demand when facing uncertainty in export markets;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the RFS has enabled the United States ethanol industry to supply more than 98 percent of gasoline sold nationwide with at least 10 percent ethanol, and has helped the biodiesel and renewable diesel industry produce over 5,000,000,000 gallons annually, about 10 percent of total onroad diesel use;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas renewable fuels have delivered real savings for United States consumers at the pump, with higher level ethanol blends like E15 reducing prices by 10 to 30 cents per gallon on average, and biodiesel driving down the price of traditional diesel by about 4 percent;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the RFS has contributed to significant reductions in greenhouse gas emissions by requiring renewable fuels to meet minimum life-cycle emissions reductions, and has helped the United States transportation sector make progress toward environmental sustainability;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the RFS has evolved over 20 years to keep pace with new technologies and shifting markets, while remaining at the heart of ongoing national conversations about energy security, environmental stewardship, and the agricultural economy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, over the past 20 years, the RFS has become a cornerstone of United States energy security by reducing reliance on volatile energy markets and supporting the domestic production of renewable fuels; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, to continue on a path toward greater energy dominance, the United States must continue its efforts to diversify its transportation fuel supply and avoid overreliance on imported fuels: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="HA950897A142B401DBA29F266EEBA0D80"><section id="H4BC15643C980472C9A8B6DF35E7FAEB6" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H2ECA24B1316A4AE4A8EE37F53C654789"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the 20th anniversary of the Renewable Fuel Standard (<quote>RFS</quote>) as a milestone in the commitment of the United States to strengthening energy security, supporting rural communities, growing the economy, and improving environmental performance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84CDCC7FD85C4082A00FE67ED544A1DF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends the contributions of the RFS in building a robust and innovative domestic renewable fuels industry;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3BDE431502D4EEC8852FAB953826334"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the positive impacts of the RFS on United States energy policy, the agricultural sector, and the environment over the past 20 years;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FCAA1F36C9843819C2E195BB1C37D0C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>affirms the continued importance of the RFS in advancing the Nation’s energy, economic, and environmental goals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAB5399900EE44FE82755C0F42486439"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">believes that diversifying the United States fuel supply with an increasing percentage of domestic renewable fuel strengthens the Nation’s economy, increases security, and improves environmental performance; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7DC0EDC902746F3B7E51C8FD8C0B717"><enum>(6)</enum><text>supports continued implementation of the RFS as enacted in 2007 to achieve this goal. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

