<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD47F631F32D0454E91E5C8ED01D1095E" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 577 IH: Demanding the immediate release of all Federal documents relating to Jeffrey Epstein.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 577</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250714">July 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr.
                    Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres
                    of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms.
                    Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr.
                    Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001136">Mr.
                    Conaway</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of
                    California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="H001094">Ms. Hoyle of Oregon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr.
                Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New
                    York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr.
                    Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr.
                    Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, and
                    <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>) submitted the following
                resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee
                    on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Demanding the immediate release of all Federal documents
 relating to Jeffrey Epstein.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on July 6, 2019, Jeffrey Epstein was arrested by Federal authorities and charged with operating a vast sex trafficking network that recruited, groomed, and abused dozens of underage girls, some as young as 14, across multiple States and countries;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Federal indictment alleged that Epstein used wealth, power, and a web of associates to exploit vulnerable minors, often luring them under the guise of providing financial assistance or modeling opportunities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Epstein had previously secured a controversial non-prosecution agreement in 2008 from the United States Attorney’s Office in the Southern District of Florida, allowing him to serve a limited sentence in local custody despite credible allegations from multiple victims;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on August 10, 2019, Epstein died by apparent suicide while in Federal custody at the Metropolitan Correctional Center in Manhattan;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on July 2, 2020, Ghislaine Maxwell, a close associate and confidante of Epstein, was arrested and later convicted on Federal charges including sex trafficking of minors, conspiracy, and perjury, for her role in recruiting and grooming underage girls on Epstein’s behalf;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas President Donald J. Trump and senior members of his administration repeatedly assured the American public that the Government would release a full accounting of the Jeffrey Epstein case, including the names of associates, thousands of pages of evidence, and potential criminal referrals;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on July 7, 2025, the Department of Justice announced that it would not pursue charges <quote>against uncharged third parties,</quote> and further declared that <quote>no further disclosure would be appropriate or warranted</quote> in the Epstein case;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this announcement directly contradicts the assurances made by prior administration officials and has caused renewed public concern that individuals involved in Epstein’s network may evade accountability;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on June 2, 2024, President Donald J. Trump stated on Fox &amp; Friends that he would declassify the Epstein files, acknowledging, <quote>Yeah, yeah, I would</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on October 22, 2024, then-Senator JD Vance said, <quote>Seriously, we need to release the Epstein list. That is an important thing,</quote> during an appearance on This Past Weekend;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on January 30, 2025, during a Senate confirmation hearing, FBI Director nominee Kash Patel affirmed his commitment to investigating Epstein’s network, stating, <quote>Absolutely, Senator,</quote> when asked by Senator Marsha Blackburn whether he would assist in uncovering those involved in building Epstein’s trafficking ring;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on February 21, 2025, Attorney General Pam Bondi told Fox News, <quote>It is sitting on my desk right now, to review,</quote> referring to the Epstein client list;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on February 26, 2025, Attorney General Bondi again confirmed possession of the files on Jesse Watters Primetime, stating, <quote>I do</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on February 27, 2025, White House Counsel Alina Habba responded to Piers Morgan’s question about potential prosecutions, stating, <quote>Absolutely. I think it would be negligent for us not to… You have to hold individuals who are indeed rapists accountable</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on March 1, 2025, Attorney General Bondi told Mark Levin, <quote>Certainly, nothing can be withheld on that</quote> in reference to public disclosure of perpetrators connected to Jeffrey Epstein;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, on March 3, 2025, Attorney General Bondi stated to Sean Hannity, <quote>A truckload of evidence arrived… [FBI Director] Kash [Patel] is going to get me and himself really a detailed report as to why all these documents and evidence had been withheld</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on March 11, 2025, White House Counsel Habba explained to Benny Johnson that the Epstein documents were under review and that <quote>you have to save the integrity of the investigation so that we can bring these people to justice</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on March 25, 2025, as interim United States Attorney for New Jersey, Habba stated, <quote>Those people that were crossing State lines and trafficking those girls or having sex with minors will be prosecuted</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on May 28, 2025, FBI Director Patel told Bret Baier, <quote>I’m not going to withhold information from the American public, ever… It takes time to go through years of investigations, years of political maneuvering, and years of cover-up</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on June 6, 2025, Director Patel told Joe Rogan, <quote>You’re going to get all that information… were going to give you every single thing we have and can</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the American people have a right to know the full extent of criminal activity, institutional complicity, and potential misconduct involving Jeffrey Epstein and his associates; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Article I of the United States Constitution grants the House of Representatives the authority to investigate, oversee, and subpoena information relevant to the public interest and national integrity: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HD6A6D9196CCF431186E94E469E1F72EE"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H1882BD50FF4042B49E82D65B7391AFC1"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HF0149C43672A44DF917CE80826E46897"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affirms its constitutional authority under Article I to conduct investigations, issue subpoenas, and expose criminal misconduct and institutional corruption;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF102A61E6EDB4B5283D7AAF7B1CB84C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demands that the Trump Administration immediately release all unclassified files, flight logs, correspondence, and evidence pertaining to Jeffrey Epstein, Ghislaine Maxwell, and all known associates, with redactions only to protect the identities of minor victims and preserve ongoing prosecutions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9421429F553E4C53B3831E1AA42F96EA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls upon the Department of Justice, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and any relevant executive branch agency to submit a full report on any delays, suppression, or destruction of evidence related to Epstein’s operations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5D70033C0F549C3918025D4410F4AD9"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">urges the relevant House Committees to initiate formal investigations into any obstruction, suppression, or delay of the files' release; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DA0840709F448B0BD3F07E0DBA4D426"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports full transparency and public access to these documents in the interest of justice, accountability, and the prevention of future abuses of power.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>


