<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC830787DF50143C8BC82BDD33AA87ABE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1073 IH: Great Lakes Gateways Network Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1073</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250206">February 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to provide technical and financial assistance to identify, conserve, restore, and interpret natural, recreational, historical, and cultural resources within the Great Lakes Watershed, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H177FEADCDC014085B506D8C2DFA6FFDD" style="OLC"><section id="HB3D43D5BB9974578BE8343FC46C435DC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Great Lakes Gateways Network Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3BEEBB624861402D811DC924227C15EB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Great Lakes Gateways</header><subsection id="H9AC0B6952F94495A9A2688D134887B9A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Great Lakes Gateways Network</header><paragraph id="HECD5DF00D4AB4A0CA30EE04E206AF83D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), in cooperation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (referred to in this section as the <quote>Administrator</quote>), shall provide technical and financial assistance, in cooperation with other Federal agencies, State and local governments, nonprofit organizations, and the private sector to—</text><subparagraph id="HE99AA37E7C194D1DA028210C4BAF5874"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify, conserve, restore, and interpret natural, recreational, historical, and cultural resources within the Great Lakes Watershed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E755AF3F633450C83F597EA85B71F7C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify and use the collective resources as Great Lakes Gateways sites for enhancing public education regarding and access to the Great Lakes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BC6A1B141B94D679568C56C40E0C8EE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>link the Great Lakes Gateways sites with trails, tour roads, scenic byways, and other connections as determined by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D8FAB78FC8F442EA6DA4356116D8CC1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>develop and establish Great Lakes Watertrails comprising water routes and connections to Great Lakes Gateways sites and other land resources within the Great Lakes Watershed; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H297154D060E44BF8AEC8631D63F43055"><enum>(E)</enum><text>create a Great Lakes Gateways Network comprised of Great Lakes Gateways sites and Great Lakes Watertrails.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA779C1FA2D4E4FCBA4FCFB6EC64265F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Components</header><text>Components of the Great Lakes Gateways Network may include—</text><subparagraph id="HA94ED7AA627640569B28D685682CFB67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State or Federal parks or refuges;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AA7C1F283E94D4E8CFD455C8432D283"><enum>(B)</enum><text>historic seaports;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30BAC78E70C24EECA2B9F7E1EBDEBF08"><enum>(C)</enum><text>archaeological, cultural, historical, or recreational sites; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H975D6DE36537407E90E4A4194BC369C6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other public access and interpretive sites as selected by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5167233372B43B1A01A2F3674DB21B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Great Lakes Gateways Grants Assistance Program</header><paragraph id="HB915859154D04ED9AE0E15E5AF728669"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in cooperation with the Administrator, shall establish a Great Lakes Gateways Grants Assistance Program to aid State and local governments, local communities, nonprofit organizations, and the private sector in conserving, restoring, and interpreting important historic, cultural, recreational, and natural resources within the Great Lakes Watershed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F57CC2BAF3946FF8FDC539CBC92D94B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The Secretary, in cooperation with the Administrator, shall develop appropriate eligibility, prioritization, and review criteria for grants under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CEF6848EAC44056A7711FE2CBB4976A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Matching funds and administrative expenses</header><text>A grant under this section—</text><subparagraph id="HF525D160FBD64656884F2E6E0E1EEEFE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall not exceed 50 percent of eligible project costs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A77D6E04351413A9B8AB12A4CCAD318"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be made on the condition that non-Federal sources, including in-kind contributions of services or materials, provide the remainder of eligible project costs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9048EB23479447D2A355D2F6EAC54960"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall be made on the condition that administrative expenses are not more than 10 percent of all eligible project costs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAB28BB463E8B4D659111FDEF1753DA9E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $6,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

