<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H17CA2AB93D084C0A9A1762C10EB550FB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4346 RH: Preventing the Escalation of Armed Conflict in Europe Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 277</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4346</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–324]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250710">July 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251003">October 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001136">Mr. Conaway</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251003">October 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on July 10, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To secure a peaceful resolution to the Russia-Ukraine conflict by requiring the Secretary of the Treasury to prohibit, or impose strict conditions on, the opening or maintaining in the United States of a correspondent account or a payable-through account by certain foreign financial institutions, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HBA00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H7552532FEE8141A3B44BA6F9AAFEEFD2"><section id="H69FFF11429574D8EAF97FCE380A5F8B4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing the Escalation of Armed Conflict in Europe Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PEACE Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H0061C9BA375B451DA7B97C524B174286" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H5FD915AC73994FE3A8BC1BC6CEB8CC58"><enum>(1)</enum><text>During the night of March 6-7, 2025, only one week after the President called for peace between Russia and Ukraine, the Russian military bombarded Ukrainian energy infrastructure and civilian residences.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE89BFC9BCDCE4B20A2C38C6B65825864"><enum>(2)</enum><text>DTEK, a Ukrainian gas producer, noted that the assault represented the sixth Russian attack on its Odesa facilities in just the preceding two and a half weeks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H919C8B2164D54345A682A6453CF3017B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>On March 7, 2025, the President published the following statement: <quote>Based on the fact that Russia is absolutely <quote>pounding</quote> Ukraine on the battlefield right now, I am strongly considering large scale Banking Sanctions, Sanctions, and Tariffs on Russia until a Cease Fire and FINAL SETTLEMENT AGREEMENT ON PEACE IS REACHED. To Russia and Ukraine, get to the table right now, before it is too late.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C086636E2CD41DA9AEA523E6BA68F3A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Despite the President’s calls for a peace settlement, Russia has continued to assault Ukraine, including an April 4 missile attack on Kryvyi Rih that killed 20 people and an April 13 strike on Sumy resulting in 35 deaths.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B505D63EEB748A2A4886C1F0441DBC1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>On May 25, 2025, Russia launched its largest aerial attack of the war, deploying hundreds of drones and ballistic missiles throughout Ukrainian territory.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FC156C9F22343B8A10B29AD4F499A32"><enum>(6)</enum><text>On May 27, 2025, the President posted on social media with reference to Russian leader Vladimir Putin: <quote>He’s playing with fire!</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H198686179DB84A91B0BE0DDD971B5687"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hours after a July 3, 2025 call between the President and Putin, Russia carried out its largest-yet aerial assault of the war against Kyiv. Less than one week later, following remarks by the President at a Cabinet meeting criticizing Putin, Russia launched an even more expansive drone strike against Ukrainian targets.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF75FAF1664F545818BDFE7821D870705"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On July 14, 2025, the President reiterated his displeasure with Putin and Moscow’s obstruction of the peace process. <quote>I speak to [Putin] a lot about getting this thing done,</quote> said the President while announcing new weapons deliveries for Ukraine. <quote>And I always hang up and say, <quote>Well, that was a nice phone call</quote>. And then missiles are launched into Kyiv or some other city.</quote> The President continued, <quote>Ultimately talk doesn’t talk. It’s got to be action. It’s got to be results.</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HF6EB35CCCD0C474F8B172573C2A9E66B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sanctions with respect to the Russian Federation</header><subsection id="HC26EE66C251449378C15F4001CEF3E68"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall prescribe regulations to prohibit, or impose strict conditions on, the opening or maintaining in the United States of a correspondent account or a payable-through account by a foreign financial institution that knowingly provides significant financial services to—</text><paragraph id="H9EAA1FBD8F3D4E949DDAE2F895E45B63"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any foreign person designated for the imposition of sanctions with respect to the Russian Federation under—</text><subparagraph id="H98AB53EA6A3144629821E63323E7E3F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 14024; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC101D2D6FA204793AE446B22BD8F2D15"><enum>(B)</enum><text>title II of the Countering America’s Adversaries through Sanctions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/44">Public Law 115–44</external-xref>) or an amendment made by that title;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB79F5B86184844EFB5D93111977F0077"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a foreign financial institution subject to the prohibitions of Directive 2 under Executive Order 14024;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD543A4106BEE4986B5A65C074F538B61"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an entity listed in Annex 1 of Directive 3 under Executive Order 14024; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H223FE4E0A1494E0D9BC5C2768F7C946E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any foreign person that the Secretary finds operates in the energy sector of the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC9EB344E8D04E31A57553B00323EFEC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties</header><paragraph id="H6C0A617AB97D4666A17F9A0B3EED62B4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><text>A person who violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of regulations prescribed under this subsection shall be subject to a civil penalty in an amount not to exceed the greater of—</text><subparagraph id="H46D1BEC834834D469A1D01492D1F589C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$377,700; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51095B56D3614D06AFB2537212DE51E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an amount that is twice the amount of the transaction that is the basis of the violation with respect to which the penalty is imposed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA0AF8DE67F040CA91343CDC0C53FEB8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criminal penalty</header><text>A person who willfully commits, willfully attempts to commit, or willfully conspires to commit, or aids or abets in the commission of, a violation of regulations prescribed under this subsection shall, upon conviction, be fined not more than $1,000,000, or if a natural person, may be imprisoned for not more than 20 years, or both.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H89C898B7718A41319A3CB380B0280E84"><enum>4.</enum><header>Determination required</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate determining whether the following are foreign persons described under section 3(a)(4):</text><paragraph id="HAD28592E3AA445EF8CCF696ECA736F27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Gazprom.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF88783D062C146F39144D6BAC43932D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Rosneft.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98212F2C49EB4EBB8B748EBD7DC8A3DA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Lukoil.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H4F3BE01A394546F6BB29793EF0AD9B67"><enum>5.</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">With respect to a foreign financial institution, the President may waive the requirements of section 3(a) for not more than 180 days at a time upon reporting to Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H160B521CFF774267B0D714AF10BE52AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the waiver advances the objective of resolving the national emergency described in the Executive Order listed under section 3(a)(1); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H752B74BCED634E33B4D095DBE44A1650"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the waiver is important to the national interest of the United States, provided that the President includes a detailed explanation of the reasons therefor.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H6686AA1990E347FAAFD957962DE2E89B" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Transfer of certain Russian assets held by United States financial institutions</header><subsection id="H2D7984E3A8214BA6AAD7F144C59D2A7E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transfer from United States financial institutions</header><paragraph id="HE5156036D0DF4E59866552222FCA3D24"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days following the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall—</text><subparagraph id="H63368AD8D28C4776948C012103F76B38"><enum>(A)</enum><text>seize, confiscate, transfer, or vest any covered Russian resources, in whole or in part, and including any interest or interests in such assets, held by a United States financial institution; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6725A88E8E241F787FA076F8B7EF4CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">deposit the resulting funds into the Ukraine Support Fund established under subsection 104(d) of the REPO for Ukrainians Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9521">22 U.S.C. 9521</external-xref> note), which may be used for the purposes specified in section 104(f) of such Act or for the purchase of defense articles for the Government of Ukraine.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1998CA428FB4E32B63E13EAE9B79D5F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall have the same authority under this subsection with respect to covered Russian resources as are provided to the President under section 104(b) of the REPO for Ukrainians Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9521">22 U.S.C. 9521</external-xref> note) with respect to Russian aggressor state sovereign assets. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6A92287CB60C41EB819EC8CD54B86608"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the requirements of subsection (a) for up to 180 days at a time, for a cumulative period not to exceed 1 year, upon reporting to Congress in writing that—</text><paragraph id="H282F21540F7A4C6893CACD8D458C269C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Government of the Russian Federation is taking meaningful steps to cease its destabilizing activities with respect to the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9408B54EA6C24EBF8691C0841B2928CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the waiver is important to the national interest of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB950942DFB854D6A86527E0A161DAFA9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H7CE6BF4B41124D31B02EF65F9A71E8FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered Russian resources</header><text>The term <quote>covered Russian resources</quote> means funds and other property of the Central Bank of the Russian Federation, the Russian National Wealth Fund, or the Ministry of Finance of the Russian Federation that—</text><subparagraph id="H26C69CA5038A4AF7BEEFA1BF7938AA4D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are included in a report pursuant to—</text><clause id="HBA00FF4F26C5404DA5DA7CFBC9591FA1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>directive 4 of Executive Order 14024; or</text></clause><clause id="H559377CE3DCC44608D06BD3E485711B1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 104(a) of the REPO for Ukrainians Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9521">22 U.S.C. 9521</external-xref> note); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H910F8EB15ED449A589FDA7AD1BAB398B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are located in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B4DBDACF81847F283ED56970E415618"><enum>(2)</enum><header>United States financial institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>United States financial institution</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HF3472E2126EE40CB994D92FEAC8B1A9B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a financial institution specified in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), (E), (F), (G), (H), (I), (J), (M), or (AA) section 5312(a)(2) of title 31, United States Code, as amended by the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59385C3409F04784915B6E983BE24A5D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such other persons or entities as the Secretary of the Treasury determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6E1BCD8BD70945A9B54177AA75824F21"><enum>7.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall have no force or effect on the earlier of—</text><paragraph id="H7B7BFCC05CF94F3FBBB19C4BF3B4FE33"><enum>(1)</enum><text>30 days after the date that the President reports to Congress that the Russian Federation has ceased destabilizing activities with respect to the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F0969AAD7A74177B4ED861178EADD1B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20251003">October 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

