<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H05BA479C278F4A479EA4FB5CB04BBE6E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4381 IH: To direct the Secretary of Defense to establish a pilot program regarding treating pregnancy as a qualifying event for enrollment in TRICARE Select.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4381</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250714">July 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to establish a pilot program regarding treating pregnancy as a qualifying event for enrollment in TRICARE Select.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H687E74341B4644F3B955A4CD537006DF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2C0FD0F08C9D4A4391CE0353922BE0E5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Pilot program to treat pregnancy as a qualifying event for enrollment in TRICARE Select</header>
<subsection id="HD7F262C9098D401B8CCAF55171EB0D2E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall commence a five-year pilot program under which the Secretary shall treat pregnancy as a qualifying event under section 1099(b)(1)(B) of title 10, United States Code, for enrollment in TRICARE Select by an eligible beneficiary.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB983BDFF8EFA4EFB949894AA5DFD540F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initial briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a briefing on the status of the pilot program under subsection (a).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HACF4272BC9554C2499F7ECEB21B7841F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the Secretary commences the pilot program under subsection (a), and annually thereafter for the next four years, the Secretary shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the pilot program. Each such report shall include the number of covered enrollment changes, disaggregated by—</text> <paragraph id="HCD4D331231C6424F9A514E9A51569C96"><enum>(1)</enum><text>month, beginning with January 2027; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0F1D357033F6409F8D91DD05C0A56BD7" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether the eligible beneficiary made such covered enrollment change—</text> <subparagraph id="H436BC2F5D9D84E528DEFA697524CC28C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">because the eligible beneficiary is a member of the uniformed services who separated from active duty;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H47BAEBD97BFD4402AD3310FE5B2258EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>because the eligible beneficiary is a member of the uniformed services who returned to active duty;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB8641C6F81A84C9F89A760F0D612A49C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">because the eligible beneficiary is a dependent of a member of the uniformed services who separated from active duty;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H585F32C8ED024E67962972917103A212"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">because the eligible beneficiary is a dependent of a member of the uniformed services who returned to active duty; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDB83AC67FB114627ABEA7E740C1361AE"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">based on the treatment, under the pilot program, of pregnancy as a qualifying event for enrollment in TRICARE Select.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HFE35A2739C3D47D58804FC170F2A849E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H29AA940B80F64F5E988D71E1D5DA7EFB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered enrollment change</term> means a change to a previous election by an eligible beneficiary under subsection (b)(1) of section 1099 of title 10, United States Code, to enroll in a health care plan designated under subsection (c) of such section.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB5E189A2C625449D99595A489DCA87F4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible beneficiary</term> means an individual who is eligible to enroll in TRICARE Select under section 1075(b) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H83D62D21D1E34B1589D10F6E2DBF51BC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The terms <term>TRICARE program</term> and <term>TRICARE Select</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 1072 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H333DC26E6B7A47A98631225933A56AF3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HED6C12DDF768445FB8C207D293B22180"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5EA4F5B4C8244C23976B677D0D31C168"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0D32AFAE3A0F431BB3FAB36D70170678"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H05ED6C6D23AD4BD2AAD46B2566601FBB"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

