<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0AAA489AF5104BFCB9DB204A7F1034FD" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 565 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the week of June 30 through July 4, 2025, as “National Tire Safety Week” in the United States, and supporting the goals and ideals of “National Tire Safety Week” to educate American motorists about the importance of proper tire care and maintenance.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 565</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250630">June 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000480">Mr. Timmons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000619">Mr. Rulli</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the week of June 30 through July 4, 2025, as <quote>National Tire Safety Week</quote> in the United States, and supporting the goals and ideals of <quote>National Tire Safety Week</quote> to educate American motorists about the importance of proper tire care and maintenance.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the first <quote>National Tire Safety Week</quote> was recognized on May 14, 1938, by the Rubber Manufacturers Association, now known as the U.S. Tire Manufacturers Association;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas <quote>National Tire Safety Week</quote> was launched to raise awareness about the need for increased education on tire safety to further reduce tire-related injuries and fatalities on the road;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas tires are highly engineered safety devices that are the only parts of a vehicle that have contact with the road;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas tires are required to meet some of the strictest Federal safety standards set by the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas data from the Federal Highway Administration indicate that motorists in the United States traveled almost 3,280,000,000,000 miles on tires in 2024;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas maintaining proper tire pressure, periodically rotating and balancing tires according to the vehicle manufacturer’s recommendations (typically every 5,000 to 7,500 miles), and regularly inspecting tires can help prevent irregular and premature tire wear;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas excessively worn tires are more susceptible to punctures and hydroplaning in wet conditions;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas proper tread depth helps tires maintain traction and improves handling;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas tire-tread depth may be checked using a tread depth gauge or simply by inserting an upside-down penny into the tread to verify it covers at least a portion of President Lincoln’s head;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas underinflation is 1 of the primary causes of tire disablement and tire failure, and underinflated tires can make controlling a car more difficult, reduce gas mileage, lead to excessive heat buildup and stress, and cause irregular wear and internal damage;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas overinflated tires are more likely to be cut, punctured, or damaged when hitting an obstacle, such as a pothole;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the U.S. Tire Manufacturers Association recommends drivers regularly check their tire-tread depth, ensure that tires are rotated and properly aligned, and check their tire pressure monthly using a tire gauge while the tires are cold, meaning the car has not been driven for 3 hours;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas a vehicle’s proper tire pressure is affixed to the vehicle’s door jamb next to the driver’s seat and contained in the vehicle owner’s manual;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas motorists should visually scan their tires for cuts, cracks, splits, punctures, and bulges, and visit a tire professional to assist with any of these conditions;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas spending just a few minutes each month to inspect and maintain a vehicle’s tires can make all the difference in the tires’ safety, life, and performance; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas this important observance should lead to greater safety awareness and a reduction in tire-related road incidents: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H9F3C8101EC344888ADE4CEE6963C31E8"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H486963256BFB4A19A9C1B937EF26C8A4"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HEDA6F8335EB4449185A1B32B2581AD64"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of <quote>National Tire Safety Week</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE3CA481C10D84CAA8A096E4EDA909BDD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses strong support for—</text> <subparagraph id="H2C9DCBCAABDB4FB884F317C29BF7F30D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the goals and ideals of <quote>National Tire Safety Week</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6FAD0C9CAA904991B3583F0D5A3D07FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>efforts to reduce tire-related accidents, fatalities, and injuries; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE609C5F772DD4EBE957A9E529D484EEC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H89F2E34A80AC417BAE0C43CC42A8093D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>participate in <quote>National Tire Safety Week</quote> events and activities; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4E4861BBD74D4332AC761A57B256E577"><enum>(B)</enum><text>educate themselves and others on the importance of regularly inspecting and maintaining a vehicle’s tires.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

