<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE64E14DFF49B4C8DB959A77489A5CC02" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2750 IH: Bridging the Broadband Gap Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2750</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000490">Mr. Taylor</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act to authorize recipients of funds under the Broadband Equity, Access, and Deployment Program to use such funds to provide broadband vouchers to households in certain locations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB26837F3ED6747F696EA3264699A3DBC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H501FE25C8B1B42A7AA13EAFD017B473B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bridging the Broadband Gap Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H971250B43F8A489F9880D39A5F946481"><enum>2.</enum><header>Use of BEAD Program funds to provide broadband vouchers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 60102 of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1702">47 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H20D6E25C38C14C84B2481A956AD57079" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H84D290BE424E4505A42E76B775AF4EF4"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Broadband vouchers</header> 
<paragraph id="HAC992B390BE84DF58F552403A668A2EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an eligible entity makes the determination described in paragraph (2) with respect to a political subdivision of such eligible entity, such eligible entity may use grant funds received under this section to provide to households in such political subdivision vouchers that such households may use to cover eligible broadband service costs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8810213041BE484787EEF6CE37839FE7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The determination described in this paragraph is a determination by an eligible entity that a political subdivision of such eligible entity lacks access to broadband service that such eligible entity considers adequate.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1482D22D4DF426093B5B8764A0527DC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In providing vouchers under this subsection, an eligible entity shall give priority to households in political subdivisions the per capita income of which is below the median per capita income of the political subdivisions of such eligible entity, as determined by such eligible entity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4BE59DF5CE61421FA74AC4FE7BFEC98E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitations</header> <subparagraph id="HC8D3EC216064403C870A2177A58DE83D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Households in unserved locations or underserved locations</header><text>An eligible entity may not provide a voucher under this subsection to a household unless, on the day before such eligible entity provides the first such voucher to such household, such household resides at a location that is an unserved location or an underserved location.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H84B046ED90FF4EC6B52414756B36BA9F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>In the case of eligible broadband service costs described in clauses (i)(II) and (ii) of paragraph (5)(B), an eligible entity may only provide vouchers under this subsection to a household to cover such costs charged to such household with respect to a single period of 12 consecutive months.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2B7E33D340847A68B76E9ECDB13AAC1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9F68288E44CE4DC094FDA496CDBF92A1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Broadband customer premises equipment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>broadband customer premises equipment</quote> means equipment employed on the premises of a household to provide satellite or fixed wireless broadband service.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H59FCA6B3C72848DD9A12EB2835C6033B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible broadband service costs</header><text>The term <quote>eligible broadband service costs</quote> means the following:</text> 
<clause id="H95A5A61AE98740DC981C4CDDF628CAE1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">50 percent of the amount charged by a provider of satellite or fixed wireless broadband service to a household for—</text> <subclause id="H8719481A5B2F4F46BEB386AACEAC877D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the purchase of broadband customer premises equipment; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HAB78BF7DC3DE4854862DDFA239F1B49E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the monthly lease or rental of broadband customer premises equipment.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H1445396C7FB1471E98B7A4BA4BA488A7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The monthly amount (not to exceed $30 per month) charged by a provider of satellite or fixed wireless broadband service to a household for providing such service to such household.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

