<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFDEF97A44D0E497699EB16D9A631D1AF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4234 IH: Safeguarding Americans From Extremist Risk (SAFER) at the Border Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4234</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250627">June 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000600">Mr. Langworthy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000619">Mr. Rulli</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001148">Mr. Simpson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000300">Mr. Evans of Colorado</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the Secretary of Homeland Security from granting parole to certain dangerous aliens, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF04491875D5E42C4BE363B2ACFB317EF" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HACA88EFA4CD3497AAFE3F96E0D72D394"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safeguarding Americans From Extremist Risk (SAFER) at the Border Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H28FCEDD5B82E4211A3428A1761F900B8"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definition of known or suspected terrorist and special interest alien</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1BC5613CCE2D4876897996CC605E02DF"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF714E7853DD440F687DD2CD425E3915E" indent="up1"><enum>(53)</enum><text>The term <term>known terrorist</term> means an individual who has been—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A856F7CD61F4299A5AA985478FD308B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">arrested, charged by information, indicted for, or convicted of a crime related to terrorism or terrorist activities by the United States Government or a foreign government authority; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF3B6770A791A43E09E48A594FCD77C21"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identified as a terrorist or as a member of a terrorist organization pursuant to statute, Executive order, or international legal obligation pursuant to a United Nations Security Council Resolution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H978FCE30DF4E4435B311C6ABDBF66067" indent="up1"><enum>(54)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>special interest alien</term> means an alien who, based upon an analysis of travel patterns and other information available to the United States Government, potentially poses a national security risk to the United States or its interests due to a known or potential nexus to terrorism. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC793C7CC93644D46B0398621B4B9D8F1" indent="up1"><enum>(55)</enum><text>The term <term>suspected terrorist</term> means an individual who is reasonably suspected to be engaging in, has engaged in, or intends to engage in conduct constituting, in preparation for, in aid of, or related to terrorism or terrorist activities.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A5F8DB73FC9435B98324816E6D3F5C9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Parole of certain aliens prohibited</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 212(d)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(d)(5)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H036F525A34794610A3536A6C3B14ABD7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (D); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE06786B0CD94AF699DCEE55358682CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subparagraphs (A) and (B) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE7E5A1A63F6747EEA0E6CE88FDFD7AC0"><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H653F99165CB04FFA94572960104A3897" indent="up2"><enum/></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H29990C06E38E43F9AD2BCDFD9873B54F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C) and in section 214(f), the Secretary of Homeland Security may temporarily parole into the United States, under such conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, and only on a case-by-case basis for urgent humanitarian reasons or significant public benefit, arriving aliens applying for admission to the United States. Such parole of any such alien shall not be regarded as an admission of the alien and when the purposes of such parole, in the opinion of the Secretary, have been served, such alien shall immediately return or be returned to the custody from which such alien was paroled. Following the conclusion of such parole, such alien's case shall continue to be dealt with in the same manner as that of any other applicant for admission to the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA5BC6738CB994FD6A239E9A4A953EC6F" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may not parole into the United States an alien who is a refugee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up2" id="HAF7BFAA67F7A4F3AABAFD1197671D626"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security may not parole into the United States any alien who has been designated by any official of the Department of State or the Department of Homeland Security as—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB49B5DD403924364A4539E7C022DF608"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an alien who is inadmissible under subsection (a)(3)(A) on the grounds that the alien seeks to enter the United States to engage solely, principally, or incidentally in an activity related to espionage, sabotage, other unlawful activity, or any activity to overthrow the Government of the United States;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E7FBC1D7CB44787BE061237DA7E307E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an alien who is inadmissible under paragraph (2), (3)(B), or (3)(F) of subsection (a) due to criminal activities (including membership in a transnational criminal organization) or terrorist activities (including association with a terrorist organization);</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BC02E984B3548BD8C40B32A7BEE625D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an alien who is listed on the Federal Bureau of Investigation Threat Screening Center’s Terrorism Watchlist or any other successor database; </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA438BD99441245B4B70D656CC4375C50"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an alien who has been arrested, charged by information, indicted, or convicted by the United States Government or by a foreign government for a crime related to terrorism or terrorist activities; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H309E86AE364C4B88A23646DB6DEF0E40"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an alien who, based upon an analysis of travel patterns and other information available to the United States Government, potentially poses a national security risk to the United States or its interests due to a known or potential nexus to terrorism.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

