<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6CEAD7D18A854F6098761F54CC737420" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1931 IH: Access to Pediatric Technologies Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1931</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250306">March 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to facilitate patient access to certain pediatric technologies.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H68B9C7D2194F409AB1C54F7FFD990781" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC12512D9F3864FCCACA2A963DE2905DD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Access to Pediatric Technologies Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H390FF6BB597F429AA7AF67C709BEBB58"><enum>2.</enum><header>Facilitating access to pediatric technologies</header> <subsection id="H282DB2CBB9EB461D8192AB26307CDEF8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1848 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86BAD7DAEAD8446E80219EE13142D363">
<subsection id="H17DE3FA379D740DCA30B25F290F49CCA"><enum>(u)</enum><header>Facilitating access to pediatric technologies</header>
<paragraph id="HE3FD28E0F4F94B7A9E4FA88545C23247"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For each qualifying pediatric technology (as defined in paragraph (4)) furnished on or after January 1, 2026, the Secretary shall, upon receipt of a manufacturer request under paragraph (3), establish national relative value units under the physician fee schedule established under this section, to the extent no such national relative value units have been established for such qualifying pediatric technology under such fee schedule.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9A29D04A64E492985E9B7C6BF9A7E49"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payment methodology</header><text>The Secretary shall establish national relative value units for a qualifying pediatric technology under this subsection—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H67698D095C844ACAA4E8422D8234094F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in accordance with the payment methodology established under this section and applicable regulations; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H393003BB213648269DD3412838AE813B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">using available data related to the qualifying pediatric technology, which may include applicable contractor pricing information, claims data, time and motion studies, invoice information, or other information used by the Secretary in establishing payment rates.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDE593F7897084A909D46F484127F627A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Implementation</header>
<subparagraph id="H0B66FB65F78141B391DF5F17C574F609"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon written request to the Secretary from the manufacturer of a qualifying pediatric technology, the Secretary shall establish national relative value units under paragraph (1) through the annual rulemaking process for the physician fee schedule established under this section, in accordance with the timeline described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE15679E59A1F42F299D2A553112DD5EB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Timeline</header> <clause id="H316D9BB175D747648C2641AFCBC762F1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>In the case where the Secretary receives a request under this paragraph on or before May 1 of a given year from a manufacturer with respect to a qualifying pediatric technology of the manufacturer, the Secretary shall establish national relative value units for the qualifying pediatric technology in the rulemaking process during that year for the physician fee schedule established under this section.</text></clause>
<clause id="H1032AC6CF7F64C4EAF109461F4A86BB2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>In the case where the Secretary receives a request under this paragraph after May 1 of a given year from a manufacturer with respect to a qualifying pediatric technology of the manufacturer, the Secretary shall establish national relative value units for the qualifying pediatric technology in the rulemaking process during the following year for the physician fee schedule established under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAF3728D1916E4045A9C19EB674BF6B10"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Content of manufacturer requests</header><text>A manufacturer submitting a request under paragraph with respect to a qualifying pediatric technology of the manufacturer shall include in such request information to verify that the technology is a qualifying pediatric technology and to allow the Secretary to establish national relative value units for such technology, including (to the extent available) contractor pricing information, claims data, time and motion studies, invoice information, or other relevant information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5103EF9A73C245CE9083FBFB08F08E0E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualifying pediatric technology defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>qualifying pediatric technology</term> means a medical device that is—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB87FA257A244123A675C2FCBD686DF8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">covered under this title;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5727A80AF51D4CDB808A33B6BA72969B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">approved, cleared, or authorized under section 510(k), 513(f)(2), or 515 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360">21 U.S.C. 360(k)</external-xref>, 360c(f)(2), 360e);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H078C39E89D1D4439971DF4C7B04059DF"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">described by a temporary Level I HCPCS Code intended for emerging technologies, services, or procedures; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H43FD253065974AE3855DB525CFACCE89"><enum>(D)</enum>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H54DAADFE1CA544A0A3FEA1D3F8D92074"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">used as part of a procedure predominantly performed on pediatric patients; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62FD57A94F6B44218108B379D33E57CA" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has otherwise been specifically designed for safe and effective use in pediatric populations.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4D06DC55DEEE46AD84573E25FB214BEB" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require coverage of a qualifying pediatric technology under this title or alter the requirements of section 1862(a)(1)(A).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

