<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC73CFFB7335F4873ADFD49E50EFC1A45" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1811 IH: Judicial Ethics Enforcement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1811</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250303">March 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 28, United States Code, to provide an Inspector General for the judicial branch, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE3799FCCD6C748AD904065279FE7946E" style="OLC"> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="H5E6A463E951149DFA31DC35D0F83D32F"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Judicial Ethics Enforcement Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF8814661367B4B0BAF9E5285B5123004"><enum>2.</enum><header>Inspector general for the judicial branch</header> <subsection id="H79C78FBB5C0F4B139989DBCBCD9E7159"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment and Duties</header><text>Part III of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H92168AD517E4426BA1468AAB0FA963A4">
<chapter id="H2AF326D791994C4EAC8E18B155C067EA"><enum>60</enum><header>INSPECTOR GENERAL FOR THE JUDICIAL BRANCH</header>
<toc container-level="chapter-container" idref="H2AF326D791994C4EAC8E18B155C067EA" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
<toc-entry idref="H82C3FD9153C94214B085ACC33713A351" level="section">Sec.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="section">1021. Establishment.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H4C427DA770644C0B87B1CA942C067F16" level="section">1022. Appointment, term, and removal of Inspector General.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H6F26628A4AC344CA9A4C0B3573C51870" level="section">1023. Duties.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H52BD438667FC48269AF07F9293BD3C4E" level="section">1024. Powers.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H94652F5A92824B4DADFEC98650F030A6" level="section">1025. Reports.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HA4C8FB601FA844D785AC848C0ED72185" level="section">1026. Whistleblower protection.</toc-entry></toc>
<section id="H82C3FD9153C94214B085ACC33713A351"><enum>1021.</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is established for the judicial branch of the Government the Office of Inspector General for the Judicial Branch (in this chapter referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>).</text></section> <section id="H4C427DA770644C0B87B1CA942C067F16"><enum>1022.</enum><header>Appointment, term, and removal of Inspector General</header> <subsection id="H9DF3C80AD1BF44F0A776387FBDB335FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The head of the Office shall be the Inspector General, who shall be appointed by the Chief Justice of the United States after consultation with the majority and minority leaders of the Senate and the Speaker and minority leader of the House of Representatives.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H3615344D700748EEA54F4A0198E5E651"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Term</header><text>The Inspector General shall serve for a term of 4 years and may be reappointed by the Chief Justice of the United States for any number of additional terms.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBCBBED29D3B8433DA9718D1798586764"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General may be removed from office by the Chief Justice of the United States. The Chief Justice shall communicate the reasons for any such removal to both Houses of Congress.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H6F26628A4AC344CA9A4C0B3573C51870"><enum>1023.</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">With respect to the judicial branch, the Office shall—</text> <paragraph id="HD82DDBF70C3E47B699C57B4B0DFE9AB1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct investigations of alleged misconduct in the judicial branch (other than the United States Supreme Court) under chapter 16 that may require oversight or other action within the judicial branch or by Congress;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD85CAB4FE39442B69C21E41FCFF77998"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conduct investigations of alleged violations of the Code of Conduct for Justices of the Supreme Court of the United States or any other alleged misconduct in the United States Supreme Court that may require oversight or other action within the judicial branch or by Congress;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A8840C9C21C412293C0DF0C3E5A747E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conduct and supervise audits and investigations;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H48A62B131D8A48B89EFB32067C74E49C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>prevent and detect waste, fraud, and abuse; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1DB7545E7F3D4D3F84DEF8B486068EC6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>recommend changes in laws or regulations governing the judicial branch.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H52BD438667FC48269AF07F9293BD3C4E"><enum>1024.</enum><header>Powers</header>
<subsection id="H27BE5DCA44254D0F8997E1DA671CD786"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Powers</header><text>In carrying out the duties of the Office, the Inspector General shall have the power to—</text> <paragraph id="H781EF2BAABD045E8A24EEEFD55C65F66"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make investigations and reports;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD001357BDFBA4D659B52ECB5CD7B4DC9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>obtain information or assistance from any Federal, State, or local governmental agency, or other entity, or unit thereof, including all information kept in the course of business by the Judicial Conference of the United States, the judicial councils of circuits, the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, and the United States Sentencing Commission;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE58BA3BAA1E449783C830D9FD88A1D5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>require, by subpoena or otherwise, the attendance and testimony of such witnesses, and the production of such books, records, correspondence, memoranda, papers, and documents, which subpoena, in the case of contumacy or refusal to obey, shall be enforceable by civil action;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H443525EDC0E54105818ED4849DB697C8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>administer to or take from any person an oath, affirmation, or affidavit;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38B1449D2D3C47609BC1819A859773C3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>employ such officers and employees, subject to the provisions of title 5, governing appointments in the competitive service, and the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEF4958C60F754FBB9AE088B22CD6497E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>obtain services as authorized by section 3109 of title 5 at daily rates not to exceed the equivalent rate for a position at level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of such title; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAABDFB902ECB4520A6021EDC454B18D0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the extent and in such amounts as may be provided in advance by appropriations Acts, to enter into contracts and other arrangements for audits, studies, analyses, and other services with public agencies and with private persons, and to make such payments as may be necessary to carry out the duties of the Office.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H4E8279F3201748259798DA7DE3F49403"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Chapter 16 matters</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General shall not commence an investigation under section 1023(1) until the denial of a petition for review by the judicial council of the circuit under section 352(c) of this title or upon referral or certification to the Judicial Conference of the United States of any matter under section 354(b) of this title.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA4E4520038274D4D8984CCE178D0FE95"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General shall not have the authority to—</text>
<paragraph id="HB75C20720ED7417FA1C0FDEA19E1FE78"><enum>(1)</enum><text>investigate or review any matter that is directly related to the merits of a decision or procedural ruling by any judge, justice, or court; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD74653607B9E40A088D7255BFF2F87AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>punish or discipline any judge, justice, or court.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H94652F5A92824B4DADFEC98650F030A6"><enum>1025.</enum><header>Reports</header>
<subsection id="H0DE5B81AF2B54AB1822D819DF157D586"><enum>(a)</enum><header>When To Be Made</header><text>The Inspector General shall—</text> <paragraph id="HCA550A788EC1426CA953B96C645A04BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make an annual report to the Chief Justice and to Congress relating to the activities of the Office; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFD875005B8C2446A84CD893FB49B468C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make prompt reports to the Chief Justice and to Congress on matters that may require action by the Chief Justice or Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD62E8BE52108404DB4132A6A7C00179C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sensitive Matter</header><text>If a report contains sensitive matter, the Inspector General may so indicate and Congress may receive that report in closed session.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HF0CF2E19BD724571B468FF6D5B06240B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duty To Inform Attorney General</header><text>In carrying out the duties of the Office, the Inspector General shall report expeditiously to the Attorney General whenever the Inspector General has reasonable grounds to believe there has been a violation of Federal criminal law.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HA4C8FB601FA844D785AC848C0ED72185"><enum>1026.</enum><header>Whistleblower protection</header> <subsection id="H56753FF684694F9AADDBE275076367CD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>No officer, employee, agent, contractor, or subcontractor in the judicial branch may discharge, demote, threaten, suspend, harass, or in any other manner discriminate against an employee in the terms and conditions of employment because of any lawful act done by the employee to provide information, cause information to be provided, or otherwise assist in an investigation regarding any possible violation of Federal law or regulation, or misconduct, by a judge, justice, or any other employee in the judicial branch, which may assist the Inspector General in the performance of duties under this chapter.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HD1E0C6C3649644F5AB517B4BBDB17C8B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil Action</header><text>An employee injured by a violation of subsection (a) may, in a civil action, obtain appropriate relief.</text></subsection></section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H3EE8F455A021406F8502C29EBD118AF8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of chapters for part III of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C654FF5E2814BDB9453F582D2337E3D">
<toc>
<multi-column-toc-entry bold="off" level="chapter"><toc-enum>60. </toc-enum><level-header level="chapter">Inspector General for the judicial branch</level-header><target>1021</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

