<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H41DDF5F95183468BB2D83473D988F469" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 32 IH: Congratulating the North Dakota State University Bison football team for winning the 2024 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Football Championship Subdivision title.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 32</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250113">January 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000482">Ms. Fedorchak</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the North Dakota State University Bison football team for winning the 2024 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Football Championship Subdivision title.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on January 6, 2025, the North Dakota State University (NDSU) Bison football team won the 2024 National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) Division I Football Championship Subdivision (FCS) title game in Frisco, Texas, in a well-fought victory over the Montana State University Bobcats by a score of 35–32;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, including the 2024 NCAA Division I FCS title, the NDSU Bison have won 19 national football championships;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the NDSU Bison have won 10 of the last 14 NCAA Division I FCS titles, from 2011 to 2024, an achievement that continues to be unmatched in modern collegiate football history;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the NDSU Bison have displayed tremendous resilience and skill since 2011, with 186 wins to 21 losses, including a streak of 39 consecutive wins from 2017 to 2021;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas head coach Tim Polasek, his staff, and their victorious student-athletes led the NDSU Bison to a championship in his first year as head coach at NDSU, continuing the culture of excellence of the NDSU Bison;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas thousands of NDSU Bison fans attended the championship game in Frisco, Texas, reflecting the tremendous pride and dedication of Bison Nation, which has supported and helped drive the achievement of the NDSU Bison; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 2024 NCAA Division I FCS title was a victory for both the NDSU Bison and the entire State of North Dakota: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H1729DBD8F71848EFA26C1465E3F2EFA5"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H1311DEB973594E5797132592E4DD29CF"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives —</text><paragraph id="H61EAE9A6957D433DB541799F3CCE2323"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the North Dakota State University Bison football team for winning the 2024 National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) Division I Football Championship Subdivision (FCS) title;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA81F674229814D41B27AA805C3226A04"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends the players, coaches, and staff of the North Dakota State University Bison football team for—</text><subparagraph id="H244BE35BF6BD4B518E00447F19501F24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>their tireless work and dedication; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC2380BEA16843748DB0A92C0EE47627"><enum>(B)</enum><text>fostering a continued tradition of excellence;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF19C583A9CA445CF8EBFFB682D9CC34F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>congratulates the North Dakota State University President David Cook, North Dakota State University Athletic Director Matt Larsen, and all the faculty and staff of North Dakota State University for creating an environment that emphasizes excellence in both academics and athletics; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07BDA4F9E6024A378EBF4317C5C19A2B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recognizes the students, alumni, and fans of North Dakota State University and all of Bison Nation for supporting the North Dakota State University Bison football team so well during its successful quest to bring home yet another NCAA Division I FCS trophy for North Dakota State University. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

