<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDA6FA025851545D9A05A0979BF6C79AD" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 529 IH: Honoring and celebrating National Boys and Girls Club Week of 2025.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 529</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250623">June 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000067">Mr. Yakym</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring and celebrating National Boys and Girls Club Week of 2025.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the young people of the United States are the leaders of tomorrow;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many young people seek out-of-school programming as a safe place to connect with caring staff that help young people achieve their full potential;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there are over 5,500 Boys and Girls Clubs of America in 50 States, Washington, DC, Puerto Rico, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, and United States military bases around the world, that serve more than 3,300,000 young people annually through more than 2,700 school-based clubs, in rural, urban, suburban communities and partnerships with over 250 Native Tribal communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Boys and Girls Clubs of America do whatever it takes to ensure every young person in the United States has the skills needed to graduate high school and be well-prepared for life and work;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, through programs that encourage career readiness, leadership development, STEM skills, academic achievement, life skills, financial literacy, and civics education, the Boys and Girls Clubs of America help youth develop the skills needed to succeed in the economy; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Boys and Girls Clubs of America, with 5,500 Boys and Girls Clubs of America and millions of students and alumni nationwide, will celebrate the week of June 23 through June 27, 2025, as National Boys and Girls Club Week: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H0889AD6CD37C4FC283AA0FDD51A75F9C"><section id="HDB6F48D2F2D448149CF31C37D701A154" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HCDDC04765C5A4C138C4F89E43B5D0F87" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls on the people of the United States to celebrate National Boys and Girls Club Week; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3297D5E6BACF4730854CA0420132D833"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages Americans to recognize and commend the Boys and Girls Clubs of America for building great futures for youth in communities throughout the United States. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

