<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3333E1DBDC7A4C868BCA74CACD06ECC3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3789 IH: Drug-price Transparency for Consumers Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3789</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250605">June 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000490">Mr. Taylor</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XI of the Social Security Act to require that direct-to-consumer advertisements for prescription drugs and biological products include an appropriate disclosure of pricing information.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9F697D9F35AF4E76BC367AD7698BA479" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF798F2C45CB4497FAB0C374D55EE8F59" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Drug-price Transparency for Consumers Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>DTC Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBC897FBC196A4B4592ADCE2325E9C118"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of the Senate</header> <subsection id="H27A5FC5F18A04A30B02206FA2DC157AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8CBB243870FE4073A35A12737D9A2B79"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Direct-to-consumer advertising of prescription pharmaceuticals is legally permitted in only 2 developed countries, the United States and New Zealand.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7BB3E5A0C98644E69B4CE759FF7DE676"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In 2018, pharmaceutical ad spending exceeded $6,046,000,000, a 4.8-percent increase over 2017, resulting in the average American seeing 9 drug advertisements per day.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC0C1F7B4F4D64171AAA0B520CC3CDBA1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The most commonly advertised medication in the United States in 2020 had a list price of more than $6,000 for a one-month supply.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD85559C3DE614B74803BBAD06F97EB07"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A 2021 Government Accountability Office report found that two-thirds of all direct-to-consumer drug advertising between 2016 and 2018 was concentrated among 39 brand-name drugs or biologicals, about half of which were recently approved by the Food and Drug Administration.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0838ECCDD9AB400682FE54D727556D77"><enum>(5)</enum><text>According to a 2011 Congressional Budget Office report, pharmaceutical manufacturers advertise their products directly to consumers in an attempt to boost demand for their products and thereby raise the price that consumers are willing to pay, increase the quantity of drugs sold, or achieve some combination of the two.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD5A00F12B4E49088F5F2852FCA79394"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Studies, including a 2012 systematic review published in the Annual Review of Public Health, a 2005 randomized trial published in the Journal of the American Medical Association, and a 2004 survey published in Health Affairs, show that patients are more likely to ask their doctor for a specific medication, and the doctor is more likely to write a prescription for it, if a patient has seen an advertisement for such medication, even if such medication is not the most clinically appropriate for the patient or if a lower cost generic medication may be available.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE5AE7DEDD8BE41EBB8935483C7A99BAD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>According to a 2011 Congressional Budget Office report, the average number of prescriptions written for newly approved brand-name drugs with direct-to-consumer advertising was 9 times greater than the average number of prescriptions written for newly approved brand-name drugs without direct-to-consumer advertising.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H674CFA1CFE1D4C99B17D59C1737E7848"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services is the single largest drug payer in the United States. Between 2016 and 2018, 58 percent of the $560,000,000,000 in Medicare drug spending was for advertised drugs, and in 2018 alone, the 20 most advertised drugs on television cost Medicare and Medicaid a combined $34,000,000,000.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H75FBEB7BE5F14A809C4FA01F3C1EECC8"><enum>(9)</enum><text>A 2021 Government Accountability Office report found that direct-to-consumer advertising may have contributed to increases in Medicare beneficiary use and spending among certain drugs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0433A1C5F1FC4AD7B25E10A6BF4B9A58"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The American Medical Association has passed resolutions supporting the requirement for price transparency in any direct-to-consumer advertising, stating that such advertisements on their own <quote>inflate demand for new and more expensive drugs, even when these drugs may not be appropriate</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE6F4E5B9780D436A8A040691769C33DD"><enum>(11)</enum><text>A 2019 study published in the Journal of the American Medical Association found that health care consumers dramatically underestimate their out-of-pocket costs for certain expensive medications, but once they learn the wholesale acquisition cost (in this section referred to as the <quote>WAC</quote>) of the product, they are far better able to approximate their out-of-pocket costs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H709FFA929167474585521D97B46B3247"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Approximately half of Americans have high-deductible health plans, under which they often pay the list price of a drug until their insurance deductible is met. All of the top Medicare prescription drug plans use coinsurance rather than fixed-dollar copayments for medications on nonpreferred drug tiers, exposing beneficiaries to WAC prices.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H675DE78E151048768C2FA15456A73757"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Section 119 of division CC of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>) requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to increase the use of real-time benefit tools to lower beneficiary costs. However, there still remains a lack of available pricing tools, so patients may not learn of their medication’s cost until after being given a prescription for the medication. A 2013 study published in The Oncologist found that one-quarter of all cancer patients chose not to fill a prescription due to cost.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE0111C6516C6486194BA0717126C2179"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The Federal Government already exercises its authority to oversee certain aspects of direct-to-consumer drug advertising, including required disclosures of information related to side effects, contraindications, and effectiveness.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA9ABBE8B086441E2A05C92B902C74114"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H4BE6E45BE9EF493ABCC4A3473FC08329"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a lack of transparency in pricing for pharmaceuticals has led to a lack of competition for such pharmaceuticals, as evidenced by a finding by the Department of Health and Human Services that <quote>Consumers of pharmaceuticals are currently missing information that consumers of other products can more readily access, namely the list price of the product, which acts as a point of comparison when judging the reasonableness of prices offered for potential substitute products</quote> (84 Fed. Reg. 20735);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H324E12E70D6441E5B07935F9C5434ECF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in an age where price information is ubiquitous, the prices of pharmaceuticals remain shrouded in secrecy and limited to those who subscribe to expensive drug price reporting services, which typically include pharmaceutical manufacturers or other health care industry entities and not the general public;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA1A267FD32B45AB94C31445CD066B80"><enum>(3)</enum><text>greater insight and transparency into drug prices will help consumers know if they can afford to complete a course of therapy before deciding to initiate that course of therapy;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H95FF0947A8E34D8DBBD8FD4445907070"><enum>(4)</enum><text>price shopping is the mark of rational economic behavior, and markets operate more efficiently when consumers have relevant information about a product, including its price, before making an informed decision about whether to buy that product;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H7BFEDA860F1E4A64B40F126636E142A0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>providing consumers with basic price information may result in the selection of lesser cost alternatives, all else being equal relative to the patient’s care, and is integral to providing adequate competition in the market;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC47E725BE64143DAA2C66CCB10964A8D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the WAC is a factual, objective, and uncontroversial definition for the list price of a medication, in that it is defined in statute, reflects an understood place in the supply chain, and is at the sole discretion of the manufacturer to set;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H30D70299178A4856AF86F502F712A54B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>there is a governmental interest in ensuring that consumers who seek to purchase pharmaceuticals for purposes of promoting their health and safety understand the objective list price of any pharmaceutical that they are encouraged through advertisements to purchase, which allows consumers to make informed purchasing decisions; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCA9651F9296145BD947298C8D7E300B7" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(8)</enum><text>there is a governmental interest in mitigating wasteful expenditures and promoting the efficient administration of the Medicare program by slowing the growth of Federal spending on prescription drugs.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HC5D80D0E2A334160B6C2D052EB30BF99"><enum>3.</enum><header>Requirement that direct-to-consumer advertisements for prescription drugs and biological products include an appropriate disclosure of pricing information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part A of title XI of the Social Security Act is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF48241267F1D4E7499C237D1A90DD8A6"> 
<section id="HBA5AD82DC386401F9E7825D7F8E8B5F3"><enum>1150D.</enum><header>Requirement that direct-to-consumer advertisements for prescription drugs and biologicals include an appropriate disclosure of pricing information</header> 
<subsection id="H0A6F3105F574461A89FBE925DC35AB3A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header> 
<paragraph id="H5E716AC4170E469D9D1A3137A65EC363"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), not later than July 1, 2026, the Secretary shall require that each direct-to-consumer advertisement for a prescription drug or biological product for which payment is available under title XVIII or XIX and that is required to include the information relating to side effects, contraindications, and effectiveness described in section 202.1(e)(1) of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation) also include an appropriate disclosure of pricing information, as described in subsection (b), with respect to such prescription drug or biological product.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H36AFF34AEB7F49E9AF332F74884BEA3C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>The requirement under paragraph (1) shall not apply to a prescription drug or biological product for which the wholesale acquisition cost for a 30-day supply of (or, if applicable, a typical course of treatment as set forth in the approved label for the primary indication addressed in the advertisement for) such prescription drug or biological product is less than $35.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H89A6170F40694795A08607A634CE2026"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appropriate disclosure of pricing information</header><text>For the purposes of subsection (a), an appropriate disclosure of pricing information, with respect to a prescription drug or biological product—</text> <paragraph id="H303BC1BB4D85443AA37B7AE2BF712CD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall clearly and conspicuously disclose the wholesale acquisition cost for a 30-day supply of (or, if applicable, a typical course of treatment for) such prescription drug or biological product; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H18B716FFEBC34841ABE26D405D67AC3B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may explain that a consumer may pay a different amount for such prescription drug or biological product than such wholesale acquisition cost depending on the health insurance coverage of the consumer.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4DC41ADAA6EE4B0EAAC8B503010BAD1A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall promulgate final regulations to carry out this section, including establishing requirements for—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA7C93C2D1D2E4B809B74200AFDED1BDA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the visual and audio components, with respect to each medium of direct-to-consumer advertisement, to communicate the wholesale acquisition cost of the advertised prescription drug or biological product; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4F4D6ACCD3984ACFB848B23909EF22DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount of time for a manufacturer to update any direct-to-consumer advertisement to reflect any change to the wholesale acquisition cost of the advertised prescription drug or biological product.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2A3898AF2EE049229F2F9960253E0AFD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sanctions</header><text>Any manufacturer of a prescription drug or biological product, or an agent of such manufacturer, that violates the requirement of this section may be subject to a civil money penalty of not more than $100,000 for each such violation. The provisions of section 1128A (other than subsections (a) and (b)) shall apply to civil money penalties under the preceding sentence in the same manner as they apply to a penalty or proceeding under section 1128A(a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD03BBA9C5F67404FAB8EA15BF4D71464"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Public reporting</header><text>In order to enforce the requirement under this section, the Secretary may use information reported about manufacturers that fail to comply with such requirement.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC5A6FE1A5F3F4E7F9BB29E8551572243"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HF2A6565A15D247F6BBE0B6DF013000BB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Biological product</header><text>The term <term>biological product</term> means any biological product (as defined in section 351(i) of the Public Health Service Act) that is licensed by the Food and Drug Administration pursuant to section 351 and is subject to the requirements of section 503(b)(1) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0CFDAFC62A1D46C8AEAE71D6EC794963"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prescription drug</header><text>The term <term>prescription drug</term> means any drug (as defined in section 201(g) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act) that has been approved by the Food and Drug Administration pursuant to section 505 of such Act and is subject to the requirements of section 503(b)(1) of such Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7FB5C60C33AD4FB6B28B769002F84E48"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Wholesale acquisition cost</header><text>The term <term>wholesale acquisition cost</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1847A(c)(6)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H708A4446DCAD40CFB4ADA05D1AA50818"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for the purposes of carrying out this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

