<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2840E613FF5B490BB42C2C9168C126CC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 344 IH: Anti-Congestion Tax Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 344</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250113">January 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To condition the receipt of certain grants by the Metropolitan Transportation Authority on exempting certain drivers from congestion fees, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H00AC06982D264E839096BDEE27D6BD4F" style="OLC"><section id="HA6A92508CC8049CFA064D8D3C66CA195" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Anti-Congestion Tax Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBAFAC3144D2844A9BBB9A9BDF933BBF9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Condition on receipt of capital investment grants</header><subsection id="HAAC6D6D03FE04F27A6A10A4D287C6368"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Transportation may not award a capital investment grant described in section 5338(d) of title 49, United States Code, to the Metropolitan Transportation Authority for a project in New York State until the Secretary certifies that any vehicle entering the congestion tolling zone using a vehicular crossing known as the Holland Tunnel, the Lincoln Tunnel, or the George Washington Bridge, or any other vehicular crossing for the use of crossing immediately before entry into the congestion tolling zone, receives an exemption as follows: The vehicle is credited an amount equal to the toll charged to such vehicle for the use of such crossing immediately before entry into the congestion tolling zone from the amount of the congestion toll charged to such vehicle for purposes of entering the congestion tolling zone.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6A85E8EC558D484081742A23E1F58EA5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction for George Washington Bridge</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a), a vehicle receives an exemption while crossing the George Washington Bridge if such vehicle is treated in the same manner as a vehicle crossing the Henry Hudson Bridge is treated on the first date on which the congestion toll is charged.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8E28BDD8EA854C0D87E1585D00E3BE97"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Subsection (a) shall apply with respect to a grant awarded on or after the first date on which the congestion toll is charged.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9049C7D0B25544F49225BB70FEB8FD80"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the following definitions apply:</text><paragraph id="HC3304B1D9A4A49DD99DEF7D667A9A57E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Congestion toll</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>congestion toll</term> means a toll charged for entry into or remaining in the congestion tolling zone.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70D2C38D3C844DAA8A98FB0EB8C64116"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Congestion tolling zone</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>congestion tolling zone</term> means any roadways, bridges, tunnels, approaches, or ramps that are located within, or enter to, the geographic area in the borough of Manhattan south of and inclusive of Sixtieth Street to the extent practicable, but does not include the Franklin D. Roosevelt Drive.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H669D7D132DD34F3696D89E4DB4B5F5E5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Credit for certain congestion tolls</header><subsection id="HEC3A3E9591094C98AB9CCCB7A3901D63"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart B of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding after section 30D the following new section:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEF4289EF4D0F4A70A0A06D76B986D9CB" style="OLC"><section id="HF14C010DBFFF46BABB0492E86C208715"><enum>30E.</enum><header>Certain congestion tolls</header><subsection id="HB94CEDB274994DA09F63AAC90FEA5A9F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year an amount equal to the sum of any congestion toll (as such term is defined in section 2(d) of the <short-title>Anti-Congestion Tax Act</short-title>) paid or incurred during the taxable year by such taxpayer for the use of any qualified vehicular crossing immediately before entry into the congestion tolling zone (as such term is defined in section 2(d) of the <short-title>Anti-Congestion Tax Act</short-title>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H991A81BDC73D42F49373B2C94641C99C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified vehicular crossing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>qualified vehicular crossing</term> means any of the vehicular crossing known as the Holland Tunnel, the Lincoln Tunnel, the George Washington Bridge, or any other vehicular crossing for the use of crossing immediately before entry into the congestion tolling zone.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3FA9904E0ED74C25825B88F32F7D1CCE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No double benefit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of any deduction or other credit allowable under this chapter for a congestion toll for which a credit is allowable under subsection (a) shall be reduced by the amount of credit allowed under such subsection.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H6BBA0B1035BE4296A57D329F512418BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for such subpart B is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 30D the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H104CC20F829A4D17A4B240183B38A9AA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 30E. Certain congestion tolls.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C8B07AA8EC447939D3DD48439AF0FC3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

