<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA1A1299C94794626A8243D915574AA2B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5626 IH: Taiwan and American Space Assistance Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5626</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250930">September 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill of Arkansas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide expanded cooperation by the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration with Taiwan, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9D28275FFEA04CDBA1058E97670478E5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H86A61DB5E19C4381A84379AB1BAB4541" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Taiwan and American Space Assistance Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF3058546363F4C2689BCAD32E6A710B1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Space cooperation with Taiwan</header> <subsection id="HA00A61C97E714025A9BB4A0F9990EAE0" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the Secretary of State, shall seek to engage Taiwan relating to expanding cooperation regarding civilian space activities.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3D765592A86C44C48F05BC1F7A307298" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cooperation efforts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In seeking to expand the cooperation regarding civilian space activities between the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and Taiwan under subsection (a), the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, may carry out efforts to identify and pursue space exploration, space applications, and science initiatives in areas of mutual benefit, consistent with the Taiwan Relations Act of 1979 and applicable export regulations, and taking all appropriate measures to protect sensitive information, intellectual property, trade secrets, and economic interests of the United States, in the following areas:</text> <paragraph id="H8DF23596FF064ABB9E7445DF8C2B3706" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Satellite programs, space exploration programs, and atmospheric and weather programs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HECB09FA3703E46CD94A4F0CEA9002D41" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Personnel exchanges of employees of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration with the Taiwan Space Agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A3C52DD7BB840D195015F92F80B583C" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Activities of mutual benefit related to commercial space and atmospheric and weather technology and services.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H74289918AE224675A05E6550E8AE122B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<paragraph id="H38761E2D08FD4599941E51D1421808EE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter for five years, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the implementation of this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D1AD49AE890467ABA4B9CAA03143127"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC6D76BA225264E01A977BC672DDFD01C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the activities conducted between the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration with Taiwan.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA449A76F7CC0458189C97F4B8EC67B68"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An identification of any challenges that need to be addressed to expand such cooperation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H247BBC93F8AF4DF99312D89A9BC77A02"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An overview of efforts undertaken pursuant to this section.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9DB76677E4904BC6A508E9B841F0443E" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other matter the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the Secretary of State consider relevant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9935816BB2A64B3C905D595FEA0E3E4D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> <paragraph id="H1273B2ECBACD48E89C2BE835B921B418"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5267F374273C43849CE24CF1592A2BCD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

