<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-RIL25611-H4N-L7-WFH"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 303 ATS: Expressing support for the designation of May 17, 2025, as “DIPG Pediatric Brain Cancer Awareness Day” to raise awareness of, and encourage research on, diffuse intrinsic pontine glioma tumors and pediatric cancers in general.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 303</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250625" legis-day="20250624">June 25 (legislative day, June 24), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of May 17, 2025, as <quote>DIPG Pediatric Brain Cancer Awareness Day</quote> to raise awareness of, and encourage research on, diffuse intrinsic pontine glioma tumors and pediatric cancers in general.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas diffuse intrinsic pontine glioma (referred to in this preamble as <quote>DIPG</quote>) tumors regularly affect 200 to 300 children in the United States each year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas brain tumors are the leading cause of cancer-related death among children;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas DIPG tumors are the leading cause of pediatric brain cancer deaths;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, with respect to a child who is diagnosed with a DIPG tumor and receives treatment for a DIPG tumor, the median amount of time that the child survives after diagnosis is approximately 11 months;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, with respect to an individual who is diagnosed with a DIPG tumor, the rate of survival 5 years after diagnosis is approximately 2 percent;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the average age at which a child is diagnosed with a DIPG tumor is between 5 and 10 years, resulting in a life expectancy approximately 70 years shorter than the average life expectancy in the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the prognosis for children diagnosed with DIPG tumors has not meaningfully improved during the past 50 years: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HD56BDDD9B5F0437D8D1A9EFB8169C33A"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H6E641AFCC661439D922E7F3F2894B8CF"><enum/><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="HF4B1C4BFF1EF4CC7B5F90A39BDE03FC8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports designating May 17, 2025, as <quote>DIPG Pediatric Brain Cancer Awareness Day</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idC9F52F3AE4DE4AE6866B2B26400ECF10"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports efforts—</text><subparagraph id="id64814AA379A644AD970532275CE273EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to better understand diffuse intrinsic pontine glioma (referred to in this resolution as <quote>DIPG</quote>) tumors;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC6E7A05F85BA450CBFF8741C9A39B880"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to develop effective treatments for DIPG tumors; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA88B275922764DE0AC8B4F9C338B034C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to provide comprehensive care for children with DIPG tumors and their families; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9724501F30F0443DB8EB38112ABF9DEB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages all individuals in the United States to become more informed about—</text><subparagraph id="idE7D53FC530704E0BB2B62C28A53E4758"><enum>(A)</enum><text>DIPG tumors;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2FD1004370C84186B3DAF259DA5DD8E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>pediatric brain cancer in general; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8256B4F4DA4A4681BF89493385C93CE1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>challenges relating to research on pediatric cancers and ways to advance that research.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

