<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD17318ADFDAD4B8AA5948F70B0E12D62" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4468 IH: Federal Interviews Reform Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4468</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250716">July 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require interviews conducted by officers and employees of Federal law enforcement agencies to be recorded.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC0FB0F08B1F041B4BBEDEF82BE17E31E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD2F6541E41A448388C4D5A6D44B6B2B2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Interviews Reform Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H24FCE098BAB445EBA5D0FACA1763D6FC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Audio recording of interviews conducted by certain Federal law enforcement officers</header> <subsection id="H465B45C79A674CDCBCDBE1F045EA2D8E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall require the recording, using an electronic audio or video recording technology, of each interview of any person who is suspected of having committed a criminal offense conducted by an officer or employee of the Department of Justice in connection with an investigation of a Federal offense or an investigation with respect to which the Department is assisting a State, local, or tribal law enforcement agency.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H43047FFF55634C249FB06E2F1D381F62"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header> 
<paragraph id="HDF60892C5F6A487AB860CEFFE57DEF9E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Custodial and non-custodial interviews</header><text>The requirements under this section apply with respect to any custodial and non-custodial interview, but do not apply with respect to communication with a confidential informant.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC686F02B54A541FAB69C085FA0C24D36"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extraterritorial application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements under this section apply with respect to any interview of a United States citizen outside of the United States conducted by an officer or employee of the Department of Justice.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBE990C92A5874A1D98E45BFDC48272DB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification, consent not required</header><text>An officer or employee of the Department of Justice may record an interview described in this section without providing notice to or obtaining consent from the interviewee.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2F537DC1A89E4E7395DA5819852FF4F1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Inadmissibility</header><text>A statement or information obtained during an interview that is not recorded in accordance with this section may not be offered as evidence by the Government in Federal court.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2F44578F880C4B1C973DC716EB82A014"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Retention</header> 
<paragraph id="HB9B47A789E474D14B68A264A68D6D517"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), a recording of an interview described in this section shall be retained for a period of 10 years beginning on the date on which the applicable investigation or any related judicial procedures is finally concluded, whichever is later.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1A1FD38E06845CAA012C0C543BEB901"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>A recording of an interview described in this section shall be retained indefinitely if the content of the recording is related to a judicial proceeding that involves a Federal capital offense or a State capital offense with respect to which the Federal law enforcement officer was assisting the law enforcement agency of the jurisdiction in which the offense occurred.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4B2CCFB9AA3943CB908D5F601E01A70C" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rules</header><text>The Attorney General shall finalize rules to carry out this section not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

