<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0CF701C42B864DA78E65711615029456" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4331 IH: Access to Claims Data Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4331</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250710">July 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a process to expand access to claims data under certain Federal health plans in order to facilitate research and quality improvement.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H45D4A947FF5E4A4BAB395B70197C0D94" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1546787C7B204D778B6D7B471A8EA836" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Access to Claims Data Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF45F5E85CC054C368FAB38FB026CF95C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expanded access to claims data to facilitate research and quality improvement</header> <subsection id="H57ADCCDDED4F4A6B8B063CC171BB9E31"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2026, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall establish a process to allow a qualified clinical data registry under section 1848(m)(3)(E) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(m)(3)(E)</external-xref>) or a clinician-led clinical data registry under section 4005 of the 21st Century Cures Act (P.L. 114–255) to request claims data described in subsection (b) (in a form and manner determined to be appropriate by the Secretary) for the purposes of—</text>
<paragraph id="H18BC104926A2443A90E8464391A709B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>linking such data with clinical outcomes data;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1EE13BA95FAB412090DE9936DA217111"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>conducting quality assessments and quality improvement activities of providers of services (as defined in subsection (u) of section 1861 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x</external-xref>) and suppliers (as defined in subsection (d) of such section)), reporting the results of such assessments and activities to such providers and suppliers, and performing risk-adjusted, scientifically valid analyses and research to support quality improvement or patient safety; and</text>
                </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7451483125E040F2823EDFB83C913DCF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>publishing research and quality improvement analyses, which may include deidentified combined claims and clinical outcomes data.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H394F7589DDDB4AEAA6746FB8EE1C0E6D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Claims data described</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the claims data described in this subsection—</text>
<paragraph id="HE3D099B851F246D892DC8BEDE4133F72"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are—</text> <subparagraph id="HD3007F5CF5B84498A7F444B13C6E5DC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>claims data under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H389A9B5FB966442A8EA65A42213664D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the Secretary determines appropriate, claims data under the Medicaid program under title XIX of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) and the State Children’s Health Insurance Program under title XXI of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397aa">42 U.S.C. 1397aa et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB9B4D60FF95240ABA8F5047521DE4A1E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may include provider-specific claims data, clinical specialty-specific claims data, State-specific claims data, or nationwide claims data.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF2DD8003D95F4E12B803EC1093854F42"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment of qualified clinical data registries and clinician-Led clinical data registries</header><text>For the purposes of this section, qualified clinical data registries and clinician-led clinical data registries shall not be required to be qualified entities, as defined in section 1874(e)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395kk">42 U.S.C. 1395kk(e)(2)</external-xref>), or quasi-qualified entities, to access claims data pursuant to subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H52EA49DF59D44B0BB076E1F782396C13"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Fee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data described in subsection (b) shall be made available to a qualified clinical data registry or clinician-led clinical data registry under this section at a reasonable fee equal to the cost of making such data available. Any fee collected pursuant to the preceding sentence shall be deposited into the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services Program Management Account.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

