<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0C99A72C432D4B3A96FC1D2D5BC82514" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 769 IH: All Aboard Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 769</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250128">January 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000398">Mr. Kean</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Transportation to issue regulations under which Amtrak is responsible for refunding rail passengers the cost of certain rail transportation that was canceled or delayed due to a failure of Amtrak, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE5B8D04E280446C6B98E816177073479" style="OLC"><section id="HB37064A28D3947058911A8A42BDE3D74" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>All Aboard Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC705BCF0FC4044599195A8EC68973301"><enum>2.</enum><header>Accountability of Amtrak for unfulfilled fares caused by maintenance and other failures</header><subsection id="H5D97D5419AAA4E74A36E8DC5BD07E153"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/243">Chapter 243</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H270DCBDF23EC46FCB6FC8118273B0A8E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HC3742D06E9DB4DD7AA91778DB953069D"><enum>24324.</enum><header>Right of rail passengers to recover certain unfulfilled fare</header><subsection id="HE4DA17A0E93741EB92CDA1C8014FAABA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the All Aboard Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall issue regulations to ensure that any person who purchases covered rail passenger transportation receives a refund equal to the rate the person paid for such transportation, at the expense of Amtrak and in accordance with this section, if due to a failure of Amtrak, such transportation, or a part of such transportation, is—</text><paragraph id="H307C6039F5394AACADFEC1E3EE1351AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>canceled; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6432BCF8D59545BB835C69BB2BBB60B4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>delayed such that the transportation is completed more than 3 hours after the expected completion time as of the time of the purchase.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5A89ECABFA60419D935A8E0C207092AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination of cause</header><paragraph id="H2FABD56039AC4C0F9B73AFA99A6CD951"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Causation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a), a cancellation or delay is not a failure of Amtrak if the cancellation or delay is attributable to forces or persons uncontrollable by Amtrak.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1ECA85DE8C224B74AE6337F5FC227CAA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dispute procedures</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall issue regulations that include—</text><subparagraph id="HF2BE095740584BF98993EF8D3B2F9EC8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>procedures for determining if a cancellation or delay is subject to subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0806D00A67B541A992B6BF1996AB7126"><enum>(B)</enum><text>procedures by which Amtrak can dispute that a cancellation or delay is subject to subsection (a), including that the cancellation or delay was due to a failure of Amtrak.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD291A4A6801F4785865237278E17A23C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Refund issuance</header><paragraph id="H47C7C0866CEC4C4EB90B5EB39AC0148A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Timing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A provider of covered rail passenger transportation shall issue a refund with respect to a cancellation or delay described in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H9AD98F56F7F04950A47CB53A0706CC78"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if Amtrak does not dispute that the cancellation or delay is due to a failure of Amtrak—</text><clause id="H1D8B633A79C14B58A64FCDD1466F232C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the covered rail passenger transportation is purchased with credit, a voucher, or rewards points issued by the provider of such transportation, not later than 7 days after the cancellation or delay; or</text></clause><clause id="H6ECE9CF9F0904D3782F0AF4286B797E8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the covered rail passenger transportation is purchased with cash, as soon as is feasible after the cancellation or delay; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H489F46D85B814DD8BF88165C04BA2EA5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if Amtrak disputes, pursuant to the procedures established under subsection (b)(2), that the cancellation or delay is subject to subsection (a), not later than a date—</text><clause id="H640106FA1A024322A2B7E5BFB88F467F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which is after the date on which a final determination is issued that the cancellation or delay is subject to subsection (a); and</text></clause><clause id="H49B7ACB606BB4987A77B6E007C87DEB5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>determined by the Secretary to be prompt and feasible.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD45CFF1322444F75A70CC4F463FBDD8F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A refund under subsection (a) shall be issued to a purchaser of covered rail passenger transportation in the form of payment used by the purchaser.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H50480B2EFD0449D4805F6BEC7F112D28"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Amtrak reimbursement of other rail carriers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amtrak shall, upon request from a rail carrier that issues a refund under subsection (a), reimburse the rail carrier in the amount equal to the refund.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC4A87B147FD94ADD9862969CA3DE1992"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Noncompliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amtrak may not receive Federal funds for any period during which the Secretary determines that Amtrak is noncompliant with this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC737D2E9D75E44008F199E789EAE4BE9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section shall apply for any fiscal year in which Amtrak accepts Federal funds.</text></subsection><subsection id="H24DB56C92DD346FAA27A151528EA4371"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Covered rail passenger transportation defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered rail passenger transportation</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H42CCF5AC9C714FCF8824FF12D4D9B0A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rail passenger transportation provided by, or on behalf, of Amtrak; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCAD7EB60CB5D4F258931056DA9B9B7F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commuter rail passenger transportation that travels over rails owned by Amtrak, regardless of if such transportation is provided by Amtrak or another rail carrier.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H914E44B919DE492CAE66EE9FA79496D0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Replacement of Amtrak asset maintenance strategy</header><paragraph id="H935C8B5708484ACBA1383C9484846562"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, Amtrak shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report including—</text><subparagraph id="HC2E5601B587C48AAB790B651387DC0D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an identification of each asset maintenance strategy that Amtrak could adopt as a replacement for a run-to-fail maintenance model; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB43F9DDD247C4B5F9EB9F440C630555E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the estimated cost of implementing each asset maintenance strategy identified pursuant to subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2855BBBDC27A4808B208F292274920CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ban on run-to-fail model</header><text>Amtrak may not use a run-to-fail maintenance model after the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E541662679A41768ABD7A63C4C696C8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Implementation of new asset maintenance strategy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, Amtrak shall implement an asset maintenance strategy identified in the report under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7334532415614F189EB48563B8C26E56"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Run-to-Fail maintenance model defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>run-to-fail maintenance model</term> means an asset maintenance strategy under which an asset (including equipment and infrastructure used for passenger rail transportation) is retired from use only at such time as—</text><paragraph id="H93C63DDC97C345B988B9FA3B5E6CD911"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the asset is no longer capable of fulfilling an intended use; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD05A3768BEAF4624A4B5205C8CFAB74C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the age of the asset exceeds the manufacturer-estimated lifespan of the asset.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H48B99D4ABD2E44DDADF40EAE9DA970DC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/243">chapter 243</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H4EE63DD4840F49808FF251F0EDE2843F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">24324. Right of rail passengers to recover certain unfulfilled fare.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

