<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF0F53E9110A0436EB12269126F8C142C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3193 IH: United States-Republic of Korea Digital Trade Enforcement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3193</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250505">May 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001222">Mr. Miller of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000067">Mr. Yakym</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Vicente Gonzalez of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the appropriate administrative authorities to impose certain restrictions with respect to the Republic of Korea, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8ED239A350F741A9A0C89E0CA42A666F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H912596BA604244258F8D42181D4FEE3F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States-Republic of Korea Digital Trade Enforcement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H67FC814997394E24AF1283DCBE3A28C4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text>
<paragraph id="H4592DB9DBDC34EA18B8592CF38229B8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States and the Republic of Korea have a longstanding, strategically important economic and security partnership and are committed to furthering their leadership in the Indo-Pacific region.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D9E511BCC1D4BF9AEA5E5C9708D62FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Nearly 30,000 United States soldiers, sailors, airmen, guardians, and marines are stationed in South Korea as part of United States Forces Korea, a deterring force against North Korea and China and ensuring the security of all Koreans.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H367D346B69C34C9C8EAEC1B22436007A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The economic relationship between the United States and South Korea is underpinned by the United States-Korea Free Trade Agreement, which promotes reciprocal trade ties between the countries.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H657933645C164EF884DD67E1AEB9D7C4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>South Korean companies have substantially increased investment into the United States due to the open investment climate maintained by the United States Government. However, the policies of the Government of South Korea often make it difficult for United States companies to invest and expand their business footprint in South Korea.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0292148BCAF644A6A1679863991DFFCC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In 2023, the United States trade deficit with South Korea was $51,100,000,000, increasing by 16 percent from 2022, due in part to South Korea’s discriminatory economic policies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H092CE876D92F446FA51A415A0081CA57"><enum>(6)</enum><text>South Korea is considering additional discriminatory digital regulations that would unduly burden United States businesses while benefitting Chinese technology companies.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6F930756D98546588BE4FACB25611F12"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Targeted enforcement measures, including office raids and threats of prosecution, risk provoking unnecessary friction with the United States when both countries should be working to strengthen this critically important economic and security alliance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94AA16A92F6042DFAB541ABA16B46EEF"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The United States must ensure a fair and nondiscriminatory regulatory environment and strictly enforce obligations to not establish discriminatory digital trade policies around the world.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HA488F24D1A864E9A95472395433FE6EF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States that—</text> <paragraph id="H0D8A39D3DE8A43ACBA7E40D18CE8001A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as the Chinese Communist Party seeks to extend its economic and military influence in the Indo-Pacific region, fair trade and economic policies in the Indo-Pacific are vitally important to United States leadership;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H104DE720F2E6473CA47BE9220B2E392A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States Government should fully enforce the terms set forth in the United States-Korea Free Trade Agreement (as such term is defined in the United States-Korea Free Trade Agreement Act; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/3805">19 U.S.C. 3805</external-xref> note);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H82B3F95CE9F24E2AB49889BE59149C30"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States Government should also use enforcement tools such as the authorities provided by section 301 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2411">19 U.S.C. 2411</external-xref>; relating to actions by the United States Trade Representative) where necessary to ensure that foreign countries do not impose discriminatory digital policies that disfavor United States companies; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBD96E580C4C14078807DC816DD395AB9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the United States Government should also use enforcement tools such as the authorities provided by section 301 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2411">19 U.S.C. 2411</external-xref>; relating to actions by the United States Trade Representative) where necessary to ensure that foreign countries do not use targeted enforcement measures, including office raids and threats of prosecution that discriminate against or unfairly disadvantage United States firms.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HA0C8140D84FE45298257F4A6F77E45CB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Determination of discriminatory economic actions against United States private entities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the enactment of any law or promulgation of any regulation by a government entity of the Republic of Korea that predesignates or post-estimates a United States online or digital platform operator and imposes discriminatory business restrictions, the United States Trade Representative shall submit a report to Congress that, includes—</text>
<paragraph id="HC4006BD47D0A4306B2C35A40C2CAFDF7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a determination whether a United States private entity was negatively impacted by an action of any government entity of South Korea that predesignates or post-estimates a United States online or digital platform operator and imposes business restrictions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H028C863730F34A85BDEA908E7E672816"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a determination whether South Korea, by adopting the law or regulation that is the subject of the report, violates any obligations or denies any rights under bilateral or multilateral trade agreements with respect to the United States; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB2BEBF36C699457796D62CA07159577E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a determination whether the law or regulation that is the subject of the report is either—</text> <subparagraph id="HF39C207F3E4B481AAD180EA9D8F574AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an unjustifiable action that burdens or restricts United States commerce, as such term is defined for purposes of section 301(a) of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2411">19 U.S.C. 2411(a)</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H44EBCEB47F1A47B2860C53B9D6C29E74"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an unreasonable or discriminatory action that burdens or restricts United States commerce, as such term is defined for purposes of section 301(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2411">19 U.S.C. 2411(b)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H44B99D38B49344C388789A5BBF0FE6F1"><enum>5.</enum><header>Imposition of trade restrictions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Upon the submission of a report to Congress pursuant to section 4 that includes an affirmative determination described in any of paragraphs (1) through (3) of that section, the United States Trade Representative shall undertake measures to protect United States commerce abroad that may include the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HDFE523EFF32943C6AD36439E28E7E441"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A dispute initiated under the terms of the World Trade Organization’s Dispute Settlement Understanding.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA179D0A197564C84B86B4E2F96BBBD2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An investigation under the authorities of section 301 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2411">19 U.S.C. 2411</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2C627EBAEF4247C29318F5C41926A2E2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A dispute under the provisions of the United States-Korea Free Trade Agreement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1348568C71B3418881437228DCDF52A3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Entering into an agreement with South Korea to mitigate all impacts of the law or regulation with respect to which the report was submitted on United States private entities.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

