<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEBD30D9EE78747C48FCE611485B6982E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5628 IH: Pay Workers What They’ve Earned Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5628</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250930">September 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 31, United States Code, to reimburse employees of the Federal Government and the District of Columbia, Federal contractors, and the States for certain costs incurred as a result of a Government shutdown, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDCB934BCE496495FA3DE99B7AAE09FAA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5C5FC8AEE2654ED7B381E67B584E2571" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pay Workers What They’ve Earned Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD4161D3DF6EA4C1DBB0F600A547B1A90" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reimbursement for individuals affected by Government shutdowns</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1341 of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF5CEE5F4765548AE9309B2DEEC674615" style="USC"> 
<subsection id="H738F428775FA411386206D2D8D14F112"><enum>(d)</enum> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H03C22C8F89E54D8FB1F6A8A958E45FBF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="H1C4C2A467937453C8E49F69499C27D48" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <quote>covered employee</quote> means—</text> 
<clause id="H417741F198C346CBAFDA6F4F7B390FB1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any employee of the United States Government or of a District of Columbia public employer furloughed as a result of a lapse in appropriations;</text></clause> <clause id="HBA157FC49AA9450586CA03D328E5D49F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any excepted employee who is required to perform work during such lapse; and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H7F99A696B3E1443E963D30325057D39C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any contractor with the Federal Government (or an employee of such contractor) placed on unpaid leave as a result of such lapse;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE6801D0CE2BF4F60A655C85E3A2517FC" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <quote>shutdown cost</quote> means any cost incurred by a covered employee as a direct result of a lapse in appropriations, including expenses for loans and credit cards, and any fees, fine, or interest resulting from the employees inability to make payments as a direct result of a loss in salary due to such lapse;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H633A50D3C9F744AE859333A3EDFEF89A" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the terms <quote>District of Columbia public employer</quote>, <quote>employee</quote>, and <quote>excepted employee</quote> have the meaning given those terms in subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H503B5D524FDE427CABEE9B3D641E8CAF" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>State</quote> means any of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and any territory or possession of the United States, and includes Indian Tribes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H44EB157F8CD748308AB8A7498F1DD863" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFCC63492C82D487597741717ADC4D69A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the lapse in appropriations beginning on or about October 1, 2025, each covered employee shall be paid for any shutdown cost at the earliest date possible after the date of enactment of this subsection, and subject to the enactment of appropriations Acts ending the lapse.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6E53256585E049A9B7B1EFB93B521796" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>With respect to any other lapse in appropriations of a duration of 14 days or longer occurring after the lapse in appropriations described in subparagraph (A), any covered employee shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, be paid for any shutdown cost at the earliest date possible after the lapse in appropriations ends.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H34AB3789349A4D10B03FFB1C59305EC9" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0FFC695123B74EC6ADD382AAA85C7575"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any State that makes an expenditure of State funds for payments for assistance programs that would be, but for a lapse in appropriations of a duration of 14 days or longer (including the lapse described in subparagraph (A)), provided by the Federal Government shall be reimbursed for such payments not later than 90 days after the lapse in appropriations ends.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H00BCD4AD0285461A8F7AD34EFD995D68" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>This paragraph shall not apply to any State expenditure with respect to which reimbursement is provided by the Federal Government under any other provision of law, including unemployment compensation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC2B002A0E0074385B035BEA295621EED" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H826CF0D378E34775ADE6D3E0E36F8ECB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In order to receive reimbursement under paragraph (2) or (3), a covered employee or State (as the case may be) shall submit an application to the Secretary of the Treasury, in such form and manner as the Secretary deems appropriate, not later than 1 year after the applicable lapse in appropriations ends.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAB7223AC0BE74FFF9315343B04ACC62E" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary shall determine what documentation shall be included with such an application to verify the shutdown costs or expenditure submitted by a covered employee or a State, respectively.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE3305915A20B4B12BF1662FE781D51D3" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Upon approval by the Secretary, reimbursement shall be provided to the covered employee or State, consistent with the requirements of this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE974DD9D53541FDB9E1F1CE62D7B232" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H56CB32DAFE254B8EA0CA50BC172ADAA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>There is established in the general fund of the Treasury a fund, to be known as the <quote>Reserve Fund for Employees Affected By Government Shutdowns</quote> (in this paragraph referred to as the <quote>Fund</quote>), which shall consist of amounts appropriated into the Fund after the date of enactment of this subsection.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H79CC34FAF4144600AB2FA1DF50915530" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, amounts in the Fund shall be available for purposes of paying the shutdown costs of any covered employee during a lapse in appropriations beginning after the lapse referred to in paragraph (2)(A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

