<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB661DDF2F16C4251B76732FDCEABDA51" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5421 IH: William Lacy Clay Sr. Memorial Stamp Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5421</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250917">September 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the issuance of a commemorative postage stamp in honor of William Lacy Clay Sr., and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD28C5A683E234603AE0BFD0C761F5B85" style="OLC"><section id="H5EA7C00830B74B528E48A480B35A6773" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>William Lacy Clay Sr. Memorial Stamp Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE6224478BFD740D399B7C729C0831882"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H952B4655F30449D7A097287E1F8C66C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>William Lacy Clay, Sr. was born on April 30, 1931, in St. Louis, Missouri, and rose from humble beginnings to become a respected national leader.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF68F44E42064489F9ECAF6D0048BA54C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Congressman Clay Sr. served honorably in the United States Army and later represented Missouri’s 1st Congressional District in the United States House of Representatives for 32 years, from 1969 to 2001.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H214DB1524C7640BA913414DBB3EEC729"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Congressman Clay Sr. was a founding member of the Congressional Black Caucus and worked tirelessly to expand political representation, opportunity, and equality for African Americans and other marginalized communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A5CF227CE8A4BECA88E3335BE39D073"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Throughout his career, Congressman Clay Sr. championed landmark legislation advancing civil rights, voting rights, fair labor standards, equal opportunity in Federal employment, and environmental justice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H292086764FF04EEAB77FE7857E376B35"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Congressman Clay Sr. sponsored, co-sponsored, or managed nearly 300 bills that became law, benefiting women, minorities, veterans, working families, the disabled, and union workers, a legislative record that remains one of the most impactful in modern congressional history.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E2AE6981A9F442F9A4D0EBCDC5078CF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>As a senior member of the Committee on Education and Labor, Congressman Clay Sr. played a leading role in the passage of the Family and Medical Leave Act, ensuring millions of Americans access to job-protected leave for family and medical needs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE43E56A35D04F36B31A81C7CAB2B68D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>As Chair of the Subcommittee on Post Office and Civil Service, Congressman Clay Sr. secured significant reforms to the Hatch Act, guaranteeing Federal employees and postal workers the right to participate fully in the democratic process.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H110D8984F44F4645B2C866EAA9021D01"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Congressman Clay Sr. authored Just Permanent Interests, a memoir that provides a candid and inspiring account of his lifelong dedication to justice, equity, and public service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA211C6240D2F4C16922C4FF4171C9EFB"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Congressman Clay Sr.’s decades of public service left an indelible mark on the legislative landscape of the United States, and his legacy continues to inspire new generations of leaders.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA16A7F1D266643368728246DBB8FEF9B"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The life and service of Congressman William Lacy Clay, Sr., represent the highest ideals of American democracy, public service, and perseverance.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HFD6C656308864DEBAA4E9185EEE48BD0"><enum>3.</enum><header>William Lacy Clay Sr. Memorial Stamp</header><subsection id="H461FF04C19FF412DB549FEACA42C6F42"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Postmaster General shall issue a commemorative postage stamp in honor of William Lacy Clay Sr.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0D5E09BD0D2C43C0960EFF9D347BC86B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The commemorative postage stamp issued under this Act shall be—</text><paragraph id="H68F515634A5A49B088836E06325CF64E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>issued in the denomination used for first class mail up to 1 ounce in weight and shall bear such designs as the Postmaster General shall determine; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80351296A6B1494A941333951AC9E082"><enum>(2)</enum><text>placed on sale as soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act and shall be sold for such period thereafter as the Postmaster General shall determine.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

