<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EHF25293-G6L-VC-LPK"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1357 IS: Secure America’s Financial Exchanges Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1357</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S389">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to address the issuance of securities by Chinese entities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Secure America’s Financial Exchanges Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAFE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id83A7ABFC41154CA7A7F643968D8580B4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Securities</header><subsection id="id0DC83CA10B5B45F29C492E49B1E32C9C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 6(b) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78f">15 U.S.C. 78f(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70DFD3D74B60470980F3139ECB4F9019"><paragraph id="idE8F3AFE02DD2426AAD6D22029DD17F15"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The rules of the exchange require an issuer, before the initial listing of any security of the issuer on the exchange, and in each annual report filed with the Commission and the exchange under section 13(a), to disclose the following information:</text><subparagraph id="id16A31D5D61D64E32A6C2F4F3E7CBC733"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Whether the Government of the People’s Republic of China has provided the issuer with any financial support, including— </text><clause id="id31B08300C5B44D32A9A3FF64FDDBAF6D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any direct subsidy, grant, loan, loan guarantee, tax concession, or benefit with respect to procurement policy; or </text></clause><clause id="idCBFDE95DCABC47C3BC1C1D7F580C1E63"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other form of support.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB5C03D1B563248E5BE26567113B3018C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If the Government of the People’s Republic of China has provided support described in subparagraph (A), the conditions under which that Government provided that support, including whether that Government required the issuer to—</text><clause id="idCBED1C7AA4BD4A9B8CA614C3164B9146"><enum>(i)</enum><text>satisfy certain requirements with respect to exports;</text></clause><clause id="id86CF5AC54B7F47659FCE9B98A79F1CE4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>purchase items from certain entities;</text></clause><clause id="id64751B462E3F4F189D137BF2658C0991"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>use certain intellectual property; or</text></clause><clause id="idE297E6CB736346B6A7D40F4488A20C96"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>employ members of the Chinese Communist Party or other employees of that Government.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEF95CB4CDF1942C3A97CB198C0E72CFD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Whether there are any committees of the Chinese Communist Party established within the issuer, which shall include the disclosure of—</text><clause id="idAEA72CD9FEDC4C448CD292034E352A69"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which employees of the issuer comprise that committee; and</text></clause><clause id="id245032FB13AC4D9CA60A06A99363F287"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the roles played by the employees described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id537AF383BC004F4DBDB4F241BC4E84B8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Information regarding each individual who, as of the date on which the disclosure is made, is an officer or director of the issuer (or a subsidiary of the issuer) and holds, or previously held, a position with the Chinese Communist Party or the Government of the People’s Republic of China, including the title of that position and the geographic location in which the individual holds or held that position, as applicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id81A37D350D1C4543B7FE5F573C84B77B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rules</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Securities and Exchange Commission shall make any amendments to the rules of the Commission that are necessary as a result of the amendments made by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

