<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1D60E49D7F1C4A5E92B20C75199F7814" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HR 2385 IH: Creating Resources for Every American To Experiment with Artificial Intelligence Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2385</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250326">March 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the National Artificial Intelligence Research Resource, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDD8C0514524449D98419A72F8FB962C1" style="OLC"><section id="H6194B2AC3A8C4F039DF8DD016CA720E1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Creating Resources for Every American To Experiment with Artificial Intelligence Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CREATE AI Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB9B174EB82BA4754BB61A63F9D98292C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H26E9B75245294CE29D37CC577DBE1944"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Cutting-edge artificial intelligence research relies on access to computational resources and large datasets. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7232259F923B42FEA99455D568499DE4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Access to the computational resources and datasets necessary for artificial intelligence research and development is often limited to very large technology companies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64F279F938464961BA342DBE05FF4277"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The lack of access to computational and data resources has resulted in insufficient diversity in the artificial intelligence research and development community. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3DF8706BAAE41079E27A55A9ECE57DE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Engaging the full and diverse talent of the United States is critical for maintaining United States leadership in artificial intelligence and ensuring that artificial intelligence is developed in a manner that benefits all people of the United States. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H00019C4AD49D4368A6C9099EDF1C26CC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The National Artificial Intelligence Research Resource Task Force, authorized under section 5106 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401 et seq.</external-xref>), recommended the establishment of a National Artificial Intelligence Research Resource in a report entitled <quote>Strengthening and Democratizing the U.S. Artificial Intelligence Innovation Ecosystem: An Implementation Plan for a National Artificial Intelligence Research Resource</quote>, issued on January 24, 2023. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H3F17F3F4B3D94C93AB261B03715C3C8F"><enum>3.</enum><header>National Artificial Intelligence Research Resource</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB75539152C38408D9D548AA110E485FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">NAIRR steering subcommittee</header><text>Section 5103 of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9413">15 U.S.C. 9413</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H74AC72A5FD81402CB9F63EF3A3141A03"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsection (e) as subsection (f); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F2185DF12F8405582D10D166C30BA30"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (d) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD689D37C70D64AF3AC591A8FB7D74A2F"><subsection id="H3037A10B0CBD483D99B0A677FBC90BA3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>NAIRR Steering Subcommittee</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33302EE9EAE342D0B821FD4CC71A861B"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the terms <term>NAIRR</term>, <term>National Artificial Intelligence Research Resource</term>, <term>Operating Entity</term>, <term>Program Management Office</term>, and <term>resources of the NAIRR</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 5601.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE92546A79D9F48F786243FFE2C5654C7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established within the Interagency Committee a Steering Subcommittee for the National Artificial Intelligence Research Resource (referred to in this section as the <quote>NAIRR Steering Subcommittee</quote>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H982F0D77F8134F09BAAB042A57656E1F" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chair and assistant chairs</header><text>The NAIRR Steering Subcommittee shall be chaired by the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy. The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy may establish assistant chairs of the NAIRR Steering Subcommittee based on members of the NAIRR Steering Subcommittee rotating into the assistant chair positions on a predetermined schedule.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4D1E322BF96745F492BA618D10DCBD6E"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Membership</header><text>The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall select members of the Interagency Committee to serve on the NAIRR Steering Subcommittee that the Director determines—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6959E81ED2DE4320BE50647F636B735D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have substantial expertise;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC986F5257A54E018F86AAC72CE18D8C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have substantially funded or conducted artificial intelligence research and development; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2469A4F7DA0D43078C0C0102F36497F8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have some other significant relationship with the NAIRR. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H58BF748046E34764B0C961AFE31EEB36"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Changes to NAIRR Steering Subcommittee composition</header><text>Not less frequently than once a year, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall review the composition of the NAIRR Steering Subcommittee and update such composition, which may include adding or removing members from the NAIRR Steering Subcommittee, if necessary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3453F8FB9E0B43C1909FBEFC4598E876"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Subcommittees and working groups</header><text>The NAIRR Steering Subcommittee may establish subcommittees, working groups, or other permanent or temporary bodies of certain members of the NAIRR Steering Subcommittee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC874F3FE4004C81B2E36FBD7E7AA5CC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The NAIRR Steering Subcommittee shall—</text><subparagraph id="HC351C0DEA2944A5283A0D148CC1009E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coordinate with the National Science Foundation and the Program Management Office to—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H453FFDB735994F25865555C45B82D31A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">oversee and approve the operating plan for the NAIRR;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73BBED16BC224E1F8C0D55AA3B54697B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review the budget for the NAIRR;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H298E42AE21AB47D0A18066A9C1766C9D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop and release a request for proposals to solicit bids for the Operating Entity, including establishing the terms and conditions and functions of the Operating Entity; and</text></clause><clause id="HE960F2E0A45B41F480115DDBB5F672B7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>develop and release funding opportunities for resources of the NAIRR;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BA5F867DE2D4D0DB58B2DEAD3974A8D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>work with the Program Management Office to establish criteria for the Operating Entity, review candidates, and select an entity to act as the Operating Entity; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E55E7E0D8D04125B1E28494C1EEF2FF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify resources that could be federated, participate in resource provider selection and funding, and provide direction to the Operating Entity about resource allocation and how those resources should be made accessible via the NAIRR; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9BC7F71187E436EBFFF0C3B44A08628"><enum>(D)</enum><text>define key performance indicators for the NAIRR, in conjunction with the Program Management Office and any relevant Advisory Committees established under section 5602(c);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87008EBB40C54FA6918D6407513D3DCD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>evaluate NAIRR performance against the key performance indicators defined under subparagraph (D) on a periodic basis and not less frequently than once every year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5706657714ED40DA830872E1B0A6F098"><enum>(F)</enum><text>develop an annual report, transmitted to the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy and publicly released, on the progress of the National Artificial Intelligence Research Resource that includes—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H68BAE6FDE3E24C13AB15059F8E0130BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of the results of the evaluation conducted under subparagraph (E); and </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D7EE6D29962407EBE4997258B569156"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any recommendations for changes to the NAIRR; and </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6F938EEABFE475284654646C4A874A4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>oversee a periodic independent assessment of the NAIRR.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H444737E0905E4D64AB49CF0479E21E0A"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Provision of resources of the NAIRR</header><text>Each agency comprising the NAIRR Steering Subcommittee is authorized to provide the Operating Entity with resources of the NAIRR or funding for resources of the NAIRR.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H67DD4DFB9F7A40C598270A70C9F5EAEC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC96764B0DD7343318C5C35F17D286CBE"><title id="HB0256A776D354906AA96FE041009507B"><enum>LVI</enum><header>National Artificial Intelligence Research Resource</header><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H35FF6BA4E076428D8C7EBD5D01EDFF0B">Sec. 5601. Definitions. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H2BE81BB755DD4EC994D5EFAF21CAF570">Sec. 5602. Establishment; governance. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA1E92F363B7146F2A21C48C7EC460E2F">Sec. 5603. Resources of the NAIRR. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H2D746675A8424E6CA36F3AF0C558CC10">Sec. 5604. NAIRR processes and procedures. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H2D746675A8424E6CA36F3AF0C558CC10">Sec. 5605. NAIRR funding. </toc-entry></toc><section id="H35FF6BA4E076428D8C7EBD5D01EDFF0B"><enum>5601.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text><paragraph id="HF83E0E795387430D9648C0E8F1F1FA92"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advisory Committee</header><text>The term <term>Advisory Committee</term> means any Advisory Committee established under section 5602(c).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H68AB5BD028F943CFB9E53E07680A8115"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">AI testbed</header><text>The term <term>AI testbed</term> means a testbed described in section 22A(g) of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/278h-1">15 U.S.C. 278h–1(g)</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H578FE4706FD042C0B8382FA5FCFCDB4A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Executive agency</header><text>The term <term>Executive agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 105 of title 5, United States Code. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC5C1047AA0044AEA4B9679494981C00"><enum>(4)</enum><header>National Artificial Intelligence Research Resource; NAIRR</header><text>The terms <term>National Artificial Intelligence Research Resource</term> and <term>NAIRR</term> have the meaning given the term <term>National Artificial Intelligence Research Resource</term> in section 5601(g). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91128CE1535840049137AEECE4102026"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Operating Entity</header><text>The term <term>Operating Entity</term> means the Operating Entity selected by the Program Management Office as described in section 5602(b)(3)(A). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F72DED0DA6245D7898D410BB76A770B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Program Management Office</header><text>The term <term>Program Management Office</term> means the Program Management Office established under section 5602(b). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3DE0FA3BA9C4E91A3D92CDD5BCB6161"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Resource of the NAIRR</header><text>The term <term>resource of the NAIRR</term> means a resource described in section 5603(b). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H033E94E62EA04B06A864D170D4A30609"><enum>(8)</enum><header>NAIRR Steering Subcommittee</header><text>The term <term>NAIRR Steering Subcommittee</term> means the NAIRR Steering Subcommittee established under section 5103(e). </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB586C859F284F5EB8BE162D6D3866FA"><enum>(9)</enum><header>STEM</header><text>The term <term>STEM</term> means science, technology, engineering, and mathematics, including computer science.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2BE81BB755DD4EC994D5EFAF21CAF570"><enum>5602.</enum><header>Establishment; governance</header><subsection id="HCB764361E81745FC9BF06D7F871CEC0F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Creating Resources for Every American To Experiment with Artificial Intelligence Act of 2025</short-title>, the Director of the National Science Foundation, in coordination with the NAIRR Steering Subcommittee, shall establish the National Artificial Intelligence Research Resource to— </text><paragraph id="H383F536350034EB69E175A2711B39EB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">spur innovation and advance the development of artificial intelligence to stimulate cutting-edge research and propel the strategic development of artificial intelligence capabilities; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H268104FBD8B14DFEB124EEE950CE00B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>improve access to artificial intelligence resources for researchers and students of artificial intelligence;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB5939A14B2F43DBAC42FB5840B2FADF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improve capacity for artificial intelligence research in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6BD4B4EC82042CEB41B2DDA3C3D288E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>support the testing, benchmarking, and evaluation of artificial intelligence systems developed and deployed in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAEC578FAFA4F402986DF5F820B2D2C33"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program Management Office</header><paragraph id="H9A24BD69C7D84FB79057DE527DEF577E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation shall establish within the National Science Foundation a Program Management Office to oversee the day-to-day functions of the NAIRR and shall appoint an individual to head the Program Management Office.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8DC0D311D35473BA6DC81104F9A233B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Staff</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58D4670BE645411A9B0C586CF58A1050"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of the Program Management Office may identify staff and direct all employees of the Program Management Office, in accordance with the applicable provisions of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D5587C7533648C1BE34DF3A576E3587"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Representation and requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The staff of the Program Management Office—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4316BA7B797E465CBBEA24838ED3414A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may include representation from other Federal agencies providing support for NAIRR resources; and </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD267D1F2A78F4F8F966FC4C2C0F7DE05"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall include not fewer than three full-time employees.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA92255F5CC2548CAACD94E5CEA64D2EC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Program Management Office shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HB5A933E560954D278072DD64C68378D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in coordination with the NAIRR Steering Subcommittee and any relevant Advisory Committee as appropriate— </text><clause id="HA35B2EC43C644C3DB04A89D9EA494C67"><enum>(i)</enum><text>developing the funding opportunity and soliciting bids for the Operating Entity, which will be responsible for operation of the National Artificial Intelligence Research Resource;</text></clause><clause id="HDDC3A774910F43FD8B70618115C7A5D4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>selecting, through a competitive and transparent process, a nongovernmental organization, which may be an independent legal entity or a consortium of 1 or more partners (which may include federally funded research and development centers), to be designated the Operating Entity;</text></clause><clause id="H2A3014C3C431495CB1F2424297D4AE76"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>overseeing compliance with the contractual obligations of the Operating Entity; </text></clause><clause id="H8D5901BA82EC4629BAFD39F17FA3FB26"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>establishing evaluation criteria for the NAIRR;</text></clause><clause id="H1FC2EB7DB1474A3CB3944793BFD57DE7"><enum>(v)</enum><text>overseeing asset allocation and utilization;</text></clause><clause id="H84C100FA22604DCBA8B46336BD2F62D5"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>identifying an external independent evaluation entity;</text></clause><clause id="H47B71B708F994344B5076F5B2C161038"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>assessing the performance of the Operating Entity on not less than an annual basis and, if such performance is unsatisfactory, ending the agreement with such Operating Entity and selecting a new Operating Entity in accordance with clause (ii);</text></clause><clause id="HF9DFAB7CD4DE49E9AF1A21368B149E03"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>developing multi-agency funding opportunities for the selection of NAIRR resources; and</text></clause><clause id="HCAD4ED1D0BF9432FBC85FFCE76F00C46"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>coordinating resource contributions from participating Federal agencies; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37C67B413EDD46D482BAF982A44A896A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>delegating, with appropriate oversight, operational tasks to the Operating Entity, including— </text><clause id="H09A8185FE88A4CDF817DE83C8698772F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>coordinating the provisioning of resources of the NAIRR;</text></clause><clause id="H20CF94AF63564CCC8D0290853D3A23C9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>maintaining a portal and associated services for users to access resources of the NAIRR; </text></clause><clause id="H87A912A343FE40FABF504AE2C58DD20B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>developing policies and procedures for the NAIRR;</text></clause><clause id="HDA6038C50EE64B728C5E2E717B5C24D9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>hiring and managing a staff (including experts in cyber infrastructure management, data science, research design, privacy, ethics, and legal and policy matters) to support the operations of the NAIRR; </text></clause><clause id="H96D297597FD042498970948C6632F05B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>continually modernizing NAIRR infrastructure;</text></clause><clause id="H4C4092D516FA4479A2F9141B97EF3A05"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>recommending key performance indicators for the NAIRR, in coordination with the NAIRR Steering Subcommittee and any relevant Advisory Committee;</text></clause><clause id="H3848B41266E7462FB9B0C79890FA1FFE"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>publishing publicly available annual reports reviewing the performance of the NAIRR, the resources of the NAIRR, and the NAIRR governance structures;</text></clause><clause id="H1B407E62ACFF43EE80EC16015972C9BD"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>establishing and administering training to new users on accessing a resource of the NAIRR, research design, and issues related to privacy, ethics, safety, and trustworthiness of artificial intelligence systems;</text></clause><clause id="H0DDD3134D3144C92947CDCBDDFAE5984"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>facilitating connections to AI testbeds; and</text></clause><clause id="H8B29D532E0AE49C9B91B5DB01158E0E1"><enum>(x)</enum><text>making educational resources of the NAIRR available to other Federal agencies, and to Congress, for the purpose of educating Federal Government officials and employees about artificial intelligence. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H196B795639FE41DC87A4D155D57F0766"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Advisory Committees</header><text>The head of the Program Management Office, acting through the Director of the Operating Entity, shall establish Advisory Committees to provide advice to the Operating Entity and the Program Management Office. Any such Advisory Committees shall be comprised of members from government agencies, the private sector, academia, and public interest groups. <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to any such Advisory Committee.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA1E92F363B7146F2A21C48C7EC460E2F"><enum>5603.</enum><header>Resources of the NAIRR</header><subsection id="HCB5B2978DC814C67B706624F7DFACBE2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of the Program Management Office, acting through the Director of the Operating Entity and in coordination with the NAIRR Steering Subcommittee and any relevant Advisory Committee, shall—</text><paragraph id="H2AA479DC209C4B16B51E724DF4BD5CFD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate and provision resources of the NAIRR;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC39580E4494D4239982B7263540391A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish processes to manage the procurement of new resources of the NAIRR, and intake of in-kind contribution of resources of the NAIRR, from Federal agencies or other entities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B0C0AA03A3D4B74A13C1E1818090BA7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish policies on and review resources of the NAIRR for concerns related to ethics and privacy; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF1E0948C2A6483380F79D5A1D8619C2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>retire resources of the NAIRR no longer available or needed; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H08C7625A65D64E90AFFF19A54DB60ED9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>publicly report a summary of categories of available resources of the NAIRR, categories of sources of such resources of the NAIRR, and issues related to resources of the NAIRR. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC28AF05A140A40F082EC5F9B802DE392"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Resources of the NAIRR</header><text>The NAIRR shall offer resources that include, at a minimum, all of the following, subject to the availability of appropriations:</text><paragraph id="H1A147248BCD042ABA3E0924DAC70C116"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A mix of computational resources, including—</text><subparagraph id="HF08817DC96634A3BBA3C1A108B6742E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on-premises, cloud-based, hybrid, and emergent resources;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5903A70613624C478F98E72846B64DD7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>public cloud providers providing access to popular computational and storage services for NAIRR users;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EF0E871CE0441D6862DAB6585978BF7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an open source software environment for the NAIRR; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA273B44D1325448EA14D46CB39C37C39"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an application programming interface providing structured access to artificial intelligence models; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6D4620DACA149A9904B771F119F7FF8"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other types of computational resources.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB6AFBBF84244F80A511C57E10BC0520"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Data, including by—</text><subparagraph id="H99554A5A9053493F8BEE99842C0604EE" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF3A4A5E139294D758C346233B287FB84"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in coordination with the National Institute of Standards and Technology and consistent with the guidance of the National Science and Technology Council titled <quote>Desirable Characteristics of Data Repositories for Federally Funded Data,</quote> dated May 2022, or any successor document, publishing interoperability standards for data repositories based on the data sharing and documentation standards and guidelines produced under section 22A of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/278h-1">15 U.S.C. 278h–1</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26C8C7BF08244F04A374622985EECC90" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">selecting and developing, through a competitive bidding process, data repositories to be available to NAIRR users; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E35D29A51274B23AE44260CFC603939"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishing acceptable criteria for datasets used as resources of the NAIRR; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC6211B07AC84A8FA2E7B780F1130B52"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identifying and providing access to existing curated datasets of value and interest to the NAIRR user community; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9DBA56F494C4973969FB8BAF2F1D93F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>establishing an artificial intelligence open data commons to facilitate community sharing and curation of data, code, and models;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA615940600A41D1A66F2A5D51A03841"><enum>(E)</enum><text>coordinating with the Interagency Council on Statistical Policy to explore options to make Federal statistical data available to NAIRR users, including through the standard application process established under section 3583(a) of title 44, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C6851B5B95D413D9FE4125A824F1904"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other types of computational resources.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H97843CE3CA2A42078CDFF5E8FAE3A4C0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Educational tools and services, including by—</text><subparagraph id="H2330DF52DDBC41EDBDB284646D34D4B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facilitating and curating educational and training materials;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6166BFF5E4B405E95BBEA037C1A5D51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing technical training and user support; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H566FCBC4D83C4654B9E5B3C6372E6CAC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing targeted outreach and programming strategies to increase participation in STEM fields.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB9D7D84F0CD43B4BE89705D90F32ED0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>AI testbeds, including by—</text><subparagraph id="H540C7D07C4FF4CBCA6797C8C68D04AA3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in coordination with the National Institute of Standards and Technology, facilitating access to artificial intelligence testbeds through which researchers can measure, benchmark, test, or evaluate engineering or algorithmic developments; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A99B7DFAF4340B8B526FDE5AF20CA17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>developing a comprehensive catalog of open AI testbeds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2D746675A8424E6CA36F3AF0C558CC10"><enum>5604.</enum><header>NAIRR processes and procedures</header><subsection id="H3C531C19DD4E4F21B9E14AC0A49F6085"><enum>(a)</enum><header>User eligibility</header><paragraph id="HF41922E8138040C0A8CF6E3998C869B5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible users</header><text>Subject to paragraph (3), the following users shall be eligible for access to the NAIRR:</text><subparagraph id="H95E199B5122D4920A42C02BBDD83C599"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A researcher, educator, or student based in the United States that is affiliated with an entity described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56237D3F415A4C6C88E8A0576B03516C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An employee of an entity described in clause (iii) or (iv) of paragraph (2)(B) with a demonstrable mission-need.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H32055E53C9524FF198E3A3B9CF7360DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Entities described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity described in this paragraph is an entity that satisfies the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB534F522F4E640C6B688A140CF2BB512"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Is based in the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H034F0FE9B15449B093EEB577C82B88C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Is one of the following:</text><clause id="HC9652394C5F9490CB6FCDAADB1290C36"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An institution of higher education.</text></clause><clause id="H18873CC52B904AD68AF03D9B01893F1E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A nonprofit institution (as such term is defined in section 4 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3703">15 U.S.C. 3703</external-xref>)). </text></clause><clause id="HAC010361D83648C395000285BF799BB5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>An Executive agency.</text></clause><clause id="H8515A44B67B94DDD9AB3A86A3ECC2C66"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A federally funded research and development center.</text></clause><clause id="H7FD491D424E84F62BD58A5F832B48BC3" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A small business concern (as such term is defined in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>), notwithstanding section 121.103 of title 13, Code of Federal Regulations) that has received funding from an Executive agency, including through the Small Business Innovation Research Program or the Small Business Technology Transfer Program (as described in section 9 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638</external-xref>)). </text></clause><clause id="HD82F195923984791BD77473850170FC4"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>A category of entity that the Director of the National Science Foundation and the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, after consultation with the NAIRR Steering Subcommittee and any relevant Advisory Committee, determine shall be eligible.</text></clause><clause id="H8A176CAF05904C8B8EF0477D9427FB82"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>A consortium composed of entities described in clauses (i) through (vi).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8F67E360CD944B1973CB5C6544783B4" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Excluded entities</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F3215A970874D5B980D80CB27A34BF5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No individual is authorized to be an eligible user under paragraph (1) if the individual is employed by a foreign country that is listed in section 4872(d)(2) of title 10, United States Code, or is otherwise authorized by such country to act for or on its behalf. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E42E26822A54B1D85F76D825574BFD3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation shall ensure that individuals authorized as eligible users meet the requirements of subparagraph (A). </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD087D21AF3D0463A9E7E22D8DD00CCD4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Privacy, ethics, civil rights and civil liberties, safety, and trustworthiness</header><paragraph id="HE2421624C9874EDD9045B209F68D3132"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F0297EB0E504A069DA58D8EBFEE6314"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of the Program Management Office, acting through the Director of the Operating Entity and in consultation with any relevant Advisory Committee, shall establish requirements, a review process for applications, and a process for auditing resources of the NAIRR and research conducted using resources of the NAIRR on matters related to privacy, ethics, safety, security, and trustworthiness of artificial intelligence systems developed using resources of the NAIRR. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D4CB2C89F314E73B545CF64297CE6B5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Federal statistical data</header><text>Any auditing process required under subparagraph (A) for Federal statistical data included in a resource of the NAIRR shall be completed by the head of a designated statistical agency (as defined in section 3576(e) of title 44, United States Code), in coordination with the Chief Statistician of the United States, consistent with relevant law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A570E6E5D1E4EDDBD2688E59300D372"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consistency</header><text>The head of the Program Management Office shall ensure the requirements and processes described in paragraph (1) are consistent with the policies of the Office of Management and Budget policy and relevant policies of other Executive agencies. The head of the Program Management Office shall coordinate with the Senior Agency Official for Privacy and the General Counsel of the National Science Foundation in ensuring compliance with applicable privacy law and policy and Federal laws and regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H46CB2776118F4FA2842A66047789ABF6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of the Program Management Office, acting through the Director of the Operating Entity, shall—</text><subparagraph id="H1FACFD3F8B124FE296EE5EFFEFE36A67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>when determining access to computational resources of the NAIRR, take into consideration the extent to which the access relates to privacy, ethics, safety, security, risk mitigation, and trustworthiness of artificial intelligence systems, or other topics that demonstrate that a project is in the public interest;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4667B3B192C483B8A444A772A32C336"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that a significant percentage of the annual allotment of computational resources of the NAIRR is provided to projects the primary focus of which is related to any of the topics described in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD20C194DAC2485884E6CB9D0B81EC5D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to the extent that demand for access to computational resources of the NAIRR exceeds availability, consider, on a priority basis, projects focusing on any of the topics described in subparagraph (A) when ranking applications for such access.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0EC525358D0A4DF8AE69E1A1947B1FF9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Scientific integrity</header><paragraph id="HE7C575F7AE5E4453A5C343AD98079D96"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of the Program Management Office, acting through the Director of the Operating Entity and in consultation with any relevant Advisory Committee, shall develop guidance for—</text><subparagraph id="HFD9E722549DE442F8FD547D119D6A757"><enum>(A)</enum><text>addressing concerns related to matters of scientific integrity, including matters related to the effects or impacts of research and potential research enabled by the NAIRR; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC01167299CAA45A1880B49ECC71EBF4F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mechanisms for an employee of the Operating Entity, an employee of the Program Management Office, a member of the NAIRR Steering Subcommittee or an Advisory Committee, a researcher or student affiliated with a NAIRR user described in subsection (a)(1), an employee of a provider of a resource of the NAIRR, an employee of a NAIRR funding agency, or a member of the public to report violations of the guidance developed under this paragraph, including by confidential and anonymous means.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H861379DF15EF413997B2E15132D4E626"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consistency with government policies on scientific integrity</header><text>The guidance developed under paragraph (1)(A) shall be published in a publicly accessible location on the website of the NAIRR. Such policies shall, to the degree practicable, be consistent with—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6461A1ECA6647CB816551050752369E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Presidential memorandum entitled <quote>Restoring Trust in Government Through Scientific Integrity and Evidence-Based Policymaking</quote>, dated January 27, 2021, or successor document; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCAF757CBE690470D9783C73722134A03"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reports produced pursuant to such Presidential memorandum (including the reports entitled <quote>Protecting the Integrity of Government Science</quote>, dated January 2022, and <quote>A Framework for Federal Scientific Integrity Policy and Practice</quote>, dated January 2023, published by the National Science and Technology Council, or successor documents).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1D8DBB6225514477B7689271DBFA64D6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>System security and user access controls</header><text>The head of the Program Management Office, acting through the Director of the Operating Entity and in consultation with the NAIRR Steering Subcommittee, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency— </text><paragraph id="H52FD00CEDB4E46BE9D90DA21DDDD5892"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall establish minimum security requirements for all persons interacting with the NAIRR, consistent with the most recent version of the Cybersecurity Framework, or successor document, maintained by the National Institute of Standards and Technology; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CD9752C2A7A49588B493F5EE0879596"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may establish tiers of security requirements and user access controls beyond the minimum requirements relative to security risks.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFB6FF35013864D34B7C5A4164C13B59F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Fee schedule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of the Program Management Office, acting through the Director of the Operating Entity, may establish a fee schedule for access to the NAIRR. Fees charged under this subsection may be retained and used for the purposes of this title. The Operating Entity may only charge fees in such fee schedule. Such fee schedule— </text><paragraph id="HB76A7D002B724D5792DA4078B9D5036C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may differ by type of eligible user and type of affiliated entity described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EEE7F9E2F22494A99B708F0357F891E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall include a free tier of access based on appropriated funds and anticipated costs and demand;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEDE4AF4B6754F3D84409A91676E2283"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may include cost-based charges for eligible users to purchase resources of the NAIRR beyond the resources included in a free or subsidized tier; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H484E31DE427646A09D3BCBAC45259191"><enum>(4)</enum><text> shall ensure that the primary purpose of the NAIRR is to support research.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H225DD2607CD84C988038D340F67AAC7A" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Research security</header><text>The head of the Program Management Office, acting through the Director of the Operating Entity and in consultation with the NAIRR Steering Subcommittee and the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, shall—</text><paragraph id="H153A2746C9F0408BB75FEB5C6B306B49" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure conformance with the requirements of National Security Presidential Memorandum–33 (relating to supported research and development national policy), issued January 2021, and its implementation guidance on research security and research integrity, or any successor policy document or guidance, by establishing NAIRR operating principles that emphasize the research integrity principles of openness, reciprocity, and transparency; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5902955D62F45C896C33D2C06D28637" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>designate a member of the leadership team for the Operating Entity as a research security point of contact with responsibility for overseeing conformance with the National Security Presidential Memorandum–33 and its implementation guidance, or any successor policy document or guidance.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF4450BC49F8B4F21860F6CDD1A6F1EA2"><enum>5605.</enum><header>NAIRR funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To carry out this title, to the maximum extent practicable, the NAIRR is authorized to accept and use donations of cash, services, and personal property from the private sector.</text></section></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C08C7CD7CC34BC58EC0FE6A855ACCD8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>The table of contents in section 2(b) of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>; 134 Stat. 3388) is amended by inserting after the items relating to title LV the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFB66F0A5658B4CF5B3F2F7F49F1E70F9"><toc><toc-entry level="title" idref="HB0256A776D354906AA96FE041009507B">Title LVI—National Artificial Intelligence Research Resource </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H35FF6BA4E076428D8C7EBD5D01EDFF0B">Sec. 5601. Definitions. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H2BE81BB755DD4EC994D5EFAF21CAF570">Sec. 5602. Establishment; governance. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA1E92F363B7146F2A21C48C7EC460E2F">Sec. 5603. Resources of the NAIRR. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H2D746675A8424E6CA36F3AF0C558CC10">Sec. 5604. NAIRR processes and procedures.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 5605. NAIRR funding.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

