<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCB718B589FB546FBB09639A29B7B706C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1698 IH: Law Enforcement Protection and Privacy Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1698</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris of Maryland</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001233">Mr. Messmer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide accountability for unlawful disclosures of firearm trace data in the Firearms Trace System database, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD8050490ADC34C0F9D3DC2F96861FB44" style="OLC"><section id="H18CDE76A4857462D897287956762E900" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Law Enforcement Protection and Privacy Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA4205FA90DDB494AAE76207D052C0B91"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendment to FOIA</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 552(b) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H76BB405502094D3C98D5E828B8270E46"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AB2E736F9F04C2DBA1682CB8F470045"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A0C6D9C3A824246964E4FEE08EC2A82"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (9) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4ABF7CD754AA485CAA482A76019DA2C6"><paragraph id="H8B115EC64BA84E27AA0DA824481F22B6"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contents of the Firearm Trace System database maintained by the National Trace Center of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, or any information required to be kept by licensees pursuant to section 923(g) of title 18 or reported pursuant to paragraph (3) or (7) of such section.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HA2B50F81BFEF47AA90337BC571560EAD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Unauthorized disclosures by agencies not part of the Federal Government</header><subsection id="H1CD2739F596D44F4BD33D5CEC3319CE9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Fines for disclosures contrary to Federal law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall fine a State, local, tribal, or foreign entity the following amount if the Attorney General determines that the entity made a disclosure of protected information in violation of the covered disclosure statute or any other applicable Federal law after the date of the enactment of this Act:</text><paragraph id="H9779051246884A36AE9F06D64539AC9D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$10,000, for the first violation by the entity or a violation by the entity occurring more than 3 years after the most recent violation by the entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7CAD2ACA8F54B01A0538CFC95ECF4B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$25,000, for any other violation by the entity. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C4547D8C6CF45C0AAD1474B4590B89D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Loss of access for 1 year after multiple violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may not disclose protected information to an entity fined under subsection (a)(2), for 1 year after the date of the imposition of the fine.</text></subsection><subsection id="H556A1607520E49E996C8C002A6BD81A5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement of fine by civil action</header><text>The Attorney General may bring an action in a court of competent jurisdiction to enforce or collect payment of a fine imposed under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HE8B3A27730C6458FB2966F1622860E5B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Assessment of fines</header><text>In assessing fines under this section, the Attorney General shall impose a fine for each disclosure of each individual piece of protected information in violation of the covered disclosure statute.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE3065E780A42432CAC5F9F786658EAB5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Private right of action for unauthorized disclosures of protected information</header><subsection id="HC012DFC72DC142A5973399A7EA96E032"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any entity with a license under section 923 of title 18, United States Code, adversely affected or aggrieved by a disclosure of protected information in violation of the covered disclosure statute or any other applicable Federal law by a Federal agency or a local, tribal, or foreign entity may bring an action in a court of competent jurisdiction against the agency or entity for remedies available under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBD63C28196B64534B1D29BA45FB597A2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver and abrogation of sovereign immunity</header><text>Sovereign immunity shall not be a defense in an action under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7F0F91766CD746C58298F9599686B7D0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Remedies</header><text>An entity that prevails on a violation alleged in a claim under this section shall be entitled to—</text><paragraph id="H69606FC9CC8E48AAA67C7D72FE992F6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the greater of—</text><subparagraph id="H378B355183FA42108526279C286A60AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>triple the amount of damages suffered by the entity, including damages resulting from loss of business income or harm to the reputation of the entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E3C62A19D2C4A9FA3D5BC044E7C6BCE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$25,000, for each disclosure of each individual piece of protected information in violation of the covered disclosure statute;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B65F238405A47BB896E8A626373D6FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such punitive damages as the court may allow; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H259E4E65E3234AF3897CC512D9909D42"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a reasonable attorney’s fee and court costs.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9FA5AA794FBA4370AE323F82D333B3E2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Other remedies; severability</header><subsection id="H30320EABAEED4E318D9A145E568AF538"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Other remedies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act shall not be interpreted to preclude any other remedy available under law.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDB1C17E55AAB4CB293F25C20300B2E23"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>If any provision of this Act, an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such a provision or amendment to any person or circumstance is held by a court to be invalid or unconstitutional, no other such provision, amendment, or application shall be affected thereby.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB994D8AA9A4D426DAE032AC7C63CA874"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H98A445F6C7B14BA5B3378B233C661106"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered disclosure statute</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered disclosure statute</quote> means the 6th proviso under the heading <quote>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives—Salaries and Expenses</quote> in the Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2012 (title II of division B of the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2012; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/923">18 U.S.C. 923</external-xref> note), or successor law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA43056028B9244279153AE2A629EF0D7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal agency</header><text>The term <quote>Federal agency</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 2671 of title 28, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D0C5E69929A46C5B0F628AB4545D7C6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Local entity</header><text>The term <quote>local entity</quote> means a city, county, municipal corporation, or other unit of government that is a political subdivision, and not an arm, of a State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBE6319C7DFC4244985BB2E32674B3F6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Protected information</header><text>The term <quote>protected information</quote> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="H51621E79ABC54E0EBDC09191264F7D7E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The contents, or a portion thereof, of the Firearms Trace System database maintained by the National Trace Center of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2475044341F14E4380F1713842BDC47F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The information required to be kept by licensees pursuant to section 923(g) or reported pursuant to paragraph (3) or (7) of such section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

