<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCDFDB0A62324467997A318B107106C69" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 243 IH: Georgian Nightmare Non-Recognition Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 243</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250109">January 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit United States recognition of Bidzina Ivanishvili or any Government of Georgia that is led by Bidzina Ivanishvili, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5B41C95862F942FB9FCAFBE107F3EE77" style="OLC"><section id="HF5D900F2D2BC4C948CA31311BFE7B8A9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Georgian Nightmare Non-Recognition Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H981E9DFC28204F0791E27708830DE806"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition of recognition of ivanishvili regime</header><subsection id="H2E8D72E9FAF14AB5A8DFD2126CE50B0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph id="HC6A19D37A8AF47B29E217AE0B06E4460"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not to recognize or normalize relations with any Government of Georgia that is led by Bidzina Ivanishvili or any proxies due to the Ivanishvili regime’s ongoing crimes against the Georgian people;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7928696FF1534B6BBFDFB25A449F43B4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to actively oppose recognition or normalization of relations by other governments with any Government of Georgia that is led by Bidzina Ivanishvili or any proxies, including by fully implementing the mandatory primary and secondary sanctions in Executive Order No. 14024; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69A17A9952A140A4BB19383B34432D3C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to use the full range of authorities, including those provided under the Global Magnitsky Act and Executive Order No. 14024, to deter corrupt activity or foreign influence operations by Georgia on behalf of the Chinese Communist Party, the Iranian regime, and the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8724CC94346E4503921F7B1F311E3FD3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>In accordance with subsection (a), no Federal official or employee may take any action, and no Federal funds may be made available, to recognize or otherwise imply, in any manner, United States recognition of Bidzina Ivanishvili or any Government in Georgia that is led by Bidzina Ivanishvili or any proxies.</text></subsection><subsection id="H739E8E96307B4058A40940C150227B3F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recognition of president of georgia</header><text>The United States shall recognize the incumbent President of Georgia prior to the fraudulent elections on October 26, 2024 as the only legitimate leader in Georgia.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF8C203302A8D4F20AF0BAFF7B55E8AA1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Restoration of georgian constitution</header><text>In the case of the restoration of the Georgian constitution as demonstrated by the holding of free and fair elections as certified by the Chairman and Co-Chairman of the U.S. Helsinki Commission, this policy may be declared void by the President.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

