<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H901F9077C8F64ADD91BCDA4309883C4B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2159 RH: Count the Crimes to Cut Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 298</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2159</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–346]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251017">October 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251017">October 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 14, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Attorney General of the United States to submit to the Congress a report on Federal criminal offenses, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HJU00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H34874783B7344976A760B591B3C19967"><section id="H2948943EDD0747E382838A3A45BEF0DC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Count the Crimes to Cut Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC43ECFD218F043CABB961512D6222D4E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on Federal criminal offenses</header><subsection id="HA9B253536E934F80AC252FDC095E77F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="H4AF80992AF044957843F5CA0A3281032"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>criminal regulatory offense</term> means a Federal regulation that is enforceable by a criminal penalty; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB312AAEE49A443FDA17BADBA5960353B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>criminal statutory offense</term> means a criminal offense under a Federal statute.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4B3BF7C8B7044F1FA6335A68C1C52F47"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on criminal statutory offenses</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report, which shall include—</text><paragraph id="HFDD86F3987F94820A528BEACEB53872C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of all criminal statutory offenses, including a list of the elements for each criminal statutory offense; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB28951492C344F09936AFE3A70861CA7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each criminal statutory offense listed under paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H1B9353130F5A4C5AADEB888B7BA6AE5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the potential criminal penalty for the criminal statutory offense;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H111D0392A77642AC8250ED8E71C6A4C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of prosecutions for the criminal statutory offense brought by the Department of Justice each year for the 15-year period preceding the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H450C1C2C8E6A4F1EBB3D8EFE587ADACC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the mens rea requirement for the criminal statutory offense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE76822E87D85480D96F4AB8FB6ECEE3F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on criminal regulatory offenses</header><paragraph id="HACB51226308943318BF8F4567142F068"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the head of each Federal agency described in paragraph (2) shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report, which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HDFD4C7E38A5D472AAE4112320E014E3F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of all criminal regulatory offenses enforceable by the agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H535F73F36FF4418BB9E81F6E136C1934"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for each criminal regulatory offense listed under subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H746BF7CD789C40B591221DAE5A1264EB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the potential criminal penalty for a violation of the criminal regulatory offense;</text></clause><clause id="HF7D1D80C312F4A5E9306247CF3DE9751"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of violations of the criminal regulatory offense referred to the Department of Justice for prosecution in each of the years during the 15-year period preceding the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></clause><clause id="HEFD68E911360487DAC2C773817CA995E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the mens rea requirement for the criminal regulatory offense.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC06B6F95A1EF4968965C950EEF4B4C06"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agencies described</header><text>The Federal agencies described in this paragraph are the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Commerce, the Department of Education, the Department of Energy, the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the Department of the Interior, the Department of Labor, the Department of Transportation, the Department of the Treasury, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, the Consumer Product Safety Commission, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the Export-Import Bank of the United States, the Farm Credit Administration, the Federal Communications Commission, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Federal Election Commission, the Federal Labor Relations Authority, the Federal Maritime Commission, the Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission, the Federal Trade Commission, the National Labor Relations Board, the National Transportation Safety Board, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, the Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission, the Office of Compliance, the Postal Regulatory Commission, the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Securities Investor Protection Corporation, the Environmental Protection Agency, the Small Business Administration, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, and the Office of Government Ethics.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5C0DB4206D70459CBAAE749A4A7E1120"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Index</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act—</text><paragraph id="H52FF686A20F54EDAB40BD676A7F1F446"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Attorney General shall establish a publically accessible index of each criminal statutory offense listed in the report required under subsection (b) and make the index available and freely accessible on the website of the Department of Justice; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA1990E2210E401CACD01ABC1D92B315"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the head of each agency described in subsection (c)(2) shall establish a publically accessible index of each criminal regulatory offense listed in the report required under subsection (c)(1) and make the index available and freely accessible on the website of the agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4A649E00BCB6472BA3B9A7FBD3633219"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require or authorize appropriations.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20251017">October 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

