<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-AEG25307-83Y-K4-R2V"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1845 IS: No Loan Forgiveness for Terrorists Act of 2025 </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1845</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250521">May 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the public service loan forgiveness program under the Higher Education Act of 1965 to ensure qualifying public service excludes employment with organizations that engage in activities that have a substantial illegal purpose.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Loan Forgiveness for Terrorists Act of 2025 </short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcdc4c9e8141c4207b1293e98632c5174"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exclusion of organizations that engage in activities that have a substantial illegal purpose from public service loan forgiveness</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 455(m)(3) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(m)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id024c819d91a34914891c07059f2bfaa1"><subparagraph id="id96897917dc64450a91dceb0c8457d9f4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exclusion from public service job</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (B), the term <term>public service job</term> excludes employment with any organization that engages in activities that have a substantial illegal purpose, including—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf123e20c0a7c49abbe52ed5cfd06e914"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">aiding or abetting a violation of section 275 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1325">8 U.S.C. 1325</external-xref>) or another Federal immigration law;</text></clause><clause id="id6f1abb5df0a44836a334a441ccc14a2b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>materially supporting terrorism, including by facilitating funding to, or the operations of, cartels designated as Foreign Terrorist Organizations consistent with section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>), or by engaging in violence for the purpose of obstructing or influencing Federal Government policy;</text></clause><clause id="id883528adb823414fa0b44d88f1188169"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>materially supporting child abuse, including the chemical or surgical castration or mutilation of children or the trafficking of children to transgender sanctuary States for purposes of emancipation from their lawful parents, in violation of applicable law;</text></clause><clause id="idb5cc450a27604abfbc38b37dfe28185e"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>engaging in a pattern of aiding or abetting illegal discrimination; or</text></clause><clause id="id96b9f905114c4a3d875b82be7fce6e84"><enum>(v)</enum><text>engaging in a pattern of violating State tort laws, including laws against trespassing, disorderly conduct, public nuisance, vandalism, or obstruction of highways.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

