<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3EB529E741C64B6EAA850EA77CD91F3A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1784 IH: Medicare Fraud Detection and Deterrence Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1784</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250303">March 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend titles XI and XVIII of the Social Security Act to strengthen health care waste, fraud, and abuse provisions.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H88BB0890030B4061B2455D13EF7A19A1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H58189051CBBF43B48CDAAD9DEBAFC5F5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicare Fraud Detection and Deterrence Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1F729009C2E8494FA47DEEAC8FA8F446"><enum>2.</enum><header>Strengthening health care waste, fraud, and abuse provisions</header> <subsection id="H628843388AE84A2893506ACBF9523ABF" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deactivation of national provider identifier for certain excluded entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1173(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-2">42 U.S.C. 1320d–2(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H731468B0C53D4A498904258606206C6B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="HCBBDD4137DC04D8BB686AF26101F7832" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mandatory deactivation of certain identifiers</header> 
<subparagraph id="HA11B5C0D359C40569CB36FBF2573DF8D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary shall revise the standards adopted under paragraph (1) to provide for—</text> <clause id="H058161375D3C4D4687E38B7D74F9F40B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the deactivation of a standard unique health identifier of entity type 1 (as defined for purposes of such standards) assigned to an entity if such entity is excluded from participation in any Federal health care program under section 1128 or 1128A; </text></clause> 
<clause id="H2AF356C241DD42DCAADE1C5E42B284E1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the deactivation of a standard unique health identifier of entity type 2 (as defined for purposes of such standards) assigned to an entity if such entity is so excluded, but only if—</text> <subclause id="H20F6FF170FF94447A8CEA940EEC225E3" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services submits to the Secretary a request for such deactivation; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H467B1925197941ECBC7CC6FCB144C660" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Secretary determines such deactivation to be appropriate; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H28E4455ADB35464C97BF93600F210DBB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the reactivation of a standard unique health identifier deactivated pursuant to clause (i) or (ii) at the end of such deactivation (as described in subparagraph (B)). </text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5607AAEB4BFE481BB9ACCCF15C82E48B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Term of deactivation</header><text>A deactivation described in subparagraph (A) made with respect to an entity excluded from participation in any Federal health care program under section 1128 or 1128A shall begin on the date of such exclusion and shall end on the date such exclusion is terminated.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD609E18AC4E64CF080DF313E5868FCEA" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Nonapplication of deactivation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), no deactivation of a standard unique health identifier assigned to an entity excluded from participation in any Federal health care program under section 1128 or 1128A shall be made pursuant to such subparagraph if the Secretary has waived such exclusion with respect to any Federal health care program pursuant to section 1128(c)(3)(B).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2F0A791447D44007AA63E2E9F25ABD54" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Annual review of exclusion list</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this paragraph and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the Secretary shall compare the list of individuals and entities excluded from participation in any Federal health care program under section 1128 or 1128A maintained by the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services (or a successor list) with a list of active standard unique health identifiers described in subparagraph (A) to ensure compliance with such subparagraph. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H276E5C23D2D447CEAA916E7E8320C4E8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Medicare Advantage plan provision of national provider identifier for certain items and services</header><text>Section 1859 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-28">42 U.S.C. 1395w–28</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H758C2EBF10C9489098270F52E4AE9DFA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H0A43BDFC0C004BAAA5649624457EEE87"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Provision of national provider identifier for certain items and services</header> 
<paragraph id="H3F67D49CE7A6484C812B0A99A16AE97B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any encounter data submitted by a Medicare Advantage plan with respect to a designated item or service furnished to an individual under such plan on or after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall require that such data include the standard unique health identifier established pursuant to standards described in section 1173(b) of the provider of services or supplier that ordered such item or service or referred such individual for such item or service.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C35E741FBB34A86AC09380D11FC21A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rejection of data</header><text>The Secretary shall reject any encounter data submitted by a Medicare Advantage plan if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H76C979812AEC43BFA009AD0EF3814465"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such data does not comply with the requirement described in paragraph (1); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF1BA20506606411E89B8D2039235285F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that a standard unique health identifier included in such data in accordance with such requirement is not active or is otherwise invalid.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5CBEE3F424594678BD0A99DD713A6AE2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definition of designated item or service</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>designated item or service</quote> means any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H480628A67584439891AAAEF4B954CC38"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An item of durable medical equipment.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC76A4F9C8FA94CB3AB8C4B812CA4E07B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A prosthetic or orthotic device.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB4B00FCB0E974FE9A717588728D19626"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A clinical diagnostic laboratory test.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H49E372BB1B32456D9D26C123500A37A3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A diagnostic imaging test (as specified by the Secretary).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H58537D39F6F142ACAF84FF821C89BED9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A home health service (as specified by the Secretary).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2DCC4D48D6154FA9AAD2497E5230CD0B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Identification of relationships between telehealth suppliers and telehealth companies under Medicare</header><text>Section 1834(m) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(m)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD668796C7E4A47D691F37BDC8B9AEA28" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H59AFDD4A37F94A68B2E264C3E35E0806"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Identification of relationships between telehealth suppliers and telehealth companies</header> <subparagraph id="H66CC5A431A0B47F19B85C5E4161AFDAA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a telehealth service furnished on or after the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this paragraph by a specified entity, no payment may be made under this section for such service unless the claim for such service includes the modifier established pursuant to subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H01B7DD90DCE74C929BE035B098E2AA20"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Establishment of modifier</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary shall establish a claims modifier for purposes of identifying telehealth services payable under this section furnished by a specified entity (as defined in subparagraph (C)). </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5C8EFEFE11044620B39CA3ED6CF40A45"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<clause id="HE057F409C8F249D2A5B306DBDA9E818B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Specified entity</header><text>The term <quote>specified entity</quote> means a physician or practitioner (as such terms are defined in paragraph (4)) that has an employment or other contractual relationship in effect with a telehealth company relating to the furnishing telehealth services.</text></clause> <clause id="H6D43184D151042A8B9688997575DB1DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Telehealth company</header><text>The term <quote>telehealth company</quote> means an entity—</text> 
<subclause id="H431B4FDF437B4F598C80FE0C70C50CC9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>that employs or otherwise contracts with physicians or practitioners to furnish telehealth services; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HBD941F17D5194DAAA36144B69FBB0464"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that does not employ or otherwise contract with any physician or practitioner to furnish items and services in-person (or that employs or otherwise contracts with physicians or practitioners to furnish such in-person items and services in a de minimis manner compared to the amount of telehealth services furnished by such physicians or practitioners, as specified by the Secretary). </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

