<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2E44F58C69CF4794AB5B37B3B55F64AF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3636 IH: To amend title 10, United States Code, to improve the process by which the Secretary of Defense verifies that health care professionals of the military departments are appropriately licensed.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3636</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250529">May 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to improve the process by which the Secretary of Defense verifies that health care professionals of the military departments are appropriately licensed.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H38FA729ECB0A47E0B0BD4080952EB2C1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H86D8B84BEFBB4D1C8D15DE8F8C355D9C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Verification of licensure of health-care professionals of the military departments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (b) of section 1094 of title 10, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H462C3EBA02EC40E78D2EB2EE4BF57742" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HF558424A1AD44A0AA966BAE3B54FB75C"><enum>(b)</enum> <paragraph id="H183D45FF778346F6827F57B6B087EBFF" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that each individual who provides health care independently as a health-care professional at a health care facility of the Department of Defense meets the requirement of subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H108949C4E96A4D14873EA5631B8F1AA7" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall establish a centralized credential system that allows the commanding officer of a health care facility of the Department to verify the licensure of a health-care professional, regardless of the location of the facility or the armed force in which the health-care professional serves. The Secretary shall ensure that not less than 90 percent of such verifications are completed within seven days of the date on which the commanding officer requests such verification if the request does not relate to a health-care professional with an adverse record.</text></paragraph> </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> </legis-body></bill>

