<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H62ADF1A893B741F38F62698EB9A863FD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4603 IH: Fair, Affordable and Inclusive Rates Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4603</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250722">July 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001239">Mr. McGuire</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to prohibit State regulatory authorities from approving rates charged by electric utilities that engage in certain diversity, equity, or inclusion practices, or that consider environmental, social, or governance factors, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H02FFEE9891F747F8B2F882930F41B110" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD92D52680DDF40A79C55ADB0F0899A67" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair, Affordable and Inclusive Rates Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FAIR Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFDF8186C5AAE409789E946B24787B101"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on approval of certain rates under PURPA</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 111(d) of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2621">16 U.S.C. 2621</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD7567DC7306E4659BF2FBE8D3893B451" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H82D41A56C9AE467588297988B205A6E6" commented="no"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Diversity, Equity, or Inclusion (DEI) practice</header><text>No State regulatory authority shall approve the rate of a State regulated electric utility if such State regulated electric utility engages in, or retains or employs a consultant or an advisor to promote or enforce, a diversity, equity, or inclusion practice, such as a practice—</text> <subparagraph id="H6C1844AD90784792A39B22ACAFB29C2B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>discriminating for or against any person on the basis of race, color, ethnicity, religion, biological sex, or national origin; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H783EE5CD3A1A4737847EA482501AED8C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>requiring, as a condition of employment, promotion, advancement, or the ability to speak, make presentations, or submit written materials, that an employee—</text> <clause id="H1F61A65EDA134973BFEC40D9BAE88B40" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>undergo training, education, coursework, or other pedagogy asserting that any particular race, color, ethnicity, religion, biological sex, or national origin is inherently or systemically superior or inferior, oppressive or oppressed, or privileged or unprivileged; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H99097CA052EF44328CB131A774B59A98" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sign or assent to any statement, code of conduct, work program, plan, or similar device that asserts that any particular race, color, ethnicity, religion, biological sex, or national origin is inherently or systemically superior or inferior, oppressive or oppressed, or privileged or unprivileged.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5728C3DDE76C41508358F156F03A9F70"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Environmental, social, or governance (ESG) factors</header> <subparagraph id="H0ADC30A8F2D54D25BBE67B4279003CC8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), no State regulatory authority shall approve the rate of a State regulated electric utility if such State regulated electric utility considers environmental, social, or governance factors in establishing rates or making operational decisions that affect rates.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5E461DC646F048CEB61010E512CB2E45"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to prohibit a State regulated electric utility from complying with—</text> <clause id="H2F814A7BABBD4DB5990B65086F82DFC2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a Federal law or regulation requiring specific ESG factors if complying with such Federal law or regulation—</text> 
<subclause id="H894F630BC92844BBBC134B24CE6608B0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is limited to fulfilling the direct legal obligation of such Federal law or regulation; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H94523F35A8044815861B2E971DF5D181"><enum>(II)</enum><text>does not involve discretionary consideration of ESG factors beyond such direct legal obligation; or</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H20F5FA157BFE47BE9390219F17B8A338"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a State law or regulation that require such State regulated electric utility to purchase from certain types of generation sources if complying with such State law or regulation—</text> <subclause id="H3E192C20FB9C45C596377F929C0EF293"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is limited to fulfilling the direct legal obligation; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HB07B61D272024570A727DFF57D9C3331"><enum>(II)</enum><text>does not involve discretionary consideration of ESG factors beyond such obligation.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0623E59CEF264B2EBE7B3FF452E89A8B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Environmental, social, or governance factor or ESG factor defined</header><text>The term <quote>environmental, social, or governance factor</quote> or <quote>ESG factor</quote> means any factor relating to—</text> 
<clause id="HD9CAF6D71043425E834DD75B1F4B75D2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>environmental considerations, including climate change policies, carbon emissions reductions, or environmental justice initiatives, unless directly tied to pecuniary impacts such as cost reduction, reliability enhancement, or compliance with Federal or State law or regulation;</text></clause> <clause id="HD97F5DC6EA33430CA09CB92A2FA0B0E8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>social considerations, including—</text> 
<subclause id="H22BEBC0464914C019658EA7965B7ACD4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>corporate board or workforce composition quotas based on race, color, ethnicity, sex, or national origin; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H14AE5D34D77F48ECB16966A61675CE90"><enum>(II)</enum><text>supplier diversity programs that grant preferences based on race, color, ethnicity, sex, or national origin, unless such programs are required by applicable Federal or State law; or</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HC3F36CB6679A45EA995D00CAB2AFDCFF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>governance considerations, including the adoption of corporate governance policies primarily for the purpose of advancing political, ideological, or social objectives unrelated to pecuniary outcomes relevant to State regulated electric utility operations, customer service, or ratepayer cost impacts.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

