<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H83206348B200406CB76B24236EE167C2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5047 IH: No Woke Indoctrination of Military Kids Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5047</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250826">August 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit activities that promote critical race theory and diversity, equity, and inclusion at schools operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCFC54C26EEB0418A9029A88072126F51" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC43B6520812146D0AC939C019F1AA193" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Woke Indoctrination of Military Kids Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H3F72982183954110A96FC59BBE823B69"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on instruction in critical race theory</header> 
<subsection id="HE340BFA01FA44F4BBB29952A9C3FA40F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for any fiscal year for the Department Defense Education Activity may be obligated or expended to—</text> <paragraph id="HBACABFBB08534E9C8FB6C908BD6BF1D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>teach or promote critical race theory to students in any classroom instruction, training, or extracurricular activity;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1C5DD291A6F4523B92598112ED0170B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require, encourage, or coerce any student to affirm, adopt, or support any belief or concept rooted in critical race theory;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0EA0382EF9304F8A91A1CB2A0A6AC550"><enum>(3)</enum><text>implement any training program relating to critical race theory; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6DFF896C40A54CC6BA06249A9067FBA1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop, purchase, or distribute any curriculum that incorporates critical race theory.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD3204959CA7249E7A29BB22DD981AD3A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Critical race theory defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>critical race theory</term> means any theory, framework, or ideology that holds or teaches that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H76F88C7F19754B1DB29F7A8BBE3C84C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any race is inherently superior or inferior to another race;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H59E354261A4E4CA0A83F0445FAEC530A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an individual, by virtue of race or sex, is inherently racist, sexist, oppressed, or oppressive, whether consciously or unconsciously;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H543E33BC394B4406BD4CCD268A69E4EF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an individual should be discriminated against or receive adverse or favorable treatment solely or partly because of race or sex;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC1318582915E4AF6BF8ACD4BAE1519AC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the United States is fundamentally or irredeemably racist or sexist;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD7A5C2ADD5154707962280050263AAD4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>individuals bear collective guilt or responsibility for actions committed in the past by others of the same race or sex;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFDDBD86D1E58403EAC604E6256572CE4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>meritocracy is inherently racist or sexist or was created to oppress members of another race or sex;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4110C215B9F241D6A35939B986FEF133"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Declaration of Independence or the Constitution of the United States of America is a fundamentally racist document;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H597DCBD341BC4477AB2DD95C3358CC70"><enum>(8)</enum><text>an individual’s moral character or worth is determined by an individual’s race; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A87AFECE845460C8A205C131FA57282"><enum>(9)</enum><text>an individual should feel discomfort, guilt, anguish, or any other form of psychological distress on account of his or her race or sex.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H74A99A095B9841FD82E08D208D9D90E2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on diversity, equity, and inclusion practices</header> <subsection id="H7B85C5EB25D44322BD428B8C6B6EFBC9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), the Director of the Department of Defense Education Activity may not—</text> 
<paragraph id="H71980F42E5C04E47BBD7A8AB87890444"><enum>(1)</enum><text>maintain an office relating to diversity, equity, inclusion, or accessibility, or any substantially similar office;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H03A219695C014902A2F845A1537CD893"><enum>(2)</enum><text>maintain or employ a chief diversity officer or a substantially similar officer;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H79D4FB57FFA844929A946D522C46B63A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop, implement, distribute, or publish—</text> <subparagraph id="H68FD5E7254EC49EFBF3E46FF923ED09C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>plans, strategic plans, reports, or surveys relating to diversity, equity, inclusion, or accessibility; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6D4A9058CCEA4AAFB9DF69BD9F9AA0F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>action plans, reports, or surveys relating to equity or substantially similar plans, reports, or surveys;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A73478E3A0441DA969AA5252BAE0669"><enum>(4)</enum><text>develop, implement, or maintain a resource group or an affinity group based on race, color, ethnicity, national origin, sexual orientation, or gender identity;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD4B433C592D34232948327FC37E73713"><enum>(5)</enum><text>develop, implement, or maintain an agency equity team or a substantially similar team;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1BAA387A6604DEE9C8B3D0ED130C73B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>develop, implement, distribute, publish, establish, or purchase—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF2ED6EF3D24B43B6903AAFC273AF75CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a training course relating to—</text> <clause id="H65412FFA64D84D7BB424B6AAA3DB1809"><enum>(i)</enum><text>diversity;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6D0DB174F26A438E959D56854F541192"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>equity;</text></clause> <clause id="H601DCE415679409C9AEEDF545956152B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>inclusion;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H288F3B379CA94E238D04A2F28609A4B9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a critical theory relating to race, gender, or otherwise; or</text></clause> <clause id="HA2F8B2FB12954C2282CC303B34BF26F2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>intersectionality; or</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8F6EC59F65B749DBB50756722298F60A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a training course substantially similar to a training course described in subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H74CEA1FE962B4F05B7C00C84A84E2208"><enum>(7)</enum><text>develop, implement, or maintain a diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility data dashboard; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9E29347F117D424C84BA95CCB6CA216A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>maintain or employ a person in a position relating to diversity, equity, inclusion, or accessibility.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC99341AB7F2D4271816E1098B1750CD2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in subsection (a) shall be construed to prevent the Director of the Department of Defense Education Activity from maintaining or operating—</text> 
<paragraph id="H41F91C4E2BB845618FAFCED80D119413"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Equal Employment Opportunity offices as historically organized and operated within the Department of Defense Education Activity; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC026C4EE3505427B99A71A0040FCEFC4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an office enforcing the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>) or similar programs or offices as historically organized and operated within the Department of Defense Education Activity.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF1D801822CAA494C8C4DB0D264BB616D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Enforcement and penalties</header> 
<subsection id="H384032B1C213424AAF4AD11319BD3128"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enforcement authority</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall take such steps as may be necessary to ensure compliance with the requirements of this Act, including compliance by the Director of the Department of Defense Education Activity, schools operated by the activity, and personnel of such schools.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H421B16EF0EC84A5F8634249563DC45E8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any employee or contractor of the Department of Defense who wilfully violates a provision of this Act shall be subject to such disciplinary action as the Secretary of Defense determines appropriate, which may include suspension or termination.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H1603AC0FDCC3476EA0B2E6BF9C2C21BA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Violation reporting</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall establish process through which a parent or legal guardian of a student at a school operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity may file a formal complaint with the Department of Defense regarding suspected violations of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H90604DC85EB548D3B95AE393FCB95332"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect on a date determined by the Secretary of Defense that is not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

