<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA1E7CD4D3C704F8987CC6265C55B2C5E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4558 IH: To designate the area between the intersections of 16th Street Northwest and Fuller Street Northwest and 16th Street Northwest and Euclid Street Northwest in Washington, District of Columbia, as “Oswaldo Payá Way”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4558</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250721">July 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000600">Mr. Diaz-Balart</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate the area between the intersections of 16th Street Northwest and Fuller Street Northwest and 16th Street Northwest and Euclid Street Northwest in Washington, District of Columbia, as <quote>Oswaldo Payá Way</quote>.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD6DF245DA6DB4F589ACC7A371139C2D6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4134D223B7E14DDFAF5DCCB09D9C2986" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="H2011BBEC353D47AC9239B9E11EF4452A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the revolution led by Fidel Castro in Cuba in 1959 started over 6 decades of an ongoing dictatorship, systemic human rights abuses, and a lack of basic freedom of press, religion, assembly, and association that continue to this day under the Communist rule of Raúl Castro and his successor, Miguel Díaz-Canel;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6CC1633A5655438099D8C3C7A0EFB4A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Oswaldo Payá Sardiñas was a Cuban political dissident and activist dedicated to promoting democratic freedoms and human rights in Cuba;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2DE6CCF512CF47398B4825721D52D48B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Communist Party of Cuba has always viewed individuals with a commitment to democracy and freedom as a threat to the existence of the Communist Party of Cuba;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA8F0FFBA4A7248C2924358B9C666B493"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on July 22, 2012, a violent car crash, widely believed to have been carried out by the Castro regime, took the lives of Oswaldo Payá and Harold Cepero, another democratic activist;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE91503925EFB479A9FCA66EE2A586971"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Cuba’s official investigation into the crash has been demonstrated to be compromised, and the Cuban regime has blocked all efforts to conduct a credible and independent investigation into the crash, leaving the circumstances of the death of Oswaldo Payá unknown;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD409B72CA4D1442AAD224B91688A5A08"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">opposition by Oswaldo Payá to the Communist Party of Cuba began at a young age, when he refused to become a member of the Young Communist League as a primary school student, and continued through high school, when he publicly criticized the invasion of Czechoslovakia by the Soviet Union;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDDC9153086D94C71BC10F367CB12BA34"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Communist Party of Cuba responded to the opposition by Oswaldo Payá to the invasion of Czechoslovakia by the Soviet Union by sending Oswaldo Payá to a labor camp for 3 years;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H95E8927F6A4D40CBB280ECDC9CE52461"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Oswaldo Payá forewent a chance to escape Cuba in the 1980 Mariel boatlift, deciding instead to continue the fight for democracy in Cuba, saying, <quote>This is what I am supposed to be, this is what I have to do.</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4CC28030AAD14C0FAF590EBE082F6E49"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by creating the Varela Project in 1998, Oswaldo Payá demonstrated his staunch commitment to peacefully advocating for freedom of speech and freedom of assembly for his fellow Cubans;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE0E462A050D240CBBE13143701A3F2BB"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in recognition of his determination for political reforms through peaceful protests, Oswaldo Payá was awarded the Sakharov Prize for Freedom of Thought by the European Parliament in 2002 and the W. Averell Harriman Democracy Award from the National Democratic Institute for International Affairs in 2003 and was nominated for the Nobel Peace Prize by former Czech President Va1clav Havel in 2005;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H722CE0828539438BB91F5091DF5E0A40"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on April 11, 2018, the Senate unanimously passed S. Res. 224, recognizing the sixth anniversary of the death of Oswaldo Payá Sardiñas, commemorating his legacy and commitment to democratic values and principles, and calling on the Cuban Government to allow an impartial, third-party investigation into the circumstances surrounding his death; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE22DDBEB719841E0BFEBCC15D2CD0572"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">renaming the street in front of the Embassy of Cuba in the District of Columbia after Oswaldo Payá serves as an expression of solidarity between the people of the United States and the people of Cuba, who are engaged in a long, nonviolent struggle for fundamental human rights.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H57067752525042D2B8E9481BB5ECE434"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation of Oswaldo Payá Way</header> <subsection id="HA570BB928BA349E788F4BDE5095BA5CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation of way</header> <paragraph id="HF0471CC98C71444AB5BE671BE0ECB3B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The area between the intersections of 16th Street Northwest and Fuller Street Northwest and 16th Street Northwest and Euclid Street Northwest in Washington, District of Columbia, shall be known and designated as <quote>Oswaldo Payá Way</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBC493D723DC14DF0B13C44A41B3F1726"><enum>(2)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the area referred to in paragraph (1) shall be deemed to be a reference to Oswaldo Payá Way.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCDB422A981E8433FB566A84688EBA06A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation of address</header> <paragraph id="H5287F0B55F7948858F6B036DA195042D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The address of 2630 16th Street Northwest, Washington, District of Columbia, shall be redesignated as 2630 Oswaldo Payá Way.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H956DCEA0F82E45EE9900ED3ABA6F8F1F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the address referred to in paragraph (1) shall be deemed to be a reference to 2630 Oswaldo Payá Way.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H685C14ADBE494341A93B3D3FF0AAB8A5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Signs</header><text>The District of Columbia shall construct 2 street signs that shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H21172FC8FFE54449909F31537B401714"><enum>(1)</enum><text>contain the phrase <quote>Oswaldo Payá Way</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C43F4122D3B4F7E91D3FAACB633E66C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be placed immediately above existing signs at the intersections of 16th Street Northwest and Fuller Street Northwest and 16th Street Northwest and Euclid Street Northwest in Washington, District of Columbia; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H73ADA31F0C804177BAEAD5B8CAC82C59"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be similar in design to the signs used by the District of Columbia to designate the location of Metro stations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

