<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H485AD86703BF43EC8AB3DA8D7B09A8C7" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 389 IH: Supporting the goals and ideals of National Nurses Week, to be observed from May 6 through May 12, 2025.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 389</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250506">May 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of National Nurses Week, to be observed from May 6 through May 12, 2025.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas, beginning in 1991, National Nurses Week has been celebrated annually from May 6, also known as <quote>National Recognition Day for Nurses</quote> through May 12, the birthday of Florence Nightingale, the founder of modern nursing;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas National Nurses Week is a time of year to reflect on the important contributions that nurses make in providing safe, high-quality health care;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas nurses serve on the front lines, risking their lives to treat the injured and sick during wartime, natural disasters, and public health emergencies;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas nurses are known to be patient advocates, acting to protect the lives of individuals under their care;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas nurses represent the largest single component of the health care profession, with an estimated population of more than 4,900,000 registered nurses in the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas nurses are leading in the delivery of quality care in a transformed health care system that improves patient outcomes and safety;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the Future of Nursing reports of the Institute of Medicine and National Academy of Medicine have highlighted the need for the nursing profession to meet the call for leadership in a team-based delivery model;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, when nurse staffing levels increase, the risk of patient complications and lengthy hospital stays decrease, resulting in cost savings;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas nurses are experienced researchers, and the work of nurses encompasses a wide scope of scientific inquiry, including clinical research, health systems and outcomes research, and nursing education research;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas nurses provide care to all individuals across the United States;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas nurses are well-positioned to provide leadership and increase access to nursing care throughout the United States and improve health outcomes for all patients;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas nurses are the cornerstone of the public health infrastructure, promoting healthy lifestyles and educating communities on disease prevention and health promotion;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas nurses help inform, educate, and work closely with legislators to improve—</text> <paragraph id="id071f8aa4ca984b9e80d1663d0f5f0cfc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the education, retention, recruitment, and practice of all nurses; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idebcd6cca8a9047efab2882b606b0058b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the health and safety of the patients for whom the nurses care;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas there is a need to—</text>
<paragraph id="id35651ab64b31474bb5f2a73e9fd9154e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>strengthen nursing workforce development programs at all levels, including the number of doctorally prepared faculty members; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idb6356d1a055848069be7178a9fbaff6f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide education to the nurse research scientists who can develop new nursing care models to improve the health status of all populations of the United States;</text></paragraph></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas nurses impact the lives of the people of the United States through every stage of life; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas nursing has been voted the most honest and ethical profession in the United States: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HF8D98591FFB346E3932A856E36A4462F"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H0465B2C3B92B40C1B9EFFA2B85566FC4"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H5590DAE74A1C474F8853DE89BD859C58"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of National Nurses Week, as founded by the American Nurses Association;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H40410BAE7B24404298164146B8475E23"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the significant contributions of nurses to the health care system of the United States; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63D53AB216344D21A92FDAABE1885602"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to observe National Nurses Week with appropriate recognition, ceremonies, activities, and programs to demonstrate the importance of nurses to the everyday lives of patients. </text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

