<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEN25434-R9R-PF-DRH"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2285 IS: Uterine Cancer Study Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2285</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250715">July 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to study and report on the relationship between hair straighteners and uterine cancer, particularly among women of color.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H27872E6A2568443A95176C70B62C271F"><section section-type="section-one" id="H0C5BF470BBFD41AEB3FCA6DE08AA4A6F"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Uterine Cancer Study Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H141A92901FE742D98DBE93EABFBF22EF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on relationship between hair straighteners and uterine cancer</header><subsection id="H271182F6AFEE4B4FB771F224EC763A4C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in coordination with the Commissioner of Food and Drugs and the Director of the National Institutes of Health, shall conduct a study on the relationship between hair straighteners and uterine cancer, with a focus on the increased incidence of such cancer among women of color. Such study shall—</text><paragraph id="HDE6E6A6768954A8E988DD806415E98E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review significant findings and recommendations from other studies regarding the relationship between hair straighteners and uterine cancer;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB37E61BDDAD44FADA8103C9C9A08EC10"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider impacts on women and other individuals at risk of uterine cancer from all racial and ethnic backgrounds;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05E67C63C7E8465D9C06F92D9BC3D0D8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disaggregate the results of the study under this section according to whether the hair straighteners contain dyes or coloring, bleach, highlights, or perms; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H836D6F10B0F840DC87FEF7420A561633"><enum>(4)</enum><text>determine whether the Food and Drug Administration should impose additional testing requirements on the manufacturers of hair straightening products to ensure the safety of such products.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H83F7EA1B41F247E2AEC8BD14186AE2FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Methodology</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a description of the methodology that will be used to conduct the study under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9547A4C730C7469A83EDF1BEC16CDA9D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Commencement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall commence the study under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5AA0C5DB58AE414CAECBD1311C7243EA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall complete the study under this section and submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report on the results of such study.</text></subsection><subsection id="H184219811C954C9393AC45E748C5C3A0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H3799768951A4481893610A9AEC139547"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hair straightener</header><text>The term <term>hair straightener</term> means a chemical hair straightener.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B37B3FE3062423090FCE0D3DA896402"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

