<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-joint" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25472-NRF-4M-KSD"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SJ 56 IS: Life Month Resolution</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. J. RES. 56</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250603">June 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S389">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S434">Mr. Moreno</cosponsor>) introduced the following joint resolution; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating the month of June as <quote>Life Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the United States of America was founded on the principle that all people are endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable rights, including the right to life;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the right to life is a fundamental truth enshrined in the Declaration of Independence and reaffirmed throughout the history of the United States as a cornerstone of liberty and justice;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas every human life is inherently precious, has equal dignity and worth, and deserves legal protection;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Supreme Court issued its ruling in Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health Organization, 597 U.S. 215 (2022) on June 24, 2022;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Supreme Court's decision in Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health Organization, 597 U.S. 215 (2022) rightfully returned to the people of the United States and their elected representatives the ability to protect innocent unborn life;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is the responsibility of the people of the United States and their elected representatives to protect unborn life and to plead the cause of those who cannot plead for themselves; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas faith-based and community organizations, pregnancy resource centers, medical professionals, and countless families across the United States serve as champions of life, offering essential care, resources, and support to pregnant mothers and families in need: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="id5276f46064f646b0a8ce2cd6e693b06f" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This resolution may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Life Month Resolution</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id85b9f49231ef463b8fb12658ddb91e20"><enum>2.</enum><header>Life Month</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">That the Senate and the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="idaeb1707b21374e0d87616dc0c0a212a2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designate a <quote>Life Month</quote> annually;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1c41e43aceca4288922bf2906e128fff"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognize that every human life is a sacred gift from God, possessing inherent dignity and worth;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4deb03744b124689bef57380f5015994"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirm the fundamental truth recognized in the Declaration of Independence that life is an unalienable right;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5f5c1bf9914a466f90e89302832e2c5d"><enum>(4)</enum><text>commend individuals, parents, families, faith-based organizations, and communities who work to promote a culture of life; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id74496b629d2b4025855ccbe2fd3ce459"><enum>(5)</enum><text>urge policymakers to defend the sanctity of human life by enacting laws that protect the unborn and provide resources to empower women and families to choose life.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

