<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE0A617A4F1444AB68625B059057C6CCE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2330 IH: Virginia Beach Heroes Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2330</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250325">March 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001239">Mr. McGuire</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To accelerate the income tax benefits for charitable cash contributions for the relief of the families of two law enforcement officers shot and killed in Virginia Beach, Virginia, on February 22, 2025.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H275B7A8577AD4C909FE88396A11622FB" style="OLC"><section id="HAA5E5378701342C89F715BA872580168" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Virginia Beach Heroes Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HED826B903FDA49F7B36366C99D74CCFB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Special rules for contributions for relief of the families of the law enforcement officers killed in Virginia Beach</header><subsection id="H68204018C52C43DC8FD20C15F7D7100D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Clarification that contribution will not fail To qualify as a charitable contribution</header><text>A cash contribution made for the relief of the families of the slain law enforcement officers in Virginia Beach, Virginia, on February 22, 2025, shall not fail to be treated as a charitable contribution for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/170">section 170</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 merely because such contribution is for the exclusive benefit of such families. The preceding sentence shall apply to contributions made on or after February 22, 2025.</text></subsection><subsection id="H41F140A4FCB44D8490D143BC94542A96"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification that payments by charitable organizations to families treated as exempt payments</header><text>For purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, payments made on or after February 22, 2025, and on or before February 23, 2028, to the spouse or any dependent (as defined in section 152 of such Code) of the slain law enforcement officers in Virginia Beach, Virginia, on February 22, 2025, by an organization which (determined without regard to any such payments) would be an organization exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code shall—</text><paragraph id="H46460F15C5A9444580BF6AF2EE8E6FB6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be treated as related to the purpose or function constituting the basis for such organization’s exemption under such section, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98FF255EC3B741E29C93A65D5B9AA8DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not be treated as inuring to the benefit of any private individual, if such payments are made in good faith using a reasonable and objective formula which is consistently applied with respect to such victims.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

