<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB38D6445D59D481C9A306AEEB903616C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5214 IH: District of Columbia Cash Bail Reform Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5214</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250908">September 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="J000307">Mr. James</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require mandatory pretrial and post conviction detention for crimes of violence and dangerous crimes and require mandatory cash bail for certain offenses that pose a threat to public safety or order in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC6F84E8CF9CA418E90ADBAB5842AF8C3" style="OLC"><section id="H1D5512C7E0024AA2B829866BFFB72B8B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>District of Columbia Cash Bail Reform Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB7442462103B43578F8336159DFC6425"><enum>2.</enum><header>Mandatory pretrial and post conviction detention for crime of violence or dangerous crime</header><subsection id="HF8442686D00F43009907D5F5CAE03AAB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pretrial detention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 23–1322, District of Columbia Official Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H32614819F55C4CDE9EFB0246CFB18A95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>with an offense</quote> and inserting <quote>with an offense, other than a crime of violence or dangerous crime (as such terms are defined in section 1331 of this title),</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46D38224E61D41589FAAD1930C234E57"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE7076CF80A7C4DA38619F2FC1A73779A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HF4A549EB59D0458E81BF6C3EE8091F49"><enum>(j)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the judicial officer shall order each person charged with a crime of violence or a dangerous crime (as such terms are defined in section 1331 of this title) be detained for the period before trial.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2353DC6EB76C49E0A8F1EA9E8DE014AE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Post conviction detention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 23–1325, District of Columbia Official Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HAC2E7B626F084EBE8551C43EFC608D1B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>unless</quote> and all that follows through <quote>section 23–1321</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFF46C4D509347BCAC786C72D7935221"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c), by striking <quote>unless</quote> and all that follows through <quote>section 23–1321</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7804259EC284B76A5E13AC6A379B011"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H60CC3A2267C14B4EB9DB8975967AD3A4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H96B1BF5E41BD4D6EB440466170651B2F"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This provisions of this section shall apply with respect to a person convicted of a crime of violence or a dangerous crime (as such terms are defined in section 1331 of this title).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9DEB774A8EAB4BF89E5C55F2250567BC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Changes to definition of dangerous crime</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 23–1331(3), D.C. Official Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HBF79942A227340169AEEF27145847209"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>Burglary or attempted burglary</quote> and inserting <quote>Burglary in the first degree, attempted burglary in the first degree, or burglary with a dangerous weapon</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C2C54E3E9DA43D8B20C467EC6D432A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (G), by striking <quote>Robbery or attempted robbery</quote> and inserting <quote>Robbery in the first degree, attempted robbery in the first degree, or robbery with a dangerous weapon</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCBB7F11E43724A708665921DCDE7DBCE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Changes to definition of crime of violence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 23–1331(4), D.C. Official Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H14BE638EC8BF4969A5A508CCF1B96C0E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>burglary</quote> and inserting <quote>burglary in the first degree, attempted burglary in the first degree, or burglar with a dangerous weapon</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEF22C9E58DA4C8FB029D7D3D9FA6405"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>robbery</quote> and inserting <quote>robbery in the first degree, attempted robbery in the first degree, or robbery with a dangerous weapon</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBF31362C8A044081B1488ACE463559BA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="HD747B1259323456E89B6B8998636FCA3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Removal of crime of violence and dangerous crime from pretrial release procedures</header><text>Section 23–1322, District of Columbia Official Code, is further amended—</text><subparagraph id="H39443A39F8D44F2FAAA7731BA4CD1E06"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), by striking subparagraph (A) and redesignating subparagraphs (B) through (D) as subparagraphs (A) through (C), respectively;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77BEA611CDEB4D4185AF2A53CB14EB85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending subsection (c) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H7EF7F29D2D864018BB13525CA7502E12" style="OLC"><subsection id="H4ADBCCB7779D465EB9F7624FC92E6590"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Subject to rebuttal by the person, it shall be presumed that no condition or combination of conditions of release will reasonably assure the safety of any other person and the community if the judicial officer finds that there is probable cause to believe that the person—</text><paragraph id="H52EBB5CC407046348F95B7E7CF4A491D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has threatened, injured, intimidated, or attempted to threaten, injure, or intimidate a law enforcement officer, an officer of the court, or a prospective witness or juror in any criminal investigation or judicial proceeding;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A65049B714B4EA2877ED1C453AA6F9B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>violated section 3 of the Act of July 8, 1932 (sec. 22–4503, D.C. Official Code), section 4(a) of such Act (sec. 22–4504(a), D.C. Official Code), or section 4(a–1) of such Act (sec. 22–4504(a)(1), D.C. Official Code); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E4B82184DE54195A17DAD44921AD0F8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>violated the Firearm Control Regulations Act of 1975 (sec. 7–2508.01 et seq., D.C. Official Code) while on probation, parole, or supervised release for committing a dangerous crime or a crime of violence (as such terms are defined in section 1331 of this title) and while armed with or having readily available a firearm, imitation firearm, or other deadly or dangerous weapon as described in section 2(a) of the Act of July 8, 1832 (sec. 22–4502(a), D.C. Official Code).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE3BDB68C2DB4447B4A220C6A8EDC02B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(1), by striking <quote>is a crime of</quote> and all that follows through <quote>, or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5022126409F419194C6AF310C88679E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking subsection (f)(3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDAF1931C5C14037A1FCFF33D769B19C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Removal of murder offenses from pretrial release procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 23–1325, District of Columbia Official Code, as amended by subsection (b), is amended by striking subsection (a) and redesignating subsections (b) through (d) as (a) through (c), respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8983BD55D85E4615864305B01AB109B7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Requiring cash bail for release of individuals charged with public safety or order offenses</header><subsection id="HEC83D14A7518443BBC0C26A16D9E7727"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 23–1321, District of Columbia Official Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H5011DA15A2D24914AF05EBD6F84D19F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H082FB6DB4DCA4262914F30728D6754D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>Released</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided under paragraph (5), released</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD44B020B3A5A42828FC6084205129D99"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93CDA7FADB1049748BB165E48B16E8D4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H243C0892906B482B8E73FF32E2017311"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H21BF0ECD65614EBCB7BE035D13B9B0BD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H796A7494A85548CF96A102AB26A55DE0"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a person charged with a public safety or order crime (as such term is defined in section 1331 of this title), released only upon execution of a secured appearance bond (as such term is defined in section 1331 of this title) and subject to any requirement under subsections (b) and (c) of this section as the judicial officer may order.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA022EAD57A814938B63FF8AAADC42922"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>or upon execution of an unsecured appearance bond in an amount specified by the court,</quote> and inserting <quote>upon execution of an unsecured appearance bond in an amount specified by the court, or upon a secured appearance bond under subsection (a)(5),</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D0593504BD04A3488D2566CB3283342"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H93E25B32458F42B08EBC072CF4561010" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H043AE6BE14BA46A79F33A1997F9FC184"><enum>(f)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who is released upon the execution of an appearance bond with a surety, under subsection (a)(5), may be arrested by the surety, and if so arrested, shall be delivered promptly to a United States marshal and brought before a judicial officer in the District of Columbia. The judicial officer shall determine in accordance with the provisions of this section 23–1322 whether to revoke the release of the person, and may absolve the surety of responsibility to pay all or part of the bond in accordance with the provisions of Rule 46 of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure. The person so committed shall be held in official detention until released pursuant to this title or any other provision of law.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0C4DD49A474B437E898362A2654DA3A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><paragraph id="H4A314F6E0CFB4BD8BB896436BA0644E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Public safety or order crime defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 23–1331, District of Columbia Official Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC7FE932E3CED4B50AEE02CC1F04492E6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H0CEABC7BEAAF4536A9D88C8F6E26F5E6"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>public safety or order crime</quote> means failure to appear when ordered to do so by a judicial officer; obstruction of justice; fleeing from a law enforcement officer; rioting; inciting a riot; destruction of property; stalking; burglary (other than burglary in the first degree or burglary with a dangerous weapon); robbery or a previous conviction of any such offense, or substantially similar offense, under Federal, State, or local law.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CF442906E5C4646A4C1D9AF36E1DEAF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secured appearance bond defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 23–1331, District of Columbia Official Code, is further amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H763A376A2E1E481D8F17552FA4395924" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HB8E372EC7D0748A3A9C49FC996226FF1"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>secured appearance bond</quote> means an agreement to forfeit upon failing to appear as required, the designated property, including money, as is reasonably necessary to assure the appearance of the person as required, and post with the court the indicia of ownership of the property, or a percentage of the money as the judicial officer may specify; or a bail bond with solvent sureties in whatever amount is reasonably necessary to assure the appearance of the person as required.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4152848DB1934A7EA4E2026F952BBC3D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 23–1321, District of Columbia Official Code, is further amended—</text><paragraph id="H3FCA6A9D82A94B13B81DAE716D4CDFD2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a), by striking <quote>with an offense</quote> and all that follows through <quote>shall issue</quote> and insert <quote>with an offense, other than a crime of violence or dangerous crime (as such terms are defined in section 1331 of this title), the judicial officer shall issue</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46F6C4E4E500450DB9CD548437F5382A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="H5DB67CD037A14A02A3607EE5C6D4B1B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="H7D11B3447325401D9CD7C6CA31620A1D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>shall</quote> and inserting <quote>may</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H94F5771C6A704AE38D6002F8B44577D8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>Least restrictive further</quote> and inserting <quote>Further</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A09C61A622746CC9A0B32F2863ABBFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3) and redesignating paragraphs (4) and (5) as paragraphs (3) and (4), respectively; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9FB3211272F44ED81B380C70DFB7960"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>additional or different conditions</quote> and inserting <quote>any additional or different condition described under this subsection</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9C97109453AD43DE8DF5936507CCD4FB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act, and the amendments made by this Act, shall apply with respect to an individual charged with an offense in the District of Columbia on or after the date that is 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

