<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE32EC640D9AD46FA995CD0A6FB5D3DC2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5550 IH: Lower Internet Costs Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5550</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250923">September 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to direct the Federal Communications Commission to promulgate regulations requiring providers of broadband service to state the aggregate price for such service and prohibiting providers of broadband service from charging certain fees, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB66AC300323E44CEB4889DCAC765D0B6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5719BFE8C7664662819E5FDCEF404F52" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Lower Internet Costs Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7E5C949CD1BB4B82BAC2964BC6DFF289"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of aggregate price for broadband service; certain fees prohibited</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VII of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/601">47 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H44E5C4A410824D20AB92F3D1C302B25F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H8630036DC8224FFF8D84D8F42C39ADDA"><enum>723.</enum><header>Statement of aggregate price for broadband service; certain fees prohibited</header> 
<subsection id="HDBBFA0861D01416ABA2F7ADB30E9A51B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Commission shall promulgate regulations that—</text> <paragraph id="H65B96F1F5EAC47B9BDF629D3F956A373"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require a provider of broadband service—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFDE8F19CD33F41FFA3DAEF146FF10237"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to state the aggregate price for such service as a clear, easy-to-understand, and accurate single line item on the bill of a subscriber; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E521AE602274834A9E2A8B734D97DA2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if such provider communicates a price for such service in any promotional materials, to state the aggregate price for such service in a clear, easy-to-understand, and accurate manner in such materials; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC0CE184E635A4660B4C8012634E51F78"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibit a provider of broadband service from charging a subscriber a covered fee.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA18BF63D4A734A9FA2B807B484810520"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements regarding statement of aggregate price</header> <paragraph id="HC7F322D2D46843EFA599E8BC22178B0C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>On bill of subscriber</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the statement on the bill of a subscriber described in subsection (a)(1)(A) (including a bill for a legacy or grandfathered broadband service plan that is no longer generally available to new customers), the regulations promulgated under subsection (a) shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC816C53FE41C4A67B95DA81F02A3790F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the aggregate price stated is introductory or otherwise limited to a period of time, require the provider of broadband service to state on the bills provided to such subscriber approximately 60 days and 30 days before the end of such period—</text> <clause id="HB310065BA71D43438504E24553D62262"><enum>(i)</enum><text>either—</text> 
<subclause id="H89DE691515CF45649D3BE81F69F7C953"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the length of such period; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF8CD73C3783242A4A5DDED847D1EC8AB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the date on which such period will end and the price charged will change; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HDA9BB314B5684E00850E24CDC7F2C3E8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the price that will be charged after the end of such period; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1360029E64F44F14A4F9B7BDA42E2E64"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">permit the provider of broadband service to complement the aggregate price stated with an itemized explanation of the elements that compose such aggregate price.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H66AEC58CD4D04E1692608D05553DCFE0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>In promotional materials</header><text>With respect to the statement in any promotional materials described in subsection (a)(1)(B), the regulations promulgated under subsection (a) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H8325C2EC8BB84C6598BEBF9EF5399D51"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the aggregate price stated is introductory or otherwise limited to a period of time, require the provider of broadband service to state in such materials—</text> 
<clause id="H9D4BBF77973E40A3B04FD021B72EC8B9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the price that will be charged after the end of such period (calculated on the date on which such materials are made available to consumers); and</text></clause> <clause id="H861921F747CF4EFF8FDB9518F6B1118A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the length of such period and the length of time for which the price described in clause (i) will be charged;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H076724CFD25149AB9748B334EFB202C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if part of the aggregate price stated fluctuates based on service location, require the provider of broadband service to state where and how a consumer may obtain the aggregate price specific to such consumer (such as electronically or by contacting a customer service or sales representative);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEA4BDD28F4924ADE8FA4AED6B00FE7AE"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">permit the provider of broadband service to complement the aggregate price stated with an itemized explanation of the elements that compose such aggregate price; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA0182318E917495F9976B656E4CCA85A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specify that the requirements in such regulations with respect to such statement do not apply with respect to legacy or grandfathered broadband service plans that are no longer generally available to new customers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E97AC5DF5584C64B1E3248DA14B2590" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exclusions from aggregate price</header><text>The regulations promulgated under subsection (a) shall specify other charges related to the provision of broadband service (such as taxes, administrative fees, and equipment fees) that are not charged for the broadband service itself and are not required to be included in the aggregate price stated under such regulations.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA62E7D833C4742BE8B7CCF0502D5A539"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Application to bundled services</header><text>The regulations promulgated under subsection (a) shall provide that, if a provider of broadband service bills for or promotes broadband service as part of a bundle with other services—</text> <subparagraph id="H0333C94B5AEC474098080C97A3A8269C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the statements described in subsection (a)(1) are required with respect to any charges for such bundle that are specific to broadband service; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H087BD07E40464277A3C96E64ABCCA0EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the prohibition on charging a covered fee under subsection (a)(2) applies with respect to all services that are part of such bundle.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEE51C8B234164DD1AB1B02EA8BD7295E" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HD65CC90202634A30A3E361E2C6DEB88E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Broadband service</header><text>The term <quote>broadband service</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>broadband internet access service</quote> in section 8.1(b) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE60D90F289EE474687283D7B7DFE8E1C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered fee</header><text>The term <quote>covered fee</quote> means, with respect to a fee charged by a provider of broadband service, the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6ECB0F0DCC80465C8F81FF502D848845" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A fee to cover the cost of compliance with State regulations and programs (commonly known as a <quote>State cost recovery charge</quote>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7F8FFE40B5F64A78A335746A85098449" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A fee to cover the cost of maintaining, building, or operating the network of such provider (commonly known as a <quote>network access and maintenance fee</quote>, <quote>internet cost recovery fee</quote>, <quote>broadband cost recovery fee</quote>, or <quote>network enhancement fee</quote>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA578C83AAE1B475C99A16786936FE3C6" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A fee imposed by a local government on such provider to compensate such local government for use of a public right-of-way (commonly known as a <quote>local access fee</quote>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H27125E86507E4A10A003A3B30D6C1A0C" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A fee for the cost of technical support or repair of equipment (commonly known as a <quote>tech assure fee</quote>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDD91F63CF0764B12A6C7F098E623FCD6" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any other fee determined by the Commission to be charged for a purpose similar to a purpose described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> </legis-body></bill>

