<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0143D020A4C44B06A4040C0EFDB0BBE9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2570 IH: Maximum Pressure Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2570</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250401">April 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</sponsor> (for himself,
                    <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001093">Mrs.
                    Houchin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr.
                    Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000475">Mr.
                    Finstad</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="F000471">Mr. Fitzgerald</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr.
                    Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr.
                    Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn of
                    Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000603">Mr. Luttrell</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001082">Mr. Hern of Oklahoma</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001213">Mr. Steil</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S001188">Mr. Stutzman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr.
                    Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="L000600">Mr. Langworthy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000246">Mr.
                    Fallon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. Scott Franklin of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001222">Mr. Miller of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000067">Mr. Yakym</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000601">Mr. Goldman of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of
                    Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the
                    <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign
                    Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>,
                    <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>,
                    <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name>, for a
                period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration
                of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee
                concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose additional sanctions with respect to Iran and modify
 other existing sanctions with respect to Iran, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H755B5714AC5C4123B3BDC49A3D4BE3B3" style="OLC"><section id="HC7828EC36CDD46C9B1699719FC12F129" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H1DCACF4AC7B641A6A2AEC8B308889D64" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Maximum Pressure Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H168B02D461A9458B903DA97B877D77C8" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="HC7828EC36CDD46C9B1699719FC12F129" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HDD0518A0F7A042369B8EC730BC6A64CE" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H03698ED2B6C94244A6C79CA42B54727B" level="section">Sec. 3. Sense of Congress on Iranian responsibility for Hamas terror attacks on October 7, 2023.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H8357E840AD1247D5BB74C10B81138F1F" level="section">Sec. 4. Statement of policy.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA0FED7F26E7C48B8A38CA61AF19C5B87" level="section">Sec. 5 Codification of united states policy.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H445D2AD290F64130BFC31362E4BDD55E" level="section">Sec. 5. Severability.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H15811D54CEAB46F6A3E65529BA815D09" level="title">Title I—Matters Relating to Sanctions and Sanction Authorities</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HC07F869C0D4E4DDA95640644489C891D" level="section">Sec. 101. Codification of executive orders and continuation of certain existing sanctions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5767D91AC50046C09B5FCA43F577C899" level="section">Sec. 102. Sanctions with respect to the Supreme Leader of Iran.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA3FABC28F61145A9BE334595B88A4736" level="section">Sec. 103. Sanctions with respect to listed persons involved in international arms sales to Iran.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H19B727ADC22A4B3F994CF5A947C58BA8" level="section">Sec. 104. Additional conditions for termination and elimination of sunset of sanctions under the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H89182DF122104CE6B0C2196DDBC54725" level="section">Sec. 105. Sectoral sanctions on Iran under the Iran Freedom and Counter-Proliferation Act of 2012.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H513DCEFD698943369B444B5A8E4DBA62" level="section">Sec. 106. Amendments to the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HDA83C1C1776B454790A53BE95805916A" level="section">Sec. 107. Congressional review of certain actions relating to sanctions imposed with respect to Iran.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H039E2AB9C46246CEB0856002C3DA9D93" level="section">Sec. 108. Clarification of guidance relating to Iran’s shipping sector.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H057140A527504EC89511647CAACD900C" level="section">Sec. 109. Sunset of waiver and license authorities.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H1C47D7D3E03446A1BBA73723ACEF0F08" level="section">Sec. 110. Codification and application on transfers of funds involving Iran.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2E00EC139EE6469A8DFBC2AE7901F0B8" level="section">Sec. 111. Applicability of congressional review of certain agency rulemaking relating to Iran.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H429C6B79DF98464A8BC4CC788EEEBA20" level="section">Sec. 112. Expansion of sanctions with respect to efforts by Iran to acquire ballistic missile and related technology.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H114DD39085F3455E86931391EF2000D8" level="section">Sec. 113. Expansion of sanctions under Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 with respect to persons that acquire or develop ballistic missiles.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H1E7662B61215471DAAF32A65FC1667B8" level="section">Sec. 114. Imposition of sanctions with respect to ballistic missile program of Iran.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5A4116E528284295AF503089ACF1F275" level="section">Sec. 115. Mandatory sanctions with respect to financial institutions that engage in certain transactions on behalf of persons involved in human rights abuses or that export sensitive technology to Iran.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H4A963CCB4208431987740897EB8B7E87" level="section">Sec. 116. Additional sanctions with respect to foreign persons that support or conduct certain transactions with Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps or other sanctioned persons.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9E3B456F3E89452ABD3C11994C024743" level="title">Title II—Matters Relating to the Financing of Terrorism</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5595F6418E61402EAEC596719655AA09" level="section">Sec. 201. Prohibitions of International Monetary Fund allocations for Iran.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H18CFA6FF29D345FCA59E73464CB1C8F1" level="section">Sec. 202. Certification requirement for removal of designation of Iran as a jurisdiction of primary money laundering concern.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H14E75A4659A94DEA9728EB6374C720EF" level="section">Sec. 203. Requirement to take special measures at domestic financial institutions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H0F96336A236D4659AC0D75846C2F22B8" level="section">Sec. 204. Additional sanctions with respect to foreign persons that are officials, agents, or affiliates of, or owned or controlled by, Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H285B65E5656D48C6A14BE58D295AC7AD" level="section">Sec. 205. Additional sanctions with respect to foreign persons that support or conduct certain transactions with Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps or other sanctioned persons.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HEAC9D775655A4639959ADF838989BD28" level="section">Sec. 206. Reports on certain Iranian persons and sectors of Iran’s economy that are controlled by Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HBC51A67F6E7D4E74BEDA4D78E6BEE9A2" level="title">Title III—Matters Relating to the Designation of Certain Entities</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H24DA38F010374CA599D8AE98E0958594" level="section">Sec. 301. Prohibition on future waivers and licenses connected to the designation of the IRGC.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5B171CB50EB24ED3991C71703B454998" level="section">Sec. 302. Prohibition on future waivers and licenses connected to the designation of the IRGC as a foreign terrorist organization.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HBC5F4511F6FF44A4837672C6CAD23C58" level="section">Sec. 303. Codification of Executive Order 14175 relating to Ansar Allah in Yemen.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H1E545E60DABA4AE38C07FC3FF6295E9D" level="title">Title IV—Determinations and Reports</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H0C3A63186EC948D9BD0641D5F4077783" level="section">Sec. 401. Determinations with respect to the imposition of sanctions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD2A15CB5BA844E4B95C86E0EB4744EB0" level="section">Sec. 402. Iranian militia watchlists.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD0011F33C85F478DBB59FD0B02CE6569" level="section">Sec. 403. Expansion of reporting to include Iranian arms shipments to the Houthis and Iranian backed militias in Iraq and Syria.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HACF4C49D57B04FBDA3507E995C97AF6F" level="section">Sec. 404. Annual report on Iran sanctions violations.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H776CB20AF7FD41BFA92F2FA08C26F92C" level="section">Sec. 405. Report on sanctions relief going to terrorism or destabilizing activities.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HC7271728CDFF4F76B93B642068B82538" level="section">Sec. 406. Supporting human rights for the people of Iran and the victims of Iranian human rights abuses in Syria, Lebanon, Yemen, and Venezuela.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H4BBCAB58C5D94B528156B5CD09BC3881" level="section">Sec. 407. Determination with respect to net worth of Iranian Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H52EB38A48ACD4B3DBFBEB97611E322A6" level="section">Sec. 408. IRGC watch list and report.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H189C834F7EFA4E6D92DFD0B39FAB0B67" level="section">Sec. 409. Report on Iran’s breakout timeline for uranium enrichment and nuclear weaponization.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H45F9ABA362684507A575203C8511FE7A" level="section">Sec. 410. Report on Iranian disinformation campaigns and counter-disinformation efforts.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H963E2C64887D49349B5DD7F914F89052" level="section">Sec. 411. Report on Iranian support to Hamas.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HAEC6ACB1BC4C4C5D833823A4D2FB3282" level="section">Sec. 412. Report on unblocked Iranian assets and terrorism.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H52353D4A08F447858F66456298EFBB33" level="section">Sec. 413. Report on Iranian counterintelligence threats in the United States.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HDB45A928484B40C1AAC02A0A38C31003" level="title">Title V—Additional Matters</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6F9E68CEB3E442979063BE5E22C8A771" level="section">Sec. 501. Increasing rewards for justice for Hamas, Hezbollah, the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps and other terrorists involved in October 7, 2023, terrorist attacks against Israel.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HFB388EEE1A5D42DE9DF9A2BB2742A27C" level="section">Sec. 502. Repurposing frozen Iranian funds for United States Victims of State Sponsored Terrorism fund.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H54EA84F1DB994A5F828E7A152491BB89" level="section">Sec. 503. Determination regarding applicable Iranian financial institutions under executive order 13902.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H606D42CD8244483EB9DB224924FC8402" level="section">Sec. 504. Maximizing the ability of Iranian terror victims to collect on existing judgments against Iran.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD9795EB533134164996F7E060B8FEBB3" level="section">Sec. 505. Creation of Iran Strike Fund.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H44D504904458462EB6806DC8E1DE863D" level="section">Sec. 506. Iran Kleptocracy Initiative.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="HDD0518A0F7A042369B8EC730BC6A64CE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HA12CE6DB2F5F4CD8A86E56BD9F4DF472"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Iran is the world’s leading State sponsor of terrorism. It seeks <quote>death to America</quote> and the destruction of the State of Israel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75E9F8C466FA444BA676B50F9BD476C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>United States sanctions will continue to be applied to and rigorously enforced against the regime in Tehran until Iran has ceased providing support for acts of international terrorism and no longer satisfies the requirements for designation as a state sponsor of terrorism, and has ceased the pursuit, acquisition, and development of, and verifiably dismantled its nuclear, biological, and chemical weapons, ballistic missiles, and ballistic missile launch technology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46D888496C3D41078BC3265CC11BD1FB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Iran’s pursuit of nuclear weapons, its efforts to destroy the State of Israel, its support of terrorism, its destabilizing behavior in the Middle East, its development and proliferation of drones and ballistic missiles, and its gross violations of human rights against its own people and the peoples of the Middle East are a threat to the national security of the United States, our allies, and international peace and security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4B754A57122475F87BF433EDE601A21"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Experts from the Institute for Science and International Security estimate that Iran, as of February 2025, has enough highly enriched uranium to produce weapons-grade uranium for 1 nuclear bomb in less than 7 days and has enough enriched uranium to make weapons-grade uranium for as many as 17 nuclear bombs within 4 months. Iran continues to enrich uranium to levels for which there is no conceivable civilian purpose, and which could only be used to produce a nuclear weapon.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6240C7B9F959456DB594E8B98AE11A53"><enum>(5)</enum><text>According to multiple United States Directors of National Intelligence, Iran has the largest arsenal of ballistic missiles in the Middle East. Iran also possesses a robust cruise missile arsenal and advanced drone capability, which threaten United States and allied air and missile defenses. Iran tests, transfers, and even uses these systems in military operations abroad.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF967220D1E5A4C0B9DDF17BD96DA65BC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Iran has given ballistic missiles, drones, and associated technology to the Houthis in Yemen, Shiite militias in Iraq, the Assad regime in Syria, and Hezbollah in Lebanon, and is trafficking precision-guided munitions parts through the Middle East to upgrade the rocket forces of its chief proxy, Hezbollah.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD802E202864A4F2D94696EDC9628CDD4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Iran has sold thousands of drones to Russia for its use in its invasion of Ukraine, leading to mass attacks on civilian infrastructure, and has given Russia the technology and knowledge to produce these drones in Russia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFAF97540FC7435181AA680A372F5ECC"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Iran continues to take United States citizens hostage to extract ransom payments from the United States and exchange arbitrarily detained United States citizens for Iranian agents arrested for violating United States sanctions and for other malign activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2132BE2840D04A6AA3CDC0A5BB8E88F7"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPOA) negotiated by former President Barack Obama was fatally flawed, did not eliminate Iran’s pathway to a nuclear weapon, and allowed Iran to retain and refine its ability to quickly resume its pursuit of a nuclear weapon.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1028566CEEB407CA66FE15A0AD88791"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The failed Iran nuclear agreement allowed Iran to export more than $300,000,000,000 of goods and services from 2015 to 2017 that was used by Iran to fuel proxy wars across the Middle East.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9495AB4CC0C44EF5AC6B787264C169B1"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The failed Iran nuclear agreement lifted the United Nations conventional arms embargo on Iran in October 2020, permitting Russia and China to engage in international arms sales with Iran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD6CF688779F4277A593ADA7ED5881C1"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The failed Iran nuclear agreement also lifted the United Nations missile embargo on Iran in October 2023, allowing Iran to sell and purchase drone and ballistic missile technology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA760DA8D653B4A7DACA1FEED3B2C2834"><enum>(13)</enum><text>A central flaw of the failed Iran nuclear deal was that the agreement solely focused on nuclear weapons and did not address non-nuclear issues like Iran’s support for terrorism, drone and ballistic missile technology, gross human rights abuses, and Iran’s other malign activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H82772B4938024A78AC8709C7023827CE"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Iran received significant sanctions relief from the previous sanctions imposed by the European Union, the United States, and previous United Nations Security Council (UNSC) resolutions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBE55355029A4A4AB1926B96FD744DFC"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Iran used this sanctions relief to fund its terrorist proxies, regional aggression, and its expansion of its ballistic missile program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3A6D5EC5AB7472AA285A6A187839DC0"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Iran has repeatedly violated the terms of the JCPOA and UNSCR 2231, including by—</text><subparagraph id="H34173953A62E456C8E945ECC47C9D5E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>lifting the cap on its stockpile of uranium;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H089A09A4D58842B0A9245061FBD1B7F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increasing its enrichment activities to 60 percent purity, expanding its enrichment capabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE18A24B7A0304BF6AC77661132998F18"><enum>(C)</enum><text>resuming its activity at prohibited nuclear facilities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F195FB25BD34A1B95A36176F27202F4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>preventing the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) from being able to effectively monitor its nuclear activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A76EAF9FDCE4D369174D4EEDF2588DE"><enum>(17)</enum><text>Iran repeatedly violated UNSCR 2231’s restrictions on ballistic missile testing and development, as well as United Nations-imposed and internationally binding arms export and import embargoes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H785FE1698DE641568A5BADFE67896122"><enum>(18)</enum><text>UNSCR 2231 includes a formal mechanism for a participant state of the JCPOA, if it believes there has been significant non-performance of commitments under the JCPOA by Iran, to trigger a process that would require the UNSC to <quote>snapback</quote> all United Nation sanctions on Iran that has been lifted pursuant to UNSCR 2231.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70C75290399348D398BA3E525C7AD85A"><enum>(19)</enum><text>On September 14, 2024, in a joint statement, the United States and United Kingdom acknowledged publicly that Iran’s nuclear program <quote>has never been more advanced and posed a clear threat to regional and global peace and security</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F6585290FD149B598E93A3D7C7EE87C"><enum>(20)</enum><text>In June and November of 2024, in efforts led by France, Germany, the United Kingdom (E3), and the United States, the IAEA’s Board of Governors voted to censure Iran for non-compliance with its obligations under the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons, done at Washington, London, and Moscow July 1, 1968 (commonly referred to as the <quote>Nuclear Nonproliferation Treaty</quote> or <quote>NPT</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H33159766D9764292BB97955CF220665C"><enum>(21)</enum><text>In February 2025, the IAEA reported that Iran has increased production of 60 percent highly enriched uranium from 7 kilograms to roughly 35 kilograms per month, and currently possesses about 275 kilograms, enough to fuel nearly 7 nuclear weapons. According to the Institute for Science and International Security, if Iran enriched all its uranium stocks to 90 percent, it could fuel 17 weapons within 4 months.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7AEFF7BF85F34709AD88F23FBFDB5C71"><enum>(22)</enum><text>Under UNSCR 2231, the resolution, including the <quote>snapback</quote> mechanism, terminates 10 years after Adoption Day for the JCPOA, which will be October 18, 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BC44CD47B694F77BC1BEB8C03CD23ED"><enum>(23)</enum><text>The E3 must invoke the <quote>snapback</quote> of United Nations sanctions against Iran under UNSCR 2231 as soon as possible before the option expires on October 18, 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB71ECB57F28240A5A48AC15466A1B4F4"><enum>(24)</enum><text>2 weeks after President Trump withdrew from the failed Iran nuclear deal, former Secretary of State Mike Pompeo laid out 12 demands that would need to be met by Iran as part of any agreement related to the lifting of sanctions, and the re-establishment of diplomatic and commercial relations with Iran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H850AC528370A40058EFB4D0510267726"><enum>(25)</enum><text>Former President Donald Trump’s maximum pressure campaign on Iran denied the regime unprecedented revenue it would have otherwise spent on terrorism.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E8EEB3BD185437F9A9E1C2EEFC5C5C0"><enum>(26)</enum><text>On December 31, 2019, then-Iranian President Hassan Rouhani admitted that Iran had lost $200,000,000,000 in revenue because of United States sanctions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE4895D1254A4266899835301151BFC7"><enum>(27)</enum><text>Iran’s 2019 defense budget cut defense spending by 28 percent, including a 17 percent cut to the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps, a designated foreign terrorist organization. Hezbollah terrorists and Iranian backed militias were denied resources and were forced to cut salaries of their fighters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B1FC07AAF59406783D6A2D65B2A449B"><enum>(28)</enum><text>The Iranian rial lost around 70 percent of its value due to President Trump’s maximum pressure campaign.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC1FED389D95407BAB7D739A53F00447"><enum>(29)</enum><text>According to the International Monetary Fund, Iran’s accessible foreign exchange reserves plunged to $4,000,000,000 in 2020 from $123,000,000,000 in 2018, or a decrease of over 96 percent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EC8F286912346CFA5D47BF8F26567C2"><enum>(30)</enum><text>During the maximum pressure campaign, the United States was able to achieve the release of 2 hostages in Iran, Xiyue Wang and Michael White, without lifting sanctions or transferring cash to Iran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C37ECF140074190A363D3021A762B14"><enum>(31)</enum><text>President Joe Biden’s relentless attempts to re-enter the failed Iran nuclear agreement squandered much of the leverage created by President Trump’s maximum pressure campaign.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCC1A278738C4D9AB50B533010173E6D"><enum>(32)</enum><text>The Biden Administration’s pursuit of an even weaker deal with Iran broke previous pledges made by administration officials to pursue a <quote>longer and stronger</quote> deal that extended sunset dates of restrictions, and which would cover a broader range of Iran’s malign activity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB08D4E7C316846068750EDFDFEA6335A"><enum>(33)</enum><text>Amid the multiple failed rounds of talks to get Iran to re-enter the Iran nuclear agreement, the Biden administration reportedly offered to remove the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps from the Foreign Terrorist Organization list, despite the group’s obvious involvement in and support for terrorism, until news of this offer became public.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0F1B0D000BE40B585DC0B2E663A8FCA"><enum>(34)</enum><text>The Iranian regime has made around $200,000,000,000 in illicit oil sales since President Biden took office due to the administration’s lax enforcement of sanctions on Iranian oil exports. Total Iranian oil exports reached nearly 2,000,000 barrels per day in August 2023, the highest since before the maximum pressure campaign began.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F58B727084D493E9D840C32F71A021B"><enum>(35)</enum><text>In 2021, Iran increased funding for the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps by 14 percent, reversing budget cuts imposed as a result of maximum pressure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BA8668E41F14EF29223E3AB45B018E2"><enum>(36)</enum><text>Iran’s accessible foreign exchange reserves have risen from $4,000,000,000 in 2020 to at least $43,000,000,000 in 2023.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H644D854691364ED9A58E0CCA2A9C109F"><enum>(37)</enum><text>In July 2023, the United States unfroze nearly $10,000,000,000 held in Iraqi banks for Iraq to pay to the Iranian regime.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H950E6C181644413FAF79F667DE21C802"><enum>(38)</enum><text>In August 2023, the Biden Administration agreed to give Iran access to $6,000,000,000 in previously frozen funds and released several Iranians in prison for violating United States sanctions in exchange for the release of 5 United States hostages. This represents the largest ransom payment in United States history.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3D7E9AC2CBA47E9977456C847DD5CD1"><enum>(39)</enum><text>On March 18, 2021, in an interview with BBC Persian, President Biden’s Special Envoy for Iran and lead United States negotiator in talks to re-enter the Iran deal, Robert Malley, stated <quote>President Biden and all of his senior advisers have said this—the maximum pressure campaign has failed. It was a failure, a predicted failure. It hasn’t made life any better for the Iranian people; it hasn’t made life any better for the United States and the region; it hasn’t brought us any closer to this better deal that President Trump spoke about.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BF2CD6863D241BF9C5960797F02ED34"><enum>(40)</enum><text>In June 2023, it was revealed that the State Department had placed Malley on leave and had suspended his security clearance, reportedly due to accusations that Malley mishandled classified information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB51EFBE43EC84A20AA8156210D3C7BC6"><enum>(41)</enum><text>In September 2023, it was revealed that Malley had deep ties to several experts who were part of an Iranian Government influence operation during the Iran deal negotiations to convince Western governments to support lighter demands on Iran. These experts have since served in senior staff positions in the Department of Defense and have advised executive branch officials on issues related to Iran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC4D7EBA3A1045A3B1EAC356A8BB34B3"><enum>(42)</enum><text>In September 2022, the Iranian regime’s <quote>Morality Police</quote> detained, brutally beat, and killed 22-year old Mahsa Amini for allegedly violating Islamic dress code. Mahsa’s death spurred the largest anti-regime and pro-democracy protests in Iran since the 1979 revolution, with hundreds of thousands of Iranians chanting <quote>Death to the Dictator</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A08C8F04952406586E9F3B7F2F23E66"><enum>(43)</enum><text>Iranian regime forces cracked down on the protests, killing at least 500 protestors, and eventually reinstated street patrols of the Morality Police and has continued brutalizing women who do not adhere to its strict dress code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC650DC2D5CBD485991A3A0F1C0D39C25"><enum>(44)</enum><text>On September 12, 2023, the House of Representatives passed the passed the MAHSA Act, which imposes sanctions on Iranian leadership, including the Supreme Leader of Iran, for their responsibility for Mahsa’s death and for their repression of innocent Iranians like Mahsa. The MAHSA Act represents a Congress bipartisan consensus that the Biden administration’s policy on Iran has clearly failed and that Iranian regime officials must be held accountable for their crimes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A17F6351B7F495EB9A60580748D58FF"><enum>(45)</enum><text>Emboldened by the failure of the Biden administration’s Iran policy, Iranian proxy group Hamas carried out a massacre of Israeli and other civilians on October 7, 2023, that killed more than 1,400 Israelis and foreign nationals, including United States citizens, and which took nearly 200 people into Gaza as hostages.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5620655FB887417F9B1C8168876609AA"><enum>(46)</enum><text>The Congress supports Israel’s defensive military campaign against Hamas and its stated goals to destroy Hamas, secure the return of all hostages, and prevent such an attack from ever happening again.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90AAAB3F445D4E158991D3319E821BAC"><enum>(47)</enum><text>Additionally, Hezbollah’s escalation of rocket, drone, and missile attacks against northern Israel following the October 7, 2023, Hamas attack displaced tens of thousands of Israeli civilians and posed an ongoing threat to regional stability.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FA59EF479254F749877109B5F72DE51"><enum>(48)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Israel’s efforts to neutralize Hezbollah’s command structure was a critical step in countering Iran’s malign influence through its proxy networks, consistent with shared United States-Israel strategic objectives to combat terrorism and promote security in the Middle East.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCE6648D16084B1CA6EA5EF84D3DDC31"><enum>(49)</enum><text>Israel’s precision airstrikes in September 2024, which resulted in the liquidation of Hassan Nasrallah, Secretary-General of Hezbollah, and other senior commanders in Beirut, effectively disrupted the operational capacity of this Iran-backed terrorist organization, responsible for over 300 projectile attacks on Israel since October 2023, and recognizes these actions as advancing shared United States-Israel goals of regional stability and counterterrorism.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H980CF9576F53440BABF6FDD613D899D9"><enum>(50)</enum><text>Taking advantage of the situation, Ansar Allah (the Houthis), an Iran-backed militant group, conducted over 100 attacks on commercial vessels and U.S. Navy warships in the Red Sea and Gulf of Aden since November 2023, endangering American personnel, disrupting global trade, and threatening freedom of navigation through critical maritime chokepoints such as the Bab al-Mandab Strait.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE693DBCE1BC441CABBE1928731E1AFF7"><enum>(51)</enum><text>President Trump’s authorization of large-scale air and naval strikes on March 15, 2025, against Ansar Allah (the Houthis) in Yemen, targeting their missile, drone, and radar capabilities, was a necessary and justified response to the Houthi attacks on United States Navy warships and commercial vessels in the Red Sea since November 2023, and supports these actions as vital to protecting American lives, securing maritime trade routes, and countering Iran-backed terrorism.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC3003ED57274B0CB01B67B8D9EDD0AC"><enum>(52)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">National Security Presidential Memorandum 2 (NSPM–2), issued by President Donald J. Trump on February 4, 2025, strengthens United States policy by directing maximum economic and diplomatic pressure on Iran to halt its support for terrorist proxies like Ansar Allah and Hezbollah, and supports this memorandum as a critical framework for denying Iran the resources to threaten United States interests and allies in the Middle East.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H54631634206F4BE0ABCCB44306712DD3"><enum>(53)</enum><text>Iran and its proxies have planned, directed, sponsored, and funded terrorist plots throughout the world and on United States soil, including the October 2023, mass murder and hostage-taking of Israeli civilians by Hamas and the killing of at least 31 United States citizens in that attack, the 2011 attempted assassination of the Saudi Arabian Ambassador to the United States in Washington, DC, the 1994 bombing of the Asociacion Mutual Israelita Argentina in Buenos Aires, Argentina, which killed over 85 people, and the 2012 bus bombing in Burgas, Bulgaria, which killed 5 Israelis.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H960B5E2931734C35B576C4CAA0040D54"><enum>(54)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">NSPM–2 is a vital component of United States national security strategy, recognizing that Iran’s Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) and Quds Force have armed, trained, and directed Ansar Allah and Hezbollah, contributing to attacks on United States forces, allies, and international shipping.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A61F43288C84C95AEA4F4D1AB036322"><enum>(55)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">NSPM–2 enhances the effectiveness of military actions against Iran’s proxies, such as the strikes on Ansar Allah and Israel’s operations against Hezbollah, by addressing the root source of their funding and logistical support, thereby advancing United States interests in a stable and secure Middle East.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H03698ED2B6C94244A6C79CA42B54727B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on Iranian responsibility for Hamas terror attacks on October
 7, 2023</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H9EF21E636FF649C996937C3E7AE79877"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Iran is clearly culpable for Hamas’ terrorist attack against Israel on October 7, 2023, as a result of its funding, training, and coordination of Hamas and other terrorist organizations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3A70AD9491C41ABBFADFA9B0EF3204B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any funds directly or indirectly released to Iran, or funds freed up by the expectation of the imminent release of those funds, benefit Iran’s terrorist proxies like Hamas and Hezbollah and encourage further acts of terrorism;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD1046D8A5844663A1454AFAB50B13C8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>all funds previously released to Iran be immediately frozen and that all licenses and waivers allowing funding to directly or indirectly flow to Iran be suspended immediately; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03A79AD9E054467CA90C0056BB921E98"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the only suitable punishment for Iran’s participation in and organization of this mass murder is for the United States to halt its appeasement of the Iranian regime and to return to a policy of maximum pressure.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H8357E840AD1247D5BB74C10B81138F1F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States as follows:</text><paragraph id="H465FD59E121C4210815A57894B6D4038"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To deny Iran all paths to a nuclear weapon and intercontinental ballistic missiles capability, including by permanently, verifiably, and irreversibly eliminating its capabilities related to enrichment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H262C979A222A4EBC93F24C2F4FD50136"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To deter and defeat any attempts by Iran and its terrorist proxies to destroy the State of Israel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FE7DDA3347647B7A808C0D59E097863"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To roll back the totality of Iran’s malign influence and activities in the Middle East.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0AA6284D30441B58999B5614670F8D6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To support the human rights of the people of Iran and to encourage their continued opposition to their illegitimate and brutal regime.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2882190E241B4488B07BE7C31527429C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To require that any new agreement with Iran should be submitted to the Senate for ratification as a treaty.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0741FEEBAF794626A0D2364648618A8F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To impose maximum economic pressure on Iran, and keep all sanctions in place on Iran, until the regime fulfills the following 12 demands laid out by former Secretary of State Pompeo on May 21, 2018:</text><subparagraph id="H8351FB7D908142618747A69FB0D8F2B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Iran must declare to the International Atomic Energy Agency a full account of the prior military dimensions of its nuclear program, and permanently and verifiably abandon such work in perpetuity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAEFE00E2D084DFC946BAE5E33003388"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Iran must stop enrichment and never pursue plutonium reprocessing, including closing its heavy water reactor.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5825B54CD89543658EB072C1616B15DB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Iran must also provide the International Atomic Energy Agency with unqualified access to all sites throughout the entire country.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB728B866955A4B61932825B6F5283C36"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Iran must end its proliferation of ballistic missiles and halt further launching or development of nuclear-capable missile systems.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56B4FDD797654F428BE01E79EE0EC5F1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Iran must release all United States citizens as well as citizens of United States partners and allies, each of them detained on spurious charges.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6700F83B16DE4F63854FB5D6021527E8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Iran must end its support for terrorism, including Hezbollah, Hamas and Palestinian Islamic Jihad.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6665E11671B4A01845ADF557CD87E1A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Iran must respect the sovereignty of the Iraqi Government and permit the disarming, demobilization and reintegration of Iranian backed militias.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA465E52CC1A421599EA324F10843400"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Iran must end its military support for the Houthi terrorists and work towards a peaceful, political settlement in Yemen.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0312B71FF033447CB40626B91FA5E81E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Iran must withdraw all forces under Iranian command throughout the entirety of Syria.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB520A4F9F944C508E8390F598AED65A"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Iran must end support for the Taliban and other terrorists in Afghanistan and the region and cease harboring senior al-Qaeda leaders.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A91F0045AB94135A4A0EDC9B787D182"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Iran must end the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps’ support for terrorists around the world.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DC311999AE94BE9B76CE1181BA7DA75"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Iran must end its threatening behavior against its neighbors including its threats to destroy Israel and its firing of missiles at Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates, and threats to international shipping and destructive cyberattacks.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HA0FED7F26E7C48B8A38CA61AF19C5B87"><enum>5.</enum><header>Codification of united states policy</header><subsection id="HD01605EF374F414E86BB6587AF9C025A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>United states policy</header><text>The United States, in 2025, declared through National Security Presidential Memorandum 2 (NSPM–2), issued by President Donald J. Trump on February 4, 2025, and has reaffirmed since, that <quote>The United States will pursue a policy of maximum economic and diplomatic pressure on the Iranian regime to deny it all paths to a nuclear weapon, curtail its ballistic missile program, and counter its support for terrorist proxies, including but not limited to Ansar Allah and Hezbollah, until such time as Iran ceases its malign activities and complies with international obligations under the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons and relevant United Nations Security Council resolutions</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H73361F7301314D70AB68894B708A9997"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reaffirmation and codification of policy</header><text>The United States hereby reaffirms that policy. In accordance with NSPM–2, no officer or employee of the United States Government and no agent or other individual acting on behalf of the United States Government shall provide sanctions relief to, rescind or otherwise fail to enforce sanctions against the Government of Iran, the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC), or any representatives thereof (except in emergency or humanitarian situations) unless and until Iran ceases its support for international terrorism, halts its ballistic missile development, and verifiably dismantles its nuclear weapons program, and no funds authorized to be appropriated by this or any other Act may be obligated or made available for the conduct of any dialogue or engagement with Iranian officials or entities if the President knows and advises the Congress that such officials or entities directly participated in the planning or execution of a particular terrorist activity which resulted in the death or kidnapping of a United States person.</text></subsection></section><section id="H445D2AD290F64130BFC31362E4BDD55E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such provision or amendment to any person or circumstance, is held to be invalid, the remainder of this Act, the amendments made by this Act, and the application of such provision and amendments to other persons or circumstances, shall not be affected.</text></section><title id="H15811D54CEAB46F6A3E65529BA815D09" commented="no"><enum>I</enum><header>Matters Relating to Sanctions and Sanction Authorities</header><section id="HC07F869C0D4E4DDA95640644489C891D" commented="no"><enum>101.</enum><header>Codification of executive orders and continuation of certain existing
 sanctions</header><subsection id="H1B265E4ADDB344BCBB5355BC9824F5E9" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Codification</header><text>Executive Orders 13606, 13628, 13846, 13871, 13876, 13902, and 13949, as in effect on January 20, 2021, shall remain in effect and continue to apply until the date on which the President submits a certification to Congress pursuant to section 8 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note), as amended by this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H98234CA7CB8946DDBFDC9E30E967D8C5" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on removal of persons from SDN list</header><text>The President may not remove the following individuals or entities from the Specially Designated Nationals and Blocked Persons list maintained by the Office of Foreign Asset Control of the Department of the Treasury, if such persons were placed on such list during the period beginning on May 8, 2019, and ending January 20, 2021, unless the President submits a certification to Congress pursuant to section 8 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) as amended by this Act:</text><paragraph id="H0D7C1E6E8B2C4A26A43923EB334C787F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any Iranian individual or entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98D921FAAB6A410C876DC60530C3D3C9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any individual or entity included in such list as a result of activities connected to Iran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AE0DA6FC7A841CB80C04DBD6C2CA2CC" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Asa’iab ahl al-Haq, Zainabiyoun, Fatemiyoun, and Harakat Hezbollah al-Nujaba.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H664630BA7872435BB425AB2FAC3F38E7" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reimposition of sanctions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any sanctions imposed during the period beginning on May 8, 2019, and ending January 20, 2021, with respect to any person described in subsection (b)(1) or (b)(2), and subsequently lifted before the date of the enactment of this Act, shall be reimposed with respect to such persons beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and shall remain in effect until the date on which the President submits a certification to Congress pursuant to section 8 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) as amended by this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5767D91AC50046C09B5FCA43F577C899" commented="no"><enum>102.</enum><header>Sanctions with respect to the Supreme Leader of Iran</header><subsection id="HA517D3A3EFD642D4B61226C676239933" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to the following individuals:</text><paragraph id="H9E70CE58B31F49D7A03D7C84F17F4180" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Supreme Leader of the Islamic Republic of Iran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F12B6DF007D4FD8A501E8261C17AFDA" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other officials in the Office of the Supreme Leader of the Islamic Republic of Iran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD25DD3D54ED64017A6FFD95B9B76537D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any person appointed by the Supreme Leader of Iran or the Supreme Leader’s Office to a position as—</text><subparagraph id="HB592903D288F4B3BAA446C2FDE8C3DED" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a state official of Iran;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB85D7B990464004961EF4D4210035DC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as the head of an entity located in Iran; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1718DF2113AB4FA58C894D5BFE870D63" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>as the head of an entity located outside of Iran that is owned or controlled by 1 or more entities in Iran.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA937C5A07D3D4566A76809CB91D26BB4" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any person appointed to a position described in subparagraphs (A) through (C) of paragraph (3) by a person described in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BF485BEFBB8450A86C499EC7429C1CD" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any person the President determines has materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to or in support of any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7501841D25874FAB8FC2D8855707B098" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any person the President determines is owned or controlled by, or to have acted or purported to act for or on behalf of, directly or indirectly, any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F933DFBE0C941429B8EE41B8A7212DB" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any person the President determines conducts a significant transaction or transactions with, or provides material support to or for anyone described in paragraphs (1) through (6).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC22E0119DC8940578893FA5B67123253" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Any person who is a member of the board of directors or a senior executive officer of any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1B76F055B8949A6BA1C13D6D3E696C1" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who is an immediate family member of each foreign person who is subject to sanctions pursuant to paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9ED022B7EA0043EBAB9CE1AB631C2C9A" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><paragraph id="HB19314AC4BE54C228B62EF87D8EC66D6" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text><subparagraph id="H1603158138F441E3AAE72004B45C34F4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>The President shall exercise all of the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of the foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68570D7650754DDD85EE58E1491D6949" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Aliens ineligible for visas, admission, or parole</header><clause id="H67273AF7E52F439D85D49B00B3572924" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien who the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) knows, or has reason to believe, has knowingly engaged in any activity described in subsection (a)(2) is—</text><subclause id="H2299EC02A2854E0D8606C9B13228F972" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></subclause><subclause id="H46BC2070ECF045748D5A2CEFF8001611" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H31455F38CEEC49E9B779272370818D4B" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H1CFB3CAE10B945A38A63C3FFEDA95AEC" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><subclause id="HEFD2F81327E845F995E63C4C4D9D67BF" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The issuing consular officer, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) shall, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>), revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to an alien described in clause (i) regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is issued.</text></subclause><subclause id="H03BAF6E39DDE4730AF940D369B495A9F" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A revocation under subclause (I) shall take effect immediately and shall automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA25A4483729F4AC981FCD8A3687B6AE4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><subparagraph id="H0F4E66DE9B644C9887E3FFE86D7DCB21" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>UN headquarters agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sanctions described under paragraph (1)(B) shall not apply with respect to an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB90CE69637534D09BFE8C6B6A9482C78" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prior transfer directive</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sanctions described under paragraph (1)(A) shall not apply with respect to property and interests in property of the Government of Iran that were blocked pursuant to Executive Order 12170 of November 14, 1979 (Blocking Iranian Government Property), and thereafter made subject to the transfer directives set forth in Executive Order 12281 of January 19, 1981 (Direction to Transfer Certain Iranian Government Assets), and any implementing regulations with respect to such Executive Order 12281.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD03BB41D64EC46719C38781E85A4A6D6" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Humanitarian exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sanctions described under paragraph (1)(B) and (1)(A) shall not apply with respect to any person for conducting or facilitating a transaction for the provision (including any sale) of agricultural commodities, food, medicine, or medical devices to Iran.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4B71783323A34FD78B72B8DAD2035E3B" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to a person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of regulations promulgated to carry out this section or the sanctions imposed pursuant to this section to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in section 206(a) of that Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA3FABC28F61145A9BE334595B88A4736" commented="no"><enum>103.</enum><header>Sanctions with respect to listed persons involved in international arms
 sales to Iran</header><subsection id="H3159D6C38C5F40549CF2D99B25411DA3" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header><paragraph id="HF43776BB6F34476AA3B3758B642CC7FA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, the President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to each foreign person the President determines, on or after such date of enactment, engages in an activity described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDA69F5B1C93443F97EE9A8B31014B28" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activity described</header><text>An activity described in this paragraph is any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H77D370BBB59E47A0A9BE9D2ED08476B3" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any activity that may contribute to the supply, sale, or transfer, directly or indirectly, to or from Iran, or for the use in or benefit of Iran, of arms or related materiel, including spare parts.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0213B3A816604E7C8F787C8BD0269ECA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The provision to the Government of Iran any technical training, financial resources or services, advice, other services, or assistance related to the supply, sale, transfer, manufacture, maintenance, or use of arms and related materiel described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B39F986EC2144C0B6A62C697BADE480" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any activity that may contribute to, or poses a risk of materially contributing to, the proliferation of arms or related materiel or items intended for military end-uses or military end-users, including any efforts to manufacture, acquire, possess, develop, transport, transfer, or use such items, by the Government of Iran (including persons owned or controlled by, or acting for or on behalf of the Government of Iran) or paramilitary organizations financially or militarily supported by the Government of Iran.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C20A5D8A51147A2A9BFFB3E224E9244" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Materially assisting, sponsoring, or providing financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to or in support of, any person that engages in the conduct described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H961412726469493FA9F4309CF2CF9C4B" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Making any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services by, to, or for the benefit of any person that engages in the conduct described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C04B26BE3EB498D826042CCDC5F6431" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Receiving any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services from any person that engages in the conduct described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H446C210B49AB4788BDE5AA64F60962F3" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Owning or controlling, or acting or purporting to act for or on behalf of, directly or indirectly, any person that engages in the conduct described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), (E), or (F).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H14237F92F15F41D6AD2AD99865899DB8" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><paragraph id="H5CBCA99F3B2D40FB95EBE563833378E9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text><subparagraph id="HFA213B65CCE84189A0F635B7DA3CEA5B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>The President shall exercise all of the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of the foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08FA2865F57C44C0AF080DF6C2D06FB1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Aliens ineligible for visas, admission, or parole</header><clause id="H86DCBEAE47BC4EC69C02B066FA07E2A3" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien who the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) knows, or has reason to believe, has knowingly engaged in any activity described in subsection (a)(2) is—</text><subclause id="H3A95902E1A9042ED8D83E8109A2937A3" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></subclause><subclause id="H06B779430D714DD481400FCCE81C45EA" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H57E3FD3DF96541A0B84DE91B5E0DDCB5" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H2F51CBB451874200B2F95BACEC01BC41" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><subclause id="H2AE287EC282049898769883E344B68DA" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The issuing consular officer, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) shall, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>), revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to an alien described in clause (i) regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is issued.</text></subclause><subclause id="H039E46768F4C4F9180FBF6C88C68B853" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A revocation under subclause (I) shall take effect immediately and shall automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H050FF450CC4646DE9EEDE195463DC189" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><subparagraph id="H73D5AE21FEDF4B08A29997E37986F9FC" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>UN headquarters agreement</header><text>The sanctions described under paragraph (1)(B) shall not apply with respect to an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4F39B12302F4468BB8DF54E10FC4FE4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prior transfer directive</header><text>The sanctions described under paragraph (1)(A) shall not apply with respect to property and interests in property of the Government of Iran that were blocked pursuant to Executive Order 12170 of November 14, 1979 (Blocking Iranian Government Property), and thereafter made subject to the transfer directives set forth in Executive Order 12281 of January 19, 1981 (Direction to Transfer Certain Iranian Government Assets), and any implementing regulations with respect to such Executive Order 12281.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD47E414BD7140558F62AB555E285046" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Humanitarian exception</header><text>The sanctions described under paragraph (1)(B) and (1)(A) shall not apply with respect to any person for conducting or facilitating a transaction for the provision (including any sale) of agricultural commodities, food, medicine, or medical devices to Iran.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB55E97CDEDB04A0E984E2ECA3AB8112E" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to a person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of regulations promulgated to carry out this section or the sanctions imposed pursuant to this section to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in section 206(a) of that Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H19B727ADC22A4B3F994CF5A947C58BA8" commented="no"><enum>104.</enum><header>Additional conditions for termination and elimination of sunset of sanctions
 under the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996</header><subsection id="H54E31BB849BF4664B7136816C3C89ED7" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Termination conditions</header><text>Section 8 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H2660AEE9128546D391D9BAFF95B9EED5" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The requirement</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection"><enum-in-header>(a)</enum-in-header> In general.—</header-in-text>The requirement</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFE6BFA8543B4F449300B6BCCEAE58BF" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HA8BFC6ED74B44F27AC54B97D42976B70" style="OLC"><subsection id="HAF6E1D04DFE84D4C8437BB449C0F70E7" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional conditions for termination</header><text>In addition to the requirement under subsection (a), sanctions imposed under section 5(a) shall remain in effect unless the President determines and certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that Iran has complied with each of the following:</text><paragraph id="HA54C6E18981442A0BD1E15F860998DBD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Declared to the International Atomic Energy Agency a full account of the prior military dimensions of its nuclear program and permanently and verifiably abandons such work in perpetuity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3B1EB792A1043A99E97BE078CBB8F66" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Stopped enrichment of and never returns to plutonium reprocessing, including by closing its heavy water reactor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39544EBF52B845469DD590C91E5476CE" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Provided the International Atomic Energy Agency with unqualified access to all sites throughout the entire country.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D9A25CFF279430F8C0233644D442A50" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Ended its proliferation of ballistic missiles and halts further launching or development of nuclear-capable missile systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04039BCBFD034A7BAD39CAC21C86AA6A" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Released all United States citizens, as well as citizens of United States partners and allies, that are unjustly detained and held captive in Iran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6717B22DA5AE45C1986C2BAEE1CB15B3" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Respected the sovereignty of the Government of Iraq through no longer preventing, hindering, or disrupting any efforts by that Government with regard to the disarming, demobilization and reintegration of Iranian-backed militias in Iraq.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FA811209B5A4D63A9C100BAD8BEDB44" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Ended its military support for the Houthi militia (Ansarallah) and worked towards a peaceful, political settlement in Yemen.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H587A1BA260E6428C8C8E2F299336F564" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Withdrawn all forces under Iran’s command throughout the entirety of Syria.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF001E96D88294EE2ACBB93F0F8C53E9E" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Ended support for the Taliban and other terrorists in Afghanistan and the region and ceased to harbor senior al-Qaeda leaders.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCCC1C74937D4780A73CF34F804D7D8A" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Ended the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps’ Quds Force’s support for terrorists around the world.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H723B3580E0314549BF7B63150A3C2916" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Ended its threatening behavior against its neighbors, including its threats to destroy Israel and its firing of missiles at Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates, threats to international shipping, and destructive cyberattacks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEB076F06DA143829BA65D4709D5BBEE" commented="no"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Ceased violently attacking and killing peaceful protesters in Iran, and provided a full accounting for the 1500 peaceful protesters reported to be killed in November 2019 when fired upon by Iranian security forces.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2EBD49794F994EBC926E77E029EFE919" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elimination of sunset</header><text>Section 13 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is repealed.</text></subsection></section><section id="H89182DF122104CE6B0C2196DDBC54725" commented="no"><enum>105.</enum><header>Sectoral sanctions on Iran under the Iran Freedom and Counter-Proliferation
 Act of 2012</header><subsection id="HA9BB27E44DB647DBA99A2EB5122AD27E" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments with respect to covered sectors</header><paragraph id="HCB1FA73EBF8549C59CD642DB405A0AC8" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subsection (b) of section 1244 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8803">22 U.S.C. 8803</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>iron, steel, aluminum, copper, construction, manufacturing, mining, textile, petrochemical, automotive, financial</quote> after <quote>energy,</quote> each place it appears.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5DC142F230A43249C7ADC1D8AC8C4F1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Subsection (c) of such section 1244 is amended by inserting <quote>iron, steel, aluminum, copper, construction, manufacturing, mining, textile, petrochemical, automotive, financial</quote> after <quote>energy,</quote> each place it appears.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5D1845661114FC6A78BD0F4FEE2F63B" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendment with respect To waiver authority</header><text>Subsection (i) of such section 1244 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H6EEDFF727E8B458B837DD4CCE6C7693A" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H50BB3F0E34E94AA6B776C3CD183EC6EF" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The authority to issue a waiver under this section shall terminate on the date that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of this paragraph.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H6F12CB5ABFBD405B9CE91A4B0A29E815" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination of certain waivers of sanctions with respect to nuclear
 activities in or with Iran</header><paragraph id="HE8FFE7EC643E442E9FF15892C0533A4F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Suspension of waiver authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may not issue any waiver of the application of sanctions provided for under any of sections 1244 through 1247 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 (22 U.S.C. 8803 through 8806), or provided to enable an activity described in paragraph (2), before February 1, 2028.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AA831253F934891B3B2736D37D40760" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Existing waivers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As of the date of the enactment of this Act, any waiver of the application of sanctions provided for under any of sections 1244 through 1247 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 (22 U.S.C. 8803 through 8806), or provided to enable an activity described in paragraph (2), is terminated.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H513DCEFD698943369B444B5A8E4DBA62" commented="no"><enum>106.</enum><header>Amendments to the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and
                    Divestment Act of 2010</header><subsection id="H91095152129D45C2B88F2A66D7247D24" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Listing of Iranian Persons for Human Rights Abuses Committed in Other
 Countries</header><text>Section 105(b)(1) of the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8514">22 U.S.C. 8514</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, or against the people of Iraq, Syria, Lebanon, Yemen, or Venezuela</quote> before the period at the end.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE0433051221045E7956B7402EDF04A35" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendments to criteria for termination</header><text>Section 401 of the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H4835C645130F41C39B90EA55FA770263" style="OLC"><subsection id="HD4DE6E68D4C441CDA2C754E79C796A29" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional matters To be certified</header><text>The certification described in subsection (a) shall also include a certification that Iran has complied with each of the following:</text><paragraph id="H280C6572AF1648498BE759C5AFAE878A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Declared to the International Atomic Energy Agency a full account of the prior military dimensions of its nuclear program and permanently and verifiably abandons such work in perpetuity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H254BE0FE53E34251937E7C85F01970A3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Stopped enrichment of and never returns to plutonium reprocessing, including by closing its heavy water reactor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H819E812C1F9C4DAEAE8EEAD2B9DA3551" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Provided the International Atomic Energy Agency with unqualified access to all sites throughout the entire country.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B1D62E2975D4CE7B04D98CAC852E4FF" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Ended its proliferation of ballistic missiles and halts further launching or development of nuclear-capable missile systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9E0E81FE86C4AA1A6223C84085B8AB3" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Released all United States citizens, as well as citizens of United States partners and allies, that are unjustly detained and held captive in Iran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE130E1FED2D64FDBAC0AB5E060D5C721" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Respected the sovereignty of the Government of Iraq through no longer preventing, hindering, or disrupting any efforts by that Government with regard to the disarming, demobilization and reintegration of Iranian-backed militias in Iraq.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8EA5BA413E644664A1382F6DDE7602F5" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Ended its military support for the Houthi militia (Ansarallah) and worked towards a peaceful, political settlement in Yemen.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4731EB04FE90420DA4E1C5F5686B62A7" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Withdrawn all forces under Iran’s command throughout the entirety of Syria.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H489F8AA6AF38415C9892E809FA65F7D2" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Ended support for the Taliban and other terrorists in Afghanistan and the region and ceased to harbor senior al-Qaeda leaders.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46B1B0CAF2224F2CACE21AECD78FE907" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Ended the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps’ Quds Force’s support for terrorists around the world.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H198AFB028FD5416EADEBEDE96F7A2B47" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Ended its threatening behavior against its neighbors, including its threats to destroy Israel and its firing of missiles at Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates, threats to international shipping, and destructive cyberattacks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69FCFDC92273453185F048FF5638E8DA" commented="no"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Ceased violently attacking and killing peaceful protesters in Iran, and provided a full accounting for the 1500 peaceful protesters reported to be killed in November 2019 when fired upon by Iranian security forces.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD56F6F2C06DA420CB1C89D1F43CA354C" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination of waiver authority</header><text>The authority to issue a waiver under this section shall terminate on the date that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HDA83C1C1776B454790A53BE95805916A" commented="no"><enum>107.</enum><header>Congressional review of certain actions relating to sanctions imposed with
 respect to Iran</header><subsection id="H3643C8D99E814EF187930B16F69D0426" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Submission to congress of proposed action</header><paragraph id="HB6B6A6006E014B1FA8D846A679D968DC" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, before taking any action described in paragraph (2), the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and leadership a report that—</text><subparagraph id="H8D03A31600F64D93AFD30793E0DC3575" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describes the proposed action and the reasons for that action; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCA51529B0BC46D385FD82557DFD49A6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a certification with respect to each foreign person subject to the sanction proposed to be terminated by such action that the person has not committed any activity during the 10-year period ending on the date of the submission of the report that would meet the criteria for the imposition of such sanction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E62659FA7734E10A8C9C4A8CA766419" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Actions described</header><subparagraph id="H21E35016ABF441EA8906C890645FBF77" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An action described in this paragraph is—</text><clause id="H5DFF00B7883B4040A6A9C0A692075F8F" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an action to terminate the application of any sanctions described in subparagraph (B);</text></clause><clause id="H0A651B102F1F46DCB28F0BF2D77FC77E" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to sanctions described in subparagraph (B) imposed by the President with respect to a person, an action to waive the application of those sanctions with respect to that person; or</text></clause><clause id="H140C2D2D31FE4326B83F9314ECC67510" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a licensing action that significantly alters United States foreign policy with respect to Iran.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDA1F7BB08634B67AE73E5DEB08A0AF9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions described in this subparagraph are sanctions with respect to Iran provided for under—</text><clause id="H8333396EEFCB4E2F84AC34D14D75CD0D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note);</text></clause><clause id="HBD8663C15278495C91863CC8C4ACC292" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8501">22 U.S.C. 8501 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="H0E01C597CE3C40B38EA25351D76276C8" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>section 1245 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8513a">22 U.S.C. 8513a</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="H1678CA4F427049DC83CE3A721A86551B" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8701">22 U.S.C. 8701 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="HD30EBBE2C5A04FA8ACBAFAF7113423B2" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the Iran Freedom and Counter-Proliferation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8801">22 U.S.C. 8801 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="H5D110FF762F04E329D96418A94AD43FC" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note); or</text></clause><clause id="H5EE58518B2B44B278C10192C2685D333" commented="no"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>any other statute or Executive order that requires or authorizes the imposition of sanctions with respect to Iran.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H579E251209F84324A34D3DC72E22FF71" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Description of type of action</header><text>Each report submitted under paragraph (1) with respect to an action described in paragraph (2) shall include a description of whether the action—</text><subparagraph id="H575B270DA89348F48EDB1DC59D38DE50" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not intended to significantly alter United States foreign policy with respect to Iran; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD221AD87F70B4FC780E6E3CD96F3BC4C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is intended to significantly alter United States foreign policy with respect to Iran.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0EA3C8B71164C23A87E802775E25CDB" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Inclusion of additional matter</header><subparagraph id="HF30C7DDC8D644A939736AFD02374F4D7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each report submitted under paragraph (1) that relates to an action that is intended to significantly alter United States foreign policy with respect to Iran shall include a description of—</text><clause id="HEDA3C55B687249B98FF29A3D9EA979AD" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the significant alteration to United States foreign policy with respect to Iran;</text></clause><clause id="H805EC0091EA54A3B8713C269B9A8922F" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the anticipated effect of the action on the national security interests of the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="HA15BB28E8EFA412384FA381B576B89E3" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the policy objectives for which the sanctions affected by the action were initially imposed.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEC7F436F80A4DF68BC3397E8CF7E273" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requests from banking and financial services committees</header><text>The Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate or the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives may request the submission to the Committee of the matter described in clauses (ii) and (iii) of subparagraph (A) with respect to a report submitted under paragraph (1) that relates to an action that is not intended to significantly alter United States foreign policy with respect to Iran.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C23BE8E0DAB4039BAA4BF3BDD1B8701" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Confidentiality of proprietary information</header><text>Proprietary information that can be associated with a particular person with respect to an action described in paragraph (2) may be included in a report submitted under paragraph (1) only if the appropriate congressional committees and leadership provide assurances of confidentiality, unless that person otherwise consents in writing to such disclosure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11B2D011A9E2463EBA4F35AE1108F6E1" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Paragraph (2)(A)(iii) shall not be construed to require the submission of a report under paragraph (1) with respect to the routine issuance of a license that does not significantly alter United States foreign policy with respect to Iran.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0A9FF697F7AF410FA80A0FD804340767" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Period for review by congress</header><paragraph id="HE30DAC5498F9446994CBA5B66B20E601" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the period of 30 calendar days beginning on the date on which the President submits a report under subsection (a)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="H49619EAE3CBE410BBF7CB5A2F1860A6A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a report that relates to an action that is not intended to significantly alter United States foreign policy with respect to Iran, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives should, as appropriate, hold hearings and briefings and otherwise obtain information in order to fully review the report; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9F5D1AAF8854CCBBA9989B034AFA86D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a report that relates to an action that is intended to significantly alter United States foreign policy with respect to Iran, the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives should, as appropriate, hold hearings and briefings and otherwise obtain information in order to fully review the report.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H89A84A5ABE68479AB9A6232D5D9EC37F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The period for congressional review under paragraph (1) of a report required to be submitted under subsection (a)(1) shall be 60 calendar days if the report is submitted on or after July 10 and on or before September 7 in any calendar year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BD8EF087CA04B5CA1F3BBB8DF5B7145" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on actions during initial congressional review
 period</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, during the period for congressional review provided for under paragraph (1) of a report submitted under subsection (a)(1) proposing an action described in subsection (a)(2), including any additional period for such review as applicable under the exception provided in paragraph (2), the President may not take that action unless a joint resolution of approval with respect to that action is enacted in accordance with subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DA0C90F42D341B2897586466AC07761" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation on actions during presidential consideration of a joint
 resolution of disapproval</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if a joint resolution of disapproval relating to a report submitted under subsection (a)(1) proposing an action described in subsection (a)(2) passes both Houses of Congress in accordance with subsection (c), the President may not take that action for a period of 12 calendar days after the date of passage of the joint resolution of disapproval.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC6DAF80926E490798A67698C495F404" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitation on actions during congressional reconsideration of a
 joint resolution of disapproval</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if a joint resolution of disapproval relating to a report submitted under subsection (a)(1) proposing an action described in subsection (a)(2) passes both Houses of Congress in accordance with subsection (c), and the President vetoes the joint resolution, the President may not take that action for a period of 10 calendar days after the date of the President’s veto.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B58F6FA70084F698CD592BF1D6064E5" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Effect of enactment of a joint resolution of disapproval</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if a joint resolution of disapproval relating to a report submitted under subsection (a)(1) proposing an action described in subsection (a)(2) is enacted in accordance with subsection (c), the President may not take that action.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEBEE6028542947759CA615DEE8AB5B5B" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Joint resolutions of disapproval or approval</header><paragraph id="HE136993EDE9849E6B9BEDAAABEE3694D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H85E3E4C677AA4C60A5DB455899C8FC3B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Joint resolution of approval</header><text>The term <term>joint resolution of approval</term> means only a joint resolution of either House of Congress—</text><clause id="HA67300B74CE14C1480B1DB1914756CD0" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the title of which is as follows: <quote>A joint resolution approving the President’s proposal to take an action relating to the application of certain sanctions with respect to Iran.</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HDB8A998498DF4AE1A8CA988537A5C661" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the sole matter after the resolving clause of which is the following: <quote>Congress approves of the action relating to the application of sanctions imposed with respect to Iran proposed by the President in the report submitted to Congress under section 2(a)(1) of the Iran Sanctions Relief Review Act of 2021 on _______ relating to ________.</quote>, with the first blank space being filled with the appropriate date and the second blank space being filled with a short description of the proposed action.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEF3279DAE4F47728D1D611B732319C1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Joint resolution of disapproval</header><text>The term <term>joint resolution of disapproval</term> means only a joint resolution of either House of Congress—</text><clause id="H9AC2DF55C4ED4039BEA3B40D54473B2B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the title of which is as follows: <quote>A joint resolution disapproving the President’s proposal to take an action relating to the application of certain sanctions with respect to Iran.</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HC9C57387C55C486DB0B1CEA6FFAA07A9" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the sole matter after the resolving clause of which is the following: <quote>Congress disapproves of the action relating to the application of sanctions imposed with respect to Iran proposed by the President in the report submitted to Congress under section 2(a)(1) of the Iran Sanctions Relief Review Act of 2021 on _______ relating to ________.</quote>, with the first blank space being filled with the appropriate date and the second blank space being filled with a short description of the proposed action.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEF94E1BBEE742AC99076C0F45B64E1A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Introduction</header><text>During the period of 30 calendar days provided for under subsection (b)(1), including any additional period as applicable under the exception provided in subsection (b)(2), a joint resolution of approval or joint resolution of disapproval may be introduced—</text><subparagraph id="H59C0891EA4AA4BA48E1630FB1CBDEE7C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the House of Representatives, by the majority leader or the minority leader; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C712C1DE05E43B3891388446667D6D6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the Senate, by the majority leader (or the majority leader’s designee) or the minority leader (or the minority leader’s designee).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H401B249E357743918B726635813F4F43" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Floor consideration in house of representatives</header><text>If a committee of the House of Representatives to which a joint resolution of approval or joint resolution of disapproval has been referred has not reported the joint resolution within 10 calendar days after the date of referral, that committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68C7D2C3B3A44400840E98D09219AFF9" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consideration in the senate</header><subparagraph id="H538F185D8DAD4984A0304C09CEAC744B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Committee referral</header><text>A joint resolution of approval or joint resolution of disapproval introduced in the Senate shall be—</text><clause id="H7CF8C69816554FB48891AA3FBA19752E" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs if the joint resolution relates to a report under subsection (a)(3)(A) that relates to an action that is not intended to significantly alter United States foreign policy with respect to Iran; and</text></clause><clause id="HBCD1833A52AB40719F56A211E410064C" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations if the joint resolution relates to a report under subsection (a)(3)(B) that relates to an action that is intended to significantly alter United States foreign policy with respect to Iran.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFCAEF378872472A8B0C74044140246F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reporting and discharge</header><text>If the committee to which a joint resolution of approval or joint resolution of disapproval was referred has not reported the joint resolution within 10 calendar days after the date of referral of the joint resolution, that committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution and the joint resolution shall be placed on the appropriate calendar.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H020F83ADB2DF4C0BA0A5E73FAE1CCC1C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Proceeding to consideration</header><text>Notwithstanding Rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, it is in order at any time after the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs or the Committee on Foreign Relations, as the case may be, reports a joint resolution of approval or joint resolution of disapproval to the Senate or has been discharged from consideration of such a joint resolution (even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to) to move to proceed to the consideration of the joint resolution, and all points of order against the joint resolution (and against consideration of the joint resolution) are waived. The motion to proceed is not debatable. The motion is not subject to a motion to postpone. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FA69DB1827648ECB7D4976F077F37F4" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Rulings of the chair on procedure</header><text>Appeals from the decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the Senate, as the case may be, to the procedure relating to a joint resolution of approval or joint resolution of disapproval shall be decided without debate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61438A7AE70B441D8BD5A6A3CFCF5543" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Consideration of veto messages</header><text>Debate in the Senate of any veto message with respect to a joint resolution of approval or joint resolution of disapproval, including all debatable motions and appeals in connection with the joint resolution, shall be limited to 10 hours, to be equally divided between, and controlled by, the majority leader and the minority leader or their designees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE860D7B31310452BA17BE613150E40E0" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rules relating to senate and house of representatives</header><subparagraph id="H44B9B01ABA8D49419D4F963A4B452A3C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Treatment of senate joint resolution in house</header><text>In the House of Representatives, the following procedures shall apply to a joint resolution of approval or a joint resolution of disapproval received from the Senate (unless the House has already passed a joint resolution relating to the same proposed action):</text><clause id="H15688478E2BD4A12BB741DB645C62353" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The joint resolution shall be referred to the appropriate committees.</text></clause><clause id="HD07C7844D94441349F2BAE6F1DE93707" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>If a committee to which a joint resolution has been referred has not reported the joint resolution within 2 calendar days after the date of referral, that committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution.</text></clause><clause id="H932EF1C84C61458481214EE9ACBF7131" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Beginning on the third legislative day after each committee to which a joint resolution has been referred reports the joint resolution to the House or has been discharged from further consideration thereof, it shall be in order to move to proceed to consider the joint resolution in the House. All points of order against the motion are waived. Such a motion shall not be in order after the House has disposed of a motion to proceed on the joint resolution. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion. The motion shall not be debatable. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is disposed of shall not be in order.</text></clause><clause id="HB42B9E82E0DA48C1890A6B1E58BE0669" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The joint resolution shall be considered as read. All points of order against the joint resolution and against its consideration are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the joint resolution to final passage without intervening motion except 2 hours of debate equally divided and controlled by the sponsor of the joint resolution (or a designee) and an opponent. A motion to reconsider the vote on passage of the joint resolution shall not be in order.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC558F3D18B8E489A84AC92DCEA1960FF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of house joint resolution in senate</header><clause id="HA26B70786745496DBD1B40FE52308164" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Receipt before passage</header><text>If, before the passage by the Senate of a joint resolution of approval or joint resolution of disapproval, the Senate receives an identical joint resolution from the House of Representatives, the following procedures shall apply:</text><subclause id="HFB28D1437941441BBCF33BD0142DF80E" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>That joint resolution shall not be referred to a committee.</text></subclause><subclause id="HEB9184801A714D4FA539A750A9DBA48F" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>With respect to that joint resolution—</text><item id="H0D3540E382AD47EDA7EC396B73686A17" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the procedure in the Senate shall be the same as if no joint resolution had been received from the House of Representatives; but</text></item><item id="H5DD312262F8F46B3ABAB98A6260F4AEA" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the vote on passage shall be on the joint resolution from the House of Representatives.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HB0106593B63A4EA48FBEA0334F474DB5" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Receipt after passage</header><text>If, following passage of a joint resolution of approval or joint resolution of disapproval in the Senate, the Senate receives an identical joint resolution from the House of Representatives, that joint resolution shall be placed on the appropriate Senate calendar.</text></clause><clause id="H7A5BDE897DAC4AAE84D48C7B42313A34" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>No companion measure</header><text>If a joint resolution of approval or a joint resolution of disapproval is received from the House, and no companion joint resolution has been introduced in the Senate, the Senate procedures under this subsection shall apply to the House joint resolution.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E893076FD6149318B9B772152D1A186" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Application to revenue measures</header><text>The provisions of this paragraph shall not apply in the House of Representatives to a joint resolution of approval or joint resolution of disapproval that is a revenue measure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC12972525504D48A575DB0072B970E0" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rules of house of representatives and senate</header><text>This subsection is enacted by Congress—</text><subparagraph id="H1C7AA231F11A495BB7B15328FF5898A4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, and as such is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, and supersedes other rules only to the extent that it is inconsistent with such rules; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CFABE77D70D412AADD1637765610F73" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF0D3A56DD139453B8D9DE68252C746D3" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees and leadership defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees and leadership</term> means—</text><paragraph id="HBA575AC4D7BF415B878496F6AEBB4720" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Speaker, the majority leader, and the minority leader of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A716C8D044F4040A76B58CD725A738D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the majority and minority leaders of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H039E2AB9C46246CEB0856002C3DA9D93" commented="no"><enum>108.</enum><header>Clarification of guidance relating to Iran’s shipping sector</header><subsection id="H10A861512D0C41ECBFE45F1B23E7FC57" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall direct the Office of Foreign Asset Control of the Department of the Treasury to issue regulations and guidance expanding the list of services constituting <quote>significant support</quote> to the shipping sector of Iran to include—</text><paragraph id="H8BC2F49B8D1F42B9B52E12C4DB677351" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>port authorities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A3E3E7959034683A627038140BA3A51" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>importing agents;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBECEBBDD17D74D71BD75F523EF0E645E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>management firms;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H872473F477A54D5EB7FFF2A2D15BFFAE" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>charterers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC66E3153A484B4AA93C6F5BAA39EA3B" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>operators;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H102102054F9D4BE7BE3D1453E5EB4C2C" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>marine insurers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29914082345E4F4FBD6DF054522E426A" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>classification societies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2697D0DCD9A4458AFF9FB9EAD3BE9BA" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>all other maritime services providers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD17209441D084DF0AB2EF2EC9719A7C2" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional update of advisory</header><text>The President shall also direct the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Coast Guard to update the <quote>Sanctions Advisory for the Maritime Industry, Energy and Metals Sectors, and Related communities</quote> issued on May 14, 2020, in accordance with the expanded definition of <quote>significant support to the shipping sector</quote> promulgated in accordance with subsection (a), as well as all other guidance and advisory documents of the Federal Government relating to such expanded definition.</text></subsection></section><section id="H057140A527504EC89511647CAACD900C" commented="no"><enum>109.</enum><header>Sunset of waiver and license authorities</header><subsection id="H72A6F6C825534808BC887DA41EE22A40" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President’s authority to issue waivers or licenses to sanctions pursuant to sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act of 1976 with regard to sanctions required or authorized by legislation or Executive orders described in subsection (b), and any waivers or licenses issued pursuant to such legislation or Executive orders, shall cease to apply beginning on February 1, 2028.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5FBF3DBBE37A4B7485D4FAF8AA16EB95" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions required or authorized by legislation and Executive orders include the following:</text><paragraph id="H953CE656B58B4A199787086F06BA4709" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>This Act, and the amendments made by this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D5BCFDF9DE045D58D98A3F3BA87A133" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H982AFDE426AE47A8A3FDBFB6BBCDD3DF" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8501">22 U.S.C. 8501 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0780412B7B234B4C92C6CD85161E23C0" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Section 1245 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8513a">22 U.S.C. 8513a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94AD1628E80944C0B121EAAAB78B555C" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8701">22 U.S.C. 8701 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A39A5FE2E8747EBBFACBF6CD3B80E9F" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Iran Freedom and Counter-Proliferation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8801">22 U.S.C. 8801 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0D11C4524C94A5291F58B5147EB1959" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H615D2AD81CE047BD872D8DDC1EBB9091" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Any other statute or Executive order that requires or authorizes the imposition of sanctions with respect to Iran.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1C47D7D3E03446A1BBA73723ACEF0F08" commented="no"><enum>110.</enum><header>Codification and application on transfers of funds involving Iran</header><subsection id="HCB29C831838D426EA6A803C3D2B47C70" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Codification and prohibition of transfers of funds involving
 Iran</header><paragraph id="H7F51559FDAF545DDB5A46A0E286E0FD7" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Codification of regulations</header><text>Notwithstanding sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704), section 560.516 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on January 1, 2021, shall apply with respect to transfers of funds to or from Iran, or for the direct or indirect benefit of an Iranian person or the Government of Iran, for the period beginning on or after such date of enactment and ending on the date on which the President makes the certification to Congress under section 8 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) as amended by this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63F9935BA2B94D6093C2FFF1B4920548" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional prohibition</header><text>Notwithstanding section 302 of this Act or sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704)—</text><subparagraph id="HD110791195CD4C22B70FCC0B634DB186" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the regulations prohibiting the debiting or crediting of an Iranian account in section 560.516 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on January 1, 2021, and codified in paragraph (1) shall apply to foreign financial institutions if the transaction or transactions is conducted in the legal tender of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66984FCE9716425DAD6F2A7C4B3CD085" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>United States financial institutions shall be prohibited from engaging in a significant transaction or transactions, including purchasing or selling foreign exchange with large-value payment systems, with a foreign financial institution that violates the regulations and prohibitions described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DFF3EF35D1A48ADB3A88F791FF8F47F" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>With the exception of paragraph (4), the President may not issue a license to permit a transaction or transactions under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H024231D9EE9D4F8F9747028CFF6E302E" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Suspension</header><text>The President may suspend the prohibition in paragraph (2) for a period not to exceed 180 days, and may renew the suspension for additional periods of not more than 180 days, on and after the date on which the President provides to the appropriate congressional committees the certification required in section 8 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) as amended by this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2E00EC139EE6469A8DFBC2AE7901F0B8" commented="no"><enum>111.</enum><header>Applicability of congressional review of certain agency rulemaking relating
 to Iran</header><subsection id="H697013396CA34591B6808B7E102C0E8D" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any rule to amend or otherwise alter a covered regulatory provision as defined in subsection (c) that is published on or after the date of the enactment of this Act shall be deemed to be a rule or major rule (as the case may be) for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/8">chapter 8</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, and shall be subject to all applicable requirements of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/8">chapter 8</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6C010242CE4449C29C1F492ABD3BEE48" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Quarterly reports</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 90 days thereafter, the head of the applicable department or agency of the Federal Government shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the operation of the licensing system under each covered regulatory provision as defined in subsection (c) for the preceding 2-year period, including—</text><paragraph id="HCDBFED12BE1F4499990D8F36BEFB15D9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number and types of licenses applied for;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06D7B3362654492C9095444FB3DC5C7D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number and types of licenses approved;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AD2687C3D6B4D9A98BBECF279C6DA15" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a summary of each license approved;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BBCE02440AF482896D5827FF71E6035" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a summary of transactions conducted pursuant to a general license;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H851216673CEB4BA9B8999DD7192AE3C1" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the average amount of time elapsed from the date of filing of a license application until the date of its approval;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF58734EABE4B48219D97346E74FAE85A" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the extent to which the licensing procedures were effectively implemented; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BB7E81B5F5D4681A51C0ACE01F3EB7D" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a description of comments received from interested parties about the extent to which the licensing procedures were effective, after the applicable department or agency holds a public 30-day comment period.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA0347FB6CBF1440DA30E416C343A3C5D" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered regulatory provision</term> means any provision of part 535, 560, 561, or 1060 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, and in EAR 742 and 746 related to Iran, as such parts were in effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H429C6B79DF98464A8BC4CC788EEEBA20" commented="no"><enum>112.</enum><header>Expansion of sanctions with respect to efforts by Iran to acquire ballistic
 missile and related technology</header><subsection id="H399EA7E2C5A94845AA2450A89FB86DE2" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Certain persons</header><text>Section 1604(a) of the Iran-Iraq Arms Non-Proliferation Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/484">Public Law 102–484</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended by inserting <quote>, to acquire ballistic missile or related technology,</quote> after <quote>nuclear weapons</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H34E4973E9AFB41C1A97E1013513A42CF" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Foreign countries</header><text>Section 1605(a) of the Iran-Iraq Arms Non-Proliferation Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/484">Public Law 102–484</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended, in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>, to acquire ballistic missile or related technology,</quote> after <quote>nuclear weapons</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="H114DD39085F3455E86931391EF2000D8" commented="no"><enum>113.</enum><header>Expansion of sanctions under Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 with respect to
 persons that acquire or develop ballistic missiles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5(b)(1)(B) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H1F982DA174274C2BBC521AD18587C4DE" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>would likely</quote> and inserting <quote>may</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EBFE8C63C3246CD97CCC5F837D10154" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text><subparagraph id="H5E64823A15B542AB9A1029CC7E030EDA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A37FE9299B544EA9C7D4DB67B109539" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subclause (II) as subclause (III); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B6564B8B99F47D18524378BD7620584" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subclause (I) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H33AE2691D50343F887E09EC3D9B81C42" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HE9B3BA6FBD90433BAC9BD25E169B662C" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>acquire or develop ballistic missiles and the capability to launch ballistic missiles; or</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H1E7662B61215471DAAF32A65FC1667B8" commented="no"><enum>114.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to ballistic missile program of
 Iran</header><subsection id="H9A49C692CC2447C29ADF137FE8174E5A" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title II of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8721">22 U.S.C. 8721 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0947C358CA204BCE95AEC6E9A6642A2C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subtitle id="H68DB11CFD5534541B5D0909EE58AF0A7" commented="no"><enum>C</enum><header>Measures Relating To Ballistic Missile Program Of Iran</header><section id="H1D85B610A9F041CABE6956F100698594" commented="no"><enum>231.</enum><header>Definitions</header><subsection id="H1A36D6FB1EFF418CA09CB2BC7FE0BE18" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this subtitle:</text><paragraph id="H6E8624EB09BF4458B5BC6D22B4C72037" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agricultural commodity</header><text>The term <term>agricultural commodity</term> has the meaning given that term in section 102 of the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/5602">7 U.S.C. 5602</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D31D6830B744F2EAD41E8B8A7F08CCE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the committees specified in section 14(2) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBE1345C2BE642FD858A4674EBC94D85" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Correspondent account; payable-through
 account</header><text>The terms <term>correspondent account</term> and <term>payable-through account</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 5318A of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C33713EC7DC41FBB5194F5963595C30" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foreign financial institution</header><text>The term <term>foreign financial institution</term> has the meaning of that term as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury pursuant to section 104(i) of the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8513">22 U.S.C. 8513(i)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE83F34CE1F6242C58F679E57752B69A1" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Government</header><text>The term <term>Government</term>, with respect to a foreign country, includes any agencies or instrumentalities of that Government and any entities controlled by that Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD53C411F23840039A154F8759F99A97" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Medical device</header><text>The term <term>medical device</term> has the meaning given the term <term>device</term> in section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3709528D98FA4A368958F50D10F961D0" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Medicine</header><text>The term <term>medicine</term> has the meaning given the term <term>drug</term> in section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE81591005A9D4BC69EB35E3C50414DE2" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determinations of significance</header><text>For purposes of this subtitle, in determining if financial transactions or financial services are significant, the President may consider the totality of the facts and circumstances, including factors similar to the factors set forth in section 561.404 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (or any corresponding similar regulation or ruling).</text></subsection></section><section id="H4522879AC49C44A490C9401A3D81652F" commented="no"><enum>232.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to persons that support
 the Ballistic Missile Program of Iran</header><subsection id="HEA77EB90DA2C4F468783659AB455AF14" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification of persons</header><paragraph id="H27477723232D4BF4AEA432F311298CC6" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of the Maximum Pressure Act, and not less frequently than once every 180 days thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report identifying persons that have provided material support to the Government of Iran in the development of the ballistic missile program or drone program of Iran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1230F650DA1B453AA9C1644663B5D006" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Each report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HD8A5C02BB54B4DB9BE4D0F2BFC54EF8D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An identification of persons (disaggregated by Iranian and non-Iranian persons) with respect to which there is credible evidence that such persons have provided material support to the Government of Iran in the development of the ballistic missile program or drone program of Iran, including persons that have—</text><clause id="H4183E60A1AC44D108F3D53CF1F301E10" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>engaged in the direct or indirect provision of material support to such programs;</text></clause><clause id="HFC3B64CAB96747D5BED06F4D365DEE68" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>facilitated, supported, or engaged in activities to further the development of such programs;</text></clause><clause id="H5999AA3A16BC48AE80B907480091804A" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>transmitted information relating to ballistic missiles or drones to the Government of Iran; or</text></clause><clause id="H7A49BA385F8C4CE68B6E845E45149DE1" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>otherwise aided such programs.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5C3A8205BB74C909A463F691B9842F0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the character and significance of the cooperation of each person identified under subparagraph (A) with the Government of Iran with respect to such programs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EB30167746D4CB091BF70C01500777D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of the cooperation of the Government of the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea with the Government of Iran with respect to such programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE22D9BE8AFE14E93A49AB55369290632" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Classified annex</header><text>Each report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H235862E3895C450C8F51D2343A780D77" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>Not later than 15 days after submitting a report required by subsection (a)(1), the President shall, in accordance with the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>), block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of any person specified in such report that engages in activities described in subsection (a) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></subsection><subsection id="H99FF52D6E24C4E62B3CA1A52C61A087C" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exclusion from United States</header><paragraph id="HB3B812B5F8944AE6BFA87335E813A898" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary of State shall deny a visa to, and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall exclude from the United States, any alien subject to blocking of property and interests in property under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4729B910CEDD48CE88AEB8E612F84F85" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compliance with united nations headquarters
 agreement</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to the head of state of Iran, or necessary staff of that head of state, if admission to the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEBFFBDAA2037414EA8431F63CF27DBF6" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Facilitation of certain transactions</header><text>The President shall prohibit the opening, and prohibit or impose strict conditions on the maintaining, in the United States of a correspondent account or a payable-through account by a foreign financial institution that the President determines knowingly, on or after the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of the Maximum Pressure Act, conducts or facilitates a significant financial transaction for a person subject to blocking of property and interests in property under subsection (b).</text></subsection></section><section id="H702C7F5BF1E84EBAA060B9276ED75338" commented="no"><enum>233.</enum><header>Blocking of property of persons affiliated with certain
 Iranian entities</header><subsection id="HB4AFFAEB1B00493C99C386B97E7052C6" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><paragraph id="H76C9F4E9C56E4B678717DDDE7C0D6E25" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall, in accordance with the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>), block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of any person described in paragraph (2) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H599592E01C2E464C8BCC85E3D4C7E138" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Persons described</header><text>A person described in this paragraph is—</text><subparagraph id="HA96B112DA1124DBD9221418F595FC0BA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an entity that is owned or controlled—</text><clause id="H25803A0601574CDE98B99874752E325A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by the Aerospace Industries Organization, the Shahid Hemmat Industrial Group, the Shahid Bakeri Industrial Group, or any agent or affiliate of such organization or group; or</text></clause><clause id="HE29E67375C39488B9DC53A9358444169" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>collectively by a group of individuals that hold an interest in the Aerospace Industries Organization, the Shahid Hemmat Industrial Group, the Shahid Bakeri Industrial Group, or any agent or affiliate of such organization or group, even if none of those individuals hold a 25 percent or greater interest in the entity; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2C217D7550044148C964B86F32B6F72" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a person that owns or controls an entity described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E41A517809C45F4A77C4E9FF6A220B5" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Facilitation of certain transactions</header><text>The President shall prohibit the opening, and prohibit or impose strict conditions on the maintaining, in the United States of a correspondent account or a payable-through account by a foreign financial institution that the President determines knowingly, on or after the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of the Maximum Pressure Act, conducts or facilitates a significant financial transaction for a person subject to blocking of property and interests in property under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H6CC0EABC7B7E412087BE0EA3F19601C5" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Iran missile proliferation watch list</header><paragraph id="HA4FBA4A140624512A38F0AB639E614E3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the Maximum Pressure Act, and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and publish in the Federal Register a list of—</text><subparagraph id="HAE9B2756C89D47DA8D7F692121BD30A7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each entity in which the Aerospace Industries Organization, the Shahid Hemmat Industrial Group, the Shahid Bakeri Industrial Group, or any agent or affiliate of such organization or group has an ownership interest of more than 0 percent and less than 25 percent;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15369F83771E4226BC330C79F72F43B4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each entity in which the Aerospace Industries Organization, the Shahid Hemmat Industrial Group, the Shahid Bakeri Industrial Group, or any agent or affiliate of such organization or group does not have an ownership interest but maintains a presence on the board of directors of the entity or otherwise influences the actions, policies, or personnel decisions of the entity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC57218591CF2416899BD4BC204FE9FA3" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>each person that owns or controls an entity described in subparagraph (A) or (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H092F4E39E70E45EF8A489EA9C77D9167" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reference</header><text>The list required by paragraph (1) may be referred to as the <quote>Iran Missile Proliferation Watch List</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0935C96C37C34713BE54EEA81966711D" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Comptroller general report</header><paragraph id="HA5C67E6FF3074AD9A5142C79B08B4153" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text><subparagraph id="H80E46090FED049629052EA4C916533A0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct a review of each list required by subsection (c)(1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7333940C680F453A87C4AB2CE7C7B2D4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after each such list is submitted to the appropriate congressional committees under that subsection, submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the review conducted under subparagraph (A) that includes a list of persons not included in that list that qualify for inclusion in that list, as determined by the Comptroller General.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7A12AB31BE749EA94835EF5289CD2C4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultations</header><text>In preparing the report required by paragraph (1)(B), the Comptroller General shall consult with nongovernmental organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2F7CBB9B5A1A4F1599EDE21D88664482" commented="no"><enum>234.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to certain persons
 involved in ballistic missile activities</header><subsection id="H631D411789EB4B48A12F1BA8AAE530A6" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of the Maximum Pressure Act, and not less frequently than once every 180 days thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a certification that each person listed in an annex of United Nations Security Council Resolution 1737 (2006), 1747 (2007), or 1929 (2010) is not directly or indirectly facilitating, supporting, or involved with the development of or transfer to Iran of ballistic missiles or technology, parts, components, or technology information relating to ballistic missiles.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9D93211DAC7B417D8F7E912BA5F7A330" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>If the President is unable to make a certification under subsection (a) with respect to a person and the person is not currently subject to sanctions with respect to Iran under any other provision of law, the President shall, not later than 15 days after that certification would have been required under that subsection—</text><paragraph id="HD1C7C821C3D647D5B67FE856767CAFF0" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in accordance with the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>), block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of that person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD085FD750B594B748DF17CEFF651AC57" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publish in the Federal Register a report describing the reason why the President was unable to make a certification with respect to that person.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0CB489D1877940FC8ADF7D126203A91B" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exclusion from united states</header><paragraph id="H6B9C28C48BD64EE59B0C2706F2EDBC23" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary of State shall deny a visa to, and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall exclude from the United States, any alien subject to blocking of property and interests in property under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86BB7B82402E46FFAFBCECA60EDE992B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compliance with united nations headquarters
 agreement</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to the head of state of Iran, or necessary staff of that head of state, if admission to the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0F10DB23AA164DA0ACDEF9AAE9414908" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Facilitation of certain transactions</header><text>The President shall prohibit the opening, and prohibit or impose strict conditions on the maintaining, in the United States of a correspondent account or a payable-through account by a foreign financial institution that the President determines knowingly, on or after the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of the Maximum Pressure Act, conducts or facilitates a significant financial transaction for a person subject to blocking of property and interests in property under subsection (b).</text></subsection></section><section id="H1340708CD59044DABD2912AD8BE643AA" commented="no"><enum>235.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to certain sectors of
 Iran that support the ballistic missile program of Iran</header><subsection id="H7D094C6089644581B242A1459B965A72" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>List of sectors</header><paragraph id="HBDF148A3E0AA4B739ED3D3201EFB9A18" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of the Maximum Pressure Act, and not less frequently than once every 180 days thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and publish in the Federal Register a list of the sectors of the economy of Iran that are directly or indirectly facilitating, supporting, or involved with the development of or transfer to Iran of ballistic missiles or technology, parts, components, or technology information relating to ballistic missiles.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3113DEDEF1DA46B2BD726DE35F81C87D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certain sectors</header><subparagraph id="HEAC396709E9C457AAA0BD517F688DA41" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of the Maximum Pressure Act, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a determination as to whether each of the chemical, computer science, construction, electronic, metallurgy, mining, research (including universities and research institutions), and telecommunications sectors of Iran meet the criteria specified in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3115F2DAFE544AB7978E64AFFFE1720F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion in initial list</header><text>If the President determines under subparagraph (A) that the sectors of the economy of Iran specified in such subparagraph meet the criteria specified in paragraph (1), that sector shall be included in the initial list submitted and published under that paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFBD6DAE364A149E3AC14C5E53D33C201" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions with respect to specified sectors of
 Iran</header><paragraph id="H1140E758D957486CABE00E43394FD97A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>The President shall, in accordance with the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>), block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of any person described in paragraph (4) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53BA5A2C2F404F7CB8A0452B18D7AC3F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusion from united states</header><subparagraph id="HFCDFA7DE7B844057B398C8B8DE947C0B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Secretary of State shall deny a visa to, and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall exclude from the United States, any alien that is a person described in paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F236A2D7CCA44719AA027A71A3F997D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Compliance with united nations headquarters
 agreement</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to the head of state of Iran, or necessary staff of that head of state, if admission to the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H68E8063E47D9462DA0DCF74ED7C000CD" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Facilitation of certain transactions</header><text>Except as provided in this section, the President shall prohibit the opening, and prohibit or impose strict conditions on the maintaining, in the United States of a correspondent account or a payable-through account by a foreign financial institution that the President determines knowingly, on or after the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of the Maximum Pressure Act, conducts or facilitates a significant financial transaction for a person described in paragraph (4).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2542D6C6D6441B680533300C5C9A185" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Persons described</header><text>A person is described in this paragraph if the President determines that the person, on or after the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of the Maximum Pressure Act—</text><subparagraph id="H4D76A26B17D54BE49FB15D6D0F398050" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>operates in a sector of the economy of Iran included in the most recent list published by the President under subsection (a);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F084E86C2794EA4AC650FCE464EB462" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>knowingly provides significant financial, material, technological, or other support to, or goods or services in support of, any activity or transaction on behalf of or for the benefit of a person described in subparagraph (A); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58E6271ACAEB459B8EB7F390FF2AD095" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is owned or controlled by a person described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H772C68CD0CCB44CAB07BE46A42B84081" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Humanitarian exception</header><text>The President may not impose sanctions under this section with respect to any person for conducting or facilitating a transaction for the sale of agricultural commodities, food, medicine, or medical devices to Iran or for the provision of humanitarian assistance to the people of Iran.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC30E5A2348A3436787BE16C2A27B3767" commented="no"><enum>236.</enum><header>Identification of foreign persons that support the ballistic
 missile program of Iran in certain sectors of Iran</header><subsection id="HFF413D54D5E448AEBE32DDBDEE8F2D24" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of the Maximum Pressure Act, and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and publish in the Federal Register a list of all foreign persons that have, based on credible information, directly or indirectly facilitated, supported, or been involved with the development of ballistic missiles or technology, parts, components, or technology information related to ballistic missiles in the following sectors of the economy of Iran during the period specified in subsection (b):</text><paragraph id="H1A746491B5E54FFFAA4A7CCF7B57753B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Chemical.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A589B5CB8BE40D0959E0BD803A44EDF" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Computer Science.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE71680AD733E40B6BB7FCCEEFF813B05" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Construction.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB22781F232BD44A7AF81599718FE2474" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Electronic.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44B06E842547447CAC7C9B7D51355729" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Metallurgy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF96CFA86CAF24BB79651229DB159497C" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Mining.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H804C1CEC96824A32AC50A9852F433E45" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Petrochemical.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H389269037E69410CA31B91B1258CAD54" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Research (including universities and research institutions).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4D791B5341245EB80AED150CAC9A713" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Telecommunications.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6074C2EA8A47459291D20F5D2872967D" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Any other sector of the economy of Iran identified under section 235(a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF1066300C5A140C39CA11EF2D7D297D2" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Period specified</header><text>The period specified in this subsection is—</text><paragraph id="H93AF3DE2C6C74E49834FDBEBF2DF2829" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>with respect to the first list submitted under subsection (a), the period beginning on the date of the enactment of the Maximum Pressure Act and ending on the date that is 120 days after such date of enactment; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H700ACE7ECEB746B29237C2642203F786" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to each subsequent list submitted under such subsection, the 1 year period preceding the submission of the list.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H997330539A5C4E258308389176E0FC1C" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Comptroller general report</header><paragraph id="H3B967B4FB4DD4CCB9CCBB4B175528AA7" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to each list submitted under subsection (a), not later than 120 days after the list is submitted under that subsection, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees—</text><subparagraph id="H95F5DAB445A64961A651C7ED6B73AD62" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of the processes followed by the President in preparing the list;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9A6179F324746EAA815A7E88262D0CD" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of the foreign persons included in the list; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60CFFCA3314D455CABE7952077705604" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a list of persons not included in the list that qualify for inclusion in the list, as determined by the Comptroller General.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H84092B9B2BC44BE3A2BCDAD0ACCC086D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultations</header><text>In preparing the report required by paragraph (1), the Comptroller General shall consult with nongovernmental organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H33A8C86B658244099409EF6B8D4BC325" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Credible information defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>credible information</term> has the meaning given that term in section 14 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note).</text></subsection></section></subtitle><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H5A4116E528284295AF503089ACF1F275" commented="no"><enum>115.</enum><header>Mandatory sanctions with respect to financial institutions that engage in
                    certain transactions on behalf of persons involved in human rights abuses or
 that export sensitive technology to Iran</header><subsection id="H2B8ABCF496084CFF857DD35EABEA7E95" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 104(c)(2) of the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8513">22 U.S.C. 8513(c)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H2EC8C6C73B394E76AAB0AE47F6779C3A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4E101FB1D0D4F4F86D90E9AF3161FE5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F6D465A9D584487A8105AC9EDE419B9" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HD2196CE63E4B4DFE9DE64A750B4923EE" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HBF234490AA004437B51B979ACF69257D" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>facilitates a significant transaction or transactions or provides significant financial services for a person that is subject to sanctions under section 105(c), 105A(c), 105B(c), or 105C(a);</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB27DACB1D3BD4C208C85014957DD63D6" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and apply with respect to any activity described in subparagraph (F) of section 104(c)(2) of the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010, as added by subsection (a)(3), initiated on or after the date that is 90 days after such date of enactment.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8BC10099252C4C11A508E4BE8CC474CA" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall prescribe regulations to carry out the amendments made by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="H4A963CCB4208431987740897EB8B7E87" commented="no"><enum>116.</enum><header>Additional sanctions with respect to foreign persons that support or conduct
                    certain transactions with Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps or other sanctioned
 persons</header><subsection id="HF290FF8C9485487D9490E241279636CC" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification</header><text>Section 302(a)(1) of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8742">22 U.S.C. 8742(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HEE1F3428D6FC4F50A5EC809C4F80316B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter,</quote> and inserting <quote>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of the Maximum Pressure Act, and every 60 days thereafter,</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE70F4FFED3C489FBA8FB72BF32456F4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>, provide significant financial services to, or provide material support to</quote> after <quote>transactions with</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8CF055DC384A4CD0941361993B6928DA" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text><subparagraph id="H897A72D4DD1D4ECA8558430D4186487F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting <quote>, provide significant financial services to, or provide material support to</quote> after <quote>transactions with</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71BF03FF4DDB4587BCD523562BD7C31C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD084596F138141629C1EC31A44621C25" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F28F7BB0C2C44C582E4F08CC45C63A0" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (i) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H0983B7F3571C41E08FB713A42B00EA49" style="OLC"><clause id="H66F191971BF94B0AA89D2AE3AD652A3D" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a person designated as a foreign terrorist organization under section 219(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189(a)</external-xref>) or that has provided support for an act of international terrorism (as defined in section 14 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note)); or</text></clause><clause id="H68EBB7BF750A4030A79EFFF4345D1810" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a foreign person whose property and access to property has been blocked pursuant to Executive Order 13224 (September 23, 2001; relating to blocking property and prohibiting transactions with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H60B475660F2940C28C8560702F5FE573" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header><text>Section 302(b) of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8742">22 U.S.C. 8742(b)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the President—</quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote>the President shall, in accordance with the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>), block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property with respect to such foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</quote>.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="H9E3B456F3E89452ABD3C11994C024743"><enum>II</enum><header>Matters Relating to the Financing of Terrorism</header><section id="H5595F6418E61402EAEC596719655AA09"><enum>201.</enum><header>Prohibitions of International Monetary Fund allocations for Iran</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6(b) of the Special Drawing Rights Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/286q">22 U.S.C. 286q(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HD7CEB173594D49B2844E82F7638D44C7" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H7AF8F57A71274398846F06680E6E3C38"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no funds shall be appropriated to allocate Special Drawing Rights under Article XVII, sections 2 and 3, of the Articles of Agreement of the Fund to the Islamic Republic of Iran.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H18CFA6FF29D345FCA59E73464CB1C8F1"><enum>202.</enum><header>Certification requirement for removal of designation of Iran as a
 jurisdiction of primary money laundering concern</header><subsection id="HC429B09E59474B348DF73798540D5E29"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may not rescind a final rule (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act) that provides for the designation of Iran as a jurisdiction of primary money laundering concern pursuant to section 5318A of title 31, United States Code, unless the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees a certification described in subsection (b) with respect to Iran.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2682BC9049024B828979608F73C66541"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>The President may only rescind a preliminary draft rule or final rule described in subsection (a) if the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees the certification required in section 8 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) as amended by this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA358BCBCBEAB4C04A29ACF50DB06431A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The certification described in subsection (b) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1D487AD946124950A71CE82E47C0B7A5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H6AC09CA0F19A4BE7BADCDDA0266040D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF775826F0714FA188E7202E6B8F4D7B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H14E75A4659A94DEA9728EB6374C720EF"><enum>203.</enum><header>Requirement to take special measures at domestic financial
 institutions</header><subsection id="HBEE8BD4DB9414D89B37007B6A7493354"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall require domestic financial institutions and domestic financial agencies to take 1 or more of the special measures described under section 5318A(b) of title 31, United States Code, with respect to a financial institution operating outside of the United States, if the Secretary determines that the financial institution operating outside of the United States knowingly conducts a significant transaction in connection with the Instrument in Support of Trade Exchanges, or any successor to such Instrument.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0EDE62082F1A48E39B6C51C9F4105FD6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>During the 2-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the President may, for periods not to exceed 180 days, waive the application of subsection (a) of this section with respect to a financial institution if the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that such a waiver is in the national security interests of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCE2511940F5840C6B218985E484AC69E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the terms <term>domestic financial institution</term>, <term>domestic financial agency</term>, and <term>financial institution</term> have the meaning given those terms, respectively, under section 5312 of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection></section><section id="H0F96336A236D4659AC0D75846C2F22B8"><enum>204.</enum><header>Additional sanctions with respect to foreign persons that are officials,
                    agents, or affiliates of, or owned or controlled by, Iran’s Revolutionary Guard
 Corps</header><subsection id="H6E9BBB68518D4A4CB8C1F8BABA451408"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 301(a) of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8741">22 U.S.C. 8741(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H99EDDCF4648440B9BE8C914B273D4553"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and as appropriate thereafter,</quote> and inserting <quote>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the Maximum Pressure Act, and every 180 days thereafter,</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88BA7BC396AD4D01A4AA3897FEC1A1D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H631C754309C946EA9D2E3FDDD167B8AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, or owned or controlled by,</quote> after <quote>affiliates of</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14386E68042F4D8C9D2324C72D575BC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H57656583D4BC451DA33EB70F09E7BA6A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF49C22AB0BEA45F7BDFA52788E06FF48"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H9DDB9339AC0F4BB7AF9F276AC1A5AA26" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HF96E7DDAD1FE4164A8BDE49A13587508"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify foreign persons with respect to which there is a reasonable basis to determine that the foreign persons have, directly or indirectly, attempted to conduct 1 or more sensitive transactions or activities described in subsection (c) for or on behalf of a foreign person described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H51CFB7FE73FF48F88CF600A5361B3E5E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority for investigation; determination and report</header><text>Section 301(b) of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8741">22 U.S.C. 8741(b)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H761DA97AF77E485F807B257C44588347" style="OLC"><subsection id="HE41352E2EC614F269F903B57BD95E4D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority for investigation; determination and report</header><paragraph id="H3D1D5111AC0544008088E697FEF1BD45"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Priority for investigation</header><text>In identifying foreign persons pursuant to subsection (a)(1) as officials, agents, or affiliates of Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps, the President shall investigate—</text><subparagraph id="H348FD0E4B3534D3BA3BBC97C3DAA768E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>foreign persons or entities identified under section 560.304 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (relating to the definition of the Government of Iran);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA259E672A0749B3931628177C73F108"><enum>(B)</enum><text>foreign persons for which there is a reasonable basis to find that the person has conducted or attempted to conduct 1 or more sensitive transactions or activities described in subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12C6E7DC439B4781903B450F83B79622"><enum>(C)</enum><text>foreign persons listed under the headings <quote>Attachment 3</quote> or <quote>Attachment 4</quote> in Annex A of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231, adopted on July 20, 2015.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9B6A2FC640443388657FEC408384E3E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination and report</header><subparagraph id="H3FF367D29B2F47B59F04EFE2D72F7B0D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Determination</header><clause id="HFD7AD922D65B44F59BC6DEC755FA80A9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall determine whether each foreign person on the list described in clause (ii) is a foreign person that is owned or controlled by Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps.</text></clause><clause id="H34362D7EDCAA487784AA8F9299829644"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>List</header><text>The list of foreign persons described in this clause are the following:</text><subclause id="H72728ED60CAA44F981EE1BA4A72F2ADE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Telecommunication Company of Iran.</text></subclause><subclause id="H7560189E1B384E9C98676DEAE642BF1F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The Mobile Telecommunication Company of Iran.</text></subclause><subclause id="HD22320BA039340F39BB70C4641307E99"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The Calcimin Public Company.</text></subclause><subclause id="HFCAB6E5203D945848FC9B25287C31C3B"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>The Iran Tractor Manufacturing Company of Iran.</text></subclause><subclause id="H78A8C1674FD44FA48A028C3B4C568F0D"><enum>(V)</enum><text>The Iran Zinc Mines Development Company.</text></subclause><subclause id="H5A10EAA36B9D440596D72CA3032CC6E3"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>The National Iranian Lead and Zinc Company.</text></subclause><subclause id="HC508866EEFE44DD78A500DFA33800B34"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>Ghadir Investment.</text></subclause><subclause id="HC61508EB7AB447CFABD4441DCC933C45"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>Parisian Oil &amp; Gas Development Company.</text></subclause><subclause id="H134D294E67F04F64A6B22BFB013EAC0B"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>The Pardis Petrochemical Company.</text></subclause><subclause id="HE6DA0E4F8B304A72A71818210D719674"><enum>(X)</enum><text>The Tabriz Oil Refinery.</text></subclause><subclause id="H4CA4E94865DC45F28DA5791FCBE29734"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>Kermanshah Petrochemical Industries.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE82985F54C2C4EC2884BF7E625CA3397"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header><clause id="HCA45499542A64F3E8DA59FCD2FD73549"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, and not later 1 year thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the determinations made under subparagraph (A) together with the reasons for those determinations.</text></clause><clause id="H691ABB149FFF4A8A9F4308CDCF9C3DFF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Form</header><text>A report submitted under clause (i) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H6CF68444F86E44E8B6542F8D79D06B8B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sensitive transactions and activities described</header><text>Section 301(c) of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8741">22 U.S.C. 8741(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H454768CBCE1F48E18CD72A330E8B7F7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H61E60312B215420ABACA6CDD7C5B1872"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$1,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$500,000</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H690956B7ACBA4B168A258AE7FE5A4BB0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>Iranian financial institution or</quote> after <quote>involving a</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H487136B0804B489D97D48B07A7F6CAED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3), (4), and (5) as paragraphs (6), (7), and (8), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5B0F7907CD94E6DB372074C66B87277"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following new paragraphs:</text><quoted-block id="HAEB1B3899F4946698BA846B3AB7CB6E8" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H7B550714521A45DC98FCA9E88BB9837A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a transaction to provide material support for an organization designated as a foreign terrorist organization under section 219(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189(a)</external-xref>) or support for an act of international terrorism (as defined in section 14 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note));</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AACA1F5B321414FABAF217979C30540"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a transaction to provide material support to a foreign person whose property and access to property has been blocked pursuant to Executive Order 13224 (September 23, 2001; relating to blocking property and prohibiting transactions with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE2FBD3BCC2B404ABDBCC45B829A18F2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a transaction to provide material support for the Government of Syria or any agency or instrumentality thereof;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5F0D027C2EC94320A8A7B7DCE2F3E07D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations, implementation, penalties, and definitions</header><text>Section 301 of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8741">22 U.S.C. 8741</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H9CB50FDAAE124BC19C905ED5287AEB74"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (f) as subsection (h); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H45B78B8CE34E4AF7BB3FFE5A76F4BF81"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (e) the following new subsections:</text><quoted-block id="H3E7295CD9AB443FB84990DDA9FA8C5D3" style="OLC"><subsection id="H94F1936AE11446EB939F6CA4C423D9B3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of subsection (a) or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out subsection (a) shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5C6C4904CAA145ABBE352F2A1BEE76E6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H4CDDA1221A724A6181AD01743963DBAF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HA1586FE8C2AA4C90926AC07264A66433"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual who is not a United States person;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73045EFC1C734E85B49174CD2F2D52E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a corporation, partnership, or other nongovernmental entity which is not a United States person; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D7C4B6513C74D8392763BA5C4ADAD28"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any representative, agent or instrumentality of, or an individual working on behalf of a foreign government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9983ECF79D5C4A6D85F2F46122B037E0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Iran’s revolutionary guard corps</header><text>The term <term>Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps</term> includes any senior foreign political figure (as defined in section 1010.605 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations) of Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB05F7E0F5E54581862C3E189A94FECD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Own or control</header><text>The term <term>own or control</term> means, with respect to an entity—</text><subparagraph id="H9ABB62B0E7C6462692FEFF6AC5BCC113"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to hold more than 25 percent of the equity interest by vote or value in the entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FEAE64E86F647FE9E0438AB96CF9714"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to hold a majority of seats on the board of directors of the entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H003C0FE0ACAD4C94BC336A760148296A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to otherwise control the actions, policies, or personnel decisions of the entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCAFB9E3F94E04FDFBA1D6BC8669486D4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H9AB776A714794755B0A8EF06FB57D2DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5C0168570554293A8B730C487B6A670"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9EDFE6E771AF494D996857B906BEDFDB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conforming and clerical amendments</header><text>The Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8701">22 U.S.C. 8701 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H7FDC83AEE0014763941AE4A13567EC31"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the heading of section 301 and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H00985B3F088946DEA956F9437939D96A" style="OLC"><section id="H7F92E816AB60462F959E0BCFF1E96F99"><enum>301.</enum><header>Identification of, and imposition of sanctions with respect
                                    to, foreign persons that are officials, agents or affiliates of,
                                    or owned or controlled by, Iran’s revolutionary guard
 corps</header></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">and</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C4F2D996B574EA6984B28FE51A1EE12"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the table of contents, by striking the item relating to section 301 and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H6884619B759144E2993EB153A7B6BC2E" style="OLC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 301. Identification of, and
                                    imposition of sanctions with respect to, foreign persons that
                                    are officials, agents or affiliates of, or owned or controlled
                                    by, Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H285B65E5656D48C6A14BE58D295AC7AD"><enum>205.</enum><header>Additional sanctions with respect to foreign persons that support or conduct
                    certain transactions with Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps or other sanctioned
 persons</header><subsection id="H311E3CD4180B4CF48943C4DFDF0A6CB0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification</header><text>Section 302(a)(1) of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8742">22 U.S.C. 8742(a)(1)</external-xref>)—</text><paragraph id="H49E497D9C69E4BD5BF83472F7136430A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><subparagraph id="H2368B0EDE9E846A19007BDE90E3D5C3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, provide significant financial services to, or provide material support to</quote> after <quote>transactions with</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02A7DF4355F24BBB9BA1442002873A13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE368B9B9B8AF43DA8C2FB54BF61CDB19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text><subparagraph id="HF84BC990F40340238609CAC9586A5C7D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting <quote>, provide significant financial services to, or provide material support to</quote> after <quote>transactions with</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03821966C83645A885AF2EFD1F8D6572"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA26402D20F241E6BB2F36A301DF295D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking clause (ii) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="HB04E458AB4834C869FB5695686B08477" style="OLC"><clause id="HF3E53815B67142D28158098970A3D2B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a person or entity designated as foreign terrorist organizations under section 219(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189(a)</external-xref>) or that has provided support for an act of international terrorism (as defined in section 14 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note)); or</text></clause><clause id="HDA0A8463DE074FB4A4D4530821C068E9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a foreign person whose property and access to property has been blocked pursuant to Executive Order 13224 (September 23, 2001; relating to blocking property and prohibiting transactions with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism); or</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H78E1D374254B4C089638F0C41BB145DC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HCBEBF66C334A41DFBF12353984089813" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H5ED268A229C24E73B488C71283DFA2CA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a person acting on behalf of or at the direction of, or owned or controlled (as that term is defined in section 301) by, a person described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H08AE7058DE7C45218F9A4F7DE1E37C0D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header><text>Section 302(b) of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8742">22 U.S.C. 8742(b)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the President—</quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote>the President shall block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property with respect to such foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="HEAC9D775655A4639959ADF838989BD28"><enum>206.</enum><header>Reports on certain Iranian persons and sectors of Iran’s economy that are
 controlled by Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps</header><subsection id="HA5141642DFE9470A8DBEF706E5386B55"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It shall be the policy of the United States to fully implement and enforce sanctions against Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps, including its officials, agents, and affiliates.</text></subsection><subsection id="H44939641F787406CABDE2FE1F517E93B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subtitle B of title III of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/158">Public Law 112–158</external-xref>; 126 Stat. 1247) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HA36BACBF08904FD08A25B7EE372A43AB" style="OLC"><section id="H5B9FDBA746C04DB492335277A8D36161"><enum>313.</enum><header>Report on certain Iranian persons</header><subsection id="HD6849CE5E8E8481EBF3092E1776FFF02"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, and annually thereafter for a period not to exceed 3 years, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains the following:</text><paragraph id="H44AA2C171888445FA80214FF97733511"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A list of foreign persons listed on the Tehran Stock Exchange and, with respect to each such foreign person—</text><subparagraph id="HD724AA88147944AF9D6FC8BF91DCBBDD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an identification of the sector of Iran’s economy in which the foreign person is located; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57D17ACE26FF42479F5F849AC531FF33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a determination of whether or not Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps or any foreign persons that are officials, agents, or affiliates of Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps, directly or indirectly, owns or controls the foreign person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FB965CA5B8841FB9B1264C671499636"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A list of foreign persons that are operating business enterprises in Iran that have a valuation of more than $100,000,000 and, with respect to each such foreign person—</text><subparagraph id="H4392D5055F4F4BD78233BFA580A891E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an identification of the sector of Iran’s economy in which the foreign person is located; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6DB3EAF47C74EB3B0A010A887EBB0D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a determination of whether or not Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps or any foreign persons that are officials, agents, or affiliates of Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps, directly or indirectly owns or controls the foreign person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE156D89E0864C61975A698FA90D2366"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A list of Iranian financial institutions that have a valuation of more than $10,000,000 and, with respect to each such Iranian financial institution—</text><subparagraph id="H38880DC5DA64463DA9072412497E7F80"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an identification of the sector of Iran’s economy in which the institution is located; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3E85A90EE16434691BA3A77E9799140"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a determination of whether or not—</text><clause id="H364323017C264038B526B831F146AAB2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the institution has knowingly facilitated a significant transaction directly or indirectly for, or on behalf of, Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps during the 2-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this section; or</text></clause><clause id="H73631259D50540C08738CA1956781517"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps or any foreign persons that are officials, agents, or affiliates of Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps, directly or indirectly, owns or controls the institution.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE94D73879E544548BAF77E01EFA66B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form of report; public availability</header><paragraph id="H3289A931FFB047BBA85AE3284EFE7C33"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC16FA78D7154EFF82609CC6D3DD3B09"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The unclassified portion of the report required by paragraph (1) shall be posted on a publicly-available Internet website of the Department of the Treasury and a publicly-available Internet website of the Department of State.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H97A4167F17EF446CBFF92C141EABDAD0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H3063B5A3952D4001A4696404F123596B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HF31256004B7743819590B7932F106D95"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual who is not a United States person;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE62EF091EE0478F82556A91D7A633B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a corporation, partnership, or other nongovernmental entity which is not a United States person; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DDF93E4ADD94430896103A0842D6E58"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any representative, agent or instrumentality of, or an individual working on behalf of a foreign government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A3BEF8EB6FC4EA49E66AAD181AE81BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Iran’s revolutionary guard corps</header><text>The term <term>Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps</term> includes any senior foreign political figure (as defined in section 1010.605 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations) of Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC56875268234D5FB1808A1DF8D0F1F2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Iranian financial institution</header><text>The term <term>Iranian financial institution</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H6AB8A03257AE40C3AB87C6AC1F098C7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a financial institution organized under the laws of Iran or any jurisdiction within Iran, including a foreign branch of such an institution;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65D65A4B2A8F463281EA2F47EADA116A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a financial institution located in Iran;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H424683A2D403415BBABBB61E0B5D8940"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a financial institution, wherever located, owned or controlled by the Government of Iran; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E6508EE92BF441E81A7A4C17E4B34F6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a financial institution, wherever located, owned or controlled by a financial institution described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9A5B0CF7AFC43568F8601B4F578AD2A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Own or control</header><text>The term <term>own or control</term> has the meaning given such term in section 301.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F437B2FB071469A99AB4A8330B4189F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Significant transaction</header><text>A transaction shall be determined to be a <quote>significant transaction</quote> in accordance with section 561.404 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3879DF3765444945BE64B869F777E5CE"><enum>(6)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HFEEB07C8E00D43559923A75376020BB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED46683E71B6489892D27C873F50E33C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE09EB4F4D0694239B06C2B57D7468254"><enum>314.</enum><header>Report on sectors of Iran’s economy that are controlled by
 Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps</header><subsection id="HD7FA071DCDDC45D6ACCC43409BC941AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, and every 180 days thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that identifies each sector of Iran’s economy described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H6EC906F2854143148CBB305C0CB3C5F3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sectors of Iran’s economy described</header><paragraph id="H7BF3D526967F4861B2388443CE9D1742"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The sectors of Iran’s economy described in this subsection are each sector in which 20 or more of any of the Iranian financial institutions or foreign persons described in paragraph (2) are located in such sector.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB21378F760D348209BCB31688BB99326"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Iranian financial institutions and foreign persons
 described</header><text>The Iranian financial institutions and foreign persons described in this subsection are the following:</text><subparagraph id="H4942AB81950D4584A981B48C931A255B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Iranian financial institutions listed under section 313(a)(1)(B)(ii).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9D5330118C34FE4ADDDCB3381CB3F2E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Foreign persons listed under section 313(a)(2)(B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H539FBA030EBE4880B3459D0601B5C938"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Foreign persons listed under section 313(a)(3)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></title><title id="HBC51A67F6E7D4E74BEDA4D78E6BEE9A2"><enum>III</enum><header>Matters Relating to the Designation of Certain Entities</header><section id="H24DA38F010374CA599D8AE98E0958594"><enum>301.</enum><header>Prohibition on future waivers and licenses connected to the designation of
 the IRGC</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, all waivers and licenses in effect as of such date issued by the President pursuant to the designation of the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps under Executive Order 13224 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property and prohibiting transactions with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism) shall remain in effect, and the President may not issue a new waiver or license with respect to any activity connected to the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps, until the date on which the President makes the certification to Congress pursuant to section 8 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) as amended by this Act.</text></section><section id="H5B171CB50EB24ED3991C71703B454998"><enum>302.</enum><header>Prohibition on future waivers and licenses connected to the designation of
 the IRGC as a foreign terrorist organization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State may not remove the designation of the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps as a foreign terrorist organization pursuant to section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>) unless the President makes the certification to Congress pursuant to section 8 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) as amended by this Act. The waiver issued by the Secretary of State pursuant to the Notice of Determination published on April 24, 2019 (84 Fed. Reg. 17227; relating to material support for certain foreign governmental sub-entities), shall remain in effect, and the President may not issue a new waiver or license with respect to any activity connected to the designation of the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps, until the date on which the President makes the certification to Congress pursuant to section 8 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) as amended by this Act.</text></section><section id="HBC5F4511F6FF44A4837672C6CAD23C58" commented="no"><enum>303.</enum><header>Codification of Executive Order 14175 relating to Ansar Allah in
 Yemen</header><subsection id="HC3DFBFDC28CF4F01BFA4ABE9FA8CBAB9" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H5DC4C8C6EA614C4695F1731549F59DBB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Houthis are armed, trained, and advised by the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps, an entity designated as a foreign terrorist organization pursuant to section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02D25DFE74CA4A389DE832F56EEED4D4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>According to former Secretary of State Mike Pompeo, the Houthis are responsible for a number of terrorist acts, <quote>including cross-border attacks threatening civilian populations, infrastructure, and commercial shipping.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB323E5A06DD24C5BA0A1169D19B23B31" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of the Congress that the designation of the Ansarallah in Yemen (otherwise known as the <quote>Houthis</quote>) as a foreign terrorist organization by former Secretary of State Mike Pompeo, which took effect on January 19, 2021, was an essential step to hold Iran’s proxies accountable.</text></subsection><subsection id="H108E52AB164145DE85DCDCEC8719E34A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Codification of Executive Order 14175</header><text>Executive Order 14175, signed on January 22, 2025 (90 Fed. Reg. 8639; relating to designation of Ansar Allah as a Foreign Terrorist Organization) shall have the force and effect of enacted law.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="H1E545E60DABA4AE38C07FC3FF6295E9D"><enum>IV</enum><header>Determinations and Reports</header><section id="H0C3A63186EC948D9BD0641D5F4077783"><enum>401.</enum><header>Determinations with respect to the imposition of sanctions</header><subsection id="HE7FB2468EE224508B2DAA285E5A7E4BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a determination, including a detailed justification, on whether Kata’ib Sayyid al-Shuhada, Kata’ib al-Imam Ali, Saraya Khorasani, and the Badr Corps, and any foreign person that is an official, agent, affiliate of, or owned or controlled by Kata’ib Sayyid al-Shuhada, Kata’ib al-Imam Ali, Saraya Khorasani, or the Badr Corps, meets the criteria for—</text><paragraph id="HE59A37CDF36748128A72AFE1C5A786A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designation as a foreign terrorist organization pursuant to section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H54C3D87E74EA4B5C8C4C306E26C8A721"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the application of sanctions pursuant to Executive Order 13224 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property and prohibiting transactions with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA8E5FA19AF34B92A4B664B95116F8C6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the application of sanctions pursuant to the Caesar Syria Civilian Protection Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8791">22 U.S.C. 8791</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6512E083400341B292D02DB9D0C5507C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The determination in subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection><subsection id="H354A76C19DB74AD883734B24290248EA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="HC815990A3AAF4F3EB208252B385D0BF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, the Committee on Financial Services, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85DDBCF0E4394A778D6895E602ACDDCF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Select Committee on Intelligence, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD2A15CB5BA844E4B95C86E0EB4744EB0"><enum>402.</enum><header>Iranian militia watchlists</header><subsection id="H22439137935440F6A91C3EE2F5B632CF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State shall annually maintain and publish a list of armed groups, militias, or proxy forces in Iraq receiving logistical, military, or financial assistance from Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps or over which the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps exerts any form of control or influence.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDD054F7AC25E422F9D09C5F147C87173"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The list required under subsection (a) shall be published concurrently with the Annual Country Reports on Terrorism required to be submitted pursuant to section 140 of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656f">22 U.S.C. 2656f</external-xref>), beginning with the first such Country Reports published after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD53F29DF3E9748E48B8C9FDDEC7B0A64"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The Secretary may, not later than 30 days after publication of the Annual Country Reports on Terrorism in accordance with subsection (b), submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a classified annex with respect to the list required under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="HD0011F33C85F478DBB59FD0B02CE6569"><enum>403.</enum><header>Expansion of reporting to include Iranian arms shipments to the Houthis and
 Iranian backed militias in Iraq and Syria</header><subsection id="H0C34958063694235B235A67D68FAC9B7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of the Congress that Iran’s influence and activities in Yemen are a threat to the national security of the United States and its regional partners, including Israel and Saudi Arabia, and that the United States must stand with Israel and Gulf allies against Houthi aggression in Yemen.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAEFA6F4F5AC543469C4F3AF74C3E2EDC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text>Section 103(b)(6)(A) of the Countering America’s Adversaries Through Sanctions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9402">22 U.S.C. 9402(b)(6)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>Ansarallah, also known as the Houthis, Iranian backed militias in Iraq and Syria, or,</quote> after <quote>bound for</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="HACF4C49D57B04FBDA3507E995C97AF6F"><enum>404.</enum><header>Annual report on Iran sanctions violations</header><subsection id="HB1CA535F32B94A0DBA24A6336F40B1E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of the State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes a list of each person not currently subject to United States sanctions that the Secretary determines is in violation of—</text><paragraph id="H7E64673E1DD54DCDA0EF318EF8C0FC54"><enum>(1)</enum><text>this Act or the amendments made by this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A6390AB4E7B4914800451AEA9C0B9EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EB3C3D8605D4EA69999303BC2A501F5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8501">22 U.S.C. 8501 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D2ED9B7738045A5B595101215BE9A52"><enum>(4)</enum><text>section 1245 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8513a">22 U.S.C. 8513a</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DE4DF88998A48DDBFF1A79A77E56768"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8701">22 U.S.C. 8701 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H179F347806FF49E1B61E6440B69693D7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Iran Freedom and Counter-Proliferation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8801">22 U.S.C. 8801 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B42D913D3EA406BA79E3E524574D711"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3BC644C6EA6402791B9ECC287E9F2E9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>any other statute or Executive order that requires or authorizes the imposition of sanctions with respect to Iran.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0AD92F758D7F4667B8A1BC27837AFDB1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Each report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1BB7DBF2D57F44339FF9F84A263A15D1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H9E58BCF4CAD44B70A0DD83D015E067C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC7E8ECF9BF3426989471A3A5FD60EBE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H776CB20AF7FD41BFA92F2FA08C26F92C"><enum>405.</enum><header>Report on sanctions relief going to terrorism or destabilizing
 activities</header><subsection id="H78871680B47146B89135300C2825AE74"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of the State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing—</text><paragraph id="H1D32845412414C7FA9C8E23E60807D30"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the status of United States sanctions on Iran;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FDF548653834B8AB89B05DABB88AFC2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the reimposition and renewed enforcement of secondary sanctions on Iran;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H223501C883CA4E8E896CA9EF8C028E2B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the impact such sanctions have had on Iran’s support for terrorism including Hamas, Hezbollah, Palestinian Islamic Jihad, and other foreign terrorist organizations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6E26FE0C76B43AFB79746DA5125529E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the impact such sanctions have had on Iran’s military budget, including the budget of the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6EEE295D0CF4434883B7420F02B4FE1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the impact such sanctions have had on the budget and resources available to the Basij, and how such sanctions have affected the ability of the Basij to commit gross human rights abuses against the people of Iran;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D9B89E2775E47AF9E075A66516791BA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the impact such sanctions have had on Iran’s support to the al-Assad regime in Syria and to Iranian backed militias operating in Syria;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D217C8CC8844C7B951D5E5FB6BE6AD9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the impact that such sanctions have had on Iran’s support for Ansarallah, also known as the Houthis, in Yemen; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2FDF06CA4014E389C70B99562E83C1B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the impact that lifting such sanctions would have on Iran’s ability to commit human rights abuses against the people of Iraq, Syria, Lebanon, and Yemen, including a detailed description of whether lifting such sanctions would increase the resources available for Iran and its proxy militias to support gross human rights abuses such as torture, extrajudicial killings, or the killing of protesters in Iraq, Syria, Lebanon, and Yemen.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H29EF3FBFF69E4502B9E6BB6BD75BF193"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><paragraph id="H149E82BAD6364508A58F2A547E453E94"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex if necessary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H512719CA30B145C28ACEF430A06F93D8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability of information</header><text>The unclassified portion of such report shall be made available on a publicly available internet website of the Federal Government.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H64C63F69F92C4693BE37A156E57A4C27"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="HDF1DE09E75D14AEAB766D0DEFCB5F8F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9015E3F20329469387C6986585BFE74A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC7271728CDFF4F76B93B642068B82538" commented="no"><enum>406.</enum><header>Supporting human rights for the people of Iran and the victims of Iranian
 human rights abuses in Syria, Lebanon, Yemen, and Venezuela</header><subsection id="H7718E6816E114EC9BBFC84503F0AE77B" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It shall be the policy of the United States to—</text><paragraph id="HC77663E16AE7461682696E8C414A58FC" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support democracy and human rights in Iran, including the robust exercise by Iranians of the rights to freedom of speech and assembly;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFC3DCE29D034F4A8D97E29B87AA43E8" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>where possible, support the free flow of information into Iran to make it easier for Iranian citizens to communicate with 1 another and with the outside world;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2517A570B2FA41A7ABCDC489D2DB4175" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>hold Iran accountable for severe human rights abuses against its own people and the people of the Middle East and Latin America, including the peoples of Iraq, Syria, Lebanon Yemen, and Venezuela; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09DC82D9E12C45A1B66376BD0DF3EB5D" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>condemn any and all attacks against protesters by Iran or its sponsored militias.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0510100FD8BD40D186C5DA092D2C023B" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination with respect to the imposition of sanctions</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a determination, including a detailed justification, of whether any person listed in subsection (c) meets the criteria for—</text><paragraph id="H44DEE27CA0B141D089ABE41088FEF885" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the application of sanctions pursuant to section 105 of the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8514">22 U.S.C. 8514</external-xref>) or pursuant to the Mahsa Amini Human Rights and Security Accountability Act (division L of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/50">Public Law 118–50</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8501">22 U.S.C. 8501</external-xref> note); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E59354A776842DDB5B75B2D3012C51B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the application of sanctions pursuant to Executive Order 13553 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property of certain persons with respect to serious human rights abuses by the Government of Iran).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H94E00A3FA807470C8E4C8EE3FC147966" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Persons listed</header><text>The persons listed in this subsection are—</text><paragraph id="H81AE7261A27F454A9B0316A4A2FA0487" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, the Supreme Leader of Iran;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AED4EFA418E480BB3F51D3C7EA80587" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Gholamali Mohammadi, the head of Iran’s Prisons Organization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H485A1B6604F2440D88FE44E56E0F9D47" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Amin Hossein Rahimi, Iran’s Minister of Justice;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H798365D632DB4B7EA69997A090C0BB30" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Mohammad Ali Zolfigol, Iran’s Minister of Science;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H466CF659539B4DC5AD2090AC8070B4D5" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Mohammad Mehdi Esmaeili, Iran’s Minister of Culture;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27D30175D4AE4BB1A6FB85335E25633A" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Hassan Hassanzadeh, Iran’s Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps commander;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1733978709184FDF99B6941C8A97CE19" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Mohammed Reza Yazdi, IRGC commander;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B2E3CA45C004CA7BC3A73D0EA22D892" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Amin Vaziri, Deputy Prosecutor of Tehran and assistant supervisor of political prisoners in Evin prison;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB978FCBE058424FBBF50AA3267A02C3" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Heshmatollah Hayat Al-Ghayb, Tehran’s Director-General of Prisons;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43567D86130045F1A2BC566109D65AE8" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Allahkaram Azizi, Head of the Rajaie-Shahr prison in Karaj, Iran;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FA72029A89B4FD28B422D418EB551E7" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Ali Al-Qasi Mehr, Prosecutor General of Tehran;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C9C1B54CFC24F51B2C0BC7CFC7E00F6" commented="no"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Ali Hemmatian, IRGC interrogator; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DB3D66EB22E47A7BF27E0506D43A315" commented="no"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Masoud Safdari, IRGC interrogator.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB0296CFA8220447EA46E1453F8D06000" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H19C2D8F6910946FABD31F63A9DAA21BF" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB19A7E8D2624E90B5546D91CEB780B4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H21C4ACC727E3470BB087392FAE11C060"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Codification of Executive Orders</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following executive orders shall have the force and effect of enacted law:</text><paragraph id="HABBFC9AB92124D1B8062FB4DD78F7642"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 13876 (84 Fed. Reg. 30573).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0817BDADBEF44EE9AF2B7FE8CAABD625"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 13553 (75 Fed. Reg. 60567).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H535E608EDAF44F7EB824F4FDF8EE8643"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 13818 (82 Fed. Reg. 60839).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4BBCAB58C5D94B528156B5CD09BC3881" commented="no"><enum>407.</enum><header>Determination with respect to net worth of Iranian Supreme Leader Ayatollah
 Ali Khamenei</header><subsection id="H82B1893688614CCD835D16BA269DA682" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Determination required</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Director of National Intelligence, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the estimated net worth and known sources of income, including income from corrupt or illicit activities, of Iranian Supreme Leader Ali Khamenei and his family members (including spouse, children, siblings, and paternal and maternal cousins), including assets, investments, other business interests, and relevant beneficial ownership information. Such report shall also include shares in and ties to Iranian parastatal institutions or bonyaads, such as the Mostazafan Foundation and the Astan Quds Razavi, as well as the total estimated value of Mostazafan Foundation and the Astan Quds Razavi.</text></subsection><subsection id="H257EC5A4AC4B473AB291A9F081C7DB5F" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex. The unclassified portion of such report shall be made available on a publicly available internet website of the Federal Government.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2E8547DA946C4E16AAED453D6B12E31A" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H82276FA725CE493E9183122330BF05E4" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43F3C938D63F4387A1F0C8760F2B6FFE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H52EB38A48ACD4B3DBFBEB97611E322A6"><enum>408.</enum><header>IRGC watch list and report</header><subsection id="HE8C37F416E29433C83CAD6A191CC4131"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall establish, maintain, and publish in the Federal Register a list (to be known as the <quote>IRGC Watch List</quote>) of—</text><paragraph id="HA331CD20D0724148BD3B369FA70BAC97"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each entity in which the IRGC has an ownership interest of less than 25 percent;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9C2BB72F48040E4BD3D2E420F844E80"><enum>(2)</enum><text>each entity in which the IRGC does not have an ownership interest if the IRGC maintains a presence on the board of directors of the entity or otherwise influences the actions, policies, or personnel decisions of the entity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8AFB8779F984CFFA3032B8021826AF7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>each person that owns or controls an entity described in paragraph (1) or (2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC0ECB6AA26D4450DB426108687261B8A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports required</header><paragraph id="H78A62540ADDC416A8E5E9DCD4DCEE209"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Treasury report</header><subparagraph id="HE73F0EBCC6524635AB15ACD4DF0283A3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text><clause id="HF0D644765D3B4511B6553B23C8C1AAD0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the list required by subsection (a) and, in the case of any report submitted under this subparagraph after the first such report, any changes to the list since the submission of the preceding such report; and</text></clause><clause id="H8529F87733004D6A9E12B859144A6ED7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an assessment of the role of the IRGC in, and its penetration into, the economy of Iran.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5F95CABBDBD4C338D2243FE3AF21C60"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>Each report required by subparagraph (A) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex if necessary. The unclassified portion of such report shall be made available on a publicly available internet website of the Federal Government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D9240A83B074D3FA9D62B2EB503DE60"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Government accountability office report</header><subparagraph id="HAEB680DA1BA84BB0AD1FF48A8195F1B1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text><clause id="HCA1D64E4395B4C30981EE76C901A7CF1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conduct a review of the list required by subsection (a); and</text></clause><clause id="H988F595FBA8843CCA28EB63622E7CCEE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after each report required by paragraph (1) is submitted to Congress, submit to Congress a report on the review conducted under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8AE8CAB7D7E4961B0874C5918ACE13B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consultations</header><text>In preparing the report required by subparagraph (A)(ii), the Comptroller General shall consult with nongovernmental organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4287964137174180B929FF6FBA32688F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H2E17FD5A379145D7BB476D03BF22C9B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9233B94C1A65483D8ED0B29728571B04"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H189C834F7EFA4E6D92DFD0B39FAB0B67"><enum>409.</enum><header>Report on Iran’s breakout timeline for uranium enrichment and nuclear
 weaponization</header><subsection id="H48CB03FB847A44338514FA9B385C81D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of the State, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="H7A2EAE7E3000497E844E22251732ADE2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of Iran’s estimated breakout timeline for uranium enrichment to achieve the fissile material necessary for a nuclear weapon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H152CAEBD5F6E4910B38F62E1711D18AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assessment of Iran’s estimated weaponization timeline to obtain a nuclear weapon.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7171CDC62D6649678D9BE380D26E338A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="HA8B333A5C9C34E5488FD25191007D7EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE01F881A93EC4E15BA3B6408D4425FB0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H45F9ABA362684507A575203C8511FE7A"><enum>410.</enum><header>Report on Iranian disinformation campaigns and counter-disinformation
 efforts</header><subsection id="HB6CB541D9EE34A388182827F922D4756"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Global Engagement Center (GEC) of the Department of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing—</text><paragraph id="H096E25575DE74FB39D4589DEB5EA07B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the scope of Iranian disinformation efforts around the world including in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A3D38FAB7D84D08B06517532D199D24"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the objectives of Iran’s disinformation campaign, the means used by Iran to further such campaigns, and the mechanisms by which Iran spreads disinformation and propaganda; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D898ABE986B4F99B64C58AED55F23F6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a detailed strategy regarding how the GEC intends to counter disinformation efforts conducted by Iran.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H36FC3ED0ED5D4D6FA576E7782E7D7FA5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex if necessary. The unclassified portion of such report shall be made available on a publicly available internet website of the Federal Government.</text></subsection><subsection id="H099DF9621A3440B48B6BD10AB91A36B7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="HE5C971E7A4D247CB8EA58FAD1C26E6F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85CE79C588064F9DBFEC7433B012AD00"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H963E2C64887D49349B5DD7F914F89052" commented="no"><enum>411.</enum><header>Report on Iranian support to Hamas</header><subsection id="H0E23C915ACF944D3AB91C2383697FD83" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing—</text><paragraph id="HABF8688A068745A8B09C2DBAB8DBAE23" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the extent of Hamas’ funding by Iran;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0275E7B593F64F2BA1642312C7D56300" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the extent regarding how the enforcement of United States sanctions on Iranian oil affect the resources of Hamas; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2603D5269F9B4DBC8B57453FC4A7BA15" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of how the enforcement of United States sanctions on Iran during the period of 2019–2020 as compared to 2021–2023 affected Hamas budgets.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H90B9E1AF6990480193CCF27A76B790F0" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex if necessary. The unclassified portion of such report shall be made available on a publicly available internet website of the Federal Government.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5B4799DC2D3048D28A442D9105A1BFD9" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H1865149F0112471E840D2D55E0117121" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FE6F3C6E4B343F3B2FF2B7A56ACF1AE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAEC6ACB1BC4C4C5D833823A4D2FB3282" commented="no"><enum>412.</enum><header>Report on unblocked Iranian assets and terrorism</header><subsection id="H0AB84871868845A995C6A288BB39CD2A" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing—</text><paragraph id="H27F503456FD44FCF9C61286FC1BA2786" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>whether any sanctions relating to Iran which have been waived, suspended, reduced, or otherwise relieved within the 3 years prior to the enactment of this Act have freed up resources for Iran to provide support to foreign terrorist organizations and other proxy militia groups; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8C11BCE43B64119830E4CF174A941AA" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the extent to which any sanctions relating to Iran which have been waived, suspended, reduced, or otherwise relieved within the last 3 year period, have provided increased resources to the IRGC or any other foreign terrorist organization or proxy militia group.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD349E8D2501F4C8B9E73EFFCF77F156D" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex if necessary. The unclassified portion of such report shall be made available on a publicly available internet website of the Federal Government.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF0F574DF54554A49B9C41B84387F668B" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="HD5B52074189A4CF4B525B699F488D071" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46DF0A36F9714674AA60E6DC164B18E2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H52353D4A08F447858F66456298EFBB33"><enum>413.</enum><header>Report on Iranian counterintelligence threats in the United States</header><subsection id="H8D8BCFA019A74D4C9161588A25397A8D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General jointly with the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing—</text><paragraph id="HE5D27CAA038A4480BBF97153CDAC19A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the scope of Iranian counterintelligence threats;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEEE438143C74B709168CE23ACA35092"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a determination regarding whether agents of the Government of Iran have sought employment or have been employed in positions in the United States Federal Government;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2947511A362E4A139984DB0B7758FFB3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of Iranian espionage, influence, and infiltration efforts in the United States, to include an assessment of the role of the Iran Experts Initiative in these efforts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA714953E977C4A3AB53EE9EC7686ADFC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a strategy to counter Iranian espionage, influence, and infiltration efforts in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H00C31857347E420DA5049993EC09B134"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex if necessary. The unclassified portion of such report shall be made available on a publicly available internet website of the Federal Government.</text></subsection><subsection id="HABE6433A31F04B01B4596F0977C7888C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H674861F4F0974F5CA83B0546E424BAD2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H249ADCA72FE544F68D4F19F2D308B89C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="HDB45A928484B40C1AAC02A0A38C31003"><enum>V</enum><header>Additional Matters</header><section id="H6F9E68CEB3E442979063BE5E22C8A771"><enum>501.</enum><header>Increasing rewards for justice for Hamas, Hezbollah, the Islamic
                    Revolutionary Guard Corps and other terrorists involved in October 7, 2023,
 terrorist attacks against Israel</header><subsection id="HBAB18105B44C4247AC51EFE9F239255C"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Section 36(b) of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2708">22 U.S.C. 2708(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H43B0800AD4284CC5AF73EECF6EF6A805"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (13), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H73C157918B3145359732690C09B130BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (14), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F1C84ED1E90403C9392321C8476ACED"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="H1102A0BD26404AD1BD95BE2C774D13B3" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HF135824180D9400D9B2139F66439A588"><enum>(15)</enum><text>the arrest or conviction in any country of any individual who is—</text><subparagraph id="HA41D59CAE2564861A6EB42D5B172A913"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a member of Hamas, Palestinian Islamic Jihad, Hezbollah, the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps, or any other foreign terrorist organization that participated in or helped fund or plan the October 7, 2023, terrorist attack against Israel; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7544D2C0B2C641A79414DE29CB5AD83B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a leader of Hamas, Palestinian Islamic Jihad, Hezbollah, the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps, or any other foreign terrorist organization aligned with or affiliated with the Islamic Republic of Iran.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H988B129FA454447981E8CAEB68653B35"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Paragraph (1) of section 36(e) of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2708">22 U.S.C. 2708(e)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows—</text><quoted-block id="H8C40D615352A402FAB83D3ECF7FEA5C7" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H663FF8881E014181899BB9F69088110B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Maximum amount</header><subparagraph id="HAA816CFC2ACE46A78E7BA0F0EA90555F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>No reward paid under this section may exceed $25,000,000, except—</text><clause id="H119C6E7E71C14C46AA160D723EACB888"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as personally authorized by the Secretary of State if they determine that offer or payment of an award of a larger amount is necessary to combat terrorism or defend the Nation against terrorist acts; or</text></clause><clause id="HDD70BFF53C2F43CE94591D49A6EF16D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the reward is for the capture or information leading to the capture of any individual described in paragraph (15) of subsection (b) of this section.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1950FDA6F01D41EBB268D69AD3694519"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Without first making such determination, the Secretary may authorize a reward of up to twice the amount specified in this paragraph for the capture or information leading to the capture of a leader of a foreign terrorist organization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HFB388EEE1A5D42DE9DF9A2BB2742A27C"><enum>502.</enum><header>Repurposing frozen Iranian funds for United States Victims of State
 Sponsored Terrorism fund</header><paragraph id="H2CD2DFEB6FE24187A95E6ABDBE988DE1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the enactment of this Act, the President shall make available for the United States Victims of State Sponsored Terrorism Fund—</text><subparagraph id="HC842918EE6AC41C890CA4AB058D8EE8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>those funds transferred from the Republic of Korea to Qatar pursuant to the waiver exercised pursuant to section 1245(d)(5) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 and sections 1244(i) and 1247(f) of the Iran Freedom and Counter-Proliferation Act of 2012 and transmitted to Congress on September 11, 2023; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17EA33BBDDFA41339B1E6BCF6778A52F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other funds held with respect to United States sanctions on the Islamic Republic of Iran that the President determines is appropriate to be made available to the United States Victims of State Sponsored Terrorism Fund.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CDE67F533B4450C85AF1B714AC72710"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as to deny payments from the United States Victims of State Sponsored Terrorism Fund to the victims of the October 7, 2023, attack in Israel who file an eligible claim under subsection (c) of section 20144 of the Justice of United States Victims of State Sponsored Terrorism Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20144">34 U.S.C. 20144(c)</external-xref>) after the President has already made the funds described in paragraph (1) of this section available to the United States Victims of State Sponsored Terrorism Fund.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H54EA84F1DB994A5F828E7A152491BB89"><enum>503.</enum><header>Determination regarding applicable Iranian financial institutions under
 executive order 13902</header><paragraph id="H19102D4928B14F6E92D94C70D8E55A40"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination required</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury shall, in consultation with the Secretary of State, determine whether any Iranian financial institution to which the applicable sanctions under Executive Order 13902 have not already been applied qualifies for such sanctions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H92C350BAF9024224B22F624DEFF1E59C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sanctions required</header><text>Should the Secretary of the Treasury determine that any institution qualifies for the applicable sanctions in Executive Order 13902, then the Secretary shall impose the applicable sanctions described in the order on the qualifying institution.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H606D42CD8244483EB9DB224924FC8402" commented="no"><enum>504.</enum><header>Maximizing the ability of Iranian terror victims to collect on existing
 judgments against Iran</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1605A of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H96FED3F3AF984F9387ECD1DD27CC2ECC" style="OLC"><subsection id="H17DBF92B28324DFDACB00521015B0FAA" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Report on Collection of Judgments Against Iran</header><paragraph id="H99889980F4B7417C9DF04785B63AE281" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of State, shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a report detailing available legal and practical mechanisms for victims awarded judgments under this section to enforce and collect on such judgments against Iran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3EF665FAD70943C5BC8665EAF5C32D68" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of Report</header><text>The report shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H376F7FDA6BE44B648F07D0C86740F25C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of Iranian assets within the jurisdiction of the United States that could be subject to attachment or execution;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF47FEE075E38420FBC06836A5963714B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations for legislative or executive actions to facilitate the satisfaction of such judgments; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FD05E2E4BBE42258632F95CEAFB170D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an analysis of existing impediments to the collection of these judgments and proposed solutions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HD9795EB533134164996F7E060B8FEBB3" commented="no"><enum>505.</enum><header>Creation of Iran Strike Fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Stop Harboring Iranian Petroleum Act (22 U.S.C. 8501 et seq) is amended by inserting after section 5 the following:</text><quoted-block id="H978A0C53E19643549D0D659334131C2D" style="OLC"><section id="HB328932CDBB9428F8D3980F50BD579D6" commented="no"><enum>5A.</enum><header>Iran labor strike and civil society support fund</header><subsection id="HBF80E6B78ADB4F509A203917F4720F10" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of Fund</header><text>There is established a fund to be known as the <quote>Iran Labor Strike and Civil Society Support Fund</quote> (hereinafter referred to as the <quote>Fund</quote>), which shall provide financial assistance to Iranian workers engaging in labor strikes and support for families of political prisoners and individuals who have lost income earners due to political repression.</text></subsection><subsection id="H621721FCE9DE47DABEADDD2A02071BF7" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding Sources</header><text>The Fund shall be financed through—</text><paragraph id="HAF920EE5FABB496C991025877B7EB149" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>penalties and fines collected from violations of Iran-related sanctions laws;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE185E7BBA4F477EA0AA0DED4FC8B929" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>asset forfeitures from Iranian regime officials and entities found to be in violation of Untied States laws; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59F0BD1E6A564BCCAAE7D03756DAE4E5" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other funds as may be appropriated by Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H35EC1E8F05F04DE1BE9E1524DA075590" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall administer the Fund and establish eligibility criteria for recipients, ensuring accountability and transparency in the distribution of funds.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H44D504904458462EB6806DC8E1DE863D" commented="no"><enum>506.</enum><header>Iran Kleptocracy Initiative</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Chapter 95 of part 1 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after section 1959 the following:</text><quoted-block id="H3F522C1E7C5B4DDAA5774B97454DA298" style="OLC"><section id="H57B733A92AD44D0588CE5F755A8AA238" commented="no"><enum>1959A.</enum><header>Iran Kleptocracy Initiative</header><subsection id="H1C2D1996B99945BEB440EDAD5AEF303B" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Attorney General shall establish an <quote>Iran Kleptocracy Initiative</quote> to investigate, expose, and counteract corruption among Iranian government officials.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFC78479A60F84E96BEB0EA20E6B04E67" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The Initiative shall—</text><paragraph id="H6714EAC48CBB4F8E87F2ED9CD9549657" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify assets held by Iranian government officials and their proxies, including those concealed through family members;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94617838D249400B983DC31EBEB16E9E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>work with the Department of the Treasury and allied governments to freeze, seize, and, where appropriate, repurpose illicitly acquired assets;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42483FFD7E594477AB374C72EAA7653B" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>publish findings regarding corrupt practices within the Iranian regime;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC20D7B6921B4C0AB65F9455F93A4E0A" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>coordinate with domestic and international law enforcement agencies to facilitate prosecutions and asset recoveries; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C4102FE381C4B6DB4C270C83B7415A3" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>submit an annual report to Congress on actions taken under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></title></legis-body></bill>


