<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCD8FAC966CB8420ABDA7AF732E6565BF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1398 IH: Securing Strictly Needy Americans’ Pivotal (SNAP) Benefits Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1398</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250218">February 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2023, to limit the conditions applicable to the use of electronic benefit transfer (EBT) cards to purchase food, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H357A95178CDA4551BC277E3D5566E806" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA0373C75491B42A0B33362A6F35566BB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing Strictly Needy Americans’ Pivotal (SNAP) Benefits Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H12DD19826C744AF3A9D55494B58699E5" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendment to Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2023</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 501 of title IV of division HH of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2023, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7E5E068112AD46A78F39F1C2FDE3FFF9" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H8614FC7E111E486D846FA576E421FC10"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Exclusively out-of-State purchases</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State agency shall suspend the accounts of households for which EBT card transactions are made exclusively out-of-State for a period longer than 60 days, until—</text> <paragraph id="HBA1C75DFF6D24199BD5BE419F7AE1A83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the household affirmatively provides substantiating evidence that the members of the household who are program participants still reside in the state from which they receive benefits; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H31FBF1667BD54D4392A46C36A43C2359"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an investigation is conducted and conclusively determines that the members of the household who are program participants still reside in the state from which they receive benefits.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HFD88E38D183C4BC3909B061BBFABC03B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitation on redemption of supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits by owners of approved retail food stores and wholesale food concerns</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 9 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2020">7 U.S.C. 2020</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2628285A695E47A996694AD95F481F85" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H7FF42E8687DA48AE844F475AB89052AA"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Limitation on redemption of supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits by households that include members who are owners of approved retail food stores or wholesale food concerns</header> 
<paragraph id="H3FF1455848934B8C96EF13B1D790E935"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A household that includes a member who is an owner of an approved retail food store or wholesale food concern may not redeem supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits at such store or such concern.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E04994ED2E74AEFBE46D784707CF984"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to a retail food store, or a wholesale food concern, that is owned by a publicly owned corporation or by a government.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HAAB560E9BC9B4212A3D22081ADAAB133"><enum>4.</enum><header> Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

