<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA32DCC23949C4D4DA7D90853C5E64BE0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 562 IH: Boosting Long-term U.S. Engagement in the Pacific Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 562</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250120">January 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To advance a comprehensive, long-term United States strategy and policy for the Pacific Islands, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H78D304EF6870466AA2F2500CE673C41C" style="OLC"><section id="HE1B228E51C9D4343A296BBAC8FD034EE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title and table of contents</header><subsection id="HD82FADF39A2B4185A2802C027EDC309F" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Boosting Long-term U.S. Engagement in the Pacific Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BLUE Pacific Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA86BA0EA953F4A65AE8833DF8AAC1CA7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="HE1B228E51C9D4343A296BBAC8FD034EE" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title and table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H562EA493764B4025A5C30AA040A7B271" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H8975E37F5F954837926A22E2D34B80CF" level="section">Sec. 3. Authority to consolidate reports; form of reports.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H413A777C0E8D47ECBF41E2C7C8239FAA" level="title">Title I—Political Leadership and Regionalism</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2E66FF8513B440E6BE97AF1D4A1539F1" level="section">Sec. 101. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9F3180C4B3624E80BB5499909D20BC32" level="section">Sec. 102. Statement of policy.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HDD1370C79DDA476C87F3AE05174B38BB" level="section">Sec. 103. Strategy for Pacific Islands Partnership.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H03E8EFC44C00455CA4443CD1CC2B50FE" level="section">Sec. 104. Staffing.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5DBBF71BC8F34F39938EAF650F3258AA" level="section">Sec. 105. Strategic communications in the Pacific Islands.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD1A7AB443A954D8EBDA34A0010E8303D" level="section">Sec. 106. Assistance with international organizations.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H43E229D53EF747D8852BF4AA1BFD0CF4" level="section">Sec. 107. Allies and partners in the Pacific Islands region.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA401DD72578B4F3F9DA63C6F039D3AF5" level="section">Sec. 108. Extension of diplomatic immunities to the Pacific Islands Forum.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H799817E478DC4C6F9B001628AFBF67C9" level="section">Sec. 109. Ambassador’s Self-Help Small Grants Program.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H673A0BDB35284EA59DCEAB13D8901676" level="section">Sec. 110. Establishing a senior official for the Compacts of Free Association at the Department of State.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H282C62459FAD410FA7B87BAEC5C85135" level="title">Title II—People-Centered Development</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H1A154B1FECFB4612BC95D63A8037EFD6" level="section">Sec. 201. Assistance to improve public health outcomes and build public health capacity.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H8D354C286D5E49669961CC3D03379063" level="section">Sec. 202. Assistance to promote freedom of the press.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H48349FBE654A498995CFD0995030AB24" level="section">Sec. 203. Indo-Pacific Media Advancement Program.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7E38E4A4D24A4EA0B75DF3CA294CC380" level="section">Sec. 204. Program to promote educational and professional development for young adult leaders and professionals.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H925EBB113685494992D18703620F0B03" level="section">Sec. 205. Education assistance.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HC88BA9A2321546C79273998224005188" level="section">Sec. 206. People-to-people ties.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA427061DDD604B64B6271BF0EDFD7490" level="section">Sec. 207. Pacific Islands TRADES Program.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HDC5FE621E12544E2994B0783FF585824" level="section">Sec. 208. Investment agreements.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7B86E29F126E4E7B98218C86C20342DC" level="section">Sec. 209. Committee on Engagement with Civil Society Organizations in the Pacific Islands.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7EDC7832C8F44341890B2334A68D3778" level="section">Sec. 210. American Spaces in the Pacific Islands.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2A70278E38F242F88A6A4BF5476CC175" level="title">Title III—Peace and Security</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H0CEEB60F6C4442578538AAD3430C5E5D" level="section">Sec. 301. Building the capacity of local civilian and national security institutions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H81337BDA5A8549DBB74EF8A35A8E051A" level="section">Sec. 302. Reporting.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H940708669FF34DFCA11D0DC83A372D0C" level="section">Sec. 303. International Law Enforcement Academy.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6EDFC9CBD12046B5BF825347A0B8B84F" level="title">Title IV—Resource and Economic Development</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H882907F324574280B6A3738FDE3E04AB" level="section">Sec. 401. Trade development with the Pacific Islands.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HEDF5768B90EE4C6D85A9BEA00D8A5DCB" level="section">Sec. 402. Trade capacity building initiative for the Pacific Islands.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H504A1442F64C4A81B6AA3CB44982303C" level="section">Sec. 403. United States Commercial Service.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6B87E97F919D4876B8A5F56CEF942754" level="title">Title V—Environmental and disaster resilience</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HAE1E6C0A0AB241B6BE6490432D7D138A" level="section">Sec. 501. Assistance to enhance preparedness for and resilience to natural disasters and other emergencies.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF3346C3A2272415C9750D5D55E231F14" level="section">Sec. 502. Climate resilient infrastructure.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF07D5A70D4824223A4B0192111BBC134" level="title">Title VI—Ocean and Environment</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA1741EB6D8E44CB29D7159818CEF3360" level="section">Sec. 601. Oceans management.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H192AD752798E4F3682A1E4EAAD6924B0" level="section">Sec. 602. Sea level rise.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5A9DDB083687496C9A2453E05737A820" level="section">Sec. 603. Illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H3D8438B0D32049DDB6EAB32A0E1625AE" level="title">Title VII—Technology and Connectivity</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H63114357F04D4290BC311AF9B540D79B" level="section">Sec. 701. Digital access and inclusion.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H97B1CC2B5E10498EA998F3D98A3BF803" level="section">Sec. 702. Cybersecurity.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H369C2E7C908C452F90556141E2B1ED2A" level="title">Title VIII—Report on the Strategy for Pacific Islands Partnership and Authorization of Appropriations</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HDB7B6DC5C44A42FDA1B474707A59EEA1" level="section">Sec. 801. Report on the Strategy for Pacific Islands Partnership.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2F90B50D0FC742528FBB20705499400C" level="section">Sec. 802. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="H562EA493764B4025A5C30AA040A7B271"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HC19189B6A98F41C9B0B7C3C142218D60"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>Except as otherwise provided, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H1D2F9619798E4441B49DCA01A6D0599D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8AE46CF51F24136971376BA964CB7BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H562D9EF68FA74DDD876D53C15C103382"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Pacific Islands</header><text>The terms <term>Pacific Islands</term> means the Cook Islands, the Republic of Fiji, the Republic of Kiribati, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of Nauru, Niue, the Republic of Palau, the Independent State of Papua New Guinea, the Independent State of Samoa, the Solomon Islands, the Kingdom of Tonga, Tuvalu, and the Republic of Vanuatu.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H8975E37F5F954837926A22E2D34B80CF" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authority to consolidate reports; form of reports</header><subsection id="H2A08E27A59DA492CB03371D9262B9F43" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To consolidate reports</header><text>Any reports required to be submitted to the appropriate congressional committees under this Act that are subject to deadlines for submission consisting of the same units of time may be consolidated into a single report that is submitted to the appropriate congressional committees pursuant to such deadlines and that contains all information required under such reports.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE89927255B484E469699FF4903F89948" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form of reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report required to be submitted to the appropriate congressional committees under this Act and any consolidated report described in subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection></section><title id="H413A777C0E8D47ECBF41E2C7C8239FAA"><enum>I</enum><header>Political Leadership and Regionalism</header><section id="H2E66FF8513B440E6BE97AF1D4A1539F1"><enum>101.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H7C8811741583419C8042C94B325282B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Pacific Islands—</text><subparagraph id="HCABA50691D254B2AA98A121087A7BC4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are home to roughly 12,300,000 residents;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BCDD772AB1949CCAEB4E3253D1BD373"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are spread across an expanse of the Pacific Ocean equivalent to 15 percent of the Earth’s surface, including the three subregions of Melanesia, Micronesia, and Polynesia; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B88FC86F14C4A31B9DA7E9384AD9180"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">face shared challenges in development that have distinct local contexts, including unique environmental challenges and rising sea levels, geographic distances from major markets, and vulnerability to external shocks such as natural disasters in both slow and sudden onset situations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H90184A0385324A90A1B0C4C67AB5F297"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The United States is a Pacific country with longstanding ties and shared values and interests with the Pacific Islands, including through the Compacts of Free Association with the Freely Associated States, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, and the Republic of Palau.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65D9B9D98C304FEFBB719245E8E815F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The United States has vital national security interests in the Pacific Islands, including—</text><subparagraph id="H318061F522554E8C9D3FFAAF782885E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>protecting regional peace and security that fully respects the sovereignty of all nations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0E3411E05FF40E9B3408F6D81D5933C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advancing economic prosperity free from coercion and unfair practices through trade and sustainable development; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D7C5159D4A64D0D9B7177A2E77A0456"><enum>(C)</enum><text>supporting democracy, good governance, the rule of law, and human rights and fundamental freedoms.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD1C29EF547A434B96B59FE44F024D57"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Successive United States administrations have recognized the importance of the Pacific region, including the Pacific Islands, in high-level strategic documents, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="H344BB805DEDD48038A50D714DB67FB24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 2015 National Security Strategy, which first declared the rebalance to Asia and the Pacific, affirmed the United States as a Pacific nation, and paved the way for subsequent United States engagement with the Pacific Islands, including several new policies focused on conservation and environmental resilience announced in September 2016.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE2FBE8F99604DC0AB6ACDB044894986"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 2017 National Security Strategy, which includes a commitment to <quote>shore up fragile partner states in the Pacific Islands region to reduce their vulnerability to economic fluctuations and natural disasters</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5A9E36A1BE24A3DB54520336D4340A4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The 2019 Indo-Pacific Strategy Report, which identified the Pacific Islands as <quote>critical to U.S. strategy because of our shared values, interests, and commitments</quote> and committed the United States to <quote>building capacity and resilience to address maritime security; Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated fishing; drug trafficking; and resilience to address climate change and disaster response</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF57082C75065409F9355D6C1190E516F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The 2022 Indo-Pacific Strategy Report, which recognized the need to engage further with the Pacific Islands on shared security goals.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9D608E6E66C46CEAFBB2E62C9E86A93"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The 2022 Strategy for Pacific Island Partnership, which outlined goals and methods for deepening the United States partnerships with Pacific Island nations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E5010CFBF12400D95EC12BD86F8527C"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 2022 National Security Strategy, which identified the Pacific Islands as an area of particular focus for expansion of regional diplomatic, development, and economic engagement in the broader Indo-Pacific. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7909EC0B1E74D9696F966AF46C8C8F6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The United States has deepened its diplomatic engagement with the Pacific Islands through several recent initiatives, including—</text><subparagraph id="HDC2AA66F920643F5ABFF81A362963189"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Pacific Pledge, which provided an additional $100,000,000 in 2019 and $200,000,000 in 2020, in addition to the foreign assistance that the United States provided annually to the region, to support shared priorities in economic and human development, environmental resilience, and more; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H122AED609A9B403987C06055BB5FC5A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Small and Less Populous Island Economies (SALPIE) Initiative launched in March 2021 to strengthen United States collaboration with island countries and territories, including in the Pacific Islands, on COVID–19 economic challenges, long-term economic development, climate change, and other shared interests;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H186D9537A71E46A880B5464364AA3544"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the declaration on U.S.-Pacific Partnership of 2022 in which the United States and the Pacific Islands resolved to strengthen their partnership, bolstering Pacific regionalism; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23723D6DA5A6475380A9D4A683C2E3F0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Partners in the Blue Pacific Initiative, a new initiative, to increase diplomatic engagement and coordination in the region; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1665279CB33482796D56EA14E198257"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the establishment of a U.S.-Pacific Islands Summit held in Washington, DC in 2022 and 2023; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1ED6F81F17DD41E3B87C3FBDD6431797"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the increase in the total amount of United States foreign assistance provided to the Pacific Islands, from $302,500,000 in fiscal year 2022 to $466,100,000 in fiscal year 2023. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H36CE8FB508AE46149F74C246501F6BCE"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Boe Declaration on Regional Security, adopted in 2018 by leaders of the Pacific Islands Forum, the central multilateral organization of the Pacific Islands and partners, affirmed that climate change <quote>remains the single greatest threat to the livelihoods, security, and well-being of the peoples of the Pacific</quote> and asserted <quote>the sovereign right of every Member to conduct its national affairs free of external interference and coercion</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1CB498F3BD2464A99016FC368768242"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Asian Development Bank has estimated that the Pacific Islands region requires upwards of $2,800,000,000 a year in investment through 2030, in addition to $300,000,000 a year for climate mitigation and adaptation over the same period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3451CEB690A14882800E5AF93DC1AA78"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Since 1966, thousands of Peace Corps volunteers have proudly served in the Pacific Islands, building strong people-to-people relationships and partnerships demonstrating the United States commitment to peace and sustainable development in the region, including supporting education, health, and economic development initiatives. Since having to suspend operations during the COVID–19 pandemic, the Peace Corps has reopened its posts in Fiji, Tonga, Samoa, and Vanuatu and has signed a Memorandum of Understanding with Palau regarding its intent to reopen that post by the end of 2025. Peace Corps volunteers continue to be in high demand in the Pacific Islands and have been requested across the region. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H9F3180C4B3624E80BB5499909D20BC32"><enum>102.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph id="H74508511717C4FFAA8D48CDE4A565494"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to articulate and commit to a comprehensive, multifaceted, and principled United States policy in the Pacific Islands that—</text><subparagraph id="H29A3690683D04843A75F1FA98FBF6B34"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promotes peace, security, and prosperity for all countries through a rules-based regional order that respects the sovereignty, self-determination, and political independence of all nations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94B52CBFAE484C10B059370D12FED86A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preserves the Pacific Ocean as an open and vibrant corridor for international maritime trade and promotes trade and sustainable development that supports inclusive economic growth and autonomy for all nations and addresses socioeconomic and environmental challenges related to public health, education, renewable energy, digital connectivity, and more;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFE25AFA5BC7483E912BEA3409A68D74"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports regional efforts to strengthen resilience to natural disasters and through responsible stewardship of natural resources and the needs for collective action to mitigate its impacts and build resilience; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AAA24D6D6D44988AEDBCA6F803BE09F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>improves civil society, strengthens democratic governance and the rule of law, and promotes human rights and the preservation of the region’s unique cultural heritages; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H174D61F80A5048948F952A976073266A"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports existing regional architecture and the international rules-based order and principles of international law;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H81C6A64DE1784D2D9EC16F3DD6917BAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to support the vision, values, and objectives of existing regional multilateral institutions and frameworks, such as the Pacific Islands Forum and the Pacific Community, including—</text><subparagraph id="H1165C395C8784EE3BE6A0FFD4B02EC23"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the 2000 Biketawa Declaration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2D0C497BBAA42F3B7B924F4471E3382"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the 2014 Framework for Pacific Regionalism;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB163DA31C3A842539846DDB45279160E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the 2018 Boe Declaration on Regional Security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D84D1FC310B489AB481A6FD3893BA1E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Boe Declaration Action Plan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05CFFB9206A64CFB9855F3237BEBCA61"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the 2050 Strategy for the Blue Pacific Continent; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF656DCAF53AB41B59623BB2C28EC1086"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to work closely with United States allies and partners with existing relationships and interests in the Pacific Islands, including Australia, New Zealand, Japan, South Korea, Taiwan, the United Kingdom, France, Germany, and India, in advancing common goals.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HDD1370C79DDA476C87F3AE05174B38BB"><enum>103.</enum><header>Strategy for Pacific Islands Partnership</header><subsection id="HCBA5FFFF209840EEAA498AC458306356"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2027, and every 4 years thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy to be known as the <quote>Strategy for Pacific Islands Partnership</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Strategy</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H137DFF9981264D77B97BBBCC3D774AF6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The Strategy shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H9B146484E4CE4F31847AD1D237A0C832"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of overarching goals for the United States-Pacific Island Partnership.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E2779CE67A24CFD84328527F6D1BAFA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of measurable objectives for United States engagement in the Pacific Islands.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3148A47C07EC4654A0C0EEDC2DCE10EA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of threats to the Pacific Islands region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80F89E1150E44DB6A8EC390EF73B765E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A plan to address the security of the Pacific Islands region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H08CD5836B45A45E79A9DBD05D598BFED"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A strategy to invest in and improve critical infrastructure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H23A64D9389EF44B09DFCDEF315EA0185"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A regional Development Cooperation Strategy formulated by the United States Agency for International Development.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE42528706A244C5CACDCBE7B337433B2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the Strategy, the President should consult, as appropriate, with—</text><paragraph id="H6076C8E23E124C26936D004833479700"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regional organizations, such as the Pacific Islands Forum, the Pacific Islands Development Program, the Pacific Community and Secretariat for the Pacific Regional Environment Programme;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H279F44445F6B4F5F89CBF3EF4600D672"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the countries of the Pacific Islands;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77F893B465F24BDFA47DB8B034C07FC3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">stakeholders such as civil society, faith-based organizations, and non-state actors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5E16B0EFE534F74A9C4C7A562ED0F40"><enum>(4)</enum><text>United States allies and partners; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93686F7CD6D14196A6AC013695595F76"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States Pacific territories and States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD9F781E332F14AA0A1323DDF393F5500"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In implementing the Strategy, the President shall coordinate with the heads of other Federal agencies, including the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Commerce, the Administrator of United States Agency for International Development, the Secretary of Defense, and the United States Trade Representative.</text></subsection></section><section id="H03E8EFC44C00455CA4443CD1CC2B50FE" commented="no"><enum>104.</enum><header>Staffing</header><subsection id="H9690E5E2C5A54643ACA6D87B56BEAC24" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Chief Executive Officer of the United States International Development Finance Corporation shall endeavor to increase the number of staff working on Pacific Islands issues and in the Pacific Islands to carry out this Act. </text></subsection><subsection id="H31D94C77A0FD4316AE690BE1490B5603" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Commerce are authorized to hire locally-employed staff in the Pacific Islands to promote increased diplomatic engagement and economic and commercial engagement between the United States and the Pacific Islands.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5DBBF71BC8F34F39938EAF650F3258AA"><enum>105.</enum><header>Strategic communications in the Pacific Islands</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development and the Secretary of Defense, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy for strategic communications in the Pacific Islands, including—</text><paragraph id="H307C2D4EC4FD4B5AA925435026B1C258"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a review of such communications, including United States interagency and multilateral efforts with like-minded partners; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BBD64F178E9485082E4483056A337DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assessment of the resources being used for such communications, including the number of staff devoted to such communications, the location of such staff, and the funds appropriated for such communications; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7920714FBA5346C1A323361114F66659"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of any additional resources needed for such communications; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H337A10F385CF4A41B304A3EA83EE79B5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an assessment of how United States engagement is being perceived in the Pacific Islands and how such perception might be improved; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H675D9CB90E654E22BD723E3FEADC30B5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an assessment of how engagement by other actors is being perceived in the Pacific Islands; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36D1B0BBF457405693BB408F2D6C5B17"><enum>(6)</enum><text>specific recommendations for the expansion and improvement of such communications.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HD1A7AB443A954D8EBDA34A0010E8303D"><enum>106.</enum><header>Assistance with international organizations</header><subsection id="HE6A64858B2894E0890902017746A8496"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Chief Executive Officer of the United States International Development Finance Corporation, as appropriate, shall provide support and technical assistance to Pacific Islands countries to assist such countries to access existing development support and funding from international organizations, such as the United Nations and multilateral financial institutions. Such support and technical assistance may include—</text><paragraph id="HEA063EBAA2B940BEBAD017C9A47D3283"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">technical support navigating grant programs, international investment mechanisms, and other opportunities offered by international organizations for sustainable development;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80CF116E5130402EAC5460EAF98E9C19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support receiving necessary certifications and complying with technical requirements to participate in international financial mechanisms from which Pacific Islands countries may benefit; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD672DF3E050A4AB2BAED6B3D7767EE7D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support complying with reporting and oversight requirements for programs conducted by international organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDB6D4EC7185542DE9E9FCE78FFA29B81"><enum>(b)</enum><header>International financial institutions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury should direct the representatives of the United States to the World Bank Group, the International Monetary Fund, and the Asian Development Bank to use the voice and vote of the United States to support resilient infrastructure projects and to build environmental resilience in the Pacific Islands.</text></subsection></section><section id="H43E229D53EF747D8852BF4AA1BFD0CF4"><enum>107.</enum><header>Allies and partners in the Pacific Islands region</header><subsection id="HDE0EECBD4A1548A89D16E6CB4C85C1F0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Commerce, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, the Secretary of Defense, the United States Trade Representative, and any other relevant official, should consult and coordinate with allies and partners in the Pacific Islands region, including Australia, New Zealand, Japan, South Korea, Taiwan, the United Kingdom, France, Germany, and India, and regional institutions such as the Pacific Islands Forum, the Pacific Islands Development Program, the Pacific Community and Secretariat for the Pacific Regional Environment Programme, with respect to programs to provide assistance to the Pacific Islands, including programs established by this Act, including for purposes of—</text><paragraph id="H174FF150FBBF453098E428D1E4437613"><enum>(1)</enum><text>deconflicting programming;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6453F846555475E91DB734B5502A79B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensuring that any programming does not adversely affect the absorptive capacity of the Pacific Islands; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4621C2E74E244399B2C839298FAD2B7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensuring complementary programs benefit the Pacific Islands to the maximum extent practicable; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96DBE95D840D464BAD3686AA5A851998"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensuring that programming aligns with regional development goals, as outlined by documents such as the 2050 Strategy for the Blue Pacific Continent in order to support sustainable development and promote a shared vision for the future of the Pacific Islands.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC41EDD5BF28A43DB8F7B30CA5A4034FB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Formal consultative process</header><text>The President shall endeavor to establish a formal consultative process with such regional allies and partners to coordinate with respect to such programs and future-years programming.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA401DD72578B4F3F9DA63C6F039D3AF5"><enum>108.</enum><header>Extension of diplomatic immunities to the Pacific Islands Forum</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The provisions of the International Organizations Immunities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/288">22 U.S.C. 288 et seq.</external-xref>) may be extended to the Pacific Islands Forum in the same manner, to the same extent, and subject to the same conditions as such provisions may be extended to a public international organization in which the United States participates pursuant to any treaty or under the authority of any Act of Congress authorizing such participation or making an appropriation for such participation.</text></section><section id="H799817E478DC4C6F9B001628AFBF67C9"><enum>109.</enum><header>Ambassador’s Self-Help Small Grants Program</header><subsection id="HD1CF805D68D7417F939CD7E426E4E128"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H49A42ECD6A3F4E5488B801B45B2BEA34"><enum>(1)</enum><text>at the 53rd Pacific Islands Forum Leaders Meeting, the United States Government announced that the United States Agency for International Development and the Department of State are working together to set up an Ambassador’s Self-Help Small Grants Program that will provide targeted funding for small-scale projects and increase the flexibility of United States funding resources across the Pacific; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F5D8E1AF484443691FA4FD2D7F0F03D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>this program will support community-led initiatives, filling a gap by providing more accessible resources for small projects that address local needs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD80B01418F3441C6A3C26246C8577E95"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State and Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall continue to administer and implement the Ambassador’s Self-Help Small Grants Program. </text></subsection><subsection id="H928DD378CD5F4769A6C39BB5D3008F19"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $650,000 for each of the fiscal years 2026 through 2033 to carry out this section. </text></subsection></section><section id="H673A0BDB35284EA59DCEAB13D8901676"><enum>110.</enum><header>Establishing a senior official for the Compacts of Free Association at the Department of State</header><subsection id="H49A3041A8BCF44979BF78CD4E61C51F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall designate a senior official at the Department of State responsible for administering the Compacts of Free Association (in this section referred to as the “Compacts”) at the Department of State (in this section referred to as the “Senior Official”). The Senior Official shall report to the Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs.</text></subsection><subsection id="H92CEB3D189E7437FBCE1BD98D829F22E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Senior Official shall—</text><paragraph id="HB9B727ACDE744750828FBE283A7C8318"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be responsible for the conduct of United States foreign policy with respect to the countries affiliated with the United States Government under the Compacts, namely the freely associated states of—</text><subparagraph id="H173BF26CC98144219A671EC0D0297DA3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Republic of Palau;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90D759CE2FB34CD69F39F92ABFA95810"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Republic of the Marshall Islands; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7E9A94A9A554159BB7CE1A5BBF8C9CE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Federated States of Micronesia;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H02566F9821C54EF19B835328029D6F51"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assist the Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs in providing overall direction, coordination, and supervision of interdepartmental activities of the United States Government in these countries, including ensuring the timely transfer of assistance and provision of benefits through the United States Department of the Interior, as specified in the Compacts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5709B002E9F4EFE85F1487EB4D2C6CE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>oversee and evaluate the adequacy and effectiveness of United States policy with respect to these countries as well as of the plans, programs, resources, and performance for implementing that policy, including programs and other activities implemented by the Department of the Interior;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DAB4ECC15DA4D8E938F79CE38D21021"><enum>(4)</enum><text>directly supervise the policy and operations of the Compacts and provide guidance to relevant United States missions within the Indo-Pacific region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CA160CF1D494C39AC6852025DFDB12C"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure the provision of an adequate, regular flow of information to posts abroad on United States Government policies, policy deliberations, and diplomatic exchanges in Washington, D.C.; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4DDB3D7035A4E24A956FA3B29075FEA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>ensure the continuity of implementation of commitments and Compact obligations and benefits, consistent with United States national interests in the Indo-Pacific region. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1DF8D51846734808A04CCE839EEAE5CE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $250,000 to support the Senior Official in the conduct and discharge of the duties described in subsection (b).</text></subsection></section></title><title id="H282C62459FAD410FA7B87BAEC5C85135"><enum>II</enum><header>People-Centered Development</header><section id="H1A154B1FECFB4612BC95D63A8037EFD6"><enum>201.</enum><header>Assistance to improve public health outcomes and build public health capacity</header><subsection id="H296C1DCBAF0B48DC9914B4C79E7E2447"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State, is authorized to assist the Pacific Islands to improve public health outcomes and build public health capacity.</text></subsection><subsection id="H42F2020D1ACF4279AEA5D08DC2D93612"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities supported</header><text>Activities authorized to be carried out under subsection (a) may include—</text><paragraph id="H54332CEC0E8847009420C8ADB60A1EA9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">programming, including grants, cooperative agreements, and other forms of assistance, as appropriate, to assist in building local capacity to ensure that Pacific Islanders have access to the essential health services they need to thrive and to address—</text><subparagraph id="H183D0A5A038647B999429329A216F01D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>maternal and child health;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5905C97AAEF4C9AAF6B3F89BB77767D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>family planning and reproductive health;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0133FA9B99AB406E86985279789F5AB0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>gender-based violence;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB42A135BF0D44678EEC1E58CCA210A4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>food security and nutrition;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BE8D087C9C34A27A3B979DBE9C5A1BF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>noncommunicable diseases;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36BE6A6C4CA142B4BC9FB5C32786946F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>communicable diseases, including neglected tropical diseases, tuberculosis, HIV/AIDS, sexually-transmitted infections, and zoonotic and emerging infectious disease threats;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB6758F291604C70B3237735B8436A82"><enum>(G)</enum><text>equitable access to quality, essential, and affordable health services and quality-assured, safe, effective medical products and their appropriate use; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27D773EF514641C19F0357A91EA5D26E"><enum>(H)</enum><text>water, sanitation, and hygiene;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1666947DBEC42DB968A8FC0D8BDC382"><enum>(2)</enum><text>technical assistance to strengthen local health system capacity and resilience in the areas of good leadership and governance, sustainable financing, interoperable information systems and high quality data for decision making, efficient medical products and supply chain systems, and management of human resources for health, with special attention to increasing health worker performance, retention, productivity, number, skill mix, and competency, including through exploring opportunities such as private sector engagement and digital health integration and access; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8EE79D2A2F546809B3D718F0110EBCE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>coordination with existing local and regional health sector goals, efforts, institutions, and frameworks; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE5F1EBCD624428BA3F737A5EDB12F9C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">investment in and improvement of critical infrastructure, including hospitals, health clinics and pharmacies in the Pacific Islands.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE43FF8833B6649F490913AC4B38345DA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the implementation of this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H8D354C286D5E49669961CC3D03379063"><enum>202.</enum><header>Assistance to promote freedom of the press</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State is authorized to provide assistance to promote the dissemination of free and accurate information in the Pacific Islands, including for the following purposes:</text><paragraph id="H91DE67BA5BF149B09117E15DC83C3A14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Media capacity building and education, including to—</text><subparagraph id="HAA8E90C6F9E643B98404D452E377AC8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide on-site media training tailored to local needs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD69DE83686074729B83A43658CDAC45E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>collaborate with local government and nongovernmental entities to promote media literacy and integrate media literacy into primary education curricula in local languages and dialects to ensure accessibility; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H628318BAFE64486E969FCC9681DF0966"><enum>(C)</enum><text>routinize funding for professional programs, such as the Pacific Islands Journalism Reporting Tour, that bring media professionals from the Pacific Islands to the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8A706DB6BC54DF79FE3C5C5393BCDE5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Strengthening and diversifying broadcast content tailored to local audiences, including content broadcast in the local vernacular.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A07518268B44898994BDB3DC7214D09"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Investing in connectivity infrastructure with an emphasis on broadcast radio and transmission.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H48349FBE654A498995CFD0995030AB24"><enum>203.</enum><header>Indo-Pacific Media Advancement Program</header><subsection id="HC99EA2987C5F42F88FF9A95186C8C0CE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall continue to implement and develop the Indo-Pacific Media Advancement Program to promote a robust, free media in the Pacific Islands and strengthen the capacity of media outlets and journalists in the Indo-Pacific region to develop their business strategies, enhance their ability to conduct independent journalism, and counter disinformation. </text></subsection><subsection id="HCDBA4B46B352452CAB47021D7B414B4B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Goals</header><text>The goals of the Indo-Pacific Media Advancement Program shall be to accomplish the following: </text><paragraph id="H2CDF97EDF852461B8F2EA76AEDBC7E45"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Increase the understanding of prevalent misinformation and disinformation narratives. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0126F58162D4427B7EB4F3E85192E32"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Develop the capacity of professional, independent media organizations and journalists to develop and implement media sustainability plans, improve business operations, and increase the quality and quantity of published information and news. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB32F1273598B417EA9AA9741200F18C4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Expand media outlets’ access to resources, content-sharing agreements, and equipment, so that such outlets can provide quality content. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3029EDBF568747D68F0442B7C2AA80CB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Develop the technical and investigative skills of journalists to conduct pre-bunking, fact-checking, and debunking to address misinformation and disinformation. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0292B032B445454AA00F952AB64291E9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the heads of other Federal departments or agencies, as appropriate, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the Indo-Pacific Media Advancement Program and the engagement of the United States with the free media in the Pacific Islands, including the following: </text><paragraph id="H82F2853144354B219667566002E1402E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An overview of the media and journalism landscape in the Pacific Islands. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA7F0BCCE4EB4CDEB5253914A648DE09"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A review of the efforts and planned efforts of the United States Government to strengthen free and independent media in the Pacific Islands, including a description of the objectives, means of implementation, and measures of success of the Indo-Pacific Media Advancement Program. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H425C72CD9F004ED198ACC331F6E5EDA3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of challenges to a free and open media in the Pacific Islands and to the implementation of the Indo-Pacific Media Advancement Program, including strategies to mitigate such challenges. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D644A8B52A54118B8DAB2924C801A48"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of any additional authorities or resources necessary for more robust United States engagement to promote a free media in the Pacific Islands and greater implementation of the Indo-Pacific Media Advancement Program. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF7A104AE6F744241B5012E30E34FCE0D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated $4,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2026 through 2033 to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H7E38E4A4D24A4EA0B75DF3CA294CC380"><enum>204.</enum><header>Program to promote educational and professional development for young adult leaders and professionals</header><subsection id="H464B1E2A78C04BD4B6D79A7E2A648205"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that routinized people-to-people exchange programs to bring Pacific Islands religious leaders, journalists, civil society members, politicians, and others to the United States, as well as supporting similar exchange participants from the United States to the Pacific Islands, strengthens existing relationships and advances United States interests and shared values in the region.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFC15F4FC242449C9965222FC1EADA460"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State shall develop and implement a program to promote educational and professional development for young adult leaders and professionals in the Pacific Islands with a demonstrated passion to contribute to the continued development of the Pacific Islands.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9DF58F61B27D49AC8035A54B95DA1BC6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conduct of program</header><text>The program developed under this section may be carried out through—</text><paragraph id="H27959E6258D54137AF2FAAA2EDC8B503"><enum>(1)</enum><text>grants provided on a competitive basis to qualified organizations with demonstrated expertise relating to the Pacific Islands;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H409EE5C4748743DD9F8B6383DCA88AB4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>grants in amounts not to exceed $50,000 provided on a competitive basis to qualified young leaders from the Pacific Islands for the purpose of carrying out projects dedicated to the improvement of their communities in the Pacific Islands;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD333E3A25BFE471A97CC6C7AA2A1CD0D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regional workshops and professional, vocational, and academic fellowships; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3995647493BA4FC189D454E19697A049"><enum>(4)</enum><text>people-to-people exchanges.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B3FE984C72F4DB6868FB989ADFDD8BC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Briefing</header><paragraph id="H51AC27EF50F046DFA49A467E9D0A6AB7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, acting through the Assistant Secretary of State for Educational and Cultural Affairs, should brief the appropriate congressional committees on exchange programs for the Pacific Islands region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA07C8394B104B358E5BAC9D91FE03C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The briefing required by paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H6474B7E848CA42B5B8E7EDCA7667DB6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of any factors constraining the number and frequency of International Visitor Leadership Program participants from countries of the Pacific Islands;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40546C88D62A4FAD823B91084A7716B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an identification of resources that are necessary to address the factors described in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50BD90D7BEEE4901B579236C699852BA"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a strategy for connecting alumni and participants of the Department of State’s professional development exchange programs in East Asia, such as the Young Southeast Asian Leaders Initiative and the Young Pacific Leaders programs, to enhance interregion and intraregion people-to-people ties.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H925EBB113685494992D18703620F0B03"><enum>205.</enum><header>Education assistance</header><subsection id="HA47E3977EEA94A20A89F3CD738E4218A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HCC14B46369F1462AA2C00491168C97B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promoting basic education in the Pacific Islands, particularly in traditionally underserved communities, advances United States foreign policy goals and requires a whole of government approach, and the United States Government currently dedicates insufficient resources and attention to assisting with education needs in the region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DDD6715BEB141DBAECE24760648B48D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Peace Corps alone is insufficient to achieve United States objectives of promoting sustainable, quality basic education; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A1869D464E040998151B94F07ED42D7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>countries of the Pacific Islands meet the requirements outlined in subsection (c)(4) of section 105 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151c">22 U.S.C. 2151c</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H07D9BDF42A9F4AAF85E7F368ABB9D293"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Education assistance</header><text>The President is authorized to provide assistance under section 105 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151c">22 U.S.C. 2151c</external-xref>) to promote sustainable, quality basic education in the Pacific Islands, including for the following purposes:</text><paragraph id="H3A00E8F0296E4D199E3C293D0EA0E0C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Supporting national nutrition and health programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94CF5728D97942F7A6E23B792C84BBD5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Working with partner governments to reform policies, improve curricula, strengthen data systems, train teachers, and provide quality learning materials.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H138464006D8B4AA8B44ECAE3F5A8F18F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Building new schools and renovating older facilities to ensure safe places for learning.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D109D68C445479BBAD011423FF5282B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Providing individuals, particularly at-risk youth, with relevant education, training, and skills for meaningful employment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFB03C1991DF4DF1AA1BF01AF1D3B370"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Removing barriers to entering formal education for out-of-school individuals, assisting in keeping them in school, and providing an opportunity to catch up on schooling for those left behind.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC12E34616064A199016FC9D7CCDBD53"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Promoting teaching and research exchanges between the Pacific Islands and United States institutions of higher education, including community colleges.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC88BA9A2321546C79273998224005188"><enum>206.</enum><header>People-to-people ties</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State and Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall continue to administer and expand programs fostering people-to-people ties between the United States and Pacific Islands, including—</text><paragraph id="H83A5FCDA5C314C259F5A8995BB8F0361"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Youth Ambassadors Program in the Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0C7F42FD5904530BA2AD52849FC45A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Academy of Women Entrepreneurs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03A23B2521734D49962EF6E20D45C575"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Minority Serving Institutions Partnerships Initiatives to the Pacific;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H510A99BE174E4DDBB57FABBC0143456E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the U.S.-Pacific Institute for Rising Leaders Fellowship; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05D2A67088814D7ABA7EE0511817CB67"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Global STEM Development Scholarship Program.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HA427061DDD604B64B6271BF0EDFD7490"><enum>207.</enum><header>Pacific Islands TRADES Program</header><subsection id="HF4BF88C6375E48AD817DDA41B25C31C6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall establish a program, to be known as the “Pacific Islands Training and Resources for Advancement in Development, Education, and Skills Program” or the “Pacific Islands TRADES Program”, to, through scholarships, training from such agency, and grants to partner organizations, assist with workforce development in the Pacific Islands to—</text><paragraph id="HD6658559D3F147A4B07D749497054729"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increase the capacity of the local workforce through medium- and long-term training and technical assistance in sectors of critical importance to the Pacific Islands, such as construction, tourism, boat maintenance, and fisheries; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE9BB4AB60B54CB9AA979CC9535FD99C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>balance maximizing workforce retention in the Pacific Islands with any necessary training outside of the Pacific Islands, with a focus on avoiding exacerbating outward labor flows; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9A30A2BD7254757898AD6046995521E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>keep Pacific priorities in mind by coordinating with like-minded allies and partners and working with local organizations and governments; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA509FF6C33D848A8AC6FBB21B3C5E7F6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide resources for technical and management skills development to adequately prepare the workforce of the Pacific Islands for any potential incoming investment. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE12C2D0AEBA34001A6E447FB57ADB8AA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the Pacific Islands TRADES Program, including the following: </text><paragraph id="HFA1F10CE7A2546409FFE6261739D15E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A comprehensive overview of such program. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E3FD87715A6416DAD7E62C3600EE96E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An identification of the office overseeing such program. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF88E4DC96D6F43379229E3F13DFF9B5B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A list of any partner organizations involved in such program. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D0235377E1B414C8C1F2113EBD2663A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of the training and workforce development planned as part of such program. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8F5F8D959F74FE5BCC0FFEEA3FC0ABE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An assessment of the impact of such program. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE610469FC6954A00A56056356314A02B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any additional resources needed to implement such program. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3AD477B523C94C14B32B3767B9D10793"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2026 through 2033 to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="HDC5FE621E12544E2994B0783FF585824"><enum>208.</enum><header>Investment agreements</header><subsection id="HD1224147A6E94F6697A147670E9837D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H126E2898F89F438CB4B3DDAE01F2EF45"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States International Development Finance Corporation has a dual mandate to advance United States foreign policy and make development-focused investment around the world with a focus on communities most in need;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD5AE0BA03044E53A08CEAF6101FB75C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States International Development Finance Corporation must enter into an investment incentive agreement with a jurisdiction’s government in order to pursue development projects in that jurisdiction;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1401F1593CF74D5BAD2D5EA421B3C28C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the market-based private sector development and inclusive economic growth of Solomon Islands and the Republic of Vanuatu are in the United States foreign policy interest;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E7839873CBB4A058C27B3901BDC793F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the United States International Development Finance Corporation has not entered into investment incentive agreements with the government of Solomon Islands or with the government of the Republic of Vanuatu; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD47073F6816547DFA9130E80A528303C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the inability of the United States International Development Finance Corporation to support investments in Solomon Islands and the Republic of Vanuatu undermines United States policy to provide countries a robust alternative to state-direct investments by authoritarian governments and United States strategic competitors.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB3CCD36CFAA14116A2C9D4B447930EC6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Investment agreements</header><text>The Chief Executive Officer of the United States International Development Finance Corporation, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall continue and prioritize efforts to enter into investment incentive agreements with the governments of those Pacific Islands in which the United States International Development Finance Corporation is otherwise authorized to operate under the BUILD Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9601">22 U.S.C. 9601 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H2F034401D9F745F9B80FABED4F563ACF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Chief Executive Officer of the United States International Development Finance Corporation, as appropriate, is authorized to provide technical assistance to assist the Pacific Islands in negotiating and executing investment incentive agreements with the United States International Development Finance Corporation.</text></subsection></section><section id="H7B86E29F126E4E7B98218C86C20342DC"><enum>209.</enum><header>Committee on Engagement with Civil Society Organizations in the Pacific Islands</header><subsection id="HFC17DD3C2D324B49A06D7C02C5F325DF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development and the Secretary of Defense, shall establish a committee, to be known as the “Committee on Engagement with Civil Society Organizations in the Pacific Islands” (referred to in this subsection as the “Committee”) for the purposes of—</text><paragraph id="HED6570DA8C064CAE8A0E9C49759003C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinating interagency engagement with civil society organizations in the Pacific Islands; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57226808C686425FBFDEE4095A93DD5A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinating collaboration with United States partners and allies on engagement with civil society organizations in the Pacific Islands; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4D58ED9CA69495E8806636D108069C0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>aligning such engagement with the needs of the Pacific Islands and the national security priorities of the United States. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7CF6445E3C964F8296E3BAD6FD8ABC4A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Committee shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy on engagement with civil society organizations in the Pacific Islands, including—</text><paragraph id="H2B270789C62846EF8F2F8E717A0353E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a review of current efforts across the United States Government to engage with such organizations, including the role of such efforts in the delivery of foreign aid to communities; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DF1AE99BB2B4FA195EA85578E96A6A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a plan for engagement across the United States Government with such organizations; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7019F3D4518644C9BB913AC8BC3516DC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of the importance of engagement by the United States with such organizations and how such engagement aligns with the advancement of Indo-Pacific and Pacific Islands priorities within the National Security Strategy, Indo-Pacific Strategy, and Pacific Partnership Strategy; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71307468EEAE451993780E05ACC32FEC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an analysis of interagency cooperation regarding United States engagement with such organizations and specific recommendations for expansion and improvement of such cooperation; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56C094AC916B41B88DA6B7484C275565"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an analysis of the resources needed to bolster and streamline United States engagement with such organizations, including any additional statutory authorities or appropriations of funds; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E0DB2DFAA854AE7969DEE19DCDEA60A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>an analysis of any engagement conducted by a country other than the United States with such organizations, including engagement that may undermine civil society in the Pacific Islands; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAE0B7FA1CF6414D803BF6F3C924A322"><enum>(7)</enum><text>an assessment of opportunities for greater coordination between the United States and like-minded partners and allies.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7EDC7832C8F44341890B2334A68D3778"><enum>210.</enum><header>American Spaces in the Pacific Islands</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall develop and submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the state of and plans for American Spaces in the Pacific Islands, including—</text><paragraph id="HAB62FC4EE85F4AA6AF9417400744B825"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an overview of American Spaces in the Pacific Islands (including American Corners and American Centers), including an assessment of the current and historical programming and resources of American Spaces; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25CD90528A1946FE804F420767EE7848"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a plan for future American Spaces in Pacific Island countries, including any new development or expansion of existing American Spaces, and a description of any additional resources needed for such expansion; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B8ABDD58BE6455A970A84E321ABDA49"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of the impact of American Spaces on American foreign policy and national security interests, including in comparison to the similar initiatives of other actors.</text></paragraph></section></title><title id="H2A70278E38F242F88A6A4BF5476CC175"><enum>III</enum><header>Peace and Security</header><section id="H0CEEB60F6C4442578538AAD3430C5E5D"><enum>301.</enum><header>Building the capacity of local civilian and national security institutions</header><subsection id="H972F097036364693AB5DED07116661FE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security, as appropriate, is authorized to provide assistance to build the capacity of local civilian and national security institutions of the Pacific Islands for purposes of—</text><paragraph id="HF698E6350CE94AFA92ABDFC8E7EC95D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enhancing maritime security and maritime domain awareness to address challenges such as illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55E9FFEAC4F84181A3043985045AEDA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assisting local law enforcement in detecting, preventing, and combating trafficking in persons and drug trafficking and other forms of transnational crime;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6996C82C346241B39F80143D4227CB39"><enum>(3)</enum><text>providing essential services to civilian populations and responding to humanitarian challenges caused by natural disasters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA6ABB7CE7474F898A9192137B165344"><enum>(4)</enum><text>participating in efforts by regional institutions and frameworks to coordinate and facilitate cooperation on shared security challenges; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1FC3C3A21674BB88A8E23CEBE018B16"><enum>(5)</enum><text>expanding information sharing and working toward operational coordination and interoperability among Pacific Island maritime security forces, including through regional fusion centers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0A1BF5B258F49E7AAF99AE69775FBCD"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing assistance in legal actions, including hiring legal counsel or providing legal support, as appropriate, to support the Pacific Islands in defending their rights and interests related to maritime security, combating transnational crime, responding to natural disasters, and participating in regional security efforts.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA775F11D8BF74BA0849A30F1ADAAD948"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Related programs and authorities</header><text>The assistance and capacity building authorized by this subsection should build on the following:</text><paragraph id="HCFB68B36D95D484199A50712C6C2C2F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The International Military Education and Training program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29A2481993394FE2A11F684FC09CC21B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Foreign Military Financing program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC27975C5B134688B356A214F4DD0A13"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Overseas Humanitarian Disaster and Civic Aid program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC59E8C771B0C4D579DFE8FC62789C397"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The authority to build the capacity of foreign security forces under section 333 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6801603C7A54448C89B660A7D9DED45A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The authority to provide excess defense articles under section 516 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321j">22 U.S.C. 2321j</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AA308DED76D49A195C209528729C4EF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The National Guard State Partnership Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05EDA74A0643473C8BAC31E06A50C64C"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The International Narcotics Control and Law Enforcement Program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD187B0F2209A424AB3041269CB624493"><enum>(c)</enum><header>National police forces and coast guards</header><text>The national police forces and coast guards of countries of the Pacific Islands are eligible to receive assistance under the programs and authorities described in subsection (b) (other than the programs and authorities described in paragraphs (1), (4), (6), and (7) of subsection (b)).</text></subsection></section><section id="H81337BDA5A8549DBB74EF8A35A8E051A"><enum>302.</enum><header>Reporting</header><subsection id="H721D32C9DDB44A4D9B1F5E7CBC114719"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Updates of certain reports</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the heads of other Federal agencies as appropriate, shall identify and update the reports described in subsection (b) to include in such reports a discussion of forms of transnational crime affecting the Pacific Islands.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE938978F79E744BEBD774BB08476E930"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports described</header><text>The reports described in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="HD62B3D333A5142039503507B26BD6223"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The International Narcotics Control Strategy report.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88142494CE7D46A89CF3BD6A054CFD69"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Improving International Fisheries Management report.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4B1EF36B176469FB7532926BB1E31EB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Trafficking in Persons report.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H940708669FF34DFCA11D0DC83A372D0C"><enum>303.</enum><header>International Law Enforcement Academy</header><subsection id="H10F51DAD0E6D45EF9A571376E277715E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H11D011F802C7465FA9010AFBDA27552D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Department of State’s International Law Enforcement Academies are valuable tools in our relationships with other countries and enhancing the capacity of foreign criminal justice partners to combat transnational crime;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A95105269704A07A4E5800FBB2C3FBD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assistance in combating transnational crime is frequently cited as an area of need from Pacific Islands leaders; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17B90DF728D84A59B80AA14C1ACFAC5F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the International Law Enforcement Academy in Bangkok, Thailand recently widened its audience to include the Pacific Islands. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H635A1ED4B5114EE69841731858A6CC47"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report—</text><paragraph id="HFC377AB21CCA4F46B02E4334941FC5C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>detailing training and other activities that the International Law Enforcement Academy in Bangkok, Thailand has conducted with Pacific Islands participants;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC35EDE6B87D431E9D586DFF237EFED1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describing any planned expansions to the Bangkok International Law Enforcement Academy’s programming, including the Pacific Islands, and any challenges to those planned expansions, including any gaps and needs in funding, staffing levels, and physical space; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1A46E11CCB54DF099700A06C2FF7416"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assessing the feasibility of continuing to administer and expand programming for the Pacific Islands through the International Law Enforcement Academy in Bangkok, or if the establishment of an additional International Law Enforcement Academy dedicated to serving the Pacific Islands is necessary, and what resources and authorities would be needed to do so. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H6EDFC9CBD12046B5BF825347A0B8B84F"><enum>IV</enum><header>Resource and Economic Development</header><section id="H882907F324574280B6A3738FDE3E04AB"><enum>401.</enum><header>Trade development with the Pacific Islands</header><subsection id="H986228458119456BAE5AC23A88086DC9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the United States should expand bilateral and multilateral trade with the Pacific Islands to promote socioeconomic development and mutual prosperity.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFC531A6680524D4BA748A4201DD02C38"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Trade development</header><text>The United States Trade Representative is authorized to expand and diversify trade and promote regional development with the Pacific Islands, including through negotiating trade and investment framework agreements.</text></subsection></section><section id="HEDF5768B90EE4C6D85A9BEA00D8A5DCB"><enum>402.</enum><header>Trade capacity building initiative for the Pacific Islands</header><subsection id="H560499CC18AD428587D647DB8ED424D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, in coordination with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Chief Executive Officer of the United States International Development Finance Corporation, and the Director of the United States Trade and Development Agency are authorized to implement programming to build trade capacity in the Pacific Islands.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA0B6C25B8BD94F78B9BE1D1C1BC4AF81"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>The activities authorized under this section include—</text><paragraph id="HE8EA931331F1451EA1717210668BE243"><enum>(1)</enum><text>development of human and institutional capacity and infrastructure across multiple sectors of economies, including digital connectivity and cybersecurity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB5786AE57664357A2D7985C8A06D4F9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assistance with development and implementation of regional and international trade agreements, including the World Trade Organization’s Agreement on Trade Facilitation and facilitation of intraregional trade flows;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H54D6DA2D808448779EE2A1DC8D488ABD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support for women-owned enterprises and gender equality; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CF8B1232DBB4A30A57524DFC7A45F8E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>promotion of government policies that encourage free and fair competition, sound governance, environmental protection, and business environments conducive to sustainable and inclusive economic growth.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H504A1442F64C4A81B6AA3CB44982303C"><enum>403.</enum><header>United States Commercial Service</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce shall expand the presence of the United States Commercial Service in the Pacific Islands and allocate additional Foreign Commercial Service Officers to the Pacific Islands, including by elevating existing partner posts and establishing new Commercial Service posts and partner posts, to—</text><paragraph id="H9E7CD65E6E094B3B9E042C9E8F28F15E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>explore opportunities for United States private sector investment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB60AB5D273B4224B3E02AEED1303A42"><enum>(2)</enum><text>examine regulations in host countries in the Pacific Islands that may hinder foreign direct investment, including those related to human rights, labor rights, and environmental protection, and provide technical assistance when requested by such host countries; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01F31389DA6040BBBFBBF8F2EDE6CCB2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>report on the commercial and investment activities of non-allied foreign actors in the Pacific Islands.</text></paragraph></section></title><title id="H6B87E97F919D4876B8A5F56CEF942754"><enum>V</enum><header>Environmental and disaster resilience</header><section id="HAE1E6C0A0AB241B6BE6490432D7D138A"><enum>501.</enum><header>Assistance to enhance preparedness for and resilience to natural disasters and other emergencies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State is authorized to assist the Pacific Islands to enhance preparedness for and resilience to natural disasters and other emergencies. Such assistance includes—</text><paragraph id="HA3AC89DBF6174830A9FDBD8E3F6A2C61"><enum>(1)</enum><text>education and training programs on natural disaster prevention and preparedness for emergency management professionals in the Pacific Islands, including by leveraging the expertise of nonprofit organizations and institutions of higher education in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB63AD24C48C4911A7E7282B7A7A5F5B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>technical assistance, including through grants and cooperative agreements for qualified United States and local nongovernmental organizations, to enhance early warning systems, emergency management and preparedness procedures, and post-disaster relief and recovery; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H060E6B321A2A4F97BE1A9EFC97F25617"><enum>(3)</enum><text>coordination of existing disaster mitigation and response plans in the region, including by United States allies and partners in the region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9B65EEFBB6A4CBCB790B9AAE9767DD4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>infrastructure development and upgrades to improve disaster preparedness and response, such as the construction of evacuation centers, flood control measures, and communication networks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CBEF7B9796B4F349F0E7D0BB8C99F09"><enum>(5)</enum><text>support for local community-based disaster risk reduction programs, including the development of evacuation plans, training in first aid and emergency response, and provision of emergency supplies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2B50E4B6624420D85CDB957467AFEA6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>technical assistance and training to enhance the capacity of local emergency response agencies, including search and rescue teams, fire departments, and medical personnel;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7E83C1F87904156AD21A7DB28187359"><enum>(7)</enum><text>provision of critical humanitarian assistance, such as food, water, shelter, and medical care, in the aftermath of disasters; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF75FFF5398A44B1B88B48AB55BF079DF"><enum>(8)</enum><text>support for programs aimed at reducing the long-term impacts of disasters, such as disaster risk insurance, small business recovery programs, and environmental restoration initiatives.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HF3346C3A2272415C9750D5D55E231F14"><enum>502.</enum><header>Climate resilient infrastructure</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Chief Executive Officer of the United States International Development Finance Corporation, as appropriate, is authorized to—</text><paragraph id="H624FC07AF7864F889560C8715E3D0CB9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">invest in and improve critical infrastructure, including transport connectivity, hospitals, health clinics, pharmacies, information and communications technology, food security, coastal zone management, marine and water resource management, and energy security and access to electricity in the Pacific Islands, with an emphasis on climate resiliency and sustainable development;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H851D15E583B04026A2DA963B924F213C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to assist local government and civil society leaders assess risks to local infrastructure, consider and implement risk mitigation efforts and policies to strengthen resilience, and evaluate proposed projects and solutions for their efficacy and sustainability; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACADEDF4D6044C62B77F95820815031C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support investment and improvement in ecosystem conservation and protection for the long-term sustainable use of ecosystem services, especially those that support environmental resilience, food security and livelihoods; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04B8670B0C10472AAEA64FB4D5830175"><enum>(4)</enum><text>invest in and improve critical telecommunications infrastructure and cybersecurity; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AB4C6AAE1DB4E56822921A42687E537"><enum>(5)</enum><text>foster public-private partnerships and cooperation among stakeholders to mobilize private sector investment and innovation for sustainable infrastructure development and climate resiliency in the Pacific Islands;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFB63A96D71E4DA0A4F981F7EAB949A0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>provide technical assistance and capacity building to local governments and communities to integrate climate resilience into their infrastructure planning and development strategies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBEFA54445ED4172ACC42E031A8DAF38"><enum>(7)</enum><text>develop and implement programs that promote the use of renewable energy and energy efficiency technologies in the Pacific Islands, including through investment in clean energy infrastructure and technical assistance to local utilities and energy regulators;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8CEFF758209546429545C2E992440630"><enum>(8)</enum><text>work with regional organizations and governments to promote the sustainable management of marine resources, including through the development of marine protected areas and ecosystem-based management approaches;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H506C3BA7B378423387BB59C3E221A98A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>foster partnerships between Pacific Island governments and research institutions to build scientific capacity and support research on impacts to climate and environment and adaptation strategies in the region; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0AA6EDDDB964EAB926774CAF6763E83"><enum>(10)</enum><text>promote the use of innovative financing mechanisms, such as green bonds and climate risk insurance, to help Pacific Island countries access affordable financing for climate-resilient infrastructure development.</text></paragraph></section></title><title id="HF07D5A70D4824223A4B0192111BBC134"><enum>VI</enum><header>Ocean and Environment</header><section id="HA1741EB6D8E44CB29D7159818CEF3360"><enum>601.</enum><header>Oceans management</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development and the Secretary of Commerce, is authorized to—</text><paragraph id="H83244EC166074A25BBA919DC98FBFDCF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support programming that promotes fisheries sustainability and marine biodiversity conservation in the Pacific Islands;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H74E1F2E252944EC58F23451B9D540447"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support the development, adoption, and implementation of regional sustainable fisheries policies, standards, and regulatory frameworks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD944E24B007942C585C6B9FC35744315"><enum>(3)</enum><text>partner with regional private sector interests in the adoption and implementation of seafood industry fair-labor standards and sustainable fishing practices; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52D4DDF883E24260BE733390A3011145"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to assist local government and civil society leaders to improve environmental and ocean management; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29CDE11D43B94A40838A83ED53B0C99D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide technical assistance and capacity building to improve data collection and management, including through the use of innovative technologies, to support sustainable fisheries management and biodiversity conservation in the region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5B2A69ACF7E45E0AE56D68927B5B6FC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>support the development and implementation of integrated ocean management and marine spatial planning frameworks that incorporate local knowledge and community input, promote ecosystem-based management approaches, and address transboundary marine conservation challenges;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H73E83BE476B04939AD6365F4F7008329"><enum>(7)</enum><text>support research and monitoring programs to better understand changes and challenges to oceans and fisheries in the Pacific Islands and to inform evidence-based management approaches;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A7AC3AC9ADB4ADF8D7D725650481AB9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>support regional efforts to combat illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing and promote sustainable fisheries practices, including through the development of traceability systems and improved monitoring and enforcement capacity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6241FBD72CE244C2979EA3E54E9137CE"><enum>(9)</enum><text>encourage private sector investment in sustainable fisheries and marine conservation efforts in the Pacific Islands, including through partnerships with local communities and businesses; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0C1B1ED0CB84F09B6C6A59F9B61CED2"><enum>(10)</enum><text>promote public awareness and engagement on issues related to sustainable fisheries and ocean management in the Pacific Islands, including through education and outreach programs.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H192AD752798E4F3682A1E4EAAD6924B0"><enum>602.</enum><header>Sea level rise</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development and the Secretary of Commerce, is authorized to provide support and technical assistance to Pacific Islands to address the impacts of sea level rise with the aim of—</text><paragraph id="HE7C76F6579D247218C79748C70659008"><enum>(1)</enum><text>protecting and mitigating the impacts of sea level rise on coastal communities and their economies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7032951BB416441CAA4E372DC39AB502"><enum>(2)</enum><text>protecting and increasing the resilience of critical coastal infrastructure; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E39133E1F5E4B7EB5B6FC19B2B55F49"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preserving Pacific Islands maritime boundaries and their entitlements;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C58B93A87434C87B6652326B21D8DD9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>preserving Pacific Islands’ statehoods;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F1072A8636F42B7B2EA2EA8C6B87F7B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>providing support to Pacific Islands to develop and implement effective and just migration policies that address the impacts of sea level rise on communities and provide options for those who wish to migrate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB7D5F365BB246E3A8898B5784A5DBDA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>collaborating with international organizations and Pacific Island to provide humanitarian assistance to those affected by sea level rise, including through access to food, water, and shelter; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7AA63D956B2C41AC97A1DE4D0DA633D2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>supporting efforts to build resilience and sustainable livelihoods in affected communities, including through the development of alternative economic opportunities and sustainable agriculture practices.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5A9DDB083687496C9A2453E05737A820"><enum>603.</enum><header>Illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3553 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/8033">16 U.S.C. 8033</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HD026011835744B43B2A536137EFD77E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BC74546BCF4430DA56E83202F3CD187"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (9) as paragraph (10); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD198A4CF64CB4964A41E4897C58ED722"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (8) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H76ABAFBBF4FA489291BA149824976F1B" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H139FA6876BD847219F023C96B786EA99"><enum>(9)</enum><text>an assessment of gaps or limitations in the ability of the United States to effectively assist priority regions and priority flag states relating to IUU fishing due to resource constraints and the additional resources necessary to overcome those constraints; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></title><title id="H3D8438B0D32049DDB6EAB32A0E1625AE"><enum>VII</enum><header>Technology and Connectivity</header><section id="H63114357F04D4290BC311AF9B540D79B"><enum>701.</enum><header>Digital access and inclusion</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development and the heads of the United States International Development Finance Corporation, the Millennium Challenge Corporation, and the United States Trade and Development Authority, is authorized to provide support to the Pacific Islands to—</text><paragraph id="H329B014103BE4C61B913557ABFE6E747"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expand access to high quality broadband and telecommunications infrastructure in the Pacific Islands;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF8609DB8E7B4F83BBBE875378279420"><enum>(2)</enum><text>partner with regional private and public sector interests to promote and expand secure and accessible broadband connectivity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39EE3A3796CC4BDD8E85C034FF55AFB7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>strengthen the private sector and civil society’s digital capacity and digital skillset.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H97B1CC2B5E10498EA998F3D98A3BF803"><enum>702.</enum><header>Cybersecurity</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development and the heads of the United States International Development Finance Corporation, the Millennium Challenge Corporation, the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, and the United States Trade and Development Authority, is authorized to provide support and technical assistance to the Pacific Islands to—</text><paragraph id="H05940B4325A2415CB78A1461E8E968C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increase adoption of policies and regulatory positions that encourage open, interoperable, reliable, and secure digital infrastructure; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6B7AF70AC6B4398A104313C6AC59D52"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase adoption of cybersecurity best practices in the Pacific Islands, including through education and training programs for government and private sector entities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7E492E17DA34C8E8EB2BE75059F166F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assist with the development and implementation of cybersecurity strategies and policies, including incident response plans and risk management frameworks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F92514CA45341B9AED02BDE5C47274B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>promote international cooperation and information sharing on cybersecurity threats and incidents; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBF743C92BA44F77AA6317BA7B0618F6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>assist in the establishment and strengthening of national and regional Computer Emergency Response Teams (CERTs) to enhance cyber incident detection and response capabilities.</text></paragraph></section></title><title id="H369C2E7C908C452F90556141E2B1ED2A"><enum>VIII</enum><header>Report on the Strategy for Pacific Islands Partnership and Authorization of Appropriations</header><section id="HDB7B6DC5C44A42FDA1B474707A59EEA1"><enum>801.</enum><header>Report on the Strategy for Pacific Islands Partnership</header><subsection id="H8555011CD2354EC484F05BB977E74789"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date on which the initial report on the progress in implementing the Strategy for Pacific Islands Partnership required by section 103 is submitted to the appropriate congressional committees, and not later than January 1 of each odd-numbered year thereafter, the President, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Commerce, the Administrator of United States Agency for International Development, the Secretary of Defense, the United States Trade Representative, and any other relevant official, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the progress in implementing the Strategy for Pacific Islands Partnership.</text></subsection><subsection id="H73A680E1463B4275BDCDFE96B14F473D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H6FEBE678B20340499F08EAC854D0153F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of the security challenges to the Pacific Islands, including—</text><subparagraph id="H47143E16342848DFB28205FDF22C706B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the status of security challenges to the Pacific Islands, including as outlined by regional documents such as the Boe Declaration on regional security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C395358EEAC43A2A91FCEA1D28BFD30"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an analysis of demonstrated needs of the Pacific Islands for assistance, including excess defense equipment and related materials with humanitarian and development uses to fulfill such needs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCCC1D7FD04954A9AA39FF97DD9241051"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a review of existing security assistance programs in the Pacific Islands, including programs and efforts provided by United States allies and partners;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBF108EDE56B42F9ABEEFD1681BAD7F3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a plan for programs for training and sustainment with respect to such excess defense equipment and related materials, including those with humanitarian and development uses;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB70EA56E13842F2BB294309CB767A32"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a list of militaries, national police forces, coast guards, and other national security forces of the Pacific Islands receiving assistance under the strategy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80212FB82ED442438D118546C2C3EC69"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a plan to provide humanitarian assistance and disaster relief, if necessary, through the Overseas Humanitarian Disaster and Civic Aid program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC692EACC41A64AD7890562BC07CE5D55"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a review of existing cross-border maritime law enforcement operations (commonly known as <quote>shiprider agreements</quote>) with the Pacific Islands, an assessment of additional resourcing needs to enhance operational capacity, and a plan to improve on these programs and operations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD722F859D5740489830E3145E5B5266"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a review of existing National Guard State Partnership Programs with the Pacific Islands, an assessment of additional opportunities to leverage National Guard State Partnership Programs to address law enforcement, disaster relief and emergency management, and related priorities, and a plan to expand, as appropriate, existing and new National Guard State Partnership Programs in the region;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28388837C6B1420692DC6206D2459AEE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a review of current efforts and progress in removing unexploded ordnance in the Pacific Islands and an assessment of additional resourcing needed to ensure continued progress, including to support coordination with regional efforts and those of United States allies and partners;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EF81656432B453F801E0DBE36807E64"><enum>(J)</enum><text>a review of existing regional fusion centers and other cooperative intelligence sharing efforts in the Pacific Islands to address maritime security, transnational crime, natural disasters, and other security challenges and an assessment of opportunities for the United States to participate in such efforts, including by allocating staff and supplying resourcing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6028E60071B64F7F8EB4DE2E1B844DAE"><enum>(K)</enum><text>measures to evaluate success for the strategy; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5234E063C7624A668FC00F7026EE6D23"><enum>(L)</enum><text>a detailed assessment of appropriations required to achieve the objectives for the strategy in future years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H12F2BA4AC9C14E2DBFAB784D231C9D6A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the diplomatic presence in the Pacific Islands, including—</text><subparagraph id="HFB2861C0752D45078853B2C7EDEBBB28"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the Department of State, United States Agency for International Development, United States International Development Finance Corporation, Millennium Challenge Corporation, United States Trade and Development Authority and United States Commercial Service presence, staffing, programming, and resourcing of operations in the Pacific Islands, including programming and resourcing not specifically allocated to the Pacific Islands; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D6739EE42D14D7490866C4BA33CD85B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of gaps in such presence, including unfilled full-time equivalent positions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEE5108CD90449ACA52EB84DAC109722"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of coordination with regional allies, including—</text><subparagraph id="H68AAD9320EB141E0A677BB0C08AD9CF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a review of ongoing efforts, initiatives, and programs undertaken by regional allies and partners, including multilateral organizations, to advance the priorities identified in this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B9B1610559E4522926FBC9C98F23395"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a review of ongoing efforts, initiatives, and programs undertaken by nonallied foreign actors that are viewed as being potentially harmful or in any way detrimental to one or more countries of the Pacific Islands; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0CDF1977DC04FCBAB405A2D052ACF6D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an assessment of United States programs in the Pacific Islands and their alignment and complementarity with the efforts of regional allies and partners.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H43DCD83335744E0D884248CCEF331CA1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of trade capacity building, including—</text><subparagraph id="HA6CBA21AFEAD48A7A9D3EBDB2604CE76"><enum>(A)</enum><text>economic opportunities for which United States businesses, or those of other like-minded partners, would be competitive;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A72CC2F2F5247E488EC125EFEE182A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>legal, economic, governance, infrastructural, or other hurdles limiting United States investment in the Pacific Islands; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06EDCE4ED62E4796B07EFE817CDD9873"><enum>(C)</enum><text>steps the United States has taken to—</text><clause id="H30025A072A1C4533952968062D0744BF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>develop human and institutional capacity and infrastructure across multiple sectors of economies, including digital connectivity and cybersecurity;</text></clause><clause id="H004B4773488C43FEB9932CBC04A67368"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assist with development and implementation of regional and international trade agreements, including the World Trade Organization’s Agreement on Trade Facilitation and facilitation of intraregional trade flows;</text></clause><clause id="HBF8E7D54469846E7A40E6F5C54C12304"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>support women-owned enterprises and gender equality; and</text></clause><clause id="H315968C67C9B41F5A6B97CF70917FD6B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>promote government policies that encourage free and fair competition, sound governance, environmental protection, and business environments conducive to sustainable and inclusive economic growth.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE07A4CDF2D954F179584CCB607391137"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of trade development, including—</text><subparagraph id="H6E4DA8DD841B4C4C879E1670924DAA97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of the readiness of countries in the Pacific Islands to enter into enhanced trade relationships with the United States, including with respect to reducing or eliminating tariff and nontariff barriers inhibiting progress towards deepening trade relationships;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB46D694D84B64FD7B38327029EFE5335"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a review of existing regional multilateral and bilateral trade agreements and preference programs involving the Pacific Islands and their impacts on regional trade and development; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04C7088249DB4AEDA2AAF40595539E58"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an identification of opportunities to work with existing regional frameworks to increase trade and economic integration with the Pacific Islands.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H53B37808AF524014ABB5A9E48290DC89"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A description of emergency preparedness for the Pacific Islands, including—</text><subparagraph id="HE248FCB728524363B8655C07F4A6DA8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of disaster risks in the Pacific Islands and existing local and regional capacity to respond to such risks; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8654D5AF00594525B8C5BEF838E5A1AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a review of existing efforts by United States allies and partners to provide assistance and training for natural disaster preparedness and emergency management.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H990A2DEE0FE14DA4A566EA3474576898"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A description of activities of the Peace Corps in the Pacific Islands, including—</text><subparagraph id="H24A46CEAC5734113BE2B94D1AAB44876"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a comparative analysis of the Peace Corps presence in the Pacific Islands region to other regions of the world, including a cost-benefit analysis of placement in the region versus elsewhere globally;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5294DBD605AE438F9B35B598B1E6B465"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an analysis of current impediments to Peace Corps expansion in the Pacific Islands region;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2511A65E7304159860AD4B6AA868483"><enum>(C)</enum><text>outcomes of consultations among United States agencies, and with regional allies and partners, on areas in which cooperation can reduce factors limiting Peace Corps expansion, particularly those related to medical transportation and personal safety; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H352110231A324E809BCB4C2C456E1389"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a plan and timeline for implementing outcomes identified to facilitate expansion of Peace Corps presence in the region, where appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H38F2720D4C3744C58970CC900FE8CF47"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of public health and health care challenges in the Pacific Islands, including health systems strengthening, immunization, noncommunicable diseases, and gender-based violence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBBA0B23B8C14AB2A442AC23E945A7D6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>A description of resilient development in the Pacific Islands, including—</text><subparagraph id="H318ACCD6BEC14DD1BF6E52D8E25C1DC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a review of foreign infrastructure developments in the Pacific Islands by non-United States allies and partners;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6B0601085AA4FF3BD81B6D098FD0684"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assessments of the environmental impact and sustainability of such developments; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H595F2B2DF8A045B0977845B975F16AC8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an analysis of the financial sustainability of such developments and their impacts on the debt of host countries in the Pacific Islands; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD78C05AF1724077B7A7C11A74B85982"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the region’s banking infrastructure and Pacific Island access to financial services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CC052EC086D470A92BB4B3FE39F5AAE"><enum>(10)</enum><text>A description of press freedom in the Pacific Islands, including—</text><subparagraph id="H6BEB4D532C7046159241B9F7E126C371"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of the national laws of the Pacific Islands with respect to foreign investment in media and related sectors; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74C8FF3E55594DD6B4DE60EB8B7B3799"><enum>(B)</enum><text>relevant licensing regulations of the Pacific Islands and governmental restrictions on free expression that limit the availability of diverse media voices in the Pacific Islands; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F329555B26C4866B3CDA31537DA054A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>analyses of covert efforts by foreign media actors in the Pacific Islands—</text><clause id="H31463DBDCF3F46C4AD79C42A10417A8E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to influence, shape, or circumvent regulations in the media or telecommunication sectors; and</text></clause><clause id="H9FDB10115800414CBA7DA2F94F793E12"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to co-opt local media and narratives.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F741E478A514382971F228D2F993E8E"><enum>(11)</enum><text>A description of civil society engagement and development, including—</text><subparagraph id="HA78D454D066E4256A27CA8F2D83CF300"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of the strength and viability of civil society sectors of the Pacific Islands, including legal, organizational capacity, financial, advocacy, services, infrastructure, and public image sectors; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADD4B117B39F43C998CAF8D46D45D7E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an identification of objectives and measures of success for the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H879616BF214A45D380EC446FF745F77C"><enum>(12)</enum><text>A description of United States Government efforts to assist the Pacific Islands in the improvement of critical physical and cyber infrastructure, including—</text><subparagraph id="H928209CFF6824987BCB2FCE5675AF86C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>investments in the development or improvement critical infrastructure supported by the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE94B714E183C4DC2AA9B82E58CCDA6E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>technical assistance for the development or improvement of critical infrastructure supported by the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9A4074C7A6042CCA441395A53D87097"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of support given to the Pacific Islands on the expansion of telecommunications infrastructure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H96A48E9B3F7F4D0C916257D8805D79E3"><enum>(13)</enum><text>A description of United States Government efforts to assist the Pacific Islands in accessing support from international organizations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BF370A1AA814D2BB604416F1ED1AF64"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how United States Government efforts align with regional development goals, as outlined in documents such as the 2050 Strategy for a Blue Pacific Continent.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2AA57F5AC1944FBF9F033A0D24478672"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recommendation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President may submit to the appropriate congressional committees a recommendation on the consolidation or elimination of any duplicative reports as required by this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H2F90B50D0FC742528FBB20705499400C"><enum>802.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated $270,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2033 to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

