<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H065503E81E2147C388B236CD7B734383" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 301 IH: Honoring the life and celebrating the birthday of Ulysses S. Grant, America’s 18th President and native son of Ohio’s Second Congressional District.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 301</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000490">Mr. Taylor</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the life and celebrating the birthday of Ulysses S. Grant, America’s 18th President and native son of Ohio’s Second Congressional District.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on April 27, 1822, Ulysses S. Grant was born in Point Pleasant, Ohio, and lived in Georgetown, Ohio, throughout his childhood until 1839, when he left to attend the United States Military Academy at West Point;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, after Grant graduated from West Point, he joined the 4th Regiment, US Infantry, where he served with distinction in the Mexican-American War;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, over the course of the American Civil War, Grant commanded and fought in the battles of Fort Donelson, Shiloh, Vicksburg, Chattanooga, the Wilderness, Petersburg, and Appomattox;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Grant was appointed the first Lieutenant General of the United States Army after Congress reestablished the position in 1864;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on March 4, 1869, Grant was sworn in as the 18th President of the United States, officially becoming the second Ohioan to serve as President of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, throughout his two terms as President, Grant worked on civil rights issues including the establishment of the Department of Justice, adoption of the 15th Amendment, and other Reconstruction efforts;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this resolution honors the 203rd birthday of President Ulysses S. Grant and the 160th anniversary of the end of the American Civil War; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Land of US Grant, Inc., located in Georgetown, Ohio, works to promote the legacy of Ulysses S. Grant by preserving his boyhood home, school house, tannery, native son statue, and murals: Now, therefore be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HB6C54501889B47C28C81D2D35E2C73A6"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HD634BD3254E944189385FA8C70B0F0D7"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H822EFDEDB104452391F47197850D61AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">honors Ulysses S. Grant and the Land of US Grant, Inc., for their many contributions to Ohio and Ohio’s Second Congressional District; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CB38D1E56D24A62AA923B16BE78B856"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes that Ulysses S. Grant was pivotal to the Union’s military success in the Civil War and affirms his legacy as a trailblazer for civil rights and Reconstruction efforts.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

