<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1E04075C5980428C89A8D1ABC3722F90" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3598 IH: Deescalation Drone Pilot Program Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3598</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250523">May 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000829">Mr. Wied</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001228">Ms. Maloy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, to establish a pilot program for small, nonlethal deescalation unmanned aircraft to be used for law enforcement and public safety, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFA6CC3325A8547DE9CAE6A75818B0622" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1A0D24E66C31471581C18FA28022BD92" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Deescalation Drone Pilot Program Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8EAD86930D4C40E091DD24F76CA66C91" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Small unmanned aircraft pilot program for law enforcement and public safety</header> <subsection id="H1207B4F0E9254CBAA2E24DDE039D6234"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/448">Chapter 448</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H652D7F708ACE4EFCBA5F9475CA6BD7DE" style="USC"> 
<section id="HE4B8B3B60D5A49408B6C9165EDAC2312"><enum>44815.</enum><header>Small unmanned aircraft pilot program for law enforcement and public safety</header> 
<subsection id="H7349A78E49B84CC694D17C2063D74B68"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition regarding weapons</header><text>The prohibition regarding unmanned aircraft armed with dangerous weapons under section 363 of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44802">49 U.S.C. 44802</external-xref> note) is reaffirmed.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H46926EB15BF143498FD6439F643DC735"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pilot program</header> <paragraph id="H90D8D2A7B8A64254890017B7BD8535A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall establish a deescalation drone pilot program to review the potential use of nonlethal deescalation unmanned aircraft by Federal, State, local, or Tribal law enforcement responding to an active shooter event.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE4F680B81F447B3BFD030AAF4DF1E6A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The pilot program required under paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H9977A50E194741B190907E1DE0E9BE23"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">address the process of reviewing and validating nonlethal weapons that may be affixed to an unmanned aircraft;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4973F14287264F6BB59B82AC23F65DB0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">address training protocols for law enforcement and agents of the Administration for the use of nonlethal deescalation unmanned aircraft;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H278AA8D3FC6242EEB4907C666BE1D4CC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">address operational and safety protocols for operators of nonlethal deescalation unmanned aircraft and agencies directly overseeing the operation of such unmanned aircraft; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H88258147BA854C5086270AB9987BBBF9"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess the efficacy of nonlethal deescalation unmanned aircraft in indoor active shooter events and the safety benefits associated with increasing the safe engagement distance between a law enforcement officer and an active shooter.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4443684387254CA69D4360E6CA8D7705"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the pilot program under this subsection, the Administrator shall use existing partnerships with the unmanned aircraft system test ranges designated under section 44803, in collaboration with Federal, State, and large metropolitan area law enforcement.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0B490DCDD29D4094AE4073FB7293103A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Interagency aviation agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may enter into interagency aviation agreements, as necessary, with the Department of Justice, the Department of Homeland Security, and State large metropolitan and rural law enforcement agencies to support the pilot program under this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D6B1BCF28DC4972809F777DCD2BD988"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Administrator shall solicit input from, and coordinate with, relevant stakeholders as appropriate in carrying out the pilot program established under this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9FC57E8355FB400EAD0CD9011D56CB43"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 months after the conclusion of the pilot program, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report on the results of the pilot program that includes a plan outlining a proposed process through which a law enforcement applicant to such program may seek permission from the Administrator to operate nonlethal deescalation unmanned aircraft.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H290CEC34131E44FA8DAEA5BDBE3DD0C3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after submitting the report required under subsection (b)(6), the Administrator shall initiate a rulemaking to create a process through which the Administrator may provide approval—</text> 
<paragraph id="HBA7D3AD01A8B4CA38911BE6A1F23F4BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for Federal, State, local, or Tribal law enforcement to operate nonlethal deescalation unmanned aircraft during an active shooter event; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCB91D1E9FDD54740803B35CA89A779B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for manufacturers of nonlethal deescalation unmanned aircraft to operate such devices for testing, validation, and law enforcement demonstrations.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8021A733A4654E0AA57252BC7C6AC685"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Manufacturing requirement</header><text>Any nonlethal deescalation unmanned aircraft used under the pilot program shall be manufactured in the United States, as defined by the Federal Trade Commission under part 323 of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H716053ADB4434415A6E17971BF442A45"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H33C22710E8CF42168576EF997C1A8146"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Active shooter event</header><text>The term <term>active shooter event</term> means an event in which—</text> <subparagraph id="HFF279D1B645A46D2996AA3ABF95F3323"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individual is actively engaged in unlawfully killing or attempting to kill people using explosives as defined under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/40">chapter 40</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, or weapons subject to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18 or <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF344CC6030584CAFB3564AF67DBF0D89"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">responding to the event poses a significant risk to human life, including the lives of law enforcement personnel and other individuals; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H04830E4B51AC43468A29C3E5A2D9E787"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">absent an immediate use of force, the individual described in subparagraph (A) would continue posing a threat to human life.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEB63395B975B4403B1973EC9B1948CFD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonlethal deescalation unmanned aircraft</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>nonlethal deescalation unmanned aircraft</term> means an unmanned aircraft operated by law enforcement that—</text> <subparagraph id="HC2C6BDA004A848ADBF1AC031E82EFB95"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is only equipped or armed with 1 or more nonlethal weapons, including those that may be subject to the definition provided in section 930(g)(2) of title 18, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7A00CB66987A474C916B325B2C80F97B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be equipped with other nonlethal devices, including intense sound distraction emitters, cameras, targeting sensors, speakers, strobe lights and other similar collateral equipment.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H42C23B5FEA344AA0A150EFAF11BD6A9A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nonlethal weapon</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>nonlethal weapon</term> means a weapon, device, or munition that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H364C168C548C4259A429D0ABB78C0D81"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is explicitly designed and primarily employed to immediately incapacitate targeted individuals or property in the target area while minimizing—</text> <clause id="HD4FF8BD0D45E4713BD67B2337E4CBC54"><enum>(i)</enum><text>fatalities;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD6D716B68D58491B919AFAEBF99DAA4B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>permanent injury to individuals; and</text></clause> <clause id="H105AEBB3BB69495090BBDC5B449F3859"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>undesired damage to property; and</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB261A4EF537A4547AFCC92EF5C53F7D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is intended to have reversible effects on individuals and property.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HBF06403424B94E57936D1DD374B47FE2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/448">chapter 448</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H071C9C9BE27E4242BE891776C5431D55" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">‘44815. Small unmanned aircraft pilot program for law enforcement and public safety.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

