<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H66B5939DFB704DE6A40D08E4E96FCAA2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4886 IH: Larry Barrett Veterans’ Memory Care Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4886</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250805">August 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001093">Mrs. Houchin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for consideration of certain factors under the Veterans Community Care Program, to provide for expedited approval of certain requests for Veterans Care Agreements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC55CBD8FAC40401B86A61F9D55E8DBDC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H407B7A5592904938925D1E38D75AE260" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Larry Barrett Veterans’ Memory Care Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H86572CAD3B92465FB98E2C15A23F0BC6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Consideration under Veterans Community Care Program of veteran preference for care, continuity of care, and need for caregiver or attendant</header> 
<subsection id="HCD26F1FB0D12430E9C0BB67F9C9B7EA1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1703(d)(2) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H7A60194DE3A84D22A9CD0BADFBC9932C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H2D5F5EF3502C4DE69C5ACAD80BAC5D0E" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the three-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of the Dignity in Veterans Aging Act of 2025—</text> 
<clause id="HA4F922248F4646A18ECE8D6BD13208C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a covered veteran seeking extended care services—</text> <subclause id="H4A39EEDDA6C541A89D530457AF0DBE39"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the preference of the covered veteran for where, when, and how to seek such services; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF01E61B97F8346139307C032E101C5FF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>whether the covered veteran requests or requires the assistance of a caregiver or attendant when seeking such services; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H96618140010746FDA203FF62209B557A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>continuity of care.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4798B3FE968A439D8D97AD9844B30A48"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a veteran who is a covered veteran under section 1703 of title 38, United States Code, and who is receiving extended care services pursuant to subparagraph (F) of subsection (d)(2) of such section, the veteran may continue to receive such care or services until the end of the episode of care notwithstanding the termination date specified in such subparagraph.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HC18B2DF58C024F65B743084B5FEF9D5F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Expedited approval process for certain requests for Veterans Care Agreements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1703A of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H253038A3393749C98B4AE7D39C9289D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (k) and (l) as subsections (l) and (m), respectively;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H599033F1F9814DF9892F3BB85331E9A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (j) the following new subsection (k):</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H8D9A7D7CB08540099090278B1E23F0A8" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HD26253D0F9FC45D89F9F779DAAEDA294"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Expedited approval process</header> 
<paragraph id="HC9278CA8C5274727A222F98AD1D81F00" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a request made by a covered individual described in paragraph (2) for a Veterans Care Agreement with an eligible entity or provider, the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H8E78BA5B85144C398CCCC42524306E0F" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>approve the request under this section, including the certification under subsection (c) regardless of whether the eligible entity or provider meets the criteria under such subsection or the requirements under subsection (e), by not later than 30 days after the date on which the request is made; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8BD33EFE9BF54AB488EE6711CB8835FB" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>during the period beginning on the date of the request and ending on the date of the approval of the request, provide in-home care services for the covered veteran under section 1720L of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFCE7B7354C764E578E11BE556991DE9D" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A covered individual described in this subsection is a covered individual who—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD5FBFC797F9C42E69BFEFE5A849320AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has expressed to the Secretary a preference to receive an extended care service required by the individual from an eligible entity or provider that—</text> <clause id="HF251E3B16CE74A53AC7950B388D3325B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not party to a Veterans Care Agreement under this section; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBDAD11D3BED44D10924A56585F45CDE9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not a health care provider specified in section 1703(c) of this title; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDB8F1F773C7E411C92EE15ECCD2F4AAE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">resides in a location that requires traveling for longer than an hour to reach the location of any health care provider specified in section 1703(c) of this title who is qualified to furnish the extended care service required by the individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H24F9F458392B4D92B1C8AD02CA15B90A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(1), by striking <quote>subsection (k)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (l)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

