<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HA72D0CA72ED348E0A8128974B47DB9E8" resolution-type="house-resolution">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 713 IH: Censuring Representative Ilhan Omar of Minnesota and removing her from the Committee on Education and Workforce and the Committee on the Budget.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 713</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250915">September 15, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSO00">Committee on Ethics</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">Censuring Representative Ilhan Omar of Minnesota and removing her from the Committee on Education and Workforce and the Committee on the Budget.</official-title>
</form>
<preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas Charlie Kirk was a lifelong advocate for freedom of speech, civil political discourse, and the political engagement of youth;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Charlie Kirk was a man of deep faith, a husband, and a father to two young children;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, on September 10, 2025, Charlie Kirk was assassinated on the campus of Utah Valley University while exercising his First Amendment right to freedom of speech;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on September 11, 2025, one day after the assassination of Charlie Kirk, Representative Ilhan Omar gave an interview on a Zeteo Town Hall with Mehdi Hasan in which she smeared Charlie Kirk and implied he was to blame for his own murder; </text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, on September 12, 2025, two days after the assassination of Charlie Kirk, Representative Ilhan Omar reposted a video on X (formerly known as Twitter), which disparaged the character of Charlie Kirk and those mourning his death;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the video Representative Ilhan Omar reposted on X states <quote>Charlie Kirk is dead, and before the body got cold, the far­ Right propped his corpse up as a cudgel for their holy war</quote>;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the video Representative Ilhan Omar reposted on X further states <quote>Don't be fooled, these people don't give a single shit about Charlie Kirk, they are just using his death to further their Christofascist agenda</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the video Representative Ilhan Omar reposted on X further states Charlie Kirk <quote>was a reprehensible human being. He enacted his political agenda by preying on weak minded people. He took complex socioeconomic issues and simplified them by pointing fingers at out-groups, demonizing those groups, and siccing his massive following on them</quote>;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the video Representative Ilhan Omar reposted on X further states Charlie Kirk was a <quote>stochastic terrorist, an adamant transphobe, he denied the genocide happening in Palestine, he believed in the subjugation of women, and in his last dying words he was spewing racist dog whistles</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the video Representative Ilhan Omar reposted on X further states <quote>Charlie Kirk was Dr. Frankenstein and his monster shot him through the neck</quote>;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the video Representative Ilhan Omar reposted on X further blames Charlie Kirk for his own murder;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas clause 1 of rule XXIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives provides, <quote>A Member, Delegate, Resident Commissioner, officer, or employee of the House shall behave at all times in a manner that shall reflect creditably on the House</quote>; and </text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Representative Ilhan Omar's actions in the wake of the assassination of Charlie Kirk are reprehensible and affect the dignity and integrity of the proceedings of the House and do not reflect credibility on the House: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body id="H56474B14AC304EB98B3F599FE6B3FF96" style="traditional"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA8863CB480414D12B40375DC7BAA46FD" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum/><text>That—</text>
<paragraph id="H75139E0D0EAE4AA599CBCDA3FF551A88"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Representative Ilhan Omar of Minnesota be censured;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0AC4B8A24F7C480F8B991EF6F5CF0D24"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Representative Ilhan Omar forthwith present herself in the well of the House of Representatives for the pronouncement of censure;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H01379D5F4C3D4625AD68B3E9A96BBEC6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Representative Ilhan Omar be censured with the public reading of this resolution by the Speaker; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H05A5B0DC5E564F2191A3769EA72CA16E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Representative Ilhan Omar be, and is hereby, removed from the Committee on Education and Workforce and the Committee on the Budget of the House.</text></paragraph></section>
</resolution-body>
</resolution> 


