<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG25526-DJD-S0-VHF">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1344 IS: Quantum Sandbox for Near-Term Applications Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>S. 1344</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title>To amend the National Quantum Initiative Act to establish a public-private partnership for near-term quantum application development and acceleration, and for other purposes. </official-title>
</form>
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H790235FED9F048CB864D296AB6A6582A">
<section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Quantum Sandbox for Near-Term Applications Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="idb87589c293ad4ac2a61df4a113c66400"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text>
<paragraph id="id5a0b61db295146c1951f0e6657b4f3d0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The National Quantum Initiative and its ongoing activities explore and promote Quantum Information Science.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id8748b64d3f04413fa5b1e12eee112062"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Continual innovation by the quantum industry of the United States is critically important.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id0df16da5e77c417c91382962fd259c5c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Quantum and quantum-hybrid applications have the ability to provide innovative solutions for near-term use cases across a variety of public and private sector challenges.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id3a4d9538efd748d09f801869fc7b96e9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Many quantum computers are available via the cloud and through a dedicated near-term quantum application acceleration program that is inclusive of the wide variety of quantum computing technologies will break down barriers to access quantum computing hardware systems.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id53cf9565e97341979b7eb626999162cc"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Business and consumers of the United States will be able to see benefits of the innovation through a program focusing on near-term use of the technology.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idcb6c14f0a6c54d7bbd568bd277c2b15a"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Quantum information science is a foundational technology that is transforming the economy of the 21st century.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="ide32f36373fe142d799b2dbe323119515"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Robust leadership in quantum research and near-term development will have a great impact on the economic security of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idebffd4e8bf3649bcb1720f02eff10648"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Unrivaled excellence in workforce development is key in developing next generation leaders in quantum applications. </text></paragraph></section>
<section id="idd3974e5d3760425ba194313cb4584e17"><enum>3.</enum><header>Public-private partnership for quantum application development acceleration</header>
<subsection id="idDE0EB2E7314443B7B85F99829F66B4F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title IV of the National Quantum Initiative Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8851">15 U.S.C. 8851 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id516f9682a9f04e36ab6fb8c5d4ab3f72"> <section id="ide39559e2e84249a6b18c04b7e016001a"><enum>405.</enum><header>Public-private partnership for quantum application development acceleration</header> <subsection id="id3bc13cb3a6c6491b9bc8780ab1eb776f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="id8673bd888b8d4116b36b30d172b03c11"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Quantum applications</header><text>The term <term>quantum applications</term> means algorithms and applications which use quantum mechanics through quantum processing units. These applications include quantum computing, quantum communication, quantum sensing, and quantum-hybrid applications which are applications that use both quantum computing and classical computing hardware systems.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idc1aee5f7773f4344bc37a20f44e93354"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Quantum sandbox</header><text>The term <term>quantum sandbox</term> means a program—</text>
<subparagraph id="idE0AF0CEFDFB046A289BFEAAA26C7D6A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for innovation and development of applications using quantum information sciences with a focus on near-term use cases; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id47D7AB7CFA2E4BF6A8756ADDE2CE2D1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that can be used to develop and test demonstrations, proofs of concepts, and pilot applications.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaf3d39758a5b4fdda0db0fe895d2e9a1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Near-term use case</header><text>The term <term>near-term use case</term> means an application that can be developed and deployed in less than 24 months.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="id5BF7193F035B42A3AEDD2EEE127D1AF6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of quantum sandbox required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce shall, in coordination with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, establish a quantum sandbox through the establishment of a public-private partnership focused on quantum application development acceleration for quantum application near-term use cases.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="id4EB20ECDBD8F4618B56B57359C249E5C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Engagement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As part of the Program and in carrying out subsection (b), the Secretary shall, acting through the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, engage with the Quantum Economic Development Consortium, the National Laboratories (as defined in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>)), federally funded research and development centers, and other members of the United States quantum computing and quantum information ecosystem.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="id1FCD13CAE1304271B66CF3B79CD768C1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of such Act is amended by adding after the item relating to section 404 the following new item:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id64BAF7DCE3CF4B90BF157728627B4385">
<toc>
<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 405. Public-private partnership for quantum application development acceleration.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


