<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H82449B1F5B2841B88AB39311D884FBEC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4881 IH: Supplying Wait-time Information to Facilitate Timely Voting with Operational and Technology Enhancements Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4881</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250805">August 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Election Assistance Commission to make grants to States for procuring and maintaining electronic pollbooks with the capability of collecting and disseminating wait time information, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB4009E94C8EE4F76AB77009F899E74D5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6F4A744420FF4D9395E1841549ABA78A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supplying Wait-time Information to Facilitate Timely Voting with Operational and Technology Enhancements Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SWIFT VOTE Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> 
<section id="H8836D71CD03E4FF0A1B54C23DF4F2698" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants for procuring and maintaining electronic pollbooks</header> 
<subsection id="HA38024C49ED146F29CBD364E9C66EB3A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header> 
<paragraph id="H204E28B5B2FF4BE2AFB08EC596AB316B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority to make grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Election Assistance Commission shall make a grant to each eligible jurisdiction in a State for the purpose of—</text> <subparagraph id="HE953A2CF384F424FB6A25F82227EBED6" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>procuring or maintaining electronic pollbooks (hereafter referred to as <quote>e-pollbooks</quote>); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA3E3CE073F9D464C92E004A6EFE391B6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>developing the capability of collecting and disseminating wait time information for use in elections for Federal office, whether through the use of e-pollbooks with such capability or through other means.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H941CCCCC1298486EA00AD7696FBC3F02"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prioritization of grants to procure e-pollbooks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making grants to eligible jurisdictions under this section, the Commission shall give priority to eligible jurisdictions showing demonstrated need for new or additional e-pollbooks which the jurisdiction will use to reduce wait times at polling places on the dates of elections for Federal office, and give priority to eligible jurisdictions that propose the development of capability to report wait time information in accordance with subsection (c)(2)(A).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H731AF0CA93B04449B7FDF3552AC84A2A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible jurisdiction is eligible to receive a grant under this section if the eligible jurisdiction submits to the Commission, at such time and in such form as the Commission may require, an application containing the information and assurances described in subsection (c).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD54915604F4743088123AFF888A13499"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Information described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The information and assurances described in this subsection are, with respect to an eligible jurisdiction, the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H4A69DDAA11D748CBA7FA3E55A7436576"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For an eligible jurisdiction seeking funding for e-pollbooks, a description of the need of the eligible jurisdiction for procuring or maintaining e-pollbooks.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDC72ACB6223740D8AE2BE22B94E9A4CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For an eligible jurisdiction seeking funding for the collection and dissemination of wait time information—</text>
<subparagraph id="H29D4983EA22C4139AB11847F08803CF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a certification that the chief election official of the eligible jurisdiction shall publish on the official public website of the chief election official the most recent wait time information for each polling place which is open for voters to vote in an election for Federal office—</text> <clause id="H4406DFF79E1145D081F6AA1E97F5B2D0" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a polling place which is open for 4 hours or fewer on such a day, on an hourly basis on such a day; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H1089EA5223CD437E997633DE715DD733">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a polling place which is open for more than 4 hours on such a day, on at least 4 regular intervals on such a day.</text>
                        </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1C7EC900D6564B4F94B5FAF7C444F9AA">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following each election cycle, publish on the official public website of the chief election official of the eligible jurisdiction a report detailing wait time information through that election cycle, including on the date of the election as well as any dates on which individuals were permitted to vote in person prior to the date of the election, including wait times throughout each such day of voting, to the extent such information is available.</text>
                    </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H21F7368C4DB3435C9051923DF531575D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assurance that—</text> <subparagraph id="H4B5550746C89466896A0AE4635E92629"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the funds provided under this section will be used to supplement and not supplant other funds used to carry out the activities for which the funds are provided; and</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9BD6D573581B4CF597551DA9BB635401"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the chief election official of the eligible jurisdiction shall provide regular reports to the Commission containing information on the procurement and maintenance of e-pollbooks with the funds provided under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1C729B861C3048C399A09CE0F6E00A99"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assurance that the eligible jurisdiction shall develop procedures for certifying that the procurement and maintenance of e-pollbooks with the funds provided under this section is in compliance with the Commission’s Voluntary Electronic Poll Book Certification Program, or any similar or successor program established by the Commission for e-pollbook certification. Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to prohibit a eligible jurisdiction in a State from receiving a grant under this section on the grounds that the State has in effect standards and procedures for the use of e-pollbooks which are in addition to the standards and procedures required by the Commission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF4B834DEEC364BF18A34FCCCA1432B29"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An assurance that the eligible jurisdiction will work with experts in voting system technology and infrastructure to develop and carry out training programs in the use of e-pollbooks by election officials, and that such programs will train election officials in methods that will enable the officials to meet the needs of individual voters, including voters with limited English language proficiency and voters with disabilities, without regard to age, gender, or sexual orientation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H11404F0F7DBA449AB17B98CA1BEEACF5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Such other information and assurances as the Commission may require.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF45B8F086CB74A4AA212A4E95F3B609A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="H6A88D530BA5B4049A2CA11F77D1D41C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Election Assistance Commission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE3BB14E4E70441A0A7F84BC6EE4B2AC7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>election cycle</quote> means the period beginning on the day after the date of the most recent regularly scheduled general election for Federal office and ending on the date of the next such election.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H58AD9354879C4FCD83532F806177EBE9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>eligible jurisdiction</term> means a State or a political subdivision of a State which is responsible for carrying out an election for Federal office in the State.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5DDB2CAABFBE4E1DB141A2209E50F875"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>e-pollbook</term> means a device or technology that may be used at a polling place in an election for Federal office in place of a traditional paper poll book and that partially automates the process of checking in voters, assigning voters the correct ballot style, and tracking voters who have been issued a ballot. An e-pollbook may be used at the polling place together with a separate copy of the list of registered voters or may be networked into a central voter registration system which enables the election official at the polling place to check and update voter records in real time.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1C09470255014D788012A4886CE8E154"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam, the United States Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H48F879F02A6B47BD864298139438D288"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>wait time information</term> means, with respect to a polling place in an election for Federal office, the length of time between when an individual arrives at the polling place and completes the polling place’s check-in process, as well as the length of time between the completion of that individual’s check-in process and when that individual receives a ballot or, if a physical ballot is not provided, until the individual is directed to an electronic voting machine.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEA17783E0EDA4E0389B7F7579808F0C2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $120,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

