<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEL25588-YVY-VH-5VP"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2346 IS: Preparing Election Administrators for AI Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2346</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSRA00">Committee on Rules and Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Election Assistance Commission to develop voluntary guidelines for the administration of elections that address the use and risks of artificial intelligence technologies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id537eeb1b-545a-439d-9ecf-eb7905c9b453" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preparing Election Administrators for AI Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="idf63fd9fe-54d8-4def-aabe-46b8f92f8c92" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Voluntary guidelines for administration of elections that address the use and risks of artificial intelligence technologies</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2ed971f1-80fc-4a70-a3b3-164b70aa3e93" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report and voluntary guidelines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Election Assistance Commission shall, in consultation with the National Institute of Standards and Technology, submit to Congress, issue to State and local election offices, and make available to the public a report with voluntary guidelines for election offices that address the use and risks of artificial intelligence technologies in the administration of elections.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc214d34-7452-49e2-984a-1ddbb7833932" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report submitted and made available pursuant to subsection (a) shall include voluntary guidelines that address—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idda868401-5bb5-46b0-bb80-1b87e1634bb9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the risks and benefits associated with using artificial intelligence technologies to conduct election administration activities;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddb928810-cb57-48ad-802d-6e6aeef48774" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the cybersecurity risks of artificial intelligence technologies to election administration;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaba8ad3d-958c-4339-b9dd-862d71f16b1d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>how information generated and distributed by artificial intelligence technologies can affect the sharing of accurate election information and how election offices should respond; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f9410e0-20a3-401c-9938-6cd49cedeb93" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>how information generated and distributed by artificial intelligence technologies can affect the spreading of election disinformation that undermines public trust and confidence in elections.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id97d01e70f09144c9aa32a9454a6c2bb1" changed="not-changed"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study on use of artificial intelligence technologies in the 2024 elections</header><subsection id="id9be92b975baf4ac3b311bfc685a83f68" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than July 31, 2026, the Election Assistance Commission, in consultation with the National Institute of Standards and Technology, shall study and submit to Congress, issue to State and local election offices, and make available to the public a report on the use and impacts of artificial intelligence technologies in the elections for Federal office held in 2024, including how information generated by artificial intelligence technologies was shared and the use of artificial intelligence technologies by election offices.</text></subsection><subsection id="id23f38dd204c14d30a51dc2c229833890" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review and update of voluntary guidelines</header><text>Taking into consideration the results of the study conducted under subsection (a), the Election Assistance Commission shall review and update the voluntary guidelines issued under section 2(a) as appropriate. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

