<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H793136F1B86047038C2DC58D2839F892" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 532 IH: Supporting the designation of “Brain and Spine Metastasis Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 532</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250623">June 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of <quote>Brain and Spine Metastasis Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas brain and spine metastasis can occur with almost any type of cancer;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas improved cancer treatments are leading to longer patient survival, but brain and spine metastasis rates are increasing;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas specific cancers commonly spread to the brain and spine, such as melanoma, lung, breast, colon, and prostate cancers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas brain metastases are a leading cause of morbidity and mortality in patients with cancer;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas brain metastases are five times more common than primary brain tumors;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas advanced treatment options are available to improve patient outcomes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas disparities in cancer care exist, and awareness is crucial to address these disparities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas different treatments are needed for brain and spine metastasis than for other cancers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there are publicly available resources where patients and families can find information on brain and spine metastasis; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas new and novel therapies are offering hope, but more support and funding for clinical trials and specialized centers are necessary: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HA1B108EF4C88405ABE67625D3A7798A3"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H651F548D8C704019BBC543E527148B85"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H795BBF5183FB41B9BE01E0F7F6EF6C85"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>Brain and Spine Metastasis Awareness Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55615196DD634571ABF292C22A7B4184"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes and affirms the commitment by the House of Representatives to increasing awareness of treatment options for people with cancer that has spread to the brain or spine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE00332E88D343FA87DB327C82CBA5AF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes and affirms the dedication of the House of Representatives to increasing education for brain and spine metastasis so individuals can better understand their cancer or the cancer of a loved one; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4982D0887C342CABA723B8FD153CC46"><enum>(4)</enum><text>calls on the Secretary of Health and Human Services to—</text><subparagraph id="H120D5D8F731A47339BA2817641DEDCBB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increase education and awareness about treatment options available for patients with brain and spine metastases, including advances and improvements in medical therapies, such as targeted therapies or immunotherapies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD60F0ECAEBF14F24A40ECBD87568B8D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>support resources to establish and support centers for brain and spine metastasis;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEDE523DAAE74A3988F2B7EDAA15B554"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide resources to increase access to dedicated clinical trials for patients with brain or spine metastases; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF1C82BDC3674D1D8DDB023CA22C1382"><enum>(D)</enum><text>invest in research specifically into the biology and treatment of brain and spine metastasis, particularly across cancers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

