<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H33673EC7595A4AC3A5F8036184B647A7" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 697 IH: Recognizing suicide as a serious public health problem and expressing support for the designation of September as “National Suicide Prevention Month” as well as September 10, 2025, as “World Suicide Prevention Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 697</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000483">Ms. Friedman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing suicide as a serious public health problem and expressing support for the designation of September as <quote>National Suicide Prevention Month</quote> as well as September 10, 2025, as <quote>World Suicide Prevention Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (in this resolution referred to as <quote>CDC</quote>), suicide was among the top 8 leading causes of death for people aged 10 to 64 in 2023;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the CDC, suicide was the second-leading cause of death for people aged 10 to 34 in 2023;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the CDC, in 2023, suicide was responsible for 49,316 deaths, or about 1 death every 11 minutes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the number of people who think about or attempt suicide is even higher;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration’s (in this resolution referred to as <quote>SAMHSA</quote>) 2024 National Survey on Drug Use and Health Report, an estimated 14,300,000 adults had serious thoughts about suicide, 4,600,000 planned a suicide attempt, and 1,700,000 attempted suicide in 2024;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to SAMHSA, 2,600,000 adolescents aged 12 to 17 in the United States had serious thoughts of suicide, 1,200,000 made a suicide plan, and 700,000 attempted suicide the previous year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to SAMHSA, trends among adolescents aged 12 to 17 reporting having serious thoughts about suicide, making a suicide plan, and attempting suicide have decreased from 2021 to 2024, reflecting meaningful progress in prevention efforts;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the estimates among adolescents are likely to be skewed due to additional survey options beyond those given to adults; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Department of Veterans Affairs’ (in this resolution referred to as <quote>VA</quote>) 2024 National Veteran Suicide Prevention Annual Report, 6,407 veterans died by suicide in 2022;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the VA, suicide was the second-leading cause of death among veterans aged 45 or under and the 12th-leading cause of death for veterans overall in 2022;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the VA, the average number of veterans who died by suicide per day rose from 16.4 in 2001 to 17.6 in 2022;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the VA, among veterans with documented Veterans Crisis Line contact in 2022, the suicide rate in the following month was 22.5 percent lower than in 2019;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the VA, the number of veterans who died by suicide in 2022 was lower than in 12 of the previous 14 years, reflecting meaningful progress in prevention efforts;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the National Institutes of Health (in this resolution referred to as <quote>NIH</quote>), men are more likely to die by suicide;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the NIH, the suicide rate among men was four times higher than among women in 2022;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas additional research must be conducted to better understand the relationship between gender and suicide;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas studies have shown that suicide is one of the leading causes of death during pregnancy and the first year postpartum;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas studies show that suicide accounts for between 20 and 39 percent of postpartum deaths, making suicide a leading cause of maternal mortality;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the exclusion of suicide from the commonly accepted definition of maternal mortality creates a gap in data, and the actual rates may be higher; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the stigma associated with mental health conditions and suicidal ideation hinders suicide prevention by discouraging at-risk individuals from seeking lifesaving help; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas September is an appropriate month to designate as <quote>National Suicide Prevention Month</quote>, aligning with <quote>World Suicide Prevention Day</quote> on September 10, a date recognized internationally and supported by the World Health Organization: Now, therefore, be it;</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H08E0AC361B1A49349A0EEAED626DAACB"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HC5E6A111AADF4851BCF3DAFAC8B5227A"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H2F1215C593A7427F83F08635CAAD4D44"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes suicide as a preventable national public health problem;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63935C80E2404D44BB2F483D235DA0AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National Suicide Prevention Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDF44179B38347A5BC22C63F5A06E877"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>World Suicide Prevention Day</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68668DC0273E4772B2102931D400C2E1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>declares suicide prevention as a priority;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAB26B03DD084F8E9BF75BA141CD4156"><enum>(5)</enum><text>acknowledges that no single suicide prevention program or effort will be appropriate for all populations or communities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H989DB4A9F211419AA6675E270D894266"><enum>(6)</enum><text>recognizes that there is no single cause for suicide and that suicide is most often an impulsive act that occurs during a moment of overwhelming hopelessness and despair;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D95F1504F534E58947E1121E0B7D1F0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>recognizes that mental health is equally as important as physical health; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93238742D53F441AAC709E3F2ED18A72"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the development and implementation of strategies to increase access to quality mental health, substance abuse, and suicide prevention services.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

