<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELT25034-4HF-PM-94J"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1074 IS: Agricultural Access to Substance Use Disorder Treatment and Mental Health Care Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1074</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for a study on the accessibility of substance use disorder treatment and mental health care providers and services for farmers and ranchers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HD7B09CB16A1042BFA73DCC6C8B5BE0AF"><section section-type="section-one" id="H0809A210676947B3A31A8D07BD77B6E5"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Agricultural Access to Substance Use Disorder Treatment and Mental Health Care Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H23DD087536474470BEAB4637125BDBE3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on accessibility of substance use disorder treatment and mental health care providers and services for farmers and ranchers</header><subsection id="id4acfe0f5b2d1439fbab3496a59b70cd6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77b27326a6634f9fb96edd5b6e24124d"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct a study on the accessibility of substance use disorder treatment and mental health care providers and services for farmers and ranchers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd26c7bc955b442cf9e3b1f881e211673"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit a report containing the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1) to—</text><subparagraph id="id692b2251c62f4d3b9fdc4cef034c9c43"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id811def6cbdd546b487863c7e11006eb0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Health and Human Services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id223f4c03ce2f4690b1c5775c540cc070"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id39823484fd58459a88828fa337523fee"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2d596dc2de4c44439a3d9cc4a631280d"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Committee on Finance of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5eb5836457004393bebf4d82816629a1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida77438f78c354cababb1ec49a55fb9cf"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0a1d40c99fe4403a90defe934e91e711"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE05C672EA5B4FA5ADD2E971EC82F7C1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Topics addressed</header><text>The study conducted under subsection (a) shall include an examination of the following topics:</text><paragraph id="H1D61CC4B2ABE4036850EE33B48D7E02A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The availability and accessibility in rural areas of substance use disorder treatment and mental health care providers and services that are trained and dedicated to serve the needs of farmers, ranchers, agricultural workers, and their family members.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD987E1F6004348C8A6EAD6EB3E1ED4B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Barriers and challenges faced by farmers and ranchers in accessing substance use disorder treatment and mental health care and health and wellness resources, including financial, geographic, and cultural barriers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H235D55322F9046F8B82A67A6F7B83A42"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Identification of best practices and successful programs at the State and local levels that can be replicated at the Federal level to address substance use disorder treatment and mental health care needs in agricultural communities, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="H75D8E408461C499C9255D43311955316"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Hiring and training of substance use disorder treatment and mental health care professionals with expertise in working with agricultural communities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF558CF308694F95B389567753957D13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Accessing cultural competency training for substance use disorder treatment and mental health care professionals that lack expertise in working with agricultural communities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27D40AABB228491F90CE0DDBB51A9AC2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Developing certificate programs for paraprofessionals and coaches to offer peer-to-peer support programming.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3186A31BEA074CADB5357D3C7623EDC0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Researching effective curricula for youth and young adults to be offered in rural schools.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H338707DB9AC64BD0885942CE0CBBEB3B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Expanding telehealth and telemedicine services to improve access to care in rural areas.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7737D15F2D8642FC8B870EF58CAB1824"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Developing outreach and educational programs to reduce stigma and increase awareness of mental health issues among farmers and ranchers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57F915720F404EA388236A174E886F95"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Enhancing coordination and collaboration between existing mental health providers and agricultural organizations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87796A68F6D349A197F38DB292FC8CD0"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Conducting research and evaluation to measure the effectiveness of substance use disorder treatment and mental health care services provided to farmers and ranchers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2921789d1f4d4128967de7b786797d99"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Utilization of, and best practices among grantees through, the Farm and Ranch Stress Assistance Network under section 7522 of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/5936">7 U.S.C. 5936</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idad283a8eb8ef451bbe0219a2d086cc43"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Recommendations for improving the accessibility and utilization of substance use disorder treatment and mental health care for farmers and ranchers.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

