<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25A33-63C-3D-RFT">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2259 IS: Protecting Military Bases from Connected Vehicles of Concern Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2259</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250710">July 10, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</sponsor> introduced the following
                bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To prohibit the operation on property of the Department of Defense of
            certain vehicles designed, developed, manufactured, or supplied by persons owned by,
            controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction of a foreign entity of concern, and for
            other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="id94c74bb9898849a5bec8566a80b74db9" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Military Bases from Connected Vehicles of Concern Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="H8DABC49220CA42DAA139E7997C3C9EDD">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Prohibition on operation of connected vehicles designed, developed,
                manufactured, or supplied by persons owned by, controlled by, or subject to the
                jurisdiction of a foreign entity of concern on Department of Defense
                property</header>
            <subsection id="HC560A38FD7D24F0F9EB9040D824876BB">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After January 1, 2028, no connected vehicle on the list required under subsection (b) may be operated on a military installation or on any other property of the Department of Defense.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H42556B6806C148FA9F6FDF5D34F2F61B">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>List required</header>
                <paragraph id="H22C66AB7494E4BC2A31E4B48C7BB3AFE">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than January 1, 2027, the Secretary of Defense shall establish and publish on a publicly available website of the Department of Defense a list of prohibited connected vehicles that—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="HE62C5EBD6811434D8FB26A950367F880">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>are designed, developed, manufactured, or supplied by persons owned by, controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction of a foreign entity of concern; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H39AA907E705348028F38187E93D002E0">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>pose—</text> <clause id="HB6DD4FA97C814A69B02C5D9EF2301FA3"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an undue risk of sabotage to or subversion of the design, integrity, manufacturing, production, distribution, installation, operation, or maintenance of information and communications technology and services in the United States;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HD858A1C5E10D4A3E91A34F0A0DF1C953">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>an undue risk of catastrophic effects on the security or resiliency of critical infrastructure in the United States or the digital economy of the United States; or</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H1170EB79DE874265964FA497997EE291">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>an unacceptable risk to the national security of the United States or the security and safety of United States persons.</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idb72702e067dd469ba1940f92d750d55f">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Incorporation of existing Federal rules</header>
 <text>In establishing the list required under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall incorporate existing Federal rules for identifying prohibited connected vehicles.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id5bd02c094058451ea5451e9022e06ef4">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Annual review</header>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id06c67ee6dac844c3a89564bea80cad43">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                        <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall review the list required under paragraph (1) not less frequently than once each year and shall make such additions, subtractions, supplements, or amendments to the list as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8528abf242504fdcbcf9a639730ab717">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <header>Explanation of subtractions</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any review under subparagraph (A) that makes subtractions from the list required under paragraph (1) shall include an explanation of why the subtraction was made.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idec58b5a67a444f41be4ff34e6d218435">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
                    <header>Consultation</header>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfb7f7f5100024b7c94cd87a8d19d6173">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                        <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall consult with the head of any Federal department or agency that the Secretary determines is appropriate in making the list required under paragraph (1) and conducting any annual review under paragraph (3).</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id364ebc63441649b996f648ed5144238c">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <header>Transmittal of list</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall transmit a copy of the list required under paragraph (1), and any modification to that list, to the heads of each Federal department or agency determined appropriate under subparagraph (A).</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id9fb49e6c37a6412abe0412ea1ff05a37">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Implementation plan and briefing</header>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f3b594f650648c3be12ab1748c12849">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than June 1, 2027, the Secretary of Defense shall establish and provide to the congressional defense committees a briefing on an implementation plan for carrying out the prohibition under subsection (a).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idba5126535d57427a85e21cbc1860d4ec">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Elements</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The implementation plan required under paragraph (1) shall include—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="id5c38f274130d4f80a6c38f8e6b8bebb9">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>an identification of the lead organization within the Department of Defense responsible for implementing and overseeing the prohibition under subsection (a);</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idd5175e8d811b4e0f8bed20d414e57389">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>a description of the process by which the Department will identify and assess prohibited connected vehicles;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idde14483841c046a69480e506f33182f0">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>a description of the means by which the Department will conduct coordination with appropriate Federal departments and agencies;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id30044403b62240cd93d69604949ac676">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>an identification of the metrics by which the Department will assess connected vehicles for threats to national security;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id28bee63001564e9c89a9399d4cd57c70">
                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>a description of the means by which military installations will ensure compliance with such prohibition; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id37e37795d17a4e1f8e4e517a5291ce81">
                        <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>an assessment of resource requirements necessary to implement and maintain such prohibition.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id6cd227a18cf24c369eb0da9e554f5d55">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Definitions</header>
 <text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="idb15cb06cd4c74ea9a8e4e54de980d595"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Congressional defense committees</header> <text>The term <term>congressional defense committees</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101(a)(16) of title 10, United States Code.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd2b5779fe98d4bc79a7e1903763e68bc">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Connected vehicle</header>
 <text>The term <term>connected vehicle</term> has the meaning given that term in section 791.301 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulations.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddfea47982dfa410e83ccdc83755e9030">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Foreign entity of concern</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>foreign entity of concern</term> has the meaning given that term in section 9901 of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/4651">15 U.S.C. 4651</external-xref>).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id0b50dc506ece4ab7b10e697dd0c60838">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
                    <header>Military installation</header>
 <text>The term <term>military installation</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2801(c) of title 10, United States Code.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

