<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFE375B1372784716981135AA18C09DA9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2878 IH: Daniel J. Harvey, Jr. and Adam Lambert Improving Servicemember Transition to Reduce Veteran Suicide Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2878</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend titles 10 and 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements in the Transition Assistance Program and Solid Start Program to address mental health issues, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAFB53DBFB6BF4369A13023BDC4C2ECFF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2F186696B667421194F9C8EB18DC73B7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Daniel J. Harvey, Jr. and Adam Lambert Improving Servicemember Transition to Reduce Veteran Suicide Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HC1EF6B1AD602487FB58CA416D0D84654"><enum>2.</enum><header>Addressing mental health issues in the Transition Assistance Program of the Department of Defense and the Solid Start Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs</header> <subsection id="HD91AA103C209462396FABB5D5B3165C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transition assistance program of the department of defense</header><text>Section 1142(b) of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H41816AAD93494B95851AE4829E03BF58"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by inserting <quote>(11),</quote> before <quote>and (16)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB26F94135C4645DAA760C9489C789A09"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (11) and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="HAFC28CA92562426BBBACC31AAD95DCE9" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H4F088068A3894A82BC9CF10B02236308"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Information concerning mental health, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HB6BF62F061E044C4A311CF06C3D129E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the availability of mental health services furnished by the Secretary concerned, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, or a non-profit entity;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4FE0B160728D4516B7DE3183A09FDF22"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the treatment of post-traumatic stress disorder, traumatic brain injury, anxiety disorders, depression, chronic pain, sleep disorders, suicidal ideation, or other mental health conditions associated with service in the armed forces;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE23432D7A7F04079A542C0DE881A0924"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the risk of suicide, including signs, symptoms, and risk factors (including adverse childhood experiences, depression, bipolar disorder, homelessness, unemployment, and relationship strain);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF60779F2746A4F38959829E0BA464CF8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the availability of treatment options and resources to address substance abuse, including alcohol, prescription drug, and opioid abuse;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAE42B969A2FD44F68DB280086226E82B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the potential effects of the loss of community and support systems experienced by a member separating from the armed forces;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDFE9D75C16854C7083922EA155885696"><enum>(F)</enum><text>isolation from family, friends, or society; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3304BB50349A47ED80898A9E177A19F9"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the potential stressors associated with separation from the armed forces.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF5C5723125A54892AA82632A52569B1C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Solid start program of the department of veterans affairs</header><text>Section 6320(b)(1) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA7B9CB1F59404646B27190A8CF35968C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (G) and (H) as subparagraphs (I) and (J), respectively; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8C250BD357644EA1B00843890F7FEF46"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (F) the following new subparagraphs:</text> <quoted-block id="HF7011CF4F01A4CE9B7AD39B63D88F973" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H8060F56C198D48C3AE85BA815F496089" indent="up1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>assisting eligible veterans who elect to enroll in the system of patient enrollment under section 1705(a) of this title;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFA72D0B01EC04E47A3B82FE50E4D5355" indent="up1"><enum>(H)</enum><text>educating veterans about mental health and counseling services available through the Veterans Health Administration;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4FC6B5579B5E47028D96BDD5D54C108D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph id="H52391CCD966546AB935C39AF2E6459FC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall jointly submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the information and materials developed pursuant to the amendments made by this Act.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD67FA0B5821D451D99F786A9B9CE0B9E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H68AC08DE64DA41C89C9D7CB0E76F2B58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2B3EBC9328914ED29D2FE1C45CE55467"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

