<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H480E24B274C74A52AA53804405C05553" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2448 IH: To direct the Secretary of Interior to submit to Congress a report on the National Park Service’s interpretation and application of the Standards for Rehabilitation for use of the Federal Historic Preservation Tax Incentives program.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2448</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Interior to submit to Congress a report on the National Park Service’s interpretation and application of the Standards for Rehabilitation for use of the Federal Historic Preservation Tax Incentives program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB87426D6FE3E4F5DAACC1D42D636AB3B" style="OLC"><section id="HA401343343904361B95EBB39097E38A1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Report</header><subsection id="H2403CA2F910847019AFEC12886AF6AE9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit a report on the Service’s interpretation and application of the Secretary’s Standards for Rehabilitation pertaining to use of the Program to—</text><paragraph id="H750480240BC74863A976786530E1FE9A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H192EE85178A04FA88CE7156A11CEF359"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B50F2DA147340F5B770DF590E6FC102"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H0BA19A688150416680F284580151EF42" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data on the processing of Program Applications during the 10 years immediately before the date of the enactment of this Act, including—</text><subparagraph id="H6C032A341BEF4B67A4B51E5D0F1A3F43" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the average time a Program Application is in the system, from the date it is submitted to the State Historic Preservation Office by the applicant until it is approved or denied by the Service, presented by project size, type, and parts 1, 2, and 3 of the Program Application; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H723C243579D8490A903551EBB298A4E4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the annual average number of—</text><clause id="H1AC846A63E8946EFB1D0B8D5659C4DAD" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>hold notices annually;</text></clause><clause id="HDA91B380309B4318B35B1C1A88FE03CF" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>conditions placed on the approval under part 2 of the Program Application;</text></clause><clause id="H08E5D860DB0C4A758E06D2049576B57C" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>denied applications; </text></clause><clause id="HFB5522893FF949BD9D6AE6D794E8FE2B" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>projects approved under part 2 of the Program Application; and</text></clause><clause id="H6052C75ED403445DA21618E8B2040935" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Program Applications withdrawn.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9AC1307FBD54A15AA5EB0B93882A870"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H858930E299BF49F69D8E0453868532DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Areas of improvement to and recommendations for the Standards to remove barriers to the development of affordable housing while safeguarding Federal historic preservation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEAAF5A3312E4A3F8DC7716420E6C4B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Opportunities for the Secretary to update or provide additional guidance to facilitate—</text><clause id="H7AB95ED3BC5442C7950E5A8DF6F0C962"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the conversion of nonresidential buildings into housing;</text></clause><clause id="HAF5ECE1EE45D4C90882BC7E480AC8807"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the remediation of environmental, health, and safety hazards;</text></clause><clause id="H8DF6888986414B5DB852B1182EAC15CB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>inclusion of energy efficient upgrades and integration of sustainability features;</text></clause><clause id="H43238AFF04D84BC4A17E4FBA281386E5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>access for persons with disabilities; and</text></clause><clause id="H8F54E050808E479A8E53E93E5EA1B321"><enum>(v)</enum><text>removal of other barriers to use raised by users and beneficiaries of the Program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA0E5DBBF42748B89D01203DC00B52CC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The specific steps the Service has taken in the 10 years immediately before the date of the enactment of this Act to improve or clarify the interpretation of the Standards to support affordable housing development.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCFBCBD2A003440CA7B637CA958275EB"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The most frequent issues that Program users, State reviewers, and other stakeholders raise when developing affordable housing projects and the steps the Service has taken to address those issues, including details of the process of the Service for soliciting, collecting, and incorporating feedback on the Service interpretation of the Standards.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C571B3D9F9E4CFF8A1DDCB7E023A805"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The process that the Service uses to decide when to update guidance, including guidelines, preservation briefs, bulletins regarding interpretation of the Standards, and tax-incentive guidance, for implementing the Standards and whether resource limitations are affecting the ability of the Service to update such guidance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H03E36768930A4A5D951B6A63D5D74B4D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations of the Secretary regarding updates and improvements that can be made to the Standards and the implementation by the Service of the Standards and accompanying guidelines to—</text><subparagraph id="H2E7A9B0D284845CD96373078EBC043CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make the Program more compatible with affordable housing needs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7C67966A7E64519904C01101B3D3CF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure historic properties are protected from climate risk; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8ED0C47E255446E1B6380065049AE02E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>take into consideration economic and technical feasibility. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCFA3069ACABB4155A8B49A7E812DC62F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H4E582258963241168BC3819EC51ED4F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Program</term> means the Federal Historic Preservation Tax Incentives program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15719EAB50A249CDB8DCE7F1FA3694DA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Program Application</term> means the Historic Preservation Certification Application.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAD36DB62DF7449587E9BE83631C6CDD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8DBD21DC1694E6496DF2B1B1965BBF3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Service</header><text>The term <term>Service</term> means the National Park Service. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AC584DFFD474BF2BC0AAE0A7DBB336F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Standards</term> means the Department of the Interior’s Standards for Rehabilitation for the Federal Historic Preservation Tax Incentives program under part 67 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

