<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6902E60DD5F14363AFBD0F4B3C7DD709" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1795 IH: Neutralizing Emerging Threats from Wireless OEMs Receiving direction from Kleptocracies and Surveillance states Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1795</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250303">March 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001220">Mr. Strong</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions with respect to foreign telecommunications companies engaged in economic or industrial espionage against United States persons, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H68888954591B4C68AB90336989D58019" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H19A4F9B99E7A4D5986BB70A2DC756455" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Neutralizing Emerging Threats from Wireless OEMs Receiving direction from Kleptocracies and Surveillance states Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>NETWORKS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFAB94D6A8EA34C5CB92561D79FEF8870"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text>
<paragraph id="H3E210483E5EF4162BEC625D84DCB9595"><enum>(1)</enum><text>secure telecommunications networks, both domestically and within partner and allied nations, are important to the national security of the United States; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H80F0A90B0B1A4DB2A95F2256C0615E25"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the risks posed by untrusted telecommunications vendors, particularly those based in the People’s Republic of China, to communications, data security, and the viability of networks outweigh any potential benefits; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB06F152C0D4D4EF0B08CD297E4739361"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States Government should use the tools of economic statecraft to promote secure telecommunications networks.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HA9B841E81D0A4C60B89C7F52C72EE0C7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to economic or industrial espionage by foreign telecommunications companies</header> <subsection id="H37E1316383E04550B6A2CE8AFC47578E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On and after the date that is 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall exercise all of the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all significant transactions in property and interests in property of a foreign person described in subsection (b) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HA84FB14254F240E69446E36317AB7330"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Foreign persons described</header><text>A foreign person is described in this subsection if the President determines that the person, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act—</text> <paragraph id="HCF7EBD56D5D84C928BBAE9E18E5E37BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>produces fifth or future generation telecommunications technology; and </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEFA6BDC2102848449B35324F4C0D67F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conducts business relating to such telecommunications technology in a manner contrary to the United States’ national security interests.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H17274F78FDB146DBB87C5D3DADC760D3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header> <paragraph id="H1540529525174A238CA82D2A55E98867"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exception for intelligence activities</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply to any activity subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091 et seq.</external-xref>) or any authorized intelligence activities of the United States.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6A7629A9AD8648A092B36E866039AE8F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception relating to the provision of humanitarian assistance</header><text>Sanctions under this section may not be imposed with respect to transactions or the facilitation of transactions for—</text> <subparagraph id="H854482A7875A4EA8A34C11CD44FBDD41"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the sale of agricultural commodities, food, medicine, or medical devices;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA48A4FF41AA64C158EAC0F6328C5A34B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the provision of humanitarian assistance;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBF93831016264ABB8E9457E6D6464087"><enum>(C)</enum><text>financial transactions relating to humanitarian assistance; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H08D1D489180D4C818C7C344AEB3D7FB4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>transporting goods or services that are necessary to carry out operations relating to humanitarian assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H39B02BD789E64F83AF9B404CE79E5BA7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of sanctions under this section with respect to a foreign person for renewable periods of not more than 90 days each if the President determines and reports to Congress that such a waiver is vital to the national security interests of the United States.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H6196842647444500BFE926904D911C8F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation; penalties</header>
<paragraph id="HE384711055C544A7844144597AEB3955"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise the authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to the extent necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H27F4DB832C11454B978CBF66A085558C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of subsection (a) or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out that subsection shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H70DEF47D22BF412994C21C9E15D5B323"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header>
<paragraph id="H5FBFE00052F847E7A1ABBB539F2006CC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this section:</text> <subparagraph id="HFB8F47F65E3F4E1A9574F491478CB8F7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Fifth or future generation telecommunications technology</header><text>The term <term>fifth or future generation telecommunications technology</term> means telecommunications technology that conforms to the technical standards followed by the telecommunications industry for telecommunications technology that is commonly known in the industry as fifth generation or future generation technology.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H194D99E938F4477AB0FD09E964B5FD41"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means any person that is not a United States person.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H43FFD635E6A04144B6BCE6C268320F35"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Knowingly</header><text>The term <term>knowingly</term>, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person has actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5AC34BF8F67442F084AE9B5256262E2B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means an individual or entity.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB1AA4858BE864F15A5C1CB33ED19988A"><enum>(E)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text>
<clause id="H55EFA01C9F15408A943975B63A1C2B33"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</text></clause> <clause id="HBF598399690D466DA8EEFCC6E71CE167"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0CA4F630D73B43B1B51310BDC092FEE5"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Untrusted telecommunications vendor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term “untrusted telecommunications vendor” has the meaning given to the term “covered communications equipment or service” in section 9 of the Secure and Trusted Communications Network Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1608">47 U.S.C. 1608</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD9705146166D441CB17A0A0C9315DED2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of significance</header><text>For the purposes of this section, in determining if transactions are significant, the President may consider the totality of the facts and circumstances, including factors similar to the factors set forth in section 561.404 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (or any corresponding similar regulation or ruling).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD0FBF607BA0C4FC6A21A21A05A7A87DB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>For purposes of this section, a transaction shall not be construed to include—</text> <subparagraph id="H0ACD18790DED454FBE52B48596C29BE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>participation in an international standards-setting body or the activities of such a body; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8416D1C526F24C59BC8067719AF38479"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a transaction involving existing third or fourth generation telecommunications networks. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

