<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H16C29D3C6E9745BEB9911A77A00F8D70" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5744 IH: Targeting Online Sales of Fentanyl Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5744</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251010">October 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a GAO study on the sale of illicit drugs online, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3FD1A13819A54D5E9C2F4ABB1B53E36C" style="OLC"><section id="H39952F1202504A17A7A66EA3CA21F547" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Targeting Online Sales of Fentanyl Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C6D9856294F4E9AB5AC50470DAEDBC3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">GAO study on the sale of illicit drugs online</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H286F6219FD3841A683D9DB0F132A0294"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the online sale of fentanyl, synthetic opioids, and methamphetamine, including—</text><paragraph id="H85C56A7BC8BD4C39A473C1DF22313C92"><enum>(1)</enum><text>business models employed by online sellers of fentanyl, synthetic opioids, and methamphetamine, including an examination of supply chains, logistics, and strategies utilized for customer acquisition, retention, and communication within illicit online marketplaces;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56743A9622674967BECC29547D16C74B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>utilization of online illicit drug markets and providers (as defined in section 2258E of title 18, United States Code) for facilitating financial transactions in the online sale of fentanyl, synthetic opioids, and methamphetamine, with a particular focus on their impact on individuals who are 18 years of age and younger;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7B331ECF01D4EE0B78AA6CD1D4D0B22"><enum>(3)</enum><text>efforts of the Federal Government to combat the online sale of fentanyl, synthetic opioids, and methamphetamine, including—</text><subparagraph id="H22414A374585421BB0FAF32B55C74AC7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>interagency collaboration, including personnel detailed to other agencies to support efforts to combat the online trafficking of fentanyl, synthetic opioids, and methamphetamine, and related illicit finance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE762D83DCD05431EB7D692409D9E02F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>intergovernmental collaboration between the Federal Government and State, Tribal, local, and foreign governments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C8A9E4FB93D495C8869B4DC84BE9597"><enum>(C)</enum><text>intersectoral collaboration with the private sector, including businesses and non-governmental organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE7018F8FA7A4F6181F76E39261F2AE5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>examination of existing procedures followed by Federal law enforcement agencies in handling cases related to online sales of fentanyl, synthetic opioids, and methamphetamine, encompassing the receipt, investigation, and prosecution processes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7651F679D2F146609BEC3A7E80B319FB"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analysis of aggregated outcomes from the past 10 years to identify patterns and areas for improvement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3BF856C71814AD1A7834C4206D81E0F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>identification of gaps or resource deficiencies in coordinating and collaborating activities described in subparagraphs (A) through (E) to combat the online sale of fentanyl, synthetic opioids, and methamphetamine;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H11ED0AB683594C18999B11FC16037EA5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>models utilized by providers, including machine learning, algorithmic technology, and data analysis techniques, to effectively detect and combat the sale of fentanyl, synthetic opioids, and methamphetamine on their platforms;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CB98927F9924C7BAA8B7238A97C4D4E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>enforcement mechanisms and processes employed by providers to penalize users involved in the sale of fentanyl, synthetic opioids, and methamphetamine, including user identification, verification procedures, and subsequent actions, such as account suspension, reporting to law enforcement agencies, and collaboration with legal proceedings; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5518C14F032940B6BEA1396FECFF4186"><enum>(6)</enum><text>analysis of referrals to the Federal Government by providers detailing information about online sales of fentanyl, synthetic opioids, and methamphetamine, including—</text><subparagraph id="HEADBC0CE28F648ED966B922859F59D12"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of referrals from providers to the Federal Government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC038C13AE5044BF2AA2403631C662020"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of referrals that were investigated by the Federal Government, including the agencies involved in the investigation and the outcome of the investigation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F421307E4FC4662A0D7CD6F459B6FCA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of referrals that resulted in an arrest, prosecution, or conviction, including the offense of the arrest, prosecution, or conviction; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A73585E9C1747EEAD8BE5DCA4DA8254"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of referrals that were shared by the Federal Government with a State, Tribal, or local government, including a law enforcement agency or prosecutor's office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC7E772F654E94D8A8918DBA2892C9F07" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report containing all findings and determinations made in carrying out the study required under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

