<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H45C9C5B32D2E4E699EFF840AE7C30236" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 817 IH: Supporting the designation of October 16, 2025, and October 16, 2026, as “World Food Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 817</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251017">October 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of October 16, 2025, and October 16, 2026, as <quote>World Food Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas hundreds of millions of people around the world are experiencing hunger and malnutrition;</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas an estimated 2,300,000,000 people are estimated to have been moderately or severely food insecure in 2024, an increase of 335,000,000 and a clear example that the number of people affected by hunger continues to grow at an alarming pace;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas women and children suffer the most serious effects of hunger and malnutrition;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas millions of children die each year from hunger-related illness and disease;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas many people suffer permanent physical or mental impairment because of vitamin or protein deficiencies due to malnutrition;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas those in rural areas experience disproportionate levels of hunger;</text></whereas> 
<whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas an estimated 673,000,000 people, or 8.2 percent of the global population, experienced food insecurity in 2024, progress in reducing food insecurity has been inconsistent across the globe, and hunger continues to rise in most subregions of Africa and western Asia;</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the total number of people facing high levels of acute food insecurity nearly tripled between 2016 and 2024, rising from 105,200,000 people in 48 countries to approximately 295,300,000 people in 53 countries and territories;</text></whereas> 
<whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, between 2016 and 2024, the number of people experiencing the most extreme level of food insecurity increased more than tenfold, from 155,000 to almost 2,000,000;</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas intensifying conflict, weather extremes, and other factors have exacerbated an already untenable food insecurity crisis;</text></whereas> 
<whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the Integrated Food Security Phase Classification (IPC) has confirmed 2 famines, noted that 1 country is currently at risk of famine, and identified 3 countries facing catastrophic levels of acute food insecurity that require urgent and immediate action;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the number of people unable to afford a healthy diet remained unacceptably high at 2,600,000,000 globally in 2024;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States has a long tradition of demonstrating humanitarian concern for the hungry and malnourished people of the world;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas there is an ever-increasing concern in the United States and in other countries about threats to the future food supply, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="idc616f96b355b49538d3a88d6ba30f45e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>misuse and overuse of land and water;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id2b1a468a1f3e40ffa6dfac90b7c39698"><enum>(2)</enum><text>loss of biological diversity;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id38de1354b2ef45e0bc15e1f5af298906"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conflict due to scarcity of natural resources;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id914b1401d4ed49e895f2d33b40c8598d"><enum>(4)</enum><text>erosion of genetic resources on a global scale; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idebe20f41c5684ae6b2badad487c28418"><enum>(5)</enum><text>transboundary pests and diseases, such as the Desert Locust for plants and anthrax for livestock;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the world community increasingly and consistently calls upon the United States to resolve food problems stemming from natural- and human-made disasters by providing humanitarian assistance;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States—</text> <paragraph id="idf292fad5f76c47e987a9f7bc8ab91632"><enum>(1)</enum><text>plays a major role in the development and implementation of international food and agricultural trade standards and practices; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id9d64e7685aab495680b2c4c88bb475b5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the positive role that global food trade can play in enhancing human nutrition and alleviating hunger;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, although progress has been made in reducing the rate of hunger and malnutrition in the United States, certain groups remain vulnerable to malnutrition and related diseases and global hunger and malnutrition rates continue to climb;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the conservation of natural resources, the preservation of biological diversity, and strong public and private agricultural research programs are required for the United States to—</text> <paragraph id="ida2a16ac78f7e4f2cb671f24fcd9fb699"><enum>(1)</enum><text>remain food secure;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id53199e0b8000469da2ff7027d60b266d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>continue to aid the hungry and malnourished people of the world;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id347bb9eddf5f4047acce61d39405ee7f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assist in building more resilient global food systems; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idde719984be554c489a2bbe45e9617811"><enum>(4)</enum><text>preserve and sustain our forests, land, oceans, and waterways;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States is a world leader in the development of agricultural innovation and technology aimed at enhancing the improved production, safety, and quality of the world food supply, and must continue to maintain that role;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas emerging and innovative participation by private voluntary organizations and businesses, working with national governments and the international community, is essential in identifying new and more sustainable ways to increase food production in developing countries and improve food distribution to hungry and malnourished people;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas World Food Day was established 80 years ago on October 16, 1945;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas October 16 of each year since has been designated as <quote>World Food Day</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas more than 130 countries have taken part in organized activities and efforts on <quote>World Food Day</quote> to promote awareness of and action for people suffering from hunger and malnutrition;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas past observances of <quote>World Food Day</quote> have been supported—</text> <paragraph id="idb64ce6966eb94a619c4a214229cbf732"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by proclamations by Congress, the President, the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and the territories and possessions of the United States; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id0d8c8bf383824b60b7b04c7e414590a1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by programs of the Department of Agriculture and other Federal departments and agencies;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas private voluntary organizations and community leaders are participating in planning <quote>World Food Day</quote> observances in 2025 and 2026, and a growing number of these organizations and leaders are using <quote>World Food Day</quote> as a focal point for year-round programs; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the people of the United States can express their concern for the plight of hungry and malnourished people throughout the world by study, advocacy, and action: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H4FB243DEB7694A61A374825B898C4075"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H9779CD3AA7E143E890E8B4F1F6917F4D"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0EB0039B1B01445987F97771B97AA0D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>World Food Day</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCED1AC52BE3C49FDB3F807B2D7198CEA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to observe the days with appropriate ceremonies and activities; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H76BF9D2063F8442A83A5EE58C421B60D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirms the commitment of the United States to combating global food insecurity and malnutrition through humanitarian support and innovative approaches.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

