<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H07EAE33D387A47CCA78EDFC69B6E40C8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3513 IH: Supreme Court Ethics, Recusal, and Transparency Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3513</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250520">May 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 28, United States Code, to provide for a code of conduct for justices of the Supreme Court of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H37283DBB1C2C48EA972BFC54D6BC5DCD" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HFBA72286B4884DA789651A4B58A31485" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supreme Court Ethics, Recusal, and Transparency Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2BE55F82B4AB4D81889EA278F1746898" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Code of conduct for the Supreme Court of the United States</header> <subsection id="HEA0A27B7228D433A8C1077560D0674EF" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/16">Chapter 16</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA866476CD9A84C74ACC4A050240054C5" changed="not-changed"> 
<section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H12E49D9AB4114C5590D53D8B65D7A659" changed="not-changed"><enum>365.</enum><header>Codes of conduct</header> 
<subsection id="H468A534BEE2340DDBAC41D4FF65E4962" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Justices</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Supreme Court of the United States shall, after appropriate public notice and opportunity for comment in accordance with section 2071, issue a code of conduct for the justices of the Supreme Court.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5472CF2E25ED455C87938C3B13FC444B" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other judges</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Judicial Conference of the United States shall, after appropriate public notice and opportunity for comment in accordance with section 2071, issue a code of conduct for the judges of the courts of appeals, the district courts (including bankruptcy judges and magistrate judges), and the Court of International Trade.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF558F0933E9E49918DD1606E351776D6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Modification</header><text>The Supreme Court of the United States and the Judicial Conference may modify the applicable codes of conduct under this section after giving appropriate public notice and opportunity for comment in accordance with section 2071.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HCA80C8D545584567BD524C9C98CC1716" changed="not-changed"><enum>366.</enum><header>Public access to ethics rules</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Supreme Court of the United States shall make available on its internet website, in a full-text, searchable, sortable, and downloadable format, copies of the code of conduct issued under section 365(a), any rules established by the Counselor to the Chief Justice of the United States under section 677 and any other related rules or resolutions, as determined by the Chief Justice of the United States, issued by the Counselor to the Chief Justice of the United States or agreed to by the justices of the Supreme Court.</text></section> 
<section section-type="subsequent-section" id="HE3000868FFC44ED3AE45F5A0083EB2D9" changed="not-changed"><enum>367.</enum><header>Complaints against justices</header> 
<subsection id="HFC37F979AE4A4E2F9B6A2D4868144AD2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Receipt of complaints</header> 
<paragraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H06198DE0BCA44F72B04CAE4B6C9360D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Supreme Court of the United States shall establish procedures, modeled after the procedures set forth in sections 351 through 364, under which individuals may file with the Court, or the Court may identify, complaints alleging that a justice of the Supreme Court—</text> <subparagraph id="H9765AE8BDDF64437B4A754695C66F733" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has violated—</text> 
<clause id="HA7DA8E65DC964A24ACE50FA193E3A8EE" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the code of conduct issued pursuant to section 365(a);</text></clause> <clause id="H942628974BE24D57A5F22A9368609431" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>section 455; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0707187EB2954DA0A45A967B276D5645" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other applicable provision of Federal law; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCA729F6D2D0C4A6E9EBC17A71E872CB1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has otherwise engaged in conduct that undermines the integrity of the Supreme Court.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB39434F952D4069BDDF3639555BA3A0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>Procedures established under this subsection shall, at minimum, contain provisions—</text> <subparagraph id="H45D86B2CA6874896A1BD2019B94ED8B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>requiring that all complaints submitted under this section contain—</text> 
<clause id="H77DD6842848A4178ADBFF84C0DC85E11"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the signature and contact address of the complainant;</text></clause> <clause id="H79F9739A54DF48A9A62FBFFB33E8DDA4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a concise statement of the specific facts on which the claim of misconduct is based; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD5835BF146604EC8A427A27C6BD1F91E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a sworn affirmation that to the best of the knowledge and belief of the complainant, under penalty of perjury, the facts alleged in the complaint are true and form a reasonable basis to believe a justice has committed misconduct under this section; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB11D83E109D04DC3A222DD693B18BD95"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing for the restriction on the future filing of complaints with respect to complainants who are shown to have filed repetitive, harassing, or frivolous complaints, or have otherwise abused the complaint procedure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6F5F2561A6B34676A2A926B8CA491997" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Judicial investigation panel</header> 
<paragraph id="H3F3330FE954247AEA4B8231DBF36AC3C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon receipt or identification of a complaint under subsection (a), the Supreme Court of the United States shall refer such complaint to a judicial investigation panel, which shall be composed of a panel of 5 judges selected randomly from among the chief judge of each circuit of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC956F995B39E4C688F554CFBE6B105B3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The judicial investigation panel—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB4A4CFC9B6A44E6EAC04BEE136D075FF" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall review and, if appropriate as determined by the panel, investigate all complaints submitted to the panel using procedures established by the panel and modeled after the procedures set forth in sections 351 through 364;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H40D6EBF5AF8A4A7485B7E02232B493F0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall present to the Supreme Court of the United States any findings and recommendations for necessary and appropriate action by the Supreme Court, including dismissal of the complaint, disciplinary actions, or changes to Supreme Court rules or procedures;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0EBE385980AB4C059732BE0A1D262B66" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if the panel does not recommend dismissal of the complaint, not later than 30 days following the presentation of any findings and recommendations under this paragraph, shall publish a report containing such findings and recommendations; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB70090B04C8E47E38AA207991D9BB001" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>if the panel recommends dismissal of the complaint, may publish any findings and recommendations if the panel determines that such publication would be in furtherance of the public interest.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D6A53B43534488D831B476C5EF3810C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Powers</header><text>In conducting any investigation under this section, the judicial investigation panel may hold hearings, take sworn testimony, issue subpoenas ad testificandum and subpoenas duces tecum, and make necessary and appropriate orders in the exercise of its authority.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85646EFC618A4976A985A5932C0BAD3A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Access</header><text>If the judicial investigation panel determines that a substantially similar complaint was previously submitted under section 351, but that such substantially similar complaint was dismissed for lack of authority to review or act upon such complaint, the panel shall have access to any information gathered pursuant to this chapter in relation to such substantially similar complaint.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H444E9084A5304E2090D7E40F031D4D7D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The judicial investigation panel may appoint and fix the compensation of such staff as it deems necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HF5931CE4722240259766CB3C7782D2E3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/16">chapter 16</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H9D0F580674F54D5992601DF92CF7993A" changed="not-changed"> 
<toc changed="not-changed"> 
<toc-entry level="section" changed="not-changed">365. Codes of conduct.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" changed="not-changed">366. Public access to ethics rules.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" changed="not-changed">367. Complaints against justices.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="HDAF48BE975BD4DEBA12D3D90D1FA6B81" changed="not-changed"><enum>3.</enum><header>Minimum gift and disclosure standards for justices of the Supreme Court</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 677 of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2EC889A34B7347E3BBD1781129FBCD8C" changed="not-changed"> <subsection id="HA8F2B39F587A4128A67CE4ACDC8EC128" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><text>The Counselor, with the approval of the Chief Justice, shall establish rules governing the acceptance of gifts and the disclosure of all gifts, income, or reimbursements, as those terms are defined in section 13101 of title 5, received by any justice and any law clerk to a justice. Such rules shall, at minimum, require disclosure of any information concerning gifts, income, and reimbursements required to be disclosed under the Standing Rules of the Senate and the Rules of the House of Representatives, and restrict the acceptance of gifts, and require processes for written approval of certain gifts, to the same extent as restricted or required under the Standing Rules of the Senate and the Rules of the House of Representatives.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HF76AD2490DE046C5AD33C65290163B74" changed="not-changed"><enum>4.</enum><header>Circumstances requiring disqualification</header> 
<subsection id="HCCBD619AD59F4E5395326E01C9C99DBB" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Anticorruption protections</header><text>Subsection (b) of section 455 of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H270FCF411A7348B1AE6ABC665C0BF65B" changed="not-changed"> <paragraph id="H17019DB833EA4606A84801E502D2A21A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Where the justice or judge knows that a party to the proceeding or an affiliate of a party to the proceeding made any lobbying contact, as defined in section 3 of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1602">2 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>), or spent substantial funds in support of the nomination, confirmation, or appointment of the justice or judge.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H56189EBA29FD418296262CD3E1B99521" changed="not-changed"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Where the justice or judge, their spouse, their minor child, or a privately held entity owned by any such person received income, a gift, or reimbursement, as those terms are defined in section 13101 of title 5—</text> <subparagraph id="H2C5193FCFC9B414091A529AA0E23E11A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>from a party to the proceeding or an affiliate of a party to the proceeding; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H98083BC244914BD98FB0DB130401DF3E" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>during the period beginning on the date that is 6 years before the date on which the justice or judge was assigned to the proceeding and ending on the date of final disposition of the proceeding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H18CA027CD87B4FCB941E6DE4FF17350B" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duty To know</header><text>Subsection (c) of section 455 of title 28, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E8173CF885843A3BA94779FD078A783" changed="not-changed"> 
<subsection id="H6891FE2918804FFF9D76FAADFA62E3CD" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><text>A justice, judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge of the United States shall ascertain—</text> <paragraph id="H3B6AFDF5B7044A72BAEE369B0CC69C57" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the personal and fiduciary financial interests of the justice or judge;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H57ACA91A3B374C3DAB6395C28D7EFC20" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the personal financial interests of the spouse and minor children residing in the household of the justice or judge; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF6C0894275E457FB22E49DE092A462C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any interest of the persons described in paragraph (2) that could be substantially affected by the outcome of the proceeding.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFE9358B7F5FF44B582B6C3FBEB7652FF" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Divestment</header><text>Subsection (f) of section 455 of title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>under subsection (b)(4)</quote> after <quote>disqualified</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2F083C042CC84B14AAA666A0CBED9E42" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duty To notify</header><text>Section 455 of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB4E2428E0A704FB7BFA4692FED60F82E" changed="not-changed"> 
<subsection id="HA688411105A9497380EC949903270070" changed="not-changed"><enum>(g)</enum><text>If at any time a justice, judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge of the United States learns of a condition that could reasonably require disqualification under this section, the justice or judge shall immediately notify all parties to the proceeding.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HAA364F620AEE4B3E94D9CC6316E9957A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text>Section 455 of title 28, United States Code, as amended by this section, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H188339B43D98419988FD23280AE87695" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">judge, or magistrate judge</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9CED20039E7486E88661B4E3C02F79C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>judge, or magistrate judge</quote> and inserting <quote>judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5954E575F9014E1AB639D009382A3CB4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="H4681EFEAA72B40FE81833A94810AC555" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>the judge or such lawyer</quote> and inserting <quote>the justice, the judge, or such lawyer</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC9CD978A54BF486C8C9FA0ED5FCE123C" changed="not-changed" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)(iii), by inserting <quote>justice or</quote> before <quote>judge</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3310249752814E729B9A373961A8EE60" changed="not-changed" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)(iv), by inserting <quote>justice’s or</quote> before <quote>judge’s</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAB05636265BF4F6F96D46B93864D86AF" changed="not-changed" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(4)(i), by inserting <quote>justice or</quote> before <quote>judge</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A4C024BA02643438FACDACA08CF2252" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by striking <quote>judge, or magistrate judge</quote> and inserting <quote>judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge of the United States</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1B09B77AA0AE41608960DDCAD98EF519" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Public notice</header><text>The rules of each court subject to section 455 of title 28, United States Code, as amended by this section, shall be amended to require that the clerk shall publish timely notice on the website of the court of—</text> <paragraph id="HDDD80DE19EF94495BE58C1693212B4F5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any matter in which a justice, judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge of the United States is disqualified under such section;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD2F31C5878E4AA6AEC6D8B0B2F77362" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any matter in which the reviewing panel under section 1660 of title 28, United States Code, as added by section 5 of this Act, rules on a motion to disqualify; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4AA1380F1075476DAC085125D95257AD" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an explanation of each reason for the disqualification or ruling, which shall include a specific identification of each circumstance that resulted in such disqualification or ruling, but which shall not include any private or sensitive information deemed by a majority of the reviewing panel under section 1660 of title 28, United States Code, as added by section 5 of this Act, to be appropriate for redaction and unnecessary in order to provide the litigants and public a full understanding of the reasons for the disqualification or ruling.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H2F89F0E70DD94FEDB8E69B8112837B2A" changed="not-changed"><enum>5.</enum><header>Review of certified disqualification motions</header> 
<subsection id="H5AC0B528569B49D999DE956A2BE7A606" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/111">Chapter 111</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF6734B33C32742EA937A8163B7A056BE" changed="not-changed"> <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H3E117D00015A4146B6B6DBFE9BC399F7" changed="not-changed"><enum>1660.</enum><header>Review of certified motions to disqualify</header> <subsection id="H75BB87DCFB154B1486F83EE7D4738522" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Motion for disqualification</header><text>If a justice, judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge of the United States is required to be disqualified from a proceeding under any provision of Federal law, a party to the proceeding may file a timely motion for disqualification, accompanied by a certificate of good faith and an affidavit alleging facts sufficient to show that disqualification of the justice, judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge is so required.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6EC8F2B91B714C41823E3A7C77973B04" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consideration of motion</header><text>A justice, judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge of the United States shall either grant or certify to a reviewing panel a timely motion filed pursuant to subsection (a) and stay the proceeding until a final determination is made with respect to the motion.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H61F24F9F156540BBBD2568CD8AFF8698" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reviewing panel</header> <paragraph id="HE890688EDFF040D7AFBA5F90F89580B4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A reviewing panel to which a motion is certified under subsection (b) with respect to a judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge of the United States shall be composed of 3 judges selected at random from judges of the United States who do not sit on the same court—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6A83C820EF374D8D84D8C3479B859161" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as the judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge who is the subject of the motion; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4D9F18A5630E4DF5BB27D8667687915A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as the other members of the reviewing panel.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF8BA1D3DC1BF4881A0BC9973095DE4A9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Circuit limitation</header><text>Not more than 1 member of the reviewing panel may be a judge of the same judicial circuit as the judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge who is the subject of the motion.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H816204D4D06A4A24B86317B823ED31D9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Participation</header><text>The reviewing panel, prior to its final determination with respect to a motion filed under subsection (a), shall provide the judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge of the United States who is the subject of such motion an opportunity to provide in writing the views of the judge on the motion, including the explanation of the judge for not granting the motion.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8E3B96C94F524381A8661882C16D8568" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Supreme Court review</header><text>The Supreme Court of the United States, not including the justice who is the subject of a motion seeking to disqualify a justice under subsection (a), shall be the reviewing panel for such motions.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H2797C772204149889D7F160D15305D4A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/111">chapter 111</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H8E13071272704D8AABB31A3DA03DD481" changed="not-changed"> 
<toc changed="not-changed"> 
<toc-entry level="section" changed="not-changed">1660. Review of certified motions to disqualify.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD33946D5F4B1488D850E5BC944FC8670" changed="not-changed"><enum>6.</enum><header>Disclosure by parties and amici</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Supreme Court of the United States shall prescribe rules of procedure in accordance with sections 2072 through 2074 of title 28, United States Code, requiring each party or amicus to list in the petition or brief of the party or amicus, as applicable, a description and value of—</text> <paragraph id="HEA6202C72F4F482FA3869DA4F2C62A23" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any gift, income, or reimbursement, as those terms are defined in section 13101 of title 5, United States Code, provided to any justice, during the period beginning 2 years prior to the commencement of the proceeding and ending on the date of final disposition of the proceeding, by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF912013171314004AAF236CBBC7B7099" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each such party, amicus, or affiliate of each such party or amicus;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCCFEE686A6684514BBE9F185B9A49923" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the lawyers or law firms in the proceeding of each such party or amicus; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD1533135ED194753B6159CD3D32FA00D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the officers, directors, or employees of each such party or amicus; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E917C1ACA2A4952B2C351973A0F3CD3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any lobbying contact or expenditure of substantial funds by any person described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of paragraph (1) in support of the nomination, confirmation, or appointment of a justice.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H94D7CCCC95604ECDAA31F12BEF7B9B36" changed="not-changed"><enum>7.</enum><header>Amicus disclosure</header> 
<subsection id="H8DB0656583764FD7A65F29AFF087BA80" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/111">Chapter 111</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, as amended by section 5, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5250CBAC1704086911F77D2363CF9FD" changed="not-changed"> <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H38AE153A89EE4BF38A75C50C090F70D1" changed="not-changed"><enum>1661.</enum><header>Disclosures related to amicus activities</header> <subsection id="H31DA05D69C874C6BA47ABE7D59CE2D3D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disclosure</header> <paragraph id="H991C61A734FD4EADBB9A8A8B326E6114" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any person that files an amicus brief in a court of the United States shall list in the amicus brief the name of any person who—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0EA26B013CB74FBB8ED58F5EF9C26FCC" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>contributed to the preparation or submission of the amicus brief;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB7C3EF18D0344CC0B6FF7497A9299F69" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>contributed not less than 3 percent of the gross annual revenue of the amicus, or an affiliate of the amicus, for the previous calendar year if the amicus is not an individual; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF6231B6A4A214A199CA1BCF8C346E548" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>contributed more than $100,000 to the amicus, or an affiliate of the amicus, in the previous calendar year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9F2519BACAFF4C4AA4CB9AE74ABEE0EA" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The requirements of this subsection shall not apply to amounts received in commercial transactions in the ordinary course of any trade or business by the amicus, or an affiliate of the amicus, or in the form of investments (other than investments by the principal shareholder in a limited liability corporation) in an organization if the amounts are unrelated to the amicus filing activities of the amicus.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H607B25A242234129BCD26B0EB1179265" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Audit</header><text>The Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall conduct an annual audit to ensure compliance with this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H4585107DFA62411CAC6CB49047583AF2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/111">chapter 111</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, as amended by section 5, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H095FAFB0F72443C2BB4D547FE30EC01E" changed="not-changed"> 
<toc changed="not-changed"> 
<toc-entry level="section" changed="not-changed">1661. Disclosures related to amicus activities.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6C263AA633864994A0371320B1224D00" changed="not-changed"><enum>8.</enum><header>Conflicts related to amici curiae</header> 
<subsection id="HBA2DB2E568304843B650265FCD0FE029" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), the Supreme Court of the United States and the Judicial Conference of the United States shall prescribe rules of procedure in accordance with sections 2072 through 2074 of title 28, United States Code, for prohibiting the filing of or striking an amicus brief that would result in the disqualification of a justice, judge, or magistrate judge.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H770C038EC479419398CD20185E3019E8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initial transmittal</header><text>The Supreme Court of the United States shall transmit to Congress—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA6CDE92C235245AC9A94143FBEFADFE8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the proposed rules required under subsection (a) not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF34B019E8E7242DA988F97436C596525" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any rules in addition to those transmitted under paragraph (1) pursuant to section 2074 of title 28, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD73F8C8318C44C2EA04CB982DBDB6BA2" changed="not-changed"><enum>9.</enum><header>Studies and reports</header> 
<subsection id="HC6540BA5F3484670AC07A14179777D5D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Studies</header> 
<paragraph id="H8ED7FFC28EE74BA1AD086F442FAECD55" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and not later than December 1 of every other year thereafter, the Director of the Federal Judicial Center shall—</text> <subparagraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC8A4531F87814797A1DAE0AB8152903D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct a study on the extent of compliance or noncompliance with the requirements of sections 144 and 455 of title 28, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8BA7AAE002042589807E09B2FAD58E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit to Congress the results of the study required under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC63F9743DA7849A99A26DD90ABF52F07" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional time</header><text>With respect to the first such study required to be submitted under paragraph (1), the requirements of that paragraph may be implemented after the date described in that paragraph if the Director of the Federal Judicial Center identifies in writing to the relevant committees of Congress the additional time needed for submission of the study.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAEBB8C2D2833431C87A66B47F4CDEFD6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Facilitation of studies</header><text>The Director of the Federal Judicial Center shall maintain a record of each instance in which—</text> <subparagraph id="H0C41C39157084304A15412AC1B526F17" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a justice, judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge of the United States was not assigned to a case due to potential or actual conflicts; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H677F697E7ECB44E19D8DF65B6BB5BA31" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a justice, judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge of the United States disqualifies themselves after a case assignment is made.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3C0B7296869A4F6C8A96E665C3758646" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than April 1 of each year following the completion of the study required under subsection (a), the Director of the Federal Judicial Center shall submit to Congress a report containing the findings of the study and any recommendations to improve compliance with sections 144 and 455 of title 28, United States Code.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H43A3A461A70D48DBA0FE2D5C614C1D0F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GAO review</header> 
<paragraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0FD43EF24CB4C50BDBA3C08CE7B06AC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the report is submitted under subsection (b), if determined appropriate by the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate or the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, after consultation with the Comptroller General of the United States, and every 5 years thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report containing—</text> <subparagraph id="H6697B084899445CF815FBF83ADA4CDD2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an review of the methodology and findings of the study required under subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2A37BFC31488477CA9758966FAD75408" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a review of the methodology and findings of the audit required under section 1661 of title 28, United States Code, as added by section 7 of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEFA1509C16224D9BBBBD369C63879DA5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Access</header><text>For purposes of conducting the reviews required under paragraph (1), and consistent with section 715 of title 31, United States Code, the Comptroller General of the United States is authorized to obtain such records of the Federal Judicial Center and the Administrative Office of the United States Courts as the Comptroller requires, including those records relating to the Supreme Court of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

