<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5E6F5225564343309DF5057F9A345EB4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1282 IH: Eliminate DEI in Colleges Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1282</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250213">February 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001307">Mr. Baird</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit Federal funding for institutions of higher education that carry out diversity, equity, and inclusion initiatives, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HECFBC3AB5532453A880E74F9958297EC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HED8BC3B8B6684320BD039EE50A31AFEB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Eliminate DEI in Colleges Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H86923049FCA1414187432C002A005823"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on Federal funding for institutions of higher education that carry out diversity, equity, and inclusion initiatives</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title I of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1011">20 U.S.C. 1011 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB33917FC41B246D5ABEBEE2DF96AF1E5" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<section id="HB010C46EF52F442B9C108EDE21E72596"><enum>124.</enum><header>Prohibition on diversity, equity, and inclusion initiatives</header>
<subsection id="HB629AF9BA76149C7AC2AABE5306E2F18"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Restriction on eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no institution of higher education shall be eligible to receive funds or any other form of financial assistance under any Federal program, including participation in any federally funded or guaranteed student loan program, unless the institution certifies to the Secretary that the institution—</text> <paragraph id="H7B1F2C284B624017A63233A8DBA0ED74"><enum>(1)</enum><text>does not and will not carry out any program, project, initiative, or other activity the primary purpose of which is to advocate, promote, or otherwise support diversity, equity, and inclusion; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7E5C578661C94CB8BD022932F03CC322"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not and will not maintain any office or other entity within the institution to advocate, promote, or otherwise support diversity, equity, and inclusion.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9FD165116E9449F697FC19912607EFFD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each institution of higher education that provides the certification required by subsection (a) shall, upon request, make available to the Secretary any information needed by the Secretary to verify the truth and accuracy of the certification.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H3DCD7882CD55425C88299B86EC66EF86"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall publish regulations to implement and enforce the provisions of this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H329F4F01B6DA42D2ABB4261B4C0D06AD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appeals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon determination by the Secretary to terminate financial assistance to any institution of higher education under this section, the institution may file an appeal with an administrative law judge before the expiration of the 30-day period beginning on the date such institution is notified of the decision to terminate financial assistance under this section. Such judge shall hold a hearing with respect to such termination of assistance before the expiration of the 45-day period beginning on the date that such appeal is filed. Such judge may extend such 45-day period upon a motion by the institution concerned. The decision of the judge with respect to such termination shall be considered to be a final agency action.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H0CADD3ADA7A54A739FA92E54A81863F5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>diversity, equity, and inclusion</quote> means the concept according to which individuals are—</text> <paragraph id="HAF7C539E5D5E4ABAB89E25405E600FC1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>classified on basis of race, color, sex, national origin, gender identity, or sexual orientation; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H647408094CE44DFA8D2CFAEDE153E9B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>afforded differential or preferential treatment basis of such classification.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

