<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H6358CDE427AA4C9E8598DC9FC8398CFD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1474 RH: International Nuclear Energy Financing Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 13</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1474</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–23]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250221">February 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill of Arkansas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250321">March 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250321">March 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on February 21, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for advocation of support for nuclear energy, and establish a nuclear energy assistance trust fund, at the World Bank, the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development, and other international financial institutions, as appropriate, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HBA00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H43AAB371B761409280F60A6DE1D8AB44"><section id="HFB140178E038492D968F675E590BB1B2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>International Nuclear Energy Financing Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H635F49C3361D4F57A801123F8AD9568B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H02C38A9F15A64215B70B8800093484A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Nuclear power is an emissions-free energy source that produces approximately 30 percent of the world’s low-carbon electricity. In 2021, 33 countries operated nuclear power plants.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF426C1E0F0C84819B0B3226F452E8A8F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The People’s Republic of China and the Russian Federation have sought to export nuclear reactors to Europe, Eurasia, Latin America, Africa, and South Asia. According to a 2017 study by Columbia University’s Center on Global Energy Policy, Chinese and Russian nuclear reactors are associated with higher safety risk than Western nuclear reactors. In addition, financial and operational support for nuclear power can extend over decades, allowing Beijing and Moscow to secure long-term influence in both advanced and developing economies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H328D9AEC2C5A4CE08560D5DD1CB74670"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Russian Federation is currently building 21 reactors outside its borders, while the People’s Republic of China is assembling more than a third of reactors under construction globally. According to research published in Nature Energy in February 2023, when the Russian Federation launched its invasion of Ukraine in 2022, Russian state-owned nuclear operator Rosatom <quote>boasted as many as 73 different projects in 29 countries. The projects were at very different stages of development from power plants in operation; through construction of reactors ongoing, contracted, ordered or planned; to involvement in tenders, invitations to partnerships or officially published proposals. On top of that, Russian companies have bilateral agreements or memoranda of understanding (MoUs) with 13 countries for services or general joint development of nuclear energy.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB787C690B2DC4D8490A61B09AEDFABC8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In its report, <quote>International Status and Prospects for Nuclear Power 2021</quote>, the International Atomic Energy Agency wrote, <quote>A total of 28 countries have expressed interest in nuclear power and are considering, planning or actively working to include it into their energy mix. Another 24 Member States participate in the Agency’s nuclear infrastructure related activities or are involved in energy planning projects through the technical cooperation programme. Ten to twelve embarking Member States plan to operate NPPs [nuclear power plants] by 2030–2035, representing a potential increase of nearly 30% in the number of operating countries. Several embarking countries have also expressed interest in SMRs [small modular reactors] technology, in particular Estonia, Ghana, Jordan, Kenya, Poland, Saudi Arabia and Sudan, as well as expanding countries such as South Africa.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEEB2896ADD94CC4BB9F017E7D283797"><enum>(5)</enum><text>On December 2, 2023, the United States, alongside more than 20 other countries, pledged to triple nuclear energy capacity by 2050 and support the financing of nuclear energy through the World Bank and regional development banks, so as to <quote>encourage the inclusion of nuclear energy in their organizations’ energy lending policies as needed, and to actively support nuclear power when they have such a mandate</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HA443484563AC47FBAF3621CA17BF93FF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Multilateral development bank support for nuclear energy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title XV of the International Financial Institutions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/262o">22 U.S.C. 262o et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD9CAED00A17A454D891B526394284DFD" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00"><section id="H5C6CD8C99FA548B1821D8CD4C0220AAC"><enum>1506.</enum><header>Multilateral development bank support for nuclear energy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Director at the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development, and, as the Secretary finds appropriate, any other multilateral development bank (as defined in section 1307(g)) to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States to advocate for—</text><paragraph id="H6C546906BEFA4EA9A031860BC54A54EE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the removal of prohibitions at the respective bank against financial and technical assistance for the generation and distribution of nuclear energy, to the extent that the prohibitions apply to nuclear technologies that meet or exceed the quality standards prevalent in the United States or a country allied with the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E56869F2CAA4F85AE80C376FF273F44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increased internal capacity-building at the respective bank for the purpose of assessing—</text><subparagraph id="H2CCF8EF551AB47DEB5201095CF2DA9F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the potential role of nuclear energy in the energy systems of client countries; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8DEDD29CC6C494999A2B1B479C5AF64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the delivery of financial and technical assistance described in paragraph (1) to the countries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H27A579AE53264F95A576C7C6B25686DB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of nuclear energy assistance trust funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title XV of the International Financial Institutions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/262o">22 U.S.C. 262o et seq.</external-xref>) is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HF11B8F5FD5C946DD9C0FFCDAB461ED87" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00"><section id="HBD28D6110BE847E9934FB59907C914F0"><enum>1507.</enum><header>Establishment of nuclear energy assistance trust funds</header><subsection id="HD2831F9329C74B1BA1FE1179EBD8C0EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Governors of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development, and, as the Secretary deems appropriate, other international financial institutions (as defined in section 1701(c)(2)) to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States to establish at each such institution a trust fund to be known as the <quote>Nuclear Energy Assistance Trust Fund</quote> that meets the requirements of subsections (b) and (c) of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8C643B1DBDEF4FC78FB4483345A9DEE3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of such a trust fund shall be the following:</text><paragraph id="HC0255607BAA1449CB7EFE190BEBC132C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To provide financial and technical assistance to support the generation and distribution of nuclear energy in borrowing countries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AB501EB112841F89A5518702D6E84B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To ensure that the international financial institution makes financing available on competitive terms, including for the purpose of countering credit extended by the government of a country that is not a member of the OECD Arrangement on Officially Supported Export Credits.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA60CDD225D8842C3B58FBB231B48B164"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To exclusively support the adoption of nuclear energy technologies that meet or exceed the quality standards prevalent in the United States or a country allied with the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H459F41C849254B1189D17C54776E5A15"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To strengthen the capacity of the international financial institution to assess, implement, and evaluate nuclear energy projects.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3697B397107348E592B1B209868F7F29"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of trust fund revenues</header><text>The revenues of such a trust fund shall be made available for activities for the purposes described in subsection (b), or the United States share of the revenues shall be remitted to the general fund of the Treasury, as the Secretary finds appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEB203CEBC875406FAC71B7242ED009D1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of interpretation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall not be interpreted to affect the ability of the United States Governor of, or the United States Executive Director at, an international financial institution (as so defined) to encourage the provision of financial or technical assistance from non-trust fund resources of the institution to support the generation or distribution of nuclear energy. </text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H79E7F6557DFE4E90845F2513800A7DE6"><enum>5.</enum><header>Inclusion in annual report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">During the 7-year period that begins with the date of enactment of this Act, the Chairman of the National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Policies shall include in the annual report required by section 1701 of the International Financial Institutions Act a description of any progress made—</text><paragraph id="H8A3513138A064977A53EC559AFBFE3FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to promote multilateral development bank (as defined in such section) assistance for nuclear energy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H193997BE4F514694B5020F190ADF9636"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to establish a trust fund pursuant to section 1507 of such Act or, as the case may be, a summary of the activities of any such trust fund.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HDD86508C81E349E0815D05115C9AE1B7"><enum>6.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall have no force or effect beginning 10 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20250321">March 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

