<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0026C0D470E34B498570420EA5CD42FD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5251 IH: To provide for the public diplomacy authorities of the Department of State, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5251</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the public diplomacy authorities of the Department of State, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC135A102C3064F50A2EA5C8393BC057D" style="OLC"> 
<title id="H973B9740E00649489505561AB8863B49"><enum>VII</enum><header>Public diplomacy</header> 
<subtitle id="H8CC85E4BA40D45C09DF6052DF5E599A0"><enum>A</enum><header>Under Secretary for Public Diplomacy</header> 
<section id="HC0A03A004133433C85F1416E55A8C3D0"><enum>701.</enum><header>Under Secretary for Public Diplomacy</header> 
<subsection id="H2BE1EC3144E4436BBE7AC33B6F00BDA3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There shall be in the Department an Under Secretary for Public Diplomacy who shall be responsible to the Secretary of State for matters pertaining to global public diplomacy, information operations targeting foreign audiences, strategic communications and information, international educational and cultural exchange programs, and such other duties as the Secretary may from time to time designate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H162473FE447741C7BFF76D4C6823FAB9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the responsibilities described under subsection (a), the Under Secretary for Public Diplomacy shall oversee and coordinate all matters pertaining to global public diplomacy and foreign information operations, including, as appropriate—</text> 
<paragraph id="H19629491C527424E95DE59A24CEB05AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">leading and directing all information and public diplomacy activities targeted at foreign audiences, communicating United States policy to foreign audiences, documenting and exposing the malign actions of foreign adversaries, ensuring global access to free information, and countering foreign censorship;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H32551A0EE4214F8EB52C2AACF64825F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preparing and leading implementation of an annual strategic plan for public diplomacy in collaboration with regional and functional bureaus and overseas posts and in consultation with relevant national security agencies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68909159509148B0A66A7F8C31265222"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensuring public diplomacy programs are assessed using effective and appropriate evaluation methods;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H482DDDBA14D5433EA6553940E3FEEBFD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>overseeing and directing Department personnel in the United States and abroad who conduct or implement public diplomacy policies, programs, and activities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H923D92D3AADC41A0AD926AF8F121D611" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assisting United States-funded media to present the policies of the United States clearly and effectively;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3611DD6B0B24418394EB3B00C003E638" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>submitting statements of United States policy and editorial material to the United States-funded media;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H723A854024204AE8ACDBFD24C2E639D2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>allocating and managing the financial and human resources for all public diplomacy functions within the Department of State, including for—</text> <subparagraph id="HEF177747F1D5446F98BA97CD24307F22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4436CD218F9641FBAF09462EB5EACFDE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Bureau of Strategic Communications; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA7838143A8594D27A9F16CAEB0D69B07"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the public diplomacy functions within the regional and functional bureaus;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC39B9EFF7F074554A2ECC42536E37B09"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing and overseeing a regional public diplomacy team for each region, each of which shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H33CD311E8BAC4F40AC7E4E5F1D71F023"><enum>(A)</enum><text>integrate all public diplomacy programming and operations of the Department;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1C5AC87FE7764474BD877B85EF36FD0C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>implement such programming and operations in the region of such team; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9B6DFEA919534A77B32BAFF4651514F8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be responsible for—</text> 
<clause id="H30BC88ECDAF048F1AA96B12F3D0947D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>operationalizing the Department’s public diplomacy strategy in the region of such team;</text></clause> <clause id="H0161579C8B60431F922C729A0444D81D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>enabling region-specific execution of such strategy; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3979857894EB43E0929D7A735E6701F8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>maintaining coherence with a unified United States strategy and overarching global objectives of the Department;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D99852170184CAD8304A7A16982C923"><enum>(9)</enum><text>serving as Chair of interagency meetings on public diplomacy to align messaging across the Department of Defense, Department of State, Department of Commerce, Department of the Treasury, the intelligence community, and members of the Group of Seven; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAA1F3962D303496A9847DCF29F0379BC"><enum>(10)</enum><text>performing such other duties as the Secretary may from time to time designate.</text></paragraph> </subsection></section> <section id="HEA47F32BB9974132B103703147161763" section-type="section-one"><enum>702.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations for public diplomacy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Of the funds authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of State under section 141, the Under Secretary for Public Diplomacy shall receive the funds necessary to fulfill missions and responsibilities for fiscal years 2026 and 2027.</text></section></subtitle> 
<subtitle id="H1E3B4E60D9354E3FB9ED0D2175D0ED22"><enum>B</enum><header>Educational and Cultural Affairs</header> 
<section id="H2B0213FFFADC44A79453F3EC3732A8CC"><enum>711.</enum><header>Assistant Secretary for Educational and Cultural Affairs</header> 
<subsection id="H68F2354951FC4B949BD00E2E42210A8B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There shall be in the Department an Assistant Secretary for Educational and Cultural Affairs who shall be responsible to the Under Secretary for Public Diplomacy for matters pertaining to the development, implementation, and oversight of all educational, cultural, and professional exchange programs, as well as related initiatives and activities, and such other related duties as the Secretary may from time to time designate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H280486E6C13D42A2B03A45ED7FB58EFF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>In addition to the responsibilities described under subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary for Educational and Cultural Affairs shall be responsible for matters pertaining to academic, cultural, and professional exchanges in the conduct of foreign policy, including, as appropriate—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0DADE3B3109E43FD8347B9A28CFCC0AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">administering programs for youth and students, young leaders, established leaders, cultural elites, members of the press, and influencers, including the programs described in section 112 of the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2460">22 U.S.C. 2460</external-xref>);</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H5092F3119C1B470C90B1ADE94025D2C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>integrating all exchange programming into global public diplomacy planning;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H505890C522374FEF94CCBFDD1A27C093"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifying regional priorities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H97E03D7ED78D49FF9C4521E0017F696D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reducing overhead and administrative spending costs for programs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4F103ECD752048299EDB36BABF60F39E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>consolidating support services for programs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBFBADA55391A49728B603FAED0968E9D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>expanding cost-sharing partnerships with the private and nonprofit sectors;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H84C67E92CA06434D9B3AD196DCC87834"><enum>(7)</enum><text>ensuring clear foreign policy outcomes and performance; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0237B08130F0450C8618829365A774F6"><enum>(8)</enum><text>performing such other duties as the Under Secretary for Public Diplomacy may from time to time designate.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
<section id="H8CC47EBD719C415589D3AED9AD1DF4F8"><enum>712.</enum><header>Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs</header> 
<subsection id="HD89EEB2CCD504FDBAB660E01E2F1C7D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall maintain the Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs described in section 112 of the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2460">22 U.S.C. 2460</external-xref>), which shall perform functions related to academic, cultural, and professional exchanges as the Under Secretary for Public Diplomacy may prescribe.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD9096F45BF054BCAB2BEA48F43AD7CFC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Head of Bureau</header><text>The Assistant Secretary for Educational and Cultural Affairs shall be the head of the Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H8583756F996847A594F5247FCA18F378"><enum>713.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations for educational and cultural affairs</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Of the funds authorized to be appropriated to the Under Secretary for Public Diplomacy under section 702, the Assistant Secretary for Educational and Cultural Affairs shall receive the funds necessary to fulfill Bureau functions and the Assistant Secretary’s responsibilities for fiscal years 2026 and 2027.</text></section></subtitle> <subtitle id="HD0DD5AC5FBB8424891B6226A2E13BA40"><enum>C</enum><header>Strategic Communications</header> <section id="H482BF3350D5D41F399A23D4E2CD90E54"><enum>721.</enum><header>Assistant Secretary for Strategic Communications</header> <subsection id="HB3FE3F5E611E442982573582DE84C94F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is authorized to be in the Department an Assistant Secretary for Strategic Communications who shall be responsible to the Under Secretary for Public Diplomacy for matters pertaining to strategic communication, global access to free information, countering foreign censorship efforts, and such other related duties as the Secretary may from time to time designate.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H93243F30D76346A88BAA50880F217168"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>In addition to the responsibilities described under subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary for Strategic Communications shall oversee and coordinate all matters pertaining to foreign policy messaging in the conduct of foreign policy, including, as appropriate—</text> <paragraph id="HDEB6201E74314F72BC0CFCAE968949D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>overseeing foreign-facing information operations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3719A2484C914243879FB0ED3A8B5E26"><enum>(2)</enum><text>managing regional content operations and media relations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H323858EAD5EE4AED98C1D0CF9E196A2B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>overseeing and providing strategic direction for all United States Government funded media entities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF26A6ACD6BE8480191C1E49EA6A22315"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establishing and overseeing an Office of Global Distribution and News Services that shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HE189DFA9D3A84CB399C6F405CBC069A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>create and lead the open-content wire service; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H74D159B0AB344F868C5EC80EC1D73847"><enum>(B)</enum><text>manage translation and distribution of United States Government content;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6C10D3A3DA545339CC168A5AE6E3167"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supporting investigative and independent media;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDB37FEF00E6B473786CDC9D0EDFB09F0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>advocating for internet freedom;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02511A847F15457EA98A84422FF3618D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>advancing circumvention and access tools;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H79F67354BA3E4457BD21A30124CD8C88"><enum>(8)</enum><text>opposing censorship by foreign governments;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F0614AC7F7547C79987151DF66DC9BB"><enum>(9)</enum><text>leading diplomatic engagements on information freedom; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4EDB2A3D75B84AE88728D89892AB1238"><enum>(10)</enum><text>performing such other duties as the Under Secretary for Public Diplomacy may from time to time designate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H698517B1A19446EB9013F4E4E4A12AB7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appointments</header> <paragraph id="HB8EAFE6516714059847816D25B3ABF19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>First appointment</header><text>The individual serving as the Assistant Secretary for Global Public Affairs on the day immediately prior to the date of the enactment of this Act shall be the Assistant Secretary for Strategic Communications on and after the date of the enactment of this Act, until such individual vacates or is removed from such position.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H930B54B82626406491CD1662CB297AEA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent appointments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any appointment of an individual to the position of Assistant Secretary for Strategic Communications subsequent to the term of the individual described in paragraph (1) shall be subject to the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H76679FD0F0424443B9BB502F95A9EF51"><enum>722.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations for strategic communications</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Of the funds authorized to be appropriated to the Under Secretary for Public Diplomacy under section 702, the Assistant Secretary for Strategic Communications shall receive the funds necessary to fulfill Bureau functions and the Assistant Secretary’s responsibilities for fiscal years 2026 and 2027.</text></section> 
<section id="HE0F2031745F84C8C8140FEA1B5F5EF76"><enum>723.</enum><header>Repeal of limitation on use of funds for international expositions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 204 of the Admiral James W. Nance and Meg Donovan Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 2000 and 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2452b">22 U.S.C. 2452b</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></section></subtitle> <subtitle id="H7EAF206AF5554056B2973CAC400B74E8"><enum>D</enum><header>United States Code Classification</header> <section id="HBBD22745A4084AC2BBFCAA4318F04EE5"><enum>731.</enum><header>United States Code Classification</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Office of Law Revision Counsel shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3E5340766C5B4EA0A31EF9EB6B7A260E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reclassify sections 211a through 214a, 217a, and 218 of title 22, United States Code, as sections 244 through 254 of title 22, United States Code;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HECFCB54486F74E07B5E2B2CF5207DEBE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>utilize sections 191 through 221 of title 22, United States Code, to classify the sections of this title; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF0FD0D3FE154462AEEA0F2D5C5C2E0B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>maintain the legislative history, under editorial notes, of repealed and reclassified law which previously occupied the corresponding sections of United States Code.</text></paragraph></section></subtitle> </title> </legis-body></bill>

