<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6BF72A05C1E74CE2A55833A317120776" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5530 IH: Postal Contracting Financial Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5530</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250919">September 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend section 404 of title 39, United States Code, to permit contractors to independently continue operating contract postal units that would otherwise be closed by the United States Postal Service, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5F76BAD27DB4424082FACCDEC810F11A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9B29F302866B479C94A524D82B5A3A3D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Postal Contracting Financial Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H40CA8DD849264163B59B5CB31B9689FD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Continued operation of contract postal units</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 404 of title 39, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA95D48A986BC456DA22048E50BFF8677" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HBEBC3B8881A2436BAB3952CA9283B2C0"><enum>(f)</enum> <paragraph id="HAA149D25A9F24E2ABBEA508C395266A7" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Postal Service makes a determination to terminate or not renew a contract postal unit operation agreement with a covered contractor for a contract postal unit, the covered contractor may, in the sole discretion of the covered contractor, elect to have such contract postal unit operation agreement remain in effect in accordance with this subsection if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF0E0DC0755B74EE5B9ED497515F6123D" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such determination to terminate or not renew the contract postal unit operation agreement is not primarily or entirely based on the covered contractor breaching such contract postal unit operation agreement;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCC8C3E3115F74E46B3600D8C907ACDAA" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Postal Service has not entered into another contract postal unit operation agreement with the covered contractor for the contract postal unit;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF4C00D3C5E3E4634A75B4E47EDBB536D" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the covered contractor submits to the Postal Service a notice of such election by the covered contractor; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8F9C7915F66F434F807AB4E2A9F12D39" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the covered contractor agrees to amend the terms and conditions of the contract postal unit operation agreement in accordance with this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4D13C18C86644AE3A47BC5D5A1432F48" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum>
<subparagraph id="HFFD220C3B2544DC18E59085EBDDED62C" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except as provided by subparagraph (B), a contract postal unit operation agreement that remains in effect pursuant to an election by a covered contractor under paragraph (1) shall have the same terms and conditions as the terms and conditions in effect immediately prior to the date on which, but for such election, the contract postal unit operation agreement would have terminated or ended, and such terms and conditions shall apply in the same manner as such terms and conditions applied immediately prior to such date, except that, after such date, the contract postal unit operation agreement shall—</text> <clause id="H165B4B9DA69E48549A73EEBA74F28726"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not obligate the Postal Service to make any payment to the covered contractor; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HE0548CD9BC2F42308275196068569025"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">remain in effect until—</text> <subclause id="H371FE38CC35E40D8B6A55A2CC409303B"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Postal Service terminates the contract postal unit operation agreement for a breach of the contract postal unit operation agreement by the covered contractor; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1320C361D8FF4066AC18CB1289496B55"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the covered contractor—</text> <item id="H88992AA428E04A969AF58DB714F57B32"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">terminates the contract postal unit operation agreement; or</text></item> 
<item id="H5FEE11D2B0F3429E8252799BBC953F6F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">permanently ceases to operate the contract postal unit with respect to which the contract postal unit operation agreement applies.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCCEC04C822324771B6AD5D496095BEFE"><enum>(B)</enum> <clause id="H39DE130CC49A47A9B2CCA428D2483620" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), a contract postal unit operation agreement that remains in effect pursuant to an election by a covered contractor under paragraph (1) shall, if determined appropriate by the Postmaster General, require the Postal Service to make payments to the covered contractor with respect to the operation of the contract postal unit with respect to which the contract postal unit operation agreement applies after the date on which, but for such election, the contract postal unit operation agreement would have terminated or ended.</text></clause>
<clause id="H867E090D5164458EAB6D093AEF044029" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Postmaster General shall determine terms and conditions of any payments the Postal Service is required to make to a covered contractor under a contract postal unit operation agreement pursuant to clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBD3A61D1B19496C8F3A1CD5E31F9F53" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a covered contractor makes the election under paragraph (1) with respect to a contract postal unit operation agreement, the Postal Service shall agree to amend the terms and conditions of the contract postal unit operation agreement in accordance with this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H09C49C35D7F0478A919E059B629080C0" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="HD68041B8A99D4E3E842651B120D0B7FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>contract postal unit</term> means a facility operated by a covered contractor at which the covered contractor provides retail postal services under a contract postal unit operation agreement;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCC1D04324A0F45138E8F95AAE136574D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>contract postal unit operation agreement</term> means a contract or other agreement between the Postal Service and a covered contractor under which the covered contractor operates a contract postal unit; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H91BA7169BB164FFBAA47C48DDB06FF46"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>covered contractor</term> means an individual or entity operating a contract postal unit under a contract postal unit operation agreement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

