<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8DA62E33D26C42EE9447EEDC330F811E" public-private="private" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1819 IH: To authorize the President to award the Medal of Honor to E. Royce Williams for acts of valor during the Korean War.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">V</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1819</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250303">March 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the President to award the Medal of Honor to E. Royce Williams for acts of valor during the Korean War.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5E4D9D068343402E88A5DD49C8DB380B" style="OLC"><section id="H534157651D854623BC2EA144D55EE7FF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H7FEDF9B844B24AE582FC1695BD99F1B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On November 18, 1952, then Lieutenant E. Royce Williams and Combat Air Patrol Task Force 77 carried out an airstrike on the Hoeryong industrial complex near the Korea-Russia border. In response, seven Soviet MiG–15s launched from a Soviet base near Vladivostok. Williams and three other U.S. pilots flying F9F–5 Panthers were dispatched from the U.S.S. Oriskany to pursue the seven MiG–15s in blizzard conditions to engage over the Sea of Japan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE0158E5B8424F9390886230924D9D1B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When the Flight Leader’s instruments reported a fuel-pump warning, he was escorted back to the U.S.S. Oriskany by his wingman.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC149E94615664929ACE59568000C48E7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Williams and his wingman, Dave Rowlands, remained airborne. Williams fired upon one MiG–15 and Rowlands followed it out of formation, leaving Williams to pursue the remaining six MiG–15s on his own. In his efforts, Williams expended all of his ammunition and shot down four, very likely five, of the seven Soviet MiG–15s, setting the American aviator record for MiGs shot in a single sortie and the only naval dogfight over water in the Korean War.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE437156889143849DF6E924F48BCD08"><enum>(4)</enum><text>After sustaining a hit from a 37 millimeter shell that disabled his electrical and hydraulic systems, Williams underwent enemy fire while returning to the carrier as well as friendly fire from escort vessels after being mistaken for enemy aircraft.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02E25C791C5A459AB113C8C8E5AD40A4"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Without rudders to slow his descent, Williams landed on the U.S.S. Oriskany at a speed of 170 knots, miraculously able to safely engage the number three wire.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63AF42F644D742B5918A2454CE801EBB"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Williams’ aircraft sustained 263 holes and a foot-long gash while the only injury sustained by Williams was a bloody neck, chafed by his gear. Williams was told not to speak of the events of that day by his commanders, and, at the time, was only officially credited for one downed and one damaged enemy in the fight.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA44AF3E9E8534ED38CAC3968657A4778"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Witnesses to this heroism were the first unit of the then newly created National Security Agency, codenamed <quote>Canoe</quote>, aboard the USS Helena. Intercepting Soviet communications, the unit recorded the transmissions that three Soviet MiGs were shot down, and one pilot ejected his compromised aircraft and then died. One aircraft returned to base in Vladivostok.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H199A1D5318D443289AA0FD6D5943D839"><enum>(8)</enum><text>At the end of the Cold War, Russia released the names of the four pilots shot down in combat on November 18, 1952.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FD60597DDB14E9B8F0F71224DDE9FAB"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When Williams was awarded the Silver Star for his actions on November 18, 1952, the drafters did not have access to the top secret radio intelligence or the subsequent Russian report released after the Cold War.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29E2E471DD764A48980EDEEA6140566E"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Williams served in the Navy for over 30 years, flew over 220 missions in Korea and Vietnam, and retired in 1984.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B2148F49B7F47988AA6EF30C4079011"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On January 20th, 2023, Williams’ Silver Star was upgraded by the Secretary of the Navy to the Navy Cross.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A5EA7E7C9564664B9C1CDA697B38772"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">E. Royce Williams deserves the Congressional Medal of Honor for his heroic actions on November 18, 1952, when he successfully eliminated four, likely five, of seven MiG–15s in a far less superior aircraft during the 35-minute-long aerial battle wherein he never once sought safety in the clouds or abandoned the mission despite being outnumbered and outgunned.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC068057BD6E440269768D6BA4F8B835C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization for award of Medal of Honor to E. Royce Williams for acts of valor during the Korean War</header><subsection id="H8086C215D21C4E2C97BAA3E3251E9697"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Waiver of time limitations</header><text>Notwithstanding the time limitations specified in section 8298 of title 10, United States Code, or any other time limitation with respect to the awarding of certain medals to persons who served in the Armed Forces, the President may award the Medal of Honor under section 8291 of such title to E. Royce Williams for the acts of valor described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H76E1B83F38324B3EB21CC64CBC5BAF89"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Acts of valor described</header><text>The acts of valor described in this subsection are the actions of E. Royce Williams, as a lieutenant in the Navy, on November 18, 1952.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

