<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H85457BC7C8AA40F4A2D245B55F84538C" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2351 : To direct the Commandant of the Coast Guard to update the policy of the Coast Guard regarding the use of medication to treat drug overdose, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2351</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250610">June 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Commandant of the Coast Guard to update the policy of the Coast Guard regarding the use of medication to treat drug overdose, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3DD1AB8B52EF46EC81B634E8E7768D58" style="OLC"><pagebreak></pagebreak><section id="H9EFDE95D5E244FF780E5FC2C42318556" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Controlled substance onboard vessels</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 70503(a) of title 46, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H5B100A6AE4884673AD3C527830A09313"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1) by striking <quote>While on board a covered vessel, an</quote> and inserting <quote>An</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE04B448CC2404E0CB4E965C5E77E9128"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H70426EC0E55B41C582024E4474270609" style="USC"><paragraph id="H53464997283F445BA98F8132AA189491"><enum>(1)</enum><text>manufacture or distribute, possess with intent to manufacture or distribute, or place or cause to be placed with intent to manufacture or distribute a controlled substance on board a covered vessel;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H334DFD2D64224AA2A48E0A8F76F73E84"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (2) by inserting <quote>on board a covered vessel</quote> before the semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBDA1B946FDF49B08DBC4C20613B0D2D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (3) by inserting <quote>while on board a covered vessel</quote> after <quote>such individual</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H1227926983D74759B0C95AB9A80D252D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Policy and briefing on availability of naloxone to treat opioid overdoses</header><subsection id="H3F3DAFA9C3D94475BAA7E7C60CB71F19"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commandant of the Coast Guard shall update the policy of the Coast Guard regarding the use of medication to treat drug overdoses, including the use of naloxone or other similar medication to treat opioid, including fentanyl, overdoses.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6E48D30237FF4BD58B08F8326E67E6B7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The updated policy required under subsection (a) shall require naloxone or other similar medication be available for members of the Coast Guard—</text><paragraph id="HEE595264ED464D01AB04B4FA6DC24D09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on all Coast Guard installations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71EC693A3A9D49B9A60C539D9EA859FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in each operational environment. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6995A24999F34CF4A644C2B29737A3B0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Participation in tracking system</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the earlier of the date of enactment of this Act or the date on which the tracking system established under section 706 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1090">10 U.S.C. 1090</external-xref> note) is established, the Commandant shall ensure the participation of the Coast Guard in the such tracking system.</text></subsection><subsection id="H79E19EE2CFD8446C953A760A1B7D1FC2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the earlier of the date of enactment of this Act or the date on which the tracking system established under section 706 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1090">10 U.S.C. 1090</external-xref> note) is established, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating when not operating as a service in the Navy and the Secretary of Defense shall finalize a memorandum of understanding to facilitate Coast Guard access such tracking system.</text></subsection><subsection id="H54CB52315CC841B7A5E02AD611546BEA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Briefing</header><paragraph id="HA5C199FC9CD84D8B9F65B526E4E53D5C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commandant shall provide the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a briefing on the use, by members and personnel of the Coast Guard at Coast Guard facilities, onboard Coast Guard assets, and during Coast Guard operations, of—</text><subparagraph id="H2589F0EBC96D46B09C2AF169616BAA51"><enum>(A)</enum><text>naloxone or other similar medication to treat opioid, including fentanyl, overdoses; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H326738482D35400E8285B23F51F4E0E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>opioids, including fentanyl.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CBF82EB804946CE818C5114D3A44AFD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The briefing required under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HBE4B97ECB66D40FC9C5AAD0C6D970FE9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of—</text><clause id="H4431596A49464E75A2EB3B7D0FD4C537"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the progress made in the implementation of the updated policy required under subsection (a);</text></clause><clause id="HB10691F6064048058596E6FE85D6D93D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the prevalence and incidence of the illegal use of fentanyl and other controlled substances in the Coast Guard during the 5-year period preceding the briefing;</text></clause><clause id="H48EED325277A4E35A6E1B87C5F04CE43"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>processes of the Coast Guard to mitigate substance abuse in the Coast Guard, particularly with respect to fentanyl; and</text></clause><clause id="HE733A39E78D94FF699D6A5715ABE3E2F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the status of the memorandum of understanding required under subsection (d).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35777494794C4E43971D3DAE15F6CA1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For the 5-year period preceding the briefing, a review of instances in which naloxone or other similar medication was used to treat opioid, including fentanyl, overdoses at a Coast Guard facility, onboard a Coast Guard asset, or during a Coast Guard operation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H24286A364F57430BAC1136CA3F67AC46"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Privacy</header><text>In carrying out the requirements of this section, the Commandant shall ensure compliance with all applicable privacy law, including section 552a of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Privacy Act</quote>), and the privacy regulations promulgated under section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-2">42 U.S.C. 1320d–2</external-xref> note).</text></subsection><subsection id="H02FE0030A1C34CBFBEB655A2DE01F1CC"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>For purposes of the availability requirement under subsection (b), with respect to a Coast Guard installation comprised of multiple Coast Guard facilities or units, naloxone or other similar medication available at a single Coast Guard facility within the installation shall be considered to be available to all Coast Guard facilities or units on the installation if appropriate arrangements are in place to ensure access, at all times during operations, to the naloxone or other similar medication contained within such single Coast Guard facility.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250609" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives June 9, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

