<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3856AE9F91F14AFDB44D9E03D54C6042" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1776 IH: New Health Options Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1776</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250303">March 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000609">Mr. Palmer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to establish a reinsurance program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H42167E76033A4A3FA636A3323054773C" style="OLC"><section id="HAEC192395E194481952281A4AA69C70F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>New Health Options Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD66C3D3959144083B25712C0E625CCCD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Creation of a reinsurance program for a new health insurance risk pool</header><subsection id="H2CD8913486254A6697F67362F64C9108"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part V of subtitle B of title I of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18061">42 U.S.C. 18061 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H6DB0EC1CAAFE478780CDE64ED64A0BA8" style="OLC"><section id="H4893680A2C244FE1AD8A8ED62CF54867"><enum>1344.</enum><header>Reinsurance program for certain off-Exchange plans</header><subsection id="H40300D3DA4C34C9FA13D09B234B32D03"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established a Reinsurance Program, to be administered by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, to provide payments to health insurance issuers with respect to claims for eligible individuals for the purpose of lowering premiums for such individuals.</text></subsection><subsection id="H30C6714BC48646AFAA61FF5F7C74EE32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><paragraph id="H6D374E1C38FF40B880958AEE154C7D59"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text>For the purpose of providing funding for the Reinsurance Program, for each year during the period beginning on January 1, 2026, and ending on December 31, 2030, there is appropriated out of any monies in the Treasury not otherwise obligated an amount equal to the product of $50 and the aggregate number of member months for all eligible individuals enrolled in a covered plan during such year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED3CCFE9F10B46B79441508745E74AA9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on appropriation</header><text>In no year shall the appropriation for the Reinsurance Program authorized in paragraph (1) exceed $6,000,000,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA19F9688F8A463C8D7FA99903E5CCAD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of unexpended funds</header><text>Appropriated amounts remaining unexpended at the end of any year may be used to make payments under the Reinsurance Program in any future year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B454F26842E4C54B9C8F748250155C0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation on use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds received under the Reinsurance Program may be used to pay for services described in section 1303(b)(1)(B)(i) (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this section).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E9E1A12CB584E76A80C8DA8B43B3979"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Operation of program</header><paragraph id="HFC0DAA88DC844F4697761F4843014C59"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish parameters for the operation of the Reinsurance Program consistent with this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06A75998DC694652B351BB878C39767A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline for initial operation</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment, the Secretary shall establish sufficient parameters to specify how the Program will operate for 2026.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB98230436BE6446085D3289521BA4C94"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><subparagraph id="H3EE012FE9054403F801B5EAA5BBCB411"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered plan</header><text>The term <quote>covered plan</quote> means individual health insurance coverage (as such term is defined in section 2791 of the Public Health Service Act)—</text><clause id="H154C7168771C44DC9133D7773D9C9A9F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to which the issuer of such coverage has made the election described in section 1312(c)(1)(A); and</text></clause><clause id="HC569AAB3045C49CCA3F4C8B803BE69F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that does not provide coverage for services described in section 1303(b)(1)(B)(i) (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this section).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H859E9739E3944E9CA21A0DC47AEEB873"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible individual</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>eligible individual</quote> means an individual enrolled in a covered plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H103A75EF3F9F4C75A9357BF36161760D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Attachment dollar amount and payment proportion</header><paragraph id="H6CA16D4CA66242B88848A8D8702E7165"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall annually establish an attachment point, payment proportion, and reinsurance cap with respect to claims for eligible individuals for payments under the Reinsurance Program, consistent with the following:</text><subparagraph id="H4701111875BB47EFB045516E771462AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The attachment point for the period beginning January 1, 2026, and ending December 31, 2026, shall be $110,000.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92DDF2BE682A4A58B505085CFFE0437F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The payment proportion for the period beginning January 1, 2026, and ending December 31, 2026, shall be 90 percent.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1177EB2271E4775A92B2AA772AB4775"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The reinsurance cap for the period beginning January 1, 2026 and ending December 31, 2026, shall be $300,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H654477EE7B244D54B8E15EB86A17D4CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adjustment authority</header><text>The Secretary may adjust any amounts described in paragraph (1) as necessary to ensure the Reinsurance Program does not make payment for a year in excess of the amount available for such year under subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H03DA0D53942542B6BC71466A9B51890B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Election To opt out of single risk pool</header><paragraph id="HB82745AAD123407D86E673AB1341EEAD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1312(c)(1) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18032">42 U.S.C. 18032(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H068A35A2E75F43038206CFE0563A4A94"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A health insurance issuer</quote> and inserting the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3B30C60FE8D64BB7AE2E16501E55F38D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HD5BBF174A0624375BC86576FD8B874C7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A health insurance issuer</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H842C253AB5A1490B8ACE9AF04FA4CFC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), as inserted by paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>and other than any health plan with respect to which such issuer has elected for this subparagraph not to apply</quote> after <quote>grandfathered health plans</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE078A42829F742ED94ACA112EBC74A74"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H38212267C22B437B831804CD520301DD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H03CE53030734466CAA0EFA63B02C212E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of plans opting out of single risk pool</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A health insurance issuer shall consider all enrollees in all health plans offered by such issuer in the individual market with respect to which such issuer has made the election described in subparagraph (A) to be members of a single risk pool.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC77A61078CE94303AEE1087438AAC8D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibiting single risk pool opt out for qualified health plans</header><text>Section 1301(a)(1)(C) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18021">42 U.S.C. 18021(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H07BDAF5612404882809662BEAB9A97E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7996295C058474486E36AAA473452EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (iv), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35D98E9BB777468C8B1173FF92BEE841"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H734D7789EB5E4416AFC208EF34372908" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="H8BEC2A6C7B754FFEA5AEB81C53BA8D81"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has not made the election described in section 1312(c)(1)(A) with respect to such plan.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6901EED84FB46C19F6BE9FD51C2E9E9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this subsection shall apply with respect to plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2026.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H662611CDA0F34B9F9038A95CF6370398"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Removing age premium variation limitation for certain plans</header><paragraph id="HC17756016A3E4E4BB7B427B6C795594C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="H3772C5F810544735B30D2CEF96FDDA91"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Removal of limitation for certain plans</header><text>Section 2701(a)(1)(A)(iii) of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C 300gg(a)(1)(A)(iii)) is amended by inserting <quote>or, in the case of such coverage with respect to which the issuer of such coverage has made the election described in section 1312(c)(1)(A) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, by more than an actuarially justified amount for adults</quote> before <quote>; and</quote>. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8F59312682B49898E84E9BC5F2A819F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subparagraph (A) shall apply with respect to plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2026.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DD125264EF54CCE87DDDD59F5EC1D01"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maintaining age premium variation limitation for qualified health plans</header><text>Section 1301(a)(1) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18021">42 U.S.C. 18021(a)(1)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (b), is further amended—</text><subparagraph id="H163BCCEED6454497953693FCE370EA4D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C22AD0DD61C4D5EA7B4DE44F2302CCF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)(v), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3C0BFE50B8645F8AA84369379340C33"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE489833F14B14DDEB12B9258DE278D94" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HCDA46FC230B84D42B91D5FBDE2E237C5"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the premium rate charged by such plan, if such plan varies such rate by age, does not vary such rate by more than 3 to 1 for adults (consistent with section 2707(c) of the Public Health Service Act).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13D0E4F056F846FA8052CD3859AD81D3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Treatment of opt out plans in relation to individual health coverage reimbursement arrangements</header><text>The Secretaries of Health and Human Services, Labor, and the Treasury shall not fail to treat any individual health insurance coverage (as defined in section 2791 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-91">42 U.S.C. 300gg–91</external-xref>)) as eligible for integration with an individual health care reimbursement arrangement on the basis that the health insurance issuer (as so defined) of such coverage has made the election described in section 1312(c)(1)(A) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (as inserted by subsection (b)). </text></subsection></section><section id="HF3FFDE3A2F9D4F118D15C3731FA19893"><enum>3.</enum><header>Promotion of high-value care</header><subsection id="HB2B0A45A720649F0BED892A7934C7075"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart II of part A of title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-11">42 U.S.C. 300gg–11 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9E780A0B84EF48D0B57053A36E933011" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H53BE8DFF94DA408D9102A363CAFFB386"><enum>2730.</enum><header>Application of certain out-of-network costs to deductibles and out-of-pocket maximums</header><subsection id="H1B08A24AEC0748E28575BB95DA2273FE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A group health plan, and a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage, shall, in the case that an individual enrolled under such plan or coverage is furnished items or services by a health care provider or health care facility that does not have in effect a contractual relationship with such plan or issuer for the furnishing of such items or services and such individual incurs any out-of-pockets costs with respect to such items and services, at the option of such individual, apply such costs to any deductible or out-of-pocket maximum applicable to items and services furnished by health care providers or health care facilities with contracts in effect with such plan or issuer for the furnishing of such items or services, but only if the following requirements are met:</text><paragraph id="HB608E945133C4700AC6180F8FC6C2D0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The item or service furnished by such provider or facility without a contract in effect with such plan or issuer is an item or service for which benefits are available under such plan or coverage.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DFCEC7152C348C6A9C6631374706006"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The amount charged by such provider or facility for such item or service is equal to or less than—</text><subparagraph id="H9669BDDEED1949128F3929F22AFF8FD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the lowest amount recognized by the plan or coverage as payment for such item or service out of all health care providers and health care facilities with a contract in effect with such plan or issuer to furnish such item or service in the same rating area (as defined for purposes of section 2701) in which the item or service described in paragraph (1) was furnished; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8036FAC24DCE4CE0922B2F2D2E35746A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the 25th percentile of charges for such item or service furnished in the same State in which the item or service described in paragraph (1) was furnished.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H80ACCB0802B04840B5D890C7277E5AD3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disclosure of information</header><text>A group health plan, and a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage, shall, with respect to each item or service for which benefits are available under such plan or coverage, make available the lowest amount described in subsection (a)(2)(A) and the 25th percentile described in subsection (a)(2)(B) to all individuals enrolled under such plan or coverage.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H408A7C90E9E44C8E8A0C473CFB9E1882"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2026.</text></subsection></section><section id="H37F89751101D4775B12CD7BB056859D6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Disclosure of lower prices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part E of title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-131">42 U.S.C. 300gg–131</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBE30556729844C7094FD3562D6D0602F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H6ED0A1DFAC3C47E1ADE85C4491462565"><enum>2799B–10.</enum><header>Disclosure of lower prices</header><subsection id="H31DE8AF1C88748D7AB0DFD2A77CE6158"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning January 1, 2026, each health care provider and health care facility shall disclose to patients and prospective patients enrolled in a group health plan, group or individual health insurance coverage, or a Federal health care program (as defined in section 1128B but including the program established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code) being furnished or seeking to be furnished an item or service by such provider or facility for which benefits are available under such plan, coverage, or program, as applicable, whether the amount of cost sharing (including deductibles, copayments, and coinsurance) that would be incurred by such individual for such item or service under such plan, coverage, or program, as applicable, exceeds the charge that would apply for such item or service for an individual without benefits under any such plan, coverage, or program for such item or service. </text></subsection><subsection id="H139579F7BE12411692E0B357C360D636"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to any other penalty applicable with respect to a violation of subsection (a), an individual who is harmed by a violation of this section by a health care provider or health care facility may bring an action against such provider or facility in an appropriate district court of the United States for—</text><paragraph id="HFBE699557D2447CF8AA1FD16F6D348B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>appropriate injunctive relief; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE530F5D198684F21BD8E99FB00727FA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">damages in an amount that is equal to the amount provided for such harm in a civil action under the law of the State in which the provider or facility is located.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

