<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2D4037FA7BE54B05833E938E917FF895" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4732 IH: Orphanage Trafficking Prevention and Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4732</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To expand the definition of <quote>severe forms of trafficking in persons</quote> to include the recruitment, harboring, transportation, transfer, or receipt of orphaned, abandoned, or minors living in public or private residential facilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE3A83C4BF9F24D67BED97ABC90B46077" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8E5AB56C860445B69B2B23358E65A4B8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Orphanage Trafficking Prevention and Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HE7033D1D17D941398437D66FE0D2208C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HDF162BBBCF554D7BA7102190DEF2F810"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Orphaned, abandoned, and children living in public or private residential facilities, including institutions, children’s homes, orphanages, boarding schools, or group homes, are among the populations most vulnerable to trafficking in persons worldwide. According to the United States Department of State, children without parental care are at significantly higher risk of being trafficked for labor, sexual exploitation, forced begging, and other illegal purposes.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF0610593297740708B4F9B36432BF0B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An estimated 5,400,000 children live in institutional care globally, many of whom are not true orphans but are separated from their families due to poverty, disability, or family breakdown.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H91CAB761BD424B4D9FE07F9203F8E201"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Traffickers often target these children under the guise of education, caregiving, or adoption.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF874AF1F6D1C4F4E907A807BE4D37E48">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of State’s 2024 Trafficking in Persons Report notes that <quote>orphanage trafficking</quote>—the recruitment of children into residential care for the purpose of exploitation and profit—occurs in multiple countries and is increasingly linked to international travel, and volun-tourism.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E073E2C73374A1FB83306E9A07EDE62"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of State’s 2019 and 2024 Trafficking in Persons Reports have identified patterns in which children are trafficked into orphanages to attract donations and international volunteers, with reports of physical, emotional, and sexual abuse in such institutions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H18D60A9F43E644B6B18B7CABFC9911A7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In some cases, children are fraudulently labeled as orphans and trafficked through inter-country adoption channels, undermining legitimate adoption systems and violating the Convention on Protection of Children and Co-operation in Respect of Intercountry Adoption, done at the Hague on May 29, 1993.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDD1A8633CD614A0C9B72CFA7167D3591"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Despite these documented abuses, current United States law does not explicitly recognize orphanage trafficking as a severe form of trafficking in persons, which, accordingly, may hinder efforts to prosecute perpetrators, protect victims, and condition foreign assistance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7ADF0316625C4B5CB2BB84ABBE27B54A"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clarifying that the trafficking of orphaned, abandoned, or children living in public or private residential facilities, including institutions, children’s homes, orphanages, boarding schools, or group homes, constitutes a severe form of trafficking in persons under the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7101">22 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>) is necessary to protect these children, enhance accountability, and strengthen United States anti-trafficking efforts.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H6E0E0F196506494BA628CFF3964BC6F4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Modification to definition of severe forms of trafficking in persons</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (11) of section 103 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H0235941781B8441ABC2B15E196ED2A33"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>; or</quote> at the end and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H19CBF704C15E4486B47A0480B67803B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF4878D1E35042A8A9ABD917655D4D67"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H10B42919BBF340A9A588906C4E83EE7E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H917BDB20948E4D52BD1B7C5A37D9B505"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the recruitment, harboring, transportation, transfer, or receipt of orphaned, abandoned, or persons living in public or private residential facilities who have not attained 18 years of age, by means of fraud, coercion, force, or abuse of a position of vulnerability, for the purpose of exploitation and profit, forced labor, involuntary servitude, peonage, debt bondage, slavery, child labor, or sex trafficking.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

