<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EHF25075-LFC-8P-3VL"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S424 IS: Retirement Fairness for Charities and Educational Institutions Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 424</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250205">February 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Federal securities laws to enhance 403(b) plans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HC521411F4EF340168C92FBF272353B66"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Retirement Fairness for Charities and Educational Institutions Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H405BEA3EEECF4C6AA1B397FD95500C99"><enum>2.</enum><header>Enhancement of 403<enum-in-header>(b)</enum-in-header> plans</header><subsection id="HE4A7D90073B14E00B217C5E97A6A0E7A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments to the Investment Company Act of <enum-in-header>1940</enum-in-header></header><text>Section 3(c)(11) of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-3">15 U.S.C. 80a–3(c)(11)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E523A7CBF1E4236A94D61EA761C167B"><paragraph id="HD262CF60FECE425788E38FA64B3B19B9"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Any—</text><subparagraph id="H228FB3FCFF33487FBE36470AD14C1932"><enum>(A)</enum><text>employee’s stock bonus, pension, or profit-sharing trust which meets the requirements for qualification under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/401">section 401</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C2DB8E62BDC466CA60BCEF918C32D58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>custodial account meeting the requirements of section 403(b)(7) of such Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H030FB37BF1C7429A87BC61BBFBEC0D31"><enum>(C)</enum><text>governmental plan described in section 3(a)(2)(C) of the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77c">15 U.S.C. 77c(a)(2)(C)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75E3D3ECEF394D2E8478526D17249372"><enum>(D)</enum><text>collective trust fund maintained by a bank consisting solely of assets of one or more—</text><clause id="HE582C10234BD40EDA15AE4670574FDE6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>trusts described in subparagraph (A); </text></clause><clause id="H32CBDB69AFD5409EAF197190F895B3C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>government plans described in subparagraph (C); </text></clause><clause id="H5E8085CFC8A14D0887AC00516E22F8C7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>church plans, companies, or accounts that are excluded from the definition of an investment company under paragraph (14) of this subsection; or</text></clause><clause id="H74A16DEBA253439DBBC1C485424C0EC1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>plans which meet the requirements of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/403">section 403(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986—</text><subclause id="H5CA0EE5C70BA4EE5BDA89B199645633A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if—</text><item id="H82828B1369104307A9CABEA044715383"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>such plan is subject to title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1001">29 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>); </text></item><item id="HFB23CE3DF18E408F8F629DCD6AF220B4"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>any employer making such plan available agrees to serve as a fiduciary for the plan with respect to the selection of the plan’s investments among which participants can choose; or </text></item><item id="HF6E1F5CEEF314BC6B331005539D43996"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>such plan is a governmental plan (as defined in section 414(d) of such Code); and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H433B6FAB2791455CB3E9B099969AC325"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the employer, a fiduciary of the plan, or another person acting on behalf of the employer reviews and approves each investment alternative offered under such plan described under subclause (I)(cc) prior to the investment being offered to participants in the plan; or</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB070CE5F77484DCDA77A173A7EFD5AD7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>separate account the assets of which are derived solely from—</text><clause id="H63CE53F6E9B1408B822617FCB6BE0A27"><enum>(i)</enum><text>contributions under pension or profit-sharing plans which meet the requirements of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/401">section 401</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 or the requirements for deduction of the employer’s contribution under section 404(a)(2) of such Code;</text></clause><clause id="H01AB3F1907B646C9B0B20BBA5BC43F2D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>contributions under governmental plans in connection with which interests, participations, or securities are exempted from the registration provisions of section 5 of the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77e">15 U.S.C. 77e</external-xref>) by section 3(a)(2)(C) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77c">15 U.S.C. 77c(a)(2)(C)</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="HC90F18DA0192496889E34BA4B726DEA9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>advances made by an insurance company in connection with the operation of such separate account; and</text></clause><clause id="H62AE98B5520A45B49CDA9DCED1886817"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>contributions to a plan described in clause (iii) or (iv) of subparagraph (D).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HBECE25DE96074FEDBC62005AF956E1BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendments to the Securities Act of <enum-in-header>1933</enum-in-header></header><text>Section 3(a)(2) of the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77c">15 U.S.C. 77c(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HEEEA4DD4029248D18F0B0085F7E08F8E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>beneficiaries, or (D)</quote> and inserting <quote>beneficiaries, (D) a plan which meets the requirements of section 403(b) of such Code (i) if (I) such plan is subject to title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1001">29 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>), (II) any employer making such plan available agrees to serve as a fiduciary for the plan with respect to the selection of the plan’s investments among which participants can choose, or (III) such plan is a governmental plan (as defined in section 414(d) of such Code), and (ii) if the employer, a fiduciary of the plan, or another person acting on behalf of the employer reviews and approves each investment alternative offered under any plan described under clause (i)(III) prior to the investment being offered to participants in the plan, or (E)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E4D067E7DF14C60A366952DF832732F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(C), or (D)</quote> and inserting <quote>(C), (D), or (E)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9602CE7AAFC54512A296950E20EE0530"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(iii) which is a plan funded</quote> and all that follows through <quote>retirement income account).</quote> and inserting <quote>(iii) in the case of a plan not described in subparagraph (D) or (E), which is a plan funded by an annuity contract described in section 403(b) of such Code.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4CFEE3E9015648E8B86F5F6333D388BE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amendments to the Securities Exchange Act of <enum-in-header>1934</enum-in-header></header><text>Section 3(a)(12)(C) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)(12)(C)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HA1F0D01DD89D4B65AB9D4C5CA346B728"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or (iv)</quote> and inserting <quote>(iv) a plan which meets the requirements of section 403(b) of such Code (I) if (aa) such plan is subject to title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1001">29 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>), (bb) any employer making such plan available agrees to serve as a fiduciary for the plan with respect to the selection of the plan’s investments among which participants can choose, or (cc) such plan is a governmental plan (as defined in section 414(d) of such Code), and (II) if the employer, a fiduciary of the plan, or another person acting on behalf of the employer reviews and approves each investment alternative offered under any plan described under subclause (I)(cc) prior to the investment being offered to participants in the plan, or (v)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4527F18F06F348509927A54B74A8D49C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(ii), or (iii)</quote> and inserting <quote>(ii), (iii), or (iv)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D74FDE1ED854CEDBEE7A7F8DBD567A9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(II) is a plan funded</quote> and inserting <quote>(II) in the case of a plan not described in clause (iv), is a plan funded</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7C1C424C2B1344BD87303A1A426876D9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming Amendment to the Securities Exchange Act of 1934</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 12(g)(2)(H) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78l">15 U.S.C. 78l(g)(2)(H)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>or (iii)</quote> and inserting <quote>(iii) a plan described in section 3(a)(12)(C)(iv) of this Act, or (iv)</quote>.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

