<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-joint" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-MDM25I53-02C-SV-NPM"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SJ 79 IS: Honoring the sacrifice of Marine Corps Lance Corporal David L. Espinoza, Marine Corps Sergeant Nicole L. Gee, Marine Corps Staff Sergeant Darin Taylor Hoover, Army Staff Sergeant Ryan Christian Knauss, Marine Corps Corporal Hunter Lopez, Marine Corps Lance Corporal Rylee J. McCollum, Marine Corps Lance Corporal Dylan R. Merola, Marine Corps Lance Corporal Kareem M. Nikoui, Marine Corps Corporal Daegan W. Page, Marine Corps Sergeant Johanny Rosario, Marine Corps Corporal Humberto A. Sanchez, Marine Corps Lance Corporal Jared M. Schmitz, and Navy Petty Officer Third Class Maxton W. Soviak. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. J. RES. 79</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250917" legis-day="20250916">September 17 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S439">Mrs. Moody</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</cosponsor>) introduced the following joint resolution; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the sacrifice of Marine Corps Lance Corporal David L. Espinoza, Marine Corps Sergeant Nicole L. Gee, Marine Corps Staff Sergeant Darin Taylor Hoover, Army Staff Sergeant Ryan Christian Knauss, Marine Corps Corporal Hunter Lopez, Marine Corps Lance Corporal Rylee J. McCollum, Marine Corps Lance Corporal Dylan R. Merola, Marine Corps Lance Corporal Kareem M. Nikoui, Marine Corps Corporal Daegan W. Page, Marine Corps Sergeant Johanny Rosario, Marine Corps Corporal Humberto A. Sanchez, Marine Corps Lance Corporal Jared M. Schmitz, and Navy Petty Officer Third Class Maxton W. Soviak. </official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the young men and women who perished as a result of the bombing at Abbey Gate on August 26, 2021, represent the best of the United States of America;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas their service secured the blessings of liberty for the United States of America and the people of Afghanistan from those who sought to harm it;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas their actions during the withdrawal of United States forces from Afghanistan saved the lives of thousands of innocents from the tyranny of the Taliban; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas their ultimate sacrifice on the 26th day of August 2021 was not made in vain, and so long as their grateful Nation draws breath, their faithful service in the cause of liberty shall not be forgotten: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H74C08E8E91B64F31939C6C2F38671C41"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H9E54C9B95E3E47FDAAFE9E0F1D9FD36D"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the United States of America—</text><paragraph id="H39270005206F46C3AC1A157A5E56BB0E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designates a National Day of Remembrance in honor of the American servicemembers who made the ultimate sacrifice at the bombing of Abbey Gate at the Hamid Karzai International Airport in Kabul, Afghanistan, on August 26, 2021;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A4EC7FD4F58413EBFBE10FCC8A9A45E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses its deepest condolences and gratitude to the Gold Star Families of those lost at Abbey Gate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD467CCA71F44B2BA1BC1277D6A51642"><enum>(3)</enum><text>remembers their honorable and faithful service to their Nation.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

