<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB21C142E2D394B40B963990CCA9F4314" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4703 IH: To establish a system to track, record, and report all instances in which a United States citizen or individual lawfully admitted for permanent resident was, for the purpose of immigration enforcement, detained or removed by the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4703</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a system to track, record, and report all instances in which a United States citizen or individual lawfully admitted for permanent resident was, for the purpose of immigration enforcement, detained or removed by the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H59B53FD914274776AFB81438F7BD505E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2883220BA6C94FA0888F0E7DBE3AD269" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Establishment of system to track, record, and report all instances in which a United States citizen or individual lawfully admitted for permanent resident was, for the purpose of immigration enforcement, detained or removed by the Department of Homeland Security</header> 
<subsection id="H92CA995FC67A438AB70868F80EC12A20"><enum>(a)</enum><header>System</header> 
<paragraph id="HF894A43B9ACA4E09857B8970FC18CE79"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish a standardized system to track, record, and report to the appropriate committees of Congress not less frequently than quarterly all instances in which a United States citizen, individual lawfully admitted for permanent resident (LPR), or individual whose status as an individual lawfully admitted for permanent residence has been revoked for not more than 30 days was, for the purpose of immigration enforcement, detained in the custody of the Department of Homeland Security for not less than 24 hours or removed by the Department.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A0EC74DFB064B25886FE696571082EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The system established pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include, to the greatest extent practicable, all instances in which a citizen or other individual described in such paragraph was, for the purpose of immigration enforcement, apprehended and detained by another Federal, State, or local law enforcement agency and transferred to the custody of the Department of Homeland Security for detention of not less than 24 hours or removal, as the case may be. Such system shall, in particular, include information with respect to such instances regarding such a citizen or other individual who on the date of such removal was less than 18 years of age and was so removed alongside an individual who on such date was without lawful status under the immigration laws and was a parent or guardian of such citizen or other individual, as the case may be.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H40AA01BEBF14442297B4498EBAC51160"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Process for proof of citizenship</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in collaboration with the Secretary of State, shall establish by rule a process for each United States citizen, or other individual, detained, removed, or apprehended as described in subsection (a) to submit to the Secretary of Homeland Security any information that indicates such individual is a United States citizen or lawfully admitted for permanent resident, as the case may be.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H2A597665AC3949AF872DC4AA9F546DED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2A5BDB61423A4E27905CEBB83485661E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HE1EC4A174F364563B2B6397379289EC9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In the House of Representatives, the following:</text> 
<clause id="H0C4809DF1C3C4E0798038DED226DA985"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Committee on Homeland Security.</text></clause> <clause id="H23CF444A38BD4805934DB62351331EE3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Committee on Judiciary.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBD3FC6E8B0A745D494F30416D7B83C86"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7AF4983E5A674331B9C4E546250964DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the Senate, the following:</text> 
<clause id="HB9EB82697F994C5596FEC0E04A064CA1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text></clause> <clause id="H8EA85D9270AB405B8FE22D94755CE90A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Committee on Judiciary.</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDE6CBAD292644DD391140311A55101E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Immigration laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>immigration laws</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF521AA6222974EC29A2EC3B8CF60F315"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Removed</header><text>The term <term>removed</term> means repatriated or otherwise transported from the United States to another country.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

