<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCA6DFA0B1E614718AA07F2212459EAD9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5791 IH: Boosting Lifesaving Operations, Opening Donation Centers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5791</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251017">October 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000829">Mr. Wied</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, to establish an expedited process for the approval of certain biologics license application supplements for blood centers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H92CE5CC133474FF1B25333DF6103324C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF9CC9BA0F6E34ABEB550015E20D79D71" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Boosting Lifesaving Operations, Opening Donation Centers Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BLOOD Centers Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H4D1D10CFA4E647069BAF0090CD57A0E1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expedited process for approval of certain BLA supplements for blood centers</header> <subsection id="H0881C31469044DD2B9A79A1439243DC8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, acting pursuant to section 351(a)(2) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262(a)(2)</external-xref>), shall establish an expedited process for the approval of a supplemental application submitted by the owner or operator of a blood center seeking to add an apheresis collection device to an existing BLA license at a location not previously licensed for such a device.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3ABBE5280BA94DEBB6589E3E7A58D6EA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the expedited procedure, the Secretary shall approve a supplemental application described in subsection (a) not later than 30 days after the date of submission of the application unless the Secretary makes a showing that there is—</text> <paragraph id="H3C7C315F044F4D17AFA78F1282779F3D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a specific concern for the safety, purity, or potency of products produced at the specific location subject to the supplemental application; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF4511439F6D4890B0F9E5BBD7C81774"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a systemic failure by the owner or operator to meet standards designed to ensure the continued safety, purity, and potency of products produced at other locations under a biologics license.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5D7A680D14F5410885A5928F31B3F355"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The expedited procedure shall apply with respect to a supplemental application described in subsection (a) if the owner or operator that submits the application—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6698F8CCE6664008AD8709C04F2C78EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>holds a biologics license for at least one blood center site; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28F0A093C0644D59BE56746E31DA11B0"><enum>(2)</enum> <subparagraph id="HE5764921FCBB423797EED4FBA8AD2B42" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been approved for a biologics license at 3 or more Food and Drug Administration registered locations under the biologics license referred to in paragraph (1); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC726CE8A05AB4CEBB354C302873CFCD5" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is accredited and in good standing for blood collection by an accreditation organization with standards that meet or exceed, as determined by the Secretary, all applicable regulatory requirements for blood collections.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2C124A905DEF429E85E766F32EF2616C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0B5660ACBDCE487BB3ECE283901650D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>BLA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>BLA</quote> means a biologics license application.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD1EC677F192F4F1FABF12DC7A09BEBFD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Blood center</header><text>The term <quote>blood center</quote> means a human blood donation center.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H60004B1E763844BF9C586B0AF083582D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Expedited procedure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>expedited procedure</quote> means the expedited procedure to be established under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEAC16FA3664F4FD2965453E342394F0B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

