<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9652CD6B7E584779A25B6C82569C3251" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1018 IH: Instructing Noteworthy Steps toward Transparency to Rout and Undo Calamitous Transactions Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1018</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250205">February 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001233">Mr. Messmer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require additional information in disclosures of foreign gifts and contracts from foreign sources.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H51B3C7C4F44E40C7B046302044F1DF57" style="OLC"><section id="HC8C65D8E5CB94792A38CB13ADBF72EF9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Instructing Noteworthy Steps toward Transparency to Rout and Undo Calamitous Transactions Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>INSTRUCT Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H92E5BE44F8AE4F2993DE38B2F9E64543" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Interagency information sharing</header><subsection id="HDEFD0DFC40854FF9BAF7FAA5724E6A65"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public records and sharing of reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 117(e) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1011f">20 U.S.C. 1011f(e)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D28AACB25D44CD7A7198DE1E2A5C41D"><subsection id="H8CCCEF65D22E4A30B064720B211FFF2B"><enum>(e)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4268B93F36E44FC491BB81AA83FF9122"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Public inspection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All disclosure reports required by this section shall be public records open to inspection and copying during business hours.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB062882BB05F463EAF26286BCFF5B0AE" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interagency information sharing</header><text>Not later than 30 days after receiving a disclosure report from an institution in compliance with this section, the Secretary shall transmit an unredacted copy of such report (that includes the name and address of a foreign source disclosed in such report) to the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Director of National Intelligence, the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Energy, the Director of the National Science Foundation, and the Director of the National Institutes of Health.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HE88370F2E9644CD2A3E3A16F5335896B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interagency information sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education shall transmit to each individual listed in section 117(e)(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965, as amended by this Act—</text><paragraph id="H90F8BB2BEEE64B37A2F461FBA04EB6DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any report received by the Department of Education under section 117 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1011f">20 U.S.C. 1011f</external-xref>) prior to the date of enactment of this Act; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1245091A1698477EA8130D47281EB178" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any report, document, or other record generated by the Department of Education in the course of an investigation—</text><subparagraph id="HE376941430904063874E569E3AAE395A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>of an institution with respect to the compliance of such institution with such section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3BA03DA0C1D4E2CA24FAED778E78551"><enum>(B)</enum><text>initiated prior to the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAAB79B12A97B4A55A38B916D510DA62B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GAO Study and Report</header><paragraph id="H26733E5BEC71440884B1FE8AD67E91DC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall initiate a study to identify ways to improve intergovernmental agency coordination regarding implementation and enforcement of sections 117 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1011f">20 U.S.C. 1011f</external-xref>), as amended by this Act, including increasing information sharing, increasing compliance rates, and establishing processes for enforcement. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF328B38762D448A82B8B28B61C9EB1E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress, and make public, a report containing the results of the study described in <internal-xref idref="H26733E5BEC71440884B1FE8AD67E91DC" legis-path="(c)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

