<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9E6E94C5B82D4D91AABF4FC4CA220B28" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4621 IH: 320th Barrage Balloon Battalion Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4621</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250722">July 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000388">Mr. Kelly of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To award a Congressional Gold Medal to the 320th Barrage Balloon Battalion, collectively, in recognition of their extraordinary heroism and life-saving actions during the D-Day invasion, and their significant contributions to the success of the Allied forces during World War II.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEA64691DA5F840FA9FCE02F4A97AB002" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H71C5B9F6BC9743D6B0AD488919A52407" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>320th Barrage Balloon Battalion Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB686602D1E144AE0B4B87FFF496A058A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9D30402DA1344B94BED264875EDDCE16"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The 320th Barrage Balloon Battalion was formed on September 21, 1942, just a year after the Coastal Artillery Corps took over responsibility for barrage balloons from the Army Air Corps. Their first combat assignment was at the Utah and Omaha beaches in Normandy, France, for the D-Day invasion.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H59D1D139D9124DD4A5D804E454BB365B"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>The Soldiers of the Battalion played a crucial role in protecting the Allied forces during the D-Day invasion by deploying barrage balloons to prevent enemy aircraft from targeting the invasion forces directly. Their bravery and determination exemplify the valor and dedication of African-American soldiers during World War II.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBF47838B15704D678E8C7389304916C2">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>The 320th Barrage Balloon Battalion was unique at Normandy for two reasons. First, it was the only American barrage balloon unit in France and second, it was the first and only segregated unit of African-American Soldiers to land on the beaches during D-Day.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H70B12671BA00434EBCDF90875083075B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The brave men of the 320th Barrage Balloon Battalion faced intense enemy fire during the D-Day invasion. Their mission was to raise hydrogen-filled barrage balloons to protect assaulting infantry and armor from being strafed by enemy aircraft. The balloons flew at an altitude of around 200 feet to defend soldiers landing on the beaches against strafing attacks by German aircraft.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8DFB078B16CD4B899C6D62D95A33BDE5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The 320th Barrage Balloon Battalion came up with an ingenious solution to one problem they had during the landing. They refitted RL–31 Signal Corps field cable winches with barrage balloon reels, which weighed only 35 pounds and were mounted in the back of a jeep to deploy and control balloons on D-Day.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEF1502611C7A4C7A9AE7BF26FC19FA48">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>Despite the severe conditions and many balloons being shot down, the battalion successfully deployed their balloons which resulted in the downing of a German JU–SS aircraft, significantly contributing to the overall security and success of the invasion and the Allied victory.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3D892904D607445BBDF093848BF3B597"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Additionally, at approximately 10:15 A.M. on June 6, 1944, five battalion medics with the 320th were the first to land on Omaha Beach, with crews of three-to-four men joining them shortly after U.S. Army Corporal Waverly B. Woodson, Jr., was among them.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE73ADB6BD2E4AED951454C85B0A1449"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Corporal Woodson was injured when his Landing Craft, Tank (LCT 856) hit a sea mine and was, then, struck by an artillery shell. Despite his injuries, Woodson continued to perform his duties, conducting an amputation, setting limbs and removing bullets over a 30-hour period. He even revived three men via artificial respiration. His efforts on D-Day are believed to have saved 200 soldiers, and he was recommended for the Medal of Honor by General John C.H. Lee, but never received it.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE441188B1A6E4BE2882F99FA87689E0B"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The 320th Barrage Balloon Battalion served 110 days in France, providing vital air defense during the critical early stages of the invasion. In late July 1944, Battery A of the 320th moved from Omaha Beach to the port city of Cherbourg, while the remaining batteries stayed on Omaha and Utah Beaches until early October, when deteriorating weather prevented ships from landing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H15F26E277C5C4537BA589981E03DAA81"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Following their service in the European Theater, the 320th underwent training at Camp Stewart, Georgia, prior to their deployment to the Pacific. On May 6, 1945, the 320th arrived in Oahu, Hawaii, in support of the proposed Allied invasion of Japan which never took place.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2456F74E99EC4778B6E2E1BD9D31D432"><enum>(11)</enum><text>A commendation by Supreme Allied Commander General Dwight D. Eisenhower cited the unit for conducting its mission with courage and determination, proving to be an important element of the air defense team. Despite their significant contributions, the 320th Barrage Balloon Battalion has not received the recognition it deserves in the annals of World War II history.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H643B6DC08D0B40C58E0FFF1D8944ACEA"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Henry Parham, the last surviving member of this unit, died in July 2021. His passing marked the end of an era, marking it fitting to honor the memory and service of these brave men.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD3ED5320810649349F3E53E2093A8834">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
 <text>The story of the 320th Barrage Balloon Battalion serves as a powerful reminder of the contributions and sacrifices of African-American soldiers in World War II, whose patriotic commitment and perseverance in the face of adversity during D-Day deserve national recognition and commemoration.</text>
      </paragraph></section> 
<section id="H52FBAEC2620D464386E6AE08253AAF73"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header> 
<subsection id="HF77C5AAEEC484BFDB05C7DBC682C6B70"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Presentation authorized</header><text>The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the presentation, on behalf of Congress, of a single gold medal of appropriate design in honor of the 320th Barrage Balloon Battalion, collectively, in recognition of their extraordinary heroism and bravery during the D-Day invasion, and their significant contributions to the success of the Allied forces during World War II.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3D57629203ED4B2EA5BEAB0E6C2D8B3B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text>For purposes of the presentation referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4E67D83E8A3644ADA0C1FF44789841F5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Smithsonian institution</header> 
<paragraph id="H2EB5D7A5A74644B782FD5C9828A8E79D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Following the award of the gold medal in honor of the 320th Barrage Balloon Battalion, the gold medal shall be given to the Smithsonian Institution, where it will be available for display as appropriate and available for research.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF2CDC1B90F74969887C35CDA7DBF164"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Sense of congress</header> <text>It is the sense of Congress that the Smithsonian Institution should make the gold medal awarded pursuant to this Act available for display elsewhere, particularly at appropriate locations associated with D-Day, World War II, and African-American servicemembers.</text>
        </paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H7F430C263E9342A58F861C83EA3BEE9B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck under section 3, at a price sufficient to cover the cost thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section> <section id="H0C12E4AFE8A54C8D9922CD3E74ED1BF8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header> <subsection id="HEE40007E08B54513A5C03F64EDA80DE2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medal</header><text>Medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA9F115C48DA1459CBC6A8FAB90F0FB12"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HF76CF6C791F54A1388FA77A9C466229F"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceed of sale</header> <subsection id="H1D91700C347F4E36B49570AC8CFEB8AA"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Authority To use fund amounts</header> <text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck under this Act.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H6B999F9AAB3646A5A667136348259ED3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 4 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

