<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0A04DB2C6BB84F4EAB0971F666B5F972" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4966 IH: Stop Price Gouging in Grocery Stores Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4966</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250812">August 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001094">Ms. Hoyle of Oregon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit retail food stores from price gouging and engaging in surveillance-based price setting practices, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE8844CDCDCF6447C9896E9B62F942B45" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4D7AF9AEA6C24AF497C1CFB98E5D4935" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Price Gouging in Grocery Stores Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD3E15863DFCB45BFBAE088D5D8BD0010"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on price gouging</header> <subsection id="H5BF17176023C4F809789ABFB0223E6A5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An operator of a retail food store may not sell or offer for sale an item at a grossly excessive price.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H756517301B6A4A47B4F257E5D380DE6C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Affirmative defense</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An operator of a retail food store does not sell or offer for sale an item at a grossly excessive price in violation of subsection (a) if the retail food store demonstrates to the Commission that the increase in the price of the item involved is directly attributable to additional costs that are—</text> <paragraph id="HA3A861CC34DA49429FCC0A43CF95BDE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not within the control of the retail food store; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HECC700FD2AD042FF9880C1AB492F77B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>incurred by the retail food store in procuring, acquiring, distributing, or providing the item.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB5354478767B4E2EBA438A2DA6C2E751" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Required guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall promulgate, pursuant to 553 of title 5, United States Code, regulations with respect to violations of subsection (a) that shall include guidelines on what constitutes (for purposes of this Act)—</text> 
<paragraph id="H184867D3E8CB43E98BB4BA8F1AB26FCA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a market;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB7239296CD344313AAF1F6CE7928F40F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a grossly excessive price for an item; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE8B2D23C950F444891CEC9661C7911A0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an excessive price for an item.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H51A74534FDBE457B96AEAB9EBE119BA3" commented="no"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Definition of grossly excessive price</header> <paragraph id="HAC0F395B7B884F71BB800EA7053B142C" commented="no"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a) and the guidelines required by subsection (c), the Commission shall define the term <term>grossly excessive price</term> using any metric it deems appropriate.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H6C1AEA44F50C46DFBB639E613DE2B21D">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Definition considerations</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In formulating the definition described in paragraph (1), the Commission shall consider whether to provide that such term shall include a price for an item that is an amount equal to or greater than 120 percent (or a lesser percentage, as determined appropriate by the Commission) of the average price for such item in the market during the 6-month period preceding the sale or offer for sale that allegedly violates subsection (a).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection></section> 
<section id="H4397B96475824A97AD1F9DF36FB1F7BA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on surveillance-based price setting</header> 
<subsection id="H825DF0A739354DF4AD0A73E172221283"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>An operator of a retail food store may not engage in surveillance-based price setting, including by—</text> <paragraph id="H033E30A25D3B465A9BBC382856D88F7C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adjusting the price of any item for a consumer (directly or indirectly) based on the personal information of the consumer, including such personal information collected using facial recognition technology; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA824274012444B26BD8FD2B0DE887716"><enum>(2)</enum><text>using an electronic shelf label to change the price of an item for a consumer based on the personal information of such consumer.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1C6E5EFFB060457C9C6248F380E4EBAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>General exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An operator of a retail food store does not engage in surveillance-based price setting in violation of subsection (a) if the retail food store demonstrates to the Commission that each of the following conditions is met:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8FEFC060451A44E1A74E89A1D1E510FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A difference in the price of an item is based solely on reasonable costs associated with providing the item to different consumers.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HDFFAD8D9757A4A54BE6AADE02B9DC8A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A discounted price of an item is offered to members of a particular group that relates to occupation, age, military service, student status, or other factors approved by the Commission, based on publicly disclosed eligibility criteria.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H105C1BABA94640A48199197048307D80"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any discount or reward with respect to an item is offered uniformly to all consumers who meet the disclosed eligibility criteria.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H846E85356361408492C761DD000A3BB0"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any personal information is used solely to offer or administer the discount or reward and is not used for any other purpose, including targeted advertising and surveillance-based price setting.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H346FDC295CD84823948DAAC0667ECF85"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions for use of biometric data</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), an operator of a retail food store may use biometric data of a consumer if such consumer chooses to voluntarily verify the identity of such consumer by providing such biometric data, if such retail food store—</text> <paragraph id="H5A8D334D102548528F64E2650F2BE4A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">informs the consumer or the legally authorized representative of the consumer in writing that such biometric data is being collected, stored, or used by such retail food store;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1CA2BF77090545C9A25E0B52919BD7FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">informs the consumer or the legally authorized representative of the consumer in writing of the specific purpose and length of term for which such biometric data is being collected, stored, and used;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB7F0A0350DEF49BDB4827C51B7A3D7A8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">informs the consumer or the legally authorized representative of the consumer in writing of the specific circumstances under which biometric data is shared with law enforcement;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB2F1BB8FBBE649C39ABFC0353AF39233"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receives a written release executed by the consumer or the legally authorized representative of the consumer for the collection, storage, or use of such biometric data; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D94BB51EE2143FA96F3AFF6FC9A374F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>does not sell such biometric data to, or share such biometric data with, any third party.</text></paragraph> </subsection></section> 
<section id="H4D9E040D76FA4498A050E4A85309A740" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Required disclosure of use of facial recognition technology</header> 
<subsection id="H941F056162514B5AA8134F4F35530535"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A retail food store that uses facial recognition technology at such retail food store shall notify consumers of such retail food store (in plain and simple language) about such use and the intended purpose of such technology and use through clear and conspicuous signage placed at the main entrance to the retail food store.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0BFAA57838A24ADDBD05B6F7D965CD34"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>retail food store</term> does not include an online entity.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H8E3207CBC1DA4F72B79D31A91C86A984"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prohibition on electronic shelf labels</header> 
<subsection id="HDE120DF3679E4D9B82CA39F092A5E8AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>An operator of a retail food store larger than 10,000 square feet—</text> <paragraph id="H2A2F2D3179D5492997575976CF98D5F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may not use an electronic shelf label or any digital shelf display technology in such retail food store; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBE92F665DDE248EA9BA78481E5587813"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall use a non-digital presentation of the price of each item in such retail food store.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H003736E15E904DD5B9193E3E2E7F5B1C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit a retail food store from providing a consumer, based on the purchase history of such consumer, a discounted or promotional price in accordance with the conditions described in section 3(b).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAC224839D4384F7A89E7FA1C581E2E19"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>retail food store</term> does not include an online entity.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H2A0EEA06D8AC406E879D92BA70317DE8"><enum>6.</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <subsection id="H87B5CEE14EA94FABA9E63A4C961D0967"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header> <paragraph id="H29E73EFF7C444110B2D6266B88EC09C6" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation of section 2(a), 3(a), 4(a), or 5(a) (or a regulation promulgated under such section) shall be treated as a violation of a regulation under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices and as a violation of section 5(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45(a)</external-xref>) regarding unfair methods of competition.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA84A644E9E05438E8AB30D5DFB22A43B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><text>The Commission shall enforce section 2(a), 3(a), 4(a), and 5(a) (and any regulations promulgated under such sections) in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act. Any retail food store that violates such sections (or any regulations promulgated under such sections) shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H67D637F2804341CEA11FE71555F2AEF7" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Commission may promulgate, pursuant to 553 of title 5, United States Code, any regulations the Commission determines necessary to carry out the provisions of this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBDB584ECA0EB45A2819C274A27FF3AB1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Actions by States</header> 
<paragraph id="H4F33CC0326064BBBB1B5E4013B0AAA53"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which the attorney general of a State, or an official or agency of a State, has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of such State has been or is threatened or adversely affected by an act or practice in violation of section 2(a), 3(a), 4(a), or 5(a) (or a regulation promulgated under such section), the State, as parens patriae, may bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate State court or an appropriate district court of the United States to—</text> <subparagraph id="HD6E387868C514B13B6C3C14E846802F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enjoin such act or practice;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD1A642805FCF4D40917A56B1B549E991"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enforce compliance with such section (or such regulation);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H190E1B31BDDB4AD59D8F38863D1D73B9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">obtain, for each such violation, the greater of—</text> 
<clause id="H8D259E86BB8747BEB0A8D6036333F291"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the actual monetary damages incurred from the violation; or</text></clause> <clause id="H961C3B269A154C508883DE276803ABB5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$3,000; or</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3BE80543F0FF4D40B83AF7B92115B9B9"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">obtain any restitution, penalties, and other legal or equitable relief as the court may deem just and proper.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E337FA5386F46D4B310305BC1516BEF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prevent an attorney general, official, or agency of a State from exercising the powers conferred on the attorney general, official, or agency by the laws of the State to conduct investigations, to administer oaths or affirmations, or to compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary or other evidence.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H120DDCD5F2A64A378456B0A4845CBD38"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Private right of action</header> 
<paragraph id="H9EB232AC68B84B52BCAF8258C62DB4ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A consumer injured by an act or practice in violation of section 2(a), 3(a), 4(a), or 5(a) (or a regulation promulgated under such section) may bring in an appropriate district court of the United States—</text> <subparagraph id="HD0E2B5F1A9E64BBF8F3217B5B43695A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an action to enjoin the violation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6CB64DD81AA3486BBD237F133A78E2BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an action to obtain, for each such violation, the greater of—</text> <clause id="HB73CE34514FA4ECDBABE41793BC17436"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the actual monetary damages incurred from the violation; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF34FE139590044259CF419A9C620805F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$3,000; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC5F9EC278D4A49CA838DE334CBBE60CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an action to obtain any restitution, penalties, and other legal or equitable relief as the court may deem just and proper.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H10AFF1FE38C54FE280F087A9914261AE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Willful or knowing violations</header><text>If the court finds that the defendant acted willfully or knowingly in committing a violation described in paragraph (1), the court shall increase the amount of the award to an amount that is 3 times the amount available under paragraph (1)(B).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8F5F476CF52A4911BC16B98D63FECB57"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Costs and attorney’s fees</header><text>The court shall award to a prevailing plaintiff in an action under this subsection the costs of such action and reasonable attorney’s fees, as determined by the court.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H298BE61D0721437289B7A29462ABE861"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>An action may be commenced under this subsection not later than 5 years after the date on which a consumer first discovered or had a reasonable opportunity to discover the violation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDAFCFD1EE42451682FF8723E8920A8A" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Nonexclusive remedy</header><text>The remedy provided by this subsection shall be in addition to any other remedies available to the consumer.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58AA9A95DEAD4F5F890ADB7332EC7369"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Invalidity of pre-dispute arbitration and joint action waivers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a pre-dispute arbitration agreement or pre-dispute joint action waiver between a retail food store and a consumer shall not be valid or enforceable for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HE3250BABB73146CF9DB40D4F654AE3D6"><enum>7.</enum><header>Preemption of directly conflicting State laws</header> <subsection id="H54FA8AEAFD754B3BA5986BEBD026701C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to preempt, displace, or supplant any State law, except to the extent that a provision of State law conflicts with a provision of this Act, and then only to the extent of the conflict.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H464906C14B214896B5321AB7B492A39B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Greater protection under State law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, a provision of State law does not conflict with a provision of this Act if such provision of State law provides additional protections to consumers protected under this Act with respect to price gouging, surveillance-based price setting, collecting personal information, or using facial recognition technology in retail food stores.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HBE7AD207763248AEB22F6FCFAA19EDFB"><enum>8.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated for the fiscal year 2025 $5,000,000 (to remain available until September 30, 2032) to carry out this Act.</text></section> 
<section id="H019EC367731D49A7959E964A51E92892"><enum>9.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H85D8767FBB874B4DBC0C035C49AA7072"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Biometric data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>biometric data</term> means data generated by automatic measurements, including data gathered through the use of facial recognition technology, or other representations of the biological characteristics of a consumer, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCEF2D1B6C22E4DBAB4E45EDC2D26F4BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>fingerprints;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H293B3C7DAA4C4290B775245552181C3C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>voice prints;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H34910102A75E4733AD5F73FC8B7C0DD9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>iris or retina scans;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9EFE01C190A34ECF8181DC480C1BE8FB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>gait; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H44CF6C5596E64CEFAF7D311DDDB4D684"><enum>(E)</enum><text>other unique biological patterns.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H405E84643F1A46F3BF547A69330BCED9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB19286A22C3F49819F975A248513B094"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Electronic shelf label</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>electronic shelf label</term> means electronic and wireless paper (E-paper) displays or digital price tags that present product and pricing information.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H66D4F2DD4AE34506BDB7308E3C498540"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Electronic surveillance technology</header><text>The term <term>electronic surveillance technology</term> means a technological method, system, or other tool of surveillance used to observe, monitor, or collect information related to an consumer, including sensors, cameras, device tracking, biometric monitoring, facial recognition technology, or other forms of observation or data collection that are capable of gathering personal information about a consumer.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCFFFDF29795342ECB9555E0E16083EB2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Facial recognition technology</header><text>The term <term>facial recognition technology</term> means technology that facilitates or otherwise enables an automated or semi-automated process that—</text> <subparagraph id="H986C02F266BA45AC83CB48855BD94AEB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assists in identifying a consumer based on the physical characteristics of the face of such consumer; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H017686C96F3F4931B7A1A12375934624"><enum>(B)</enum><text>logs characteristics of the face, head, or body of a consumer to infer the emotion, associations, activities, or location of such consumer.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8253C9D0649742288BB3295EE2A73F85"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Item</header><text>The term <term>item</term> means a specific and distinct product, good, or commodity available for sale.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F93DFCFE3C042789F1A4C7609E6DCA3"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Non-digital presentation of price</header><text>The term <term>non-digital presentation of price</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HDAE6249549644A16958D438552F480C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a sign that offers the unit price for 1 or more brands or sizes of a given item;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA1E94A2F2DB64B128BE66A1A8766FCEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a sticker, stamp, sign, label, or tag affixed to the shelf upon which the item is displayed; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF33CBFEDE8C3448AAC8AC4798BC8F03A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a sticker, stamp, sign, label, or tag affixed to the item.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3B2B6E6A4F1E40E0884DD010CE904DB0"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Personal information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>personal information</term> means any quality, feature, attribute, or trait of a consumer that is reasonably capable of being associated with, or could be reasonably linked to, directly or indirectly, a particular consumer or a household of a particular consumer, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H5E137A57C8234C66884F088309E01DA6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any immutable characteristic, including race and eye color;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2C9F465F04184F05BEC9527BEC122609"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any mutable characteristic, including address, weight, citizenship, and family or parental status;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H143645E711354E119E1D48C443F9ECF8"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>identifiers, including a real name, alias, postal address, unique personal identifier, online identifier, Internet Protocol address, email address, account name, social security number, driver’s license number, passport number, and other similar identifier;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1446A5F788204D57ADA912B4BB157F1E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>commercial information, including records of personal property, products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, and other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB3185027A1724934BF5B1B1AFFAF9888"><enum>(E)</enum><text>biometric data;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF031C960C3D549B1A0D52B2EE4F63554"><enum>(F)</enum><text>internet or other electronic network activity information, including browsing history, search history, and other information regarding interaction by such consumer with a website, application, or advertisement;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC91632C5DD1745F3BD055BBF2F1AD6D4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>geolocation data;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9FC2A3D973F14552888CC884C55930D8"><enum>(H)</enum><text>audio, electronic, visual, thermal, olfactory, and other similar information;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2E3A494A72ED4A11B80FEFD2D4E8E424"><enum>(I)</enum><text>professional or employment-related information;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEA4576D049C54C4C96AC3D5B7CE6743F"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">educational information, including educational experience, qualifications, and affiliations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE5D3BAC5514A47BDA3A234DAEA90AB16"><enum>(K)</enum><text>inferences drawn from any of the information described in this paragraph and used to create a profile about such consumer reflecting the preferences, characteristics, psychological trends, predispositions, behavior, attitudes, intelligence, abilities, and aptitudes of such consumer;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H724AE6ED8D204D8BB625A6E79F8C2C9C"><enum>(L)</enum><text>interests, including the political, personal, and professional affiliation of such consumer;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H73F0C6CD02C54B2CAD73142FC9785076"><enum>(M)</enum><text>financial circumstances, including personal or household wealth, income, property, debt, and credit history; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5D19EB6699D94E6D8BBBFA3F271A223E" commented="no"><enum>(N)</enum><text>actions, habits, behaviors, and attributes of such consumer, whether in a physical or digital environment.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F6D9A3A593140C9AFEA84330EF71746"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Pre-dispute arbitration agreement</header><text>The term <term>pre-dispute arbitration agreement</term> means any agreement to arbitrate a dispute that has not yet arisen at the time of the making of the agreement.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1127002ADC284274B1A8297D3586FB0E"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Pre-dispute joint action waiver</header><text>The term <term>pre-dispute joint action waiver</term> means an agreement, including as part of a pre-dispute arbitration agreement, that would prohibit, or waive the right of, a party to the agreement from participating in a joint, class, or collective action in a judicial, arbitral, administrative, or other forum, concerning a dispute that has not yet arisen at the time of the making of the agreement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H56910FC9241D49D6AE9A80828FEB064C"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Price</header><text>The term <term>price</term> means the amount charged to a consumer in relation to a transaction, including any related cost, fee, and other material term of the transaction that has a direct bearing on the amount paid by the consumer for the item sold or offered for sale to the consumer.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3AC76A9D7A5B4689867B8B39054D310D"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Retail food store</header><text>The term <term>retail food store</term> has the same meaning given the term in section 3 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2012">7 U.S.C. 2012</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DF9AF07D827497D9CED0BC03C967501"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Surveillance-based price setting</header><text>The term <term>surveillance-based price setting</term> means offering, setting, or informing a customized price for an item for a specific consumer or group of consumers, based, in whole or in part, on personal information collected through electronic surveillance technology, including such information gathered, purchased, or otherwise acquired.</text></paragraph> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

