<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELL25384-VS9-4D-M83">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1897 IS: To amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to establish the Adverse Childhood Experiences Response Team grant program, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 1897</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250522">May 22, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which
                was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee
                    on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to establish
            the Adverse Childhood Experiences Response Team grant program, and for other
            purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H28AD94211ABB411898E26F6381B38783">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="HF2B9D1FD49634E639BCDDC3C6D04F982">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Adverse childhood experiences response team grant program</header>
            <subsection id="id509710DECE924AA69839025807463208">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10101">34 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
                <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83AFD605FC3F4E5E9385211E251F5F64">
                    <part id="HA01AF38C258D4400BBABB3D0931DD88E" style="OLC">
                        <enum>PP</enum>
                        <header>Adverse childhood experiences response team grant program</header>
                        <section id="H0929EB93C5264D23B3F7CB54A288FAF3">
                            <enum>3061.</enum>
                            <header>Grants for adverse childhood experiences response teams</header>
                            <subsection id="H6131D063F066422F870532CA589931A9">
                                <enum>(a)</enum>
                                <header>Grants authorized</header>
 <text>From amounts made available to carry out this section, the Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall make grants to States, units of local government, Indian Tribes, and neighborhood or community-based organizations to address adverse childhood experiences associated with exposure to trauma.</text>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="H98F1787FB10E4FA4B1E53978142E3B37">
                                <enum>(b)</enum>
                                <header>Use of funds</header>
 <text>Amounts received under a grant under this section may be used to establish an adverse childhood experiences response team, including by—</text>
                                <paragraph id="HEE57CB5A100B428492B70FA0C0F6DAC6">
                                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>establishing protocols to follow when encountering a child or youth exposed to trauma to facilitate access to services;</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="HE19FC1D297514FCAAF47BF56E8A743EC">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>developing referral partnership agreements with behavioral health providers, substance treatment facilities, and recovery services for family members of children exposed to trauma;</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="HB44577A3676B4EE0A995E35C9E87D896">
                                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>integrating law enforcement, mental health, and crisis services to respond to situations where children have been exposed to trauma;</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="HBB13E8C40CC0488981F004B023F5F95F">
                                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implementing comprehensive programs and practices to support children exposed to trauma;</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="H2517CBCC038F4AB48702B1E464AED058">
                                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>identifying barriers for children to access trauma-informed care in their communities;</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="H9B37AD5EED4E47F1B03404684A8048BD">
                                    <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>providing training in trauma-informed care to emergency response providers, victim service providers, child protective service professionals, educational institutions, and other community partners; </text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="H1FDD262BF8A0482BB4C41C76583D12DA">
                                    <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>supporting cross-system planning and collaboration among officers and employees who work in law enforcement, court systems, child welfare services, correctional reentry programs, emergency medical services, health care services, public health, and substance abuse treatment and recovery support; and</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="id315301A38C644BDE9BEE5938E378ABD3">
                                    <enum>(8)</enum>
 <text>providing technical assistance to communities, organizations, and public agencies on how to prevent and mitigate the impact of exposure to trauma and violence. </text>
                                </paragraph>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="H683B2C623F514894BAF85EBA5B744D89">
                                <enum>(c)</enum>
                                <header>Application</header>
 <text>A State, unit of local government, Indian Tribe, or neighborhood or community-based organization desiring a grant under this section shall submit to the Attorney General an application in such form, and containing such information, as the Attorney General may reasonably require.</text>
                            </subsection>
                        </section>
                    </part>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id0EF8260C20574CEB9C5310EE64722A63">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text>Section 1001(a) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10261">34 U.S.C. 10261(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
                <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB5ADB98343A7460BA3A824C0B2D3EB31">
                    <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8FB4184518DE4552B29FF974B5A0957A" indent="up1">
                        <enum>(29)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out part PP $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

