<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDFC5ABDCE8B54FF38B8CC5066A388A7B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4775 IH: SBIR/STTR Foreign Interference Safeguard Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4775</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250725">July 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure small business concerns indirectly owned or controlled by certain foreign entities are ineligible to receive SBIR or STTR awards, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA954720674514DCABCC99B91F747E8CF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9C1F1049FB3B4AF283AAFE17E69B789E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>SBIR/STTR Foreign Interference Safeguard Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5C20C2D9031641E5A865067A82FA0003"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extension of due diligence program to assess security risks</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 9(vv)(3)(C) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638(vv)(3)(C)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2025</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2030</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H9F3AFFFEBC054E3F82BEF53E7BEA3AC2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Codifying safeguards for small business concerns majority-owned by venture capital operating companies, hedge funds, or private equity firms</header> 
<subsection id="HA24B46B53D154027B24416E06E003437"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 9(dd) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638(dd)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H9F270625B9164DDD98F589C213B2FDB6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (6)(B), by striking <quote>If a Federal</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in paragraph (8), if a Federal</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8BBDC790734149BE9364D7347E6ECB76"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H580C941D6F3D437EA72D2FDA0812A14D" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H64083A16D4DB4B3EB933483A99637EFA"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Participation limits</header> <subparagraph id="H02CB8E22EB4E4BC4A548536567DE0705"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A small business concern that is majority-owned by multiple venture capital operating companies, hedge funds, or private equity firms is ineligible to receive an award under any SBIR program if the Administrator determines that such small business concern is, or is owned and controlled in majority part by, a covered foreign entity.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFFA40280B4D240368E7F96A8F6990A2E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ownership determination</header><text>In determining whether a small business concern is ineligible to receive an award under any SBIR program under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall consider whether the small business concern is a direct or indirect subsidiary of a foreign-owned firm.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H49D19472D090460FBC8238D14E84B806"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Size standards</header><text>The Administrator shall establish size standards for small business concerns seeking to participate in an SBIR program solely under the authority under this section.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H64C4FD45B431451A9027BAEB49B0619F"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text> <clause id="H9E7B097943404DF98CCD158917C3B041"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Covered foreign entity</header><text>the term <term>covered foreign entity</term>—</text> 
<subclause id="HA429B4799AAD4DD4A5E1D64FBA2093C2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>means—</text> <item id="HFC03B39125F34BBBB22D0F3FA9B12182"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a foreign entity of concern;</text></item> 
<item id="H12236668FD8046A9971E5326E131938A"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a government or political party of a foreign country of concern;</text></item> <item id="H6AC5A1811F354F3099D9E6A0140C6420"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>a natural person who is not a lawful permanent resident of the United States, citizen of the United States, or any other protected individual (as such term is defined in section 274B(a)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324b">8 U.S.C. 1324b(a)(3)</external-xref>)); or</text></item> 
<item id="H1D126954536741D9B838F1240462A223"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>a partnership, association, corporation, organization, or other combination of persons organized under the laws of or having its principal place of business in a foreign country of concern; and</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H31CCD99B18B841E3A40F875304A55B00"><enum>(II)</enum><text>includes—</text> 
<item id="H1C0F6B44753A4AFA8BC59329FB447781"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>any entity owned by, controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of a an entity listed in subclause (I);</text></item> <item id="H0ECAF58E99994791AD751C29A9159916"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any person, wherever located, who acts as an agent, representative, or employee of an entity listed in subclause (I);</text></item> 
<item id="HD5746512B362423D9283CE6C151946E0"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any person who acts in any other capacity at the order, request, or under the direction or control, of an entity listed in subclause (I), or of a person whose activities are directly or indirectly supervised, directed, controlled, financed, or subsidized in whole or in majority part by an entity listed in subclause (I);</text></item> <item id="H77FC5A53D4854CF4A8F90D1FC864AAFF"><enum>(dd)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any person who directly or indirectly through any contract, arrangement, understanding, relationship, or otherwise, owns 25 percent or more of the equity interests of an entity listed in subclause (I);</text></item> 
<item id="H43E6FD1205304F21A19184E10600303A"><enum>(ee)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any person with significant responsibility to control, manage, or direct an entity listed in subclause (I);</text></item> <item id="HEEDDC56F1CDE4DA987FB973D374C765D"><enum>(ff)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any person, wherever located, who is a citizen or resident of a country controlled by an entity listed in subclause (I); or</text></item> 
<item id="H0EAAA4FD3B064F0ABF42FDB274D66D44"><enum>(gg)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any corporation, partnership, association, or other organization organized under the laws of a country controlled by an entity listed in subclause (I).</text></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="H920F36754C844C2AA322E1472A3D697B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Foreign entity of concern</header><text>The term <term>foreign entity of concern</term> means a foreign entity that is—</text> 
<subclause id="H27E9F1D3A1F94E1DB2C2F30FD287644C"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designated as a foreign terrorist organization by the Secretary of State under section 219(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189(a)</external-xref>);</text></subclause> <subclause id="H9886353B87E14969A586D462E715DB9E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>included on the list of specially designated nationals and blocked persons maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury (commonly known as the SDN list);</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H7E6EF30F14454A5CB55EC33E1A66BC32"><enum>(III)</enum><text>owned by, controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of a government of a foreign country that is a covered nation (as such term is defined in section 4872 of title 10, United States Code);</text></subclause> <subclause id="HBA7344D7E01C4CC19B35899E58EA9427"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>alleged by the Attorney General to have been involved in activities for which a conviction was obtained under—</text> 
<item id="H3AC7A344EE0E4A2BB011B146A5FD49E5"><enum>(aa)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/37">chapter 37</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code (commonly known as the Espionage Act);</text></item> <item id="H69CB68AAAD6147C8932B41A3270B87FC"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>section 951 or 1030 of such title;</text></item> 
<item id="HE8E5FBB3373C4F46B0FBA41D103A06DD"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>chapter 90 of such title (commonly known as the Economic Espionage Act of 1996);</text></item> <item id="H4502491FCEC14FBBBC19D5434DCD5204"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2751">22 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></item> 
<item id="HBFF279E200E04EF589F9C23C68A0CE6C"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>section 224, 225, 226, 227, or 236 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2274">42 U.S.C. 2274</external-xref>, 2275, 2276, 2277, and 2284);</text></item> <item id="HD2FAD3EF63664C22A6185C59F675675E"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></item> 
<item id="HDFF6810673074E7884A92E49F15F7E94"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="HE7A1F8409F854E598F7BA5B417F222AB"><enum>(V)</enum><text>determined by the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the Director of National Intelligence, to be engaged in unauthorized conduct that is detrimental to the national security or foreign policy of the United States.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2206C632E21B4335AE3C2CFCE6F00DF1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply only with respect to awards made under an Small Business Innovation Research Program (as defined in section 9(e) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638(e)</external-xref>)) after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

