<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H7D2C97C3F282435384FBA31A04190E41" resolution-type="house-resolution"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 581 IH: Epstein Files Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 581</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250715">July 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 185) to advance responsible policies.</official-title></form><resolution-body id="H65B540E9362F4D2289024962B98DEC08" style="traditional"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H342FCE3460C947FD9F080824AF537018" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum/><text> That immediately upon adoption of this resolution, the House shall proceed to the consideration in the House of the bill (H.R. 185) to advance responsible policies. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The amendment in the nature of a substitute specified in section 4 of this resolution shall be considered as adopted. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended, are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill, as amended, and on any further amendment thereto, to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on the Judiciary or their respective designees; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text></section><section id="HEE8642FEB6E34CC4880DED2522949855"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clause 1(c) of rule XIX and clause 8 of rule XX shall not apply to the consideration of H.R. 185.</text></section><section id="H244EEB4165EE4DC8B5D20835D3FDBB73"><enum>3.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Clerk shall transmit to the Senate a message that the House has passed H.R. 185 no later than one week after passage.</text></section><section id="H9740E1F78AA242268CE89200FBCD379E"><enum>4.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment in the nature of a substitute referred to in the first section of this resolution is as follows:</text><paragraph id="ide871fc96f0dd420ab910e1fcd9f0c19a"><enum/><text>Strike all after the enacting clause and insert the following:</text><quoted-block id="H2BD7FBAA169942BEB012957D94AD5ACF" style="OLC"><section id="H507BA3E268B64C0AA0A1D36A15CA31C2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Epstein Files Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7F4617BF65344FE88FA519AF94C94843"><enum>2.</enum><header>Release of documents relating to Jeffrey Epstein</header><subsection id="HB0C52085D06C40E99D50AFF4326E42EF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall, subject to subsection (b), make publicly available in a searchable and downloadable format all unclassified records, documents, communications, and investigative materials in the possession of the Department of Justice, including the Federal Bureau of Investigation and United States Attorneys’ Offices, that relate to:</text><paragraph id="H35FC15D9F7044568B993C0BDF6B93890"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Jeffrey Epstein including all investigations, prosecutions, or custodial matters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFE2C18B147C409B9F6DABDDCF8B901E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Ghislaine Maxwell.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12B5E5F4F4F8494685F748F0C9B8FE95"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Flight logs or travel records, including but not limited to manifests, itineraries, pilot records, and customs or immigration documentation, for any aircraft, vessel, or vehicle owned, operated, or used by Jeffrey Epstein or any related entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8333A2BB2F6B4927A8D24139AFB4A8A0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Individuals, including government officials, named or referenced in connection with Epstein’s criminal activities, civil settlements, immunity or plea agreements, or investigatory proceedings.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CB792472E43478DBD286DCFBD9C5A5F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Entities (corporate, nonprofit, academic, or governmental) with known or alleged ties to Epstein’s trafficking or financial networks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H54B350B54F77451D9B62681CD6389090"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any immunity deals, non-prosecution agreements, plea bargains, or sealed settlements involving Epstein or his associates.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF07D10FD2C54419FB4E995CCEB122EA8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Internal DOJ communications, including emails, memos, meeting notes, concerning decisions to charge, not charge, investigate, or decline to investigate Epstein or his associates.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H806FFCC3E3524435923737268887286F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>All communications, memoranda, directives, logs, or metadata concerning the destruction, deletion, alteration, misplacement, or concealment of documents, recordings, or electronic data related to Epstein, his associates, his detention and death, or any investigative files.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H881B4097C2D548859E0F6D0B91D9164A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Documentation of Epstein’s detention or death, including incident reports, witness interviews, medical examiner files, autopsy reports, and written records detailing the circumstances and cause of death.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF4AFD7C496C045F484783C8207999519"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibited grounds for withholding</header><text>No record shall be withheld, delayed, or redacted on the basis of any of the following:</text><paragraph id="H872084F66FAF494EBE79D9B4F5A470AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Embarrassment, reputational harm, or political sensitivity, including to any government official, public figure, or foreign dignitary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8042D5CCEDAA47E1A4B54E73AB1A3367"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Permitted withholdings</header><paragraph id="H1A27F403159F48EFA92CB06A134D709D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Attorney General may withhold or redact the segregable portions of records that—</text><subparagraph id="HD3255CD6118D49B7B33520CAD765FF1F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>contain personally identifiable information of victims or victims’ personal and medical files and similar files the disclosure of which would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H836849B95AB14924BBEE988CD7C46F2B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>depicts or contains child sexual abuse materials (CSAM) as defined under 18 U.S.C. 2256 and prohibited under 18 U.S.C. 2252–2252A;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCDA12AD45AD47C99E9DBB649C887439"><enum>(C)</enum><text>would jeopardize an active federal investigation or ongoing prosecution, provided that such withholding is narrowly tailored and temporary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BEE536A665549EE82DD655664E52F21"><enum>(D)</enum><text>depicts or contains images of death, physical abuse, or injury of any person; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE568D5B5F674D47A67CF384225085E2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>contain information specifically authorized under criteria established by an Executive order to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or foreign policy and are in fact properly classified pursuant to such Executive order.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B100247816B42F4A28DDC50487C0A12"><enum>(2)</enum><text>All redactions must be accompanied by a written justification published in the Federal Register and submitted to Congress.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCF1C5B68A984CD283D1ADE40BDD1A8D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To the extent that any covered information would otherwise be redacted or withheld as classified information under this section, the Attorney General shall declassify that classified information to the maximum extent possible.</text><subparagraph id="HF9BEADDB03EF4C27AD2989168BE59963"><enum>(A).</enum><text>If the Attorney General makes a determination that covered information may not be declassified and made available in a manner that protects the national security of the United States, including methods or sources related to national security, the Attorney General shall release an unclassified summary for each of the redacted or withheld classified information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC0AFA952E0245929ADBA19C5BE109FB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>All decisions to classify any covered information after July 1, 2025 shall be published in the Federal Register and submitted to Congress, including the date of classification, the identity of the classifying authority, and an unclassified summary of the justification.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HECB0897CF49845588A15BED4275C7FD4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Within 15 days of completion of the release required under Section 2, the Attorney General shall submit to the House and Senate Committees on the Judiciary a report listing:</text><paragraph id="H00D9CA7EDB3B4DBC88CFA3C0AE3BBC25"><enum>(1)</enum><text>All categories of records released and withheld.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H281F9363696D4E92A78C698942CAF3A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A summary of redactions made, including legal basis.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H420FFD48F0914322903D6236790FC895"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A list of all government officials and politically exposed persons named or referenced in the released materials, with no redactions permitted under subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

