<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H788F3FB0B2A14B1BB1B35040D601C681" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2121 IH: Commission to Study the Creation of a National Museum of Irish American History</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2121</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000590">Ms. Lee of Nevada</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Commission to study the potential creation of a National Museum of Irish American History, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDE85886311FA4410ABB8066A3D047CDA" style="OLC"><section id="HFF5EAA3C1B89419EBAE96CD755DF92EA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Commission to Study the Creation of a National Museum of Irish American History</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0D7877CE8D5F41AFA51B62F785276C60"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HCC53CCC8F0714E74922AA1EE34469A73"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Commission to study the potential creation of a National Museum of Irish American History established by section 3(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E371ED4E04E45A592ED936D7C017816"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Museum</header><text>The term <term>Museum</term> means the National Museum of Irish American History.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H783E1A06D24A407E90852322B8066F83"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of commission</header><subsection id="H092869807656464CAE6C5E0B47112F76"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of commission</header><paragraph id="H19F39703B8CD42BE87692A1ECBFB2CF0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established the Commission to study the potential creation of an Irish American Museum.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53F291EE018B41F9924F99CA8E9C455A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Commission shall consist of 23 members appointed not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act as follows:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H78397DBA9A1847AEB424158F7F11D355"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The President shall appoint 7 voting members.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H098CD7F3D4C147A79196307830D2A70A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, the Majority Leader of the Senate, and the Minority Leader of the Senate shall each appoint—</text><clause id="H7935DB3B4C9F4C4F82A7FA7E9B4E6B80"><enum>(i)</enum><text>3 voting members; and</text></clause><clause id="H163D630A79F94135BB79ED09EA374E1A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>1 nonvoting member.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC61182FF965243488860B9C4AB26DA94"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>Members of the Commission shall be chosen from individuals, or representatives of institutions or entities, who possess either—</text><subparagraph id="H5D772AEE304344E297D7CC2A0FA3A2CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a demonstrated commitment to the research, study, or promotion of Irish-American life, art, history, political or economic status, or culture, together with—</text><clause id="H32B7C4A51DA74520ABBDA98F97FA049A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>expertise in museum administration;</text></clause><clause id="H78C0741CB5934ED9A7B5897126748012"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>expertise in fundraising for nonprofit or cultural institutions;</text></clause><clause id="H6EF3B2A1673D4E24A201BC57819CEC0C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>experience in the study and teaching of Irish-American culture and history at the post-secondary level;</text></clause><clause id="HE4EE6855435A401F95F8F9BAA0A66C6E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>experience in studying the issue of the Smithsonian Institution’s representation of Irish-American art, life, history, and culture; or</text></clause><clause id="H6C02C8DD665F47958C422AEDE0D63BDB"><enum>(v)</enum><text>extensive experience in public or elected service; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF888B60898B44B188E2A83ACBB983AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>experience in the administration of, or the planning for the establishment of, museums devoted to the study and promotion of the role of ethnic, racial, or cultural groups in American history.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A343D9C339444E9A0BA245D9C784343"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>A vacancy in the Commission—</text><subparagraph id="H78EDF5111C4744A0BBE1DD061DED877F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall not affect the powers of the Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9C96C4FAE1E43A9BBEE84A6AD3CA8AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment was made.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0297E3E783A4442597FB7E417A1AC0E0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Commission shall, by majority vote of all of the members, select 1 member of the Commission to serve as the Chairperson of the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6375F87BB5804E23A61F6914C66103B3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duties of the commission</header><subsection id="H65BA5D0C50AE46D78D2CB4166E799C6D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H66B00F4229AA4BE990D9FF2664386067"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Plan of action for the establishment and maintenance of museum</header><text>The Commission shall submit a report to the President and the Congress containing its recommendations with respect to a plan of action for the establishment and maintenance of an Irish-American Museum in Washington, DC.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC058FB1B4BFF45A59EB2A85C6474E0D2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report on issues</header><text>The Commission shall examine, in consultation with the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution, and submit a report to the President and the Congress on the following issues:</text><subparagraph id="HD6B15EF046B04D2B94D5D03A173DC829"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The availability and cost of collections to be acquired and housed in the Museum.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC38EB5F8CB0D4DEC94A6A2E33FC9F036"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The impact of the Museum on regional Irish-American-related museums.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA3CEC992BC84F23B370CC88463A08BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Possible locations for the Museum in Washington, DC and its environs, to be considered in consultation with the National Capital Planning Commission and the Commission of Fine Arts, the Department of the Interior, and Smithsonian Institution.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H236CDE5E76F54507B499440C477DDD38"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Whether the Museum should be located within the Smithsonian Institution.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71ACDD51D18B47ACB82301D8FB3D7F06"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The governance and organizational structure from which the Museum should operate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49B49F5E15254FE5AFD02FC48526ED4B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>How to engage the Irish-American community in the development and design of the Museum.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BE0354C85104DCD9074ADEB79613112"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The cost of constructing, operating, and maintaining the Museum.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B346E61377E458C9BCAE19D747C820B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fundraising plan</header><paragraph id="H6B33A727B7DA4EF7BA3D47C27F912B86"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall develop a fundraising plan to support the establishment, operation, and maintenance of the Museum through contributions from the public.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1815C127E23B4DCBB057194A91FBC8BF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In developing the fundraising plan under paragraph (1), the Commission shall consider issues relating to funding the operations and maintenance of the Museum in perpetuity without reliance on appropriations of Federal funds.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F3EEC1209E6439BB258B5A9F2C074CA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Independent review</header><text>The Commission shall obtain an independent review of the viability of the plan developed under subsection (b)(1) and such review shall include an analysis as to whether the plan is likely to achieve the level of resources necessary to fund the construction of the Museum and the operations and maintenance of the Museum in perpetuity without reliance on appropriations of Federal funds.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBFC90D9B529F4D30822816BAE7371653"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>The Commission shall submit the plan developed under subsection (b)(1) and the review conducted under paragraph (3) to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, House Administration, Natural Resources, and Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Rules and Administration, Energy and Natural Resources, and Appropriations of the Senate.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDBA3836305B241FEA55CF84D88927D62"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Recommendations for legislation To carry out plan of action</header><text>Based on the recommendations contained in the report submitted under subsection (a), the Commission shall submit for consideration recommendations for a legislative plan of action to create and construct the Museum to—</text><paragraph id="H9DE2513F296F465590F20E799A965382"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7405DC98A88E45F69F2D34BDC137CCDB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF4D0064B0C245ADB6DBE4CB75732A97"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE978BE72F964C548C0A0F5C009A9830"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DFC9FE2EF42473E995C94A03962779B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2135C70992A42958D8C9A43522FA8DC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3057688528DB4E2D817CC21D7BBAEA56"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Deadline for submission of reports</header><text>The Commission shall submit final versions of the reports and plans required—</text><paragraph id="H6F166442794F4FF7B583C3C3CBF664E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>under subsection (a) and (b) not later than 24 months after the date of the Commission’s first meeting; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC049E5C9EC324279B35537A5683D610C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>under subsection (e) not later than 12 months after the date that the reports and plans referred to in paragraph (1) are submitted.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE49A5C523B314945932361A0EFCCA35C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>National conference</header><text>In carrying out its functions under this section, not later than 18 months after the commission members are selected, the Commission may host a national conference on the Museum, comprised of individuals committed to the advancement of Irish-American life, art, history, and culture.</text></subsection></section><section id="H9F066A5AAB8E4873A88920AAF7B14662"><enum>5.</enum><header>Director and staff of commission</header><subsection id="H02F41A9D16F949BB8D7DAE7AE965F10C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Director and staff</header><paragraph id="H46AF1E39D37B4882B4E5C5D427FBE2A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission may employ and compensate an executive director and any other additional personnel that are necessary to enable the Commission to perform the duties of the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0245191590B41DE8F66790928CF9173"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rates of pay</header><text>Rates of pay for persons employed under paragraph (1) shall be consistent with the rates of pay allowed for employees of a temporary organization under section 3161 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H684084D9B28243BFA54E2497F718229A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Not federal employment</header><text>Any individual employed under this Act shall not be considered a Federal employee for the purpose of any law governing Federal employment.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC12F8F2499314AD5A055F95744DB8BE9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><paragraph id="HBBBB1A1F77EA4EC5BBF87F4D0EECAEF0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), on request of the Commission the head of a Federal agency may provide technical assistance to the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC00FC508C08D41408CDF4E9FC4865AFA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Detailees</header><text>No Federal employees may be detailed to the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA72EDBE95FFF439598B80F7C08CC5693"><enum>6.</enum><header>Administrative provisions</header><subsection id="H1D3028D3FEEF40A89BFF2FF319AA64EF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Compensation</header><paragraph id="HF7E079DA88624BEBB86828BA9D14CFED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A member of the Commission—</text><subparagraph id="H101C4839DEE549E0868D03918FE39F97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall not be considered to be a Federal employee for any purpose by reason of service on the Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC9954FDA8854A29A0BF53969A2BB80A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall serve without pay.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H66D4E9F7897C41A1A839226DAD5A9E4F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>A member of the Commission shall be allowed a per diem allowance for travel expenses, at rates consistent with those authorized under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC681F04CF59431085E034E2671BA1FF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Gifts, bequests, devises</header><text>The Commission may solicit, accept, use, and dispose of gifts, bequests, or devises of money, services, or real or personal property for the purpose of aiding or facilitating the work of the Commission.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFEFA5956EB894C378E3D1562AC3ED92E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal advisory committee act</header><text>The Commission is not subject to the provisions of the Federal Advisory Committee Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE445E1CD31E94E1286F1E1DF648C621B"><enum>7.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission shall terminate on the date that is 30 days after the date on which the final versions of the reports and plans required under section 4 are submitted.</text></section><section id="H741E665662E7490882ACE07D22276B60"><enum>8.</enum><header>Authorization for appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated for carrying out the activities of the Commission—</text><paragraph id="H5BEA8C7236D04FB1A79E4BD03696000A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$2,100,000 for the first fiscal year beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H08A6CEED681243788BF503932D120F8E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$1,100,000 for the second fiscal year beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

