<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3568281C8B6F4A169A0932A6520D00EE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2418 IH: Federal Reserve Regulatory Oversight Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2418</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000626">Mr. Davidson</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Reserve Act to bring the non-monetary policy related functions of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System into the appropriations process, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H229B1A957C2C462CAF08BD3A76758A14" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H96487CF163C54C469A20BD53698263AC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Reserve Regulatory Oversight Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAA15B85CB27A4674B7CF72B42A514CAE" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Bringing the non-monetary policy related functions of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System into the appropriations process</header> <subsection id="HD97682EF84B245DF867E388CD2822993"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal Reserve Act is amended by inserting after section 11C the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HA984E2A0DEA64CA3AAEC7EAC24ABF938" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8AA4EF0B34644FC88596DF0CBA30211C"><enum>11D.</enum><header>Appropriations requirement for non-monetary policy related administrative costs</header> 
<subsection id="HF232C8488904480E85FA849AC0DAD44B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appropriations requirement</header> 
<paragraph id="H840B9574B5A34A8DAFB0EC60BC117633"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Recovery of costs of annual appropriation</header><text>The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Federal reserve banks shall collect assessments and other fees, as provided under this Act, that are designed to recover the costs to the Government of the annual appropriation to the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System by Congress. The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Federal reserve banks may only incur obligations or allow and pay expenses with respect to non-monetary policy related administrative costs pursuant to an appropriations Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H18FB1DFDFC85479182AFDDB41AB1735F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Offsetting collections</header><text>Assessments and other fees described under paragraph (1) for any fiscal year—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCE9BF9B1A3AB4F97B1CF0D9B58CA1EBD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be deposited and credited as offsetting collections to the account providing appropriations to the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAC1A0E74B15F480C96388C10311470CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall not be collected for any fiscal year except to the extent provided in advance in appropriation Acts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A41C702438744899AEE3188A47AAE48"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>This subsection shall only apply to the non-monetary policy related administrative costs of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBCE08D4955FD4DE8A25C30F725A05EC2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HD63E547C70A4406EB33CD18C72A644C6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Monetary policy</header><text>The term <term>monetary policy</term> means a strategy for producing a generally acceptable exchange medium that supports the productive employment of economic resources by reliably serving as both a unit of account and store of value.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD89CB604BDD04769B676EE19D336074F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-monetary policy related administrative costs</header><text>The term <term>non-monetary policy related administrative costs</term> means administrative costs not related to the conduct of monetary policy, and includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H83202FA3934E4A5F89D0D0C2F09C02BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>direct operating expenses for supervising and regulating entities supervised and regulated by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, including conducting examinations, conducting stress tests, communicating with the entities regarding supervisory matters and laws, and regulations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD700A63C75684B8DAB91C0B20759537B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>operating expenses for activities integral to carrying out supervisory and regulatory responsibilities, such as training staff in the supervisory function, research and analysis functions including library subscription services, and collecting and processing regulatory reports filed by supervised institutions; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9B4BC9DB319D4B609BBB11A438775C82"><enum>(C)</enum><text>support, overhead, and pension expenses related to the items described under subparagraphs (A) and (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HBE049E3EA5074BAA9F4ED24A3EB6ADA3" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to expenses paid and fees collected on or after October 1, 2025.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

