<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD25E1DEF3AA540DDB8FE53C1BE565438" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 770 IH: Expressing support for “Military Sexual Trauma Awareness Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 770</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250926">September 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000604">Ms. Goodlander</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for <quote>Military Sexual Trauma Awareness Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas military sexual trauma (hereinafter, <quote>MST</quote>) encompasses sexual assault or repeated, threatening sexual harassment that occurs during military service;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas MST affects both women and men in the Armed Forces, with research indicating that approximately 1 in 3 women and 1 in 50 men experience MST during service as a member, whether active duty, Reserve, or National Guard;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas MST is an experience rather than a diagnosis or mental health condition, and can result in significant and long-lasting impacts on survivors, including heightened risks of post-traumatic stress disorder (hereinafter, <quote>PTSD</quote>), depression, anxiety, substance abuse, and physical health issues, with an increased risk of suicide;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas MST survivors who identify as members of marginalized and minority groups may face additional stressors and barriers to engaging in MST-related care which may compound the trauma and hinder their access to necessary support;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas MST survivors often encounter feelings of being unsupported, disrespected, or retraumatized when seeking care, which can exacerbate their psychological distress and elevate the risk of suicide, highlighting the urgent need for reforms to ensure they receive compassionate and respectful treatment;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas MST not only affects the individual but also impacts their families, friends, and overall military readiness, as the trauma can strain relationships and affect the survivor’s ability to perform effectively within the military setting;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas there is a critical need to address the stigma associated with MST and to provide comprehensive support that considers the needs of survivors, their families, and the broader military community;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas there is an urgent need for the Armed Forces to intensify efforts to prevent MST by implementing comprehensive training programs, promoting a culture of zero tolerance, and strengthening reporting and support mechanisms to protect all members and ensure a safer military environment; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas September 25, 2025, is observed as <quote>Military Sexual Trauma Awareness Day</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H0D6D773865424065BAC0DA885FD31889"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HC965A4245AC646E08B113BA5F926E57C"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H36538A63055648D796EFB0AF9C70CF18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for <quote>Military Sexual Trauma Awareness Day</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00289962AFFD45729C8294478302E3F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affirms its commitment to supporting military sexual trauma survivors and acknowledges the importance of providing them with the highest quality care and support;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H36B908F10B4446F8A4707DBC5D3EFE34"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acknowledges the profound impact of military sexual trauma, commits to breaking the stigma surrounding it, and reaffirms its dedication to improving support systems for military sexual trauma survivors and their families;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC9A4C70FE4F14E1D99106D05DB479596"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages the Department of Defense and Department of Veterans Affairs to continue efforts to expand access to military sexual trauma-related services, ensuring these services are well-publicized and accessible to all veterans; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8E1BFCE4870B4D73B2E3D6A933FE5346"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promotes transparency and accountability in the Department of Defense’s and the Department of Veterans Affairs’ handling of military sexual trauma cases to build trust and ensure that survivors receive the support they need without fear of retaliation or discrimination; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF04CAEA5164541858F7682CDEA1C669D"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">underscores its commitment to working with the Department of Defense to address root problems and causes of military sexual trauma with the goal of eradicating it.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

