<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-joint" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-DAV25920-S91-RC-MYW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SJ 54 IS: Providing for congressional disapproval of the proposed foreign military sale to the Government of the United Arab Emirates of certain defense articles and services.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. J. RES. 54</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250515">May 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>) introduced the following joint resolution; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing for congressional disapproval of the proposed foreign military sale to the Government of the United Arab Emirates of certain defense articles and services.</official-title></form><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the following proposed foreign military sale to the Government of the United Arab Emirates is prohibited: </text></section><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H989ECF5139D54D76ADB5C1A2622B7489"><paragraph id="H3097CF3D5718499F8467A0E4F8AB6418"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The sale of the following defense articles and services described in Transmittal No. 24–118, submitted to Congress pursuant to section 36(b)(1) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2776">22 U.S.C. 2776(b)(1)</external-xref>), and published in the Congressional Record on May 13, 2025: The following Major Defense Equipment (MDE): Six (6) CH–47F Block II Chinook helicopters with air-to-air refuel probe capability and extended range fuel tanks; Sixteen (16) T–55–GA–714A engines (12 installed, 4 spares); Fourteen (14) Embedded Global Positioning System (GPS)/ Inertial Navigation System (INS) (EGD devices with M-Code (12 installed, 2 spares); Eight (8) AN/AAR–57 Common Missile Warning Systems (CMWS) (6 installed, 2 spares); Twenty (20) AN/ARC–231A communications security (COMSEC) radios (18 installed, 2 spares); and Twenty (20) M–240 machine guns (18 installed, 2 spares). The following non-MDE items will also be included: Common Missile Warning System (CMWS) classified software; AN/APR–39A radar warning receivers; AN/ AVR–2B Laser Detecting Sets (LDS); AN/ARC–220 high frequency radios; KY–100M CONISEC terminals; aircraft survivability equipment (including impulse cartridges for cable cutters and aircraft cartridges); AN/ARN–147 Very High Frequency (VHF) Omni Directional Radio Range/Instrument Landing System (VOR/ILS) receivers; WESCAM MX–15HDi electro- optical/infrared imaging systems; AN/ARN–153 Tactical Airborne Navigation System (TACAN) radios; AN/APN–209 radar altimeters; AN/APX–123A identification friend or foe (IFF) transponders; KIV–77 COMSEC IFF cryptographic appliques; AN/ PYQ–10 Simple Key Loaders; services to support the mission equipment; hardware and services required to implement partner-unique modifications; Fast Rope Insertion/Extraction Systems (FRIES); Internal Extended Range Fuel Systems (ERFS); in-flight refueling capability; firefighting equipment; ballistic armor protection systems; air worthiness support; spare and repair parts; communications equipment; personnel training and training equipment; site surveys; tool and test equipment; ground support equipment; repair and return; publications and technical documentation; Quality Assurance Team (QAT); U.S. Government and contractor engineering, technical, and logistics support services; and other related elements of logistics and program support.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

