<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA4A0EFBE74A34D239A52901B6888DD04" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5347 IH: Health Care Efficiency Through Flexibility Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5347</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250915">September 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000585">Mr. LaHood</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to ensure the availability of appropriate collection types for quality reporting under the Medicare Shared Savings Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5874FA113FD24B97AF2ED8F889908CEA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC8663568A40D493EA353DD62B63E39A4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Health Care Efficiency Through Flexibility Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H070185E8ADC142F6826A7DD95AF9994C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Ensuring availability of appropriate collection types for quality reporting under the Medicare Shared Savings Program</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1899(b)(3)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395jjj">42 U.S.C. 1395jjj(b)(3)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE4B0C393A03A4DC69B98BD4655AC5B4E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>An ACO shall submit</quote> and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H27324C51ECEA432984A536DC0544F1CB" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<clause id="H71A807CEB59744F690BFFEE583DF4349"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An ACO shall submit</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H79038AC7AA994B00BE8FFFF4F8E9BA33"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clauses:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1F2C3C49359E45539C42314C3D5031EF" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<clause id="H9FBAF33F1FF44254BF2D13C5651E9FA4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Required availability of collection types for certain years</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For performance years 2025 through 2029, the Secretary shall ensure that the following collection types (as described in section 414.1305 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation)) are available with respect to each measure described in subparagraph (A)(i) required to be reported by an ACO under this paragraph:</text> <subclause id="H65B86946FD2F4D3084BFED584894913C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Electronic clinical quality measures.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HC223680ED3B544DEBD9DC1417360F7A0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>MIPS clinical quality measures.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA9485F648229463AA967483399845DA0"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Medicare Clinical Quality Measures for Accountable Care Organizations Participating in the Medicare Shared Savings Program.</text></subclause> </clause> 
<clause id="H4CD2AA6306814C96A3292891F4166CF9"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Clarification on application of data completeness requirements in certain cases</header> 
<subclause id="HD5716D7FC5FE458C8BD21A4592ECDAF4"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether data submitted by an ACO with respect to a measure described in subparagraph (A)(i) for a performance year beginning on or after January 1, 2025, satisfies the data completeness requirements applicable to such measure under section 414.1340 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation) (as applied pursuant to section 425.512 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation)), the Secretary may not find such data to be unrepresentative of such ACO’s performance for such year (as described in paragraph (e) of such section 414.1340) based solely on the fact that such data excludes applicable data from 1 or more ACO participants in such ACO if—</text> <item id="H4E2ADE46409A45A89E756CAD1E8F019A"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>such data submitted by the ACO otherwise complies with the data completeness requirements of such section 414.1340; and</text></item> 
<item id="HCF65C9AC7E494E7DB4BD9E2EA71D5C6E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>such ACO demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that such ACO participant was unable to collect such data through the collection type (as described in clause (ii)) selected by the ACO for the submission of such data.</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H8F98646EB6604CE0ADCCC32D07993F7C"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this clause, the term <quote>ACO participant</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 425.20 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H02E7D57EF745400BB321A1D884F6613E"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The Secretary may implement this clause by program instruction or otherwise.</text></subclause></clause> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="HA4A1B5C68EAF46F39C20208A96AC0C38"><enum>3.</enum><header>Pilot program for digital quality measure reporting</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1899(b)(3)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395jjj">42 U.S.C. 1395jjj(b)(3)(B)</external-xref>), as amended by section 2, is further amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF8F5BA306D1746EA9FCBB163ECB22193" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<clause id="H344AA98A8E2D45738E55051B2108DD19"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Pilot program for digital quality measure reporting</header> 
<subclause id="H1109ED2BD7A24277AA71A1F22B6FDA66"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each of performance years 2028 through 2032, the Secretary shall establish a digital quality measure reporting pilot program (in this clause referred to as the <quote>program</quote>) under which ACOs selected under subclause (II) for such performance year report quality measures specified by the Secretary under subclause (III) for such performance year through a digital quality measure collection type specified by the Secretary.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HAEFE9FF59D7F4D838BE8172CAF24323A"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The Secretary shall select ACOs to participate in the program for a performance year from among ACOs that submit an application at such time and in such form and manner as specified by the Secretary.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1CAAE7385A6A486487D12C6A31114879"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Specification of quality measures</header><text>For each performance year of the program, the Secretary shall specify 2 measures described in subparagraph (A)(i) otherwise required to be reported by ACOs for such performance year for which an ACO selected under subclause (II) shall submit data through the collection type specified in subclause (I).</text></subclause> <subclause id="H360F6C557FDD4E368C3E5297A5036ED4"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Waiver of requirement to report other measures</header><text>The Secretary may not require an ACO selected under subclause (II) for a performance year to report data on any measure described in subparagraph (A) otherwise required to be reported by an ACO under this paragraph for such performance year, other than such a measure specified under subclause (III) for such performance year.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA6C4F28D313849DD83ECB1D59F248322"><enum>(V)</enum><header>Disregard of data for certain measures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not take into account any data for a measure specified under subclause (III) for a performance year submitted by an ACO selected under subclause (II) for such performance year, or any data for a measure with respect to which such ACO is not required to report data for such performance year under subclause (IV), in determining—</text> <item id="HCED57D7E4DB84429A82F658CA350A0E4"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>whether such ACO has met quality performance standards established by the Secretary under subparagraph (C) for such performance year; or</text></item> 
<item id="H40C8B4DD9DFD4A46A41F32F7DDF58AAD"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>any score for the quality performance category (as described in section 1848(q)(2)(A)(i)) for an ACO participant (as defined in clause (iii)(II)) in such ACO for such performance year.</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H867A63A21B19447890852F0DBD011904"><enum>(VI)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary shall provide such technical assistance to ACOs selected to participate in the program as is practicable.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H250690D39D0D40F7B6493CE5F46F8F97"><enum>(VII)</enum><header>Provision of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31, 2032, the Secretary shall publicly post (or include as part of annual rulemaking for this section) the following:</text> <item id="HE060E8CB28574D14A3615B5E6BA7BAAB"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>An analysis of the program.</text></item> 
<item id="H52B16468E6EB4F2DA8BB524AE0202A31">
                            <enum>(bb)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any recommendations for increasing submissions of data for measures described in subparagraph (A)(i) through the collection type specified in subclause (I).</text>
                        </item> 
<item id="H694CB4BB674F454CBB79755CA7D3329F"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>A proposed timeline for requiring such measures to be submitted through such collection type.</text></item></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

