<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5D5B78ACC04F4F1B9772BF9F2A308349" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1498 IH: Disengaging Entirely From the United Nations Debacle Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1498</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250221">February 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001317">Mr. Brecheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000596">Ms. Greene of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To terminate membership by the United States in the United Nations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA63B8102C86148BF92FA5A7C305BF07B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFD165BB9A18648A6BB940401BEDD6872" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Disengaging Entirely From the United Nations Debacle Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>DEFUND Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD44221C5A09146AA8F8D7F45120E974F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Repeal of United Nations Participation Act of 1945</header> <subsection id="H756E4FF1E46D444AB860CE8F32DCF985"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text>The United Nations Participation Act of 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/79/264">Public Law 79–264</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/287">22 U.S.C. 287 et seq.</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H5E57BB85763942B38750926B7448D493"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Termination of membership in United Nations</header><text>The President shall terminate all membership by the United States in the United Nations, and in any organ, specialized agency, commission, or other formally affiliated body of the United Nations.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H50F12E2A01CE4EE6B18E34EB128ED67A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Closure of United States Mission to United Nations</header><text>The United States Mission to the United Nations is closed. Any remaining functions of such office shall not be carried out.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HC2977B50D6EB474196472B5ADB7CFADD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Repeal of United Nations Headquarters Agreement Act</header>
<subsection id="HED6429E124AC4B9FBBCC0C1BDB9C844C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text>The Joint Resolution of August 4, 1947 (61 Stat. 756, chapter 482; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/287">22 U.S.C. 287</external-xref> note) (commonly known as the <quote>United Nations Headquarters Agreement Act</quote>) is repealed.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB9DD99861BAE47C9A8CEEEC7B751A89C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>The United States withdraws from the agreement between the United States of America and the United Nations regarding the headquarters of the United Nations (signed at Lake Success, New York, on June 26, 1947, which was brought into effect by the United Nations Headquarters Agreement Act).</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H7661C576E4C140F2B4D367465D66C18C"><enum>4.</enum><header>United States assessed and voluntary contributions to the United Nations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No funds are authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for assessed or voluntary contributions of the United States to the United Nations or to any organ, specialized agency, commission or other formally affiliated body of the United Nations, except that funds may be appropriated to facilitate termination of United States membership and withdrawal of United States personnel and equipment, in accordance with sections 2 and 3, respectively. Upon termination of United States membership, no payments shall be made to the United Nations or to any organ, specialized agency, commission or other formally affiliated body of the United Nations, out of any funds appropriated prior to such termination or out of any other funds available for such purposes.</text></section> <section id="H40115A66A354451D94C5086FBA9AFDE5"><enum>5.</enum><header>United Nations peacekeeping operations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The United States may not participate in any peacekeeping operation of the United Nations.</text></section>
<section id="HEAF29AADD35C44C7A2C4634593126647"><enum>6.</enum><header>Withdrawal of United Nations presence in facilities of the Government of the United States and repeal of diplomatic immunity</header>
<subsection id="HDC61D428CCAA443096EE3C1D5AAA42BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Withdrawal from United States Government property</header><text>The United Nations (including any organ, specialized agency, commission or other formally affiliated body of the United Nations) may not occupy or use any property or facility of the United States Government.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8715D88A39694E4798DB7F8FB4F2CE1C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Diplomatic immunity</header><text>No officer or employee of the United Nations (including any organ, specialized agency, commission or other formally affiliated body of the United Nations) or any representative, officer, or employee of any mission to the United Nations of any foreign government shall be entitled to enjoy the privileges and immunities of the Vienna Convention on Diplomatic Relations done at Vienna April 18, 1961, nor may any such privileges and immunities be extended to any such individual. The privileges, exemptions, and immunities provided for in the International Organizations Immunities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/288">22 U.S.C. 288 et seq.</external-xref>), or in any agreement or treaty to which the United States is a party, including the Agreement Between the United Nations and the United States of America Regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, and the Convention on the Privileges and Immunities of the United Nations, done at New York February 13, 1946, and entered into force with respect to the United States on April 29, 1970, shall not apply to the United Nations or to any organ, specialized agency, commission or other formally affiliated body of the United Nations, to the officers and employees of the United Nations, or of any organ, specialized agency, commission or other formally affiliated body of the United Nations, or to the families, suites, or servants of such officers or employees.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HE6988679A7374A37B8C5A8654E844224"><enum>7.</enum><header>Repeal of United States participation in the World Health Organization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The joint resolution entitled <quote>Joint Resolution providing for membership and participation by the United States in the World Health Organization and authorizing an appropriation therefor</quote>, approved June 14, 1948 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/290">22 U.S.C. 290</external-xref>), is repealed.</text></section> <section id="H7777E92907994A83B70EC0FD46235114"><enum>8.</enum><header>Repeal of involvement in United Nations conventions and agreements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The United States shall end any participation in any conventions and agreements with the United Nations and any organ, specialized agency, commission, or other formally affiliated body of the United Nations. Any remaining functions of such conventions and agreements shall not be carried out.</text></section>
<section id="H0297F2ECC897445DAB12576CB7C41C6F"><enum>9.</enum><header>Prohibition on United States reentry into United Nations</header>
<subsection id="HBBFBB68E285F40A58467C89ECFE2BBFA" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may not enter into an agreement for membership in the United Nations or any organ, specialized agency, commission, or other formally affiliated body of the United Nations without the advice and consent of the Senate. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H65FF3FC695244269AAF8DD4E218422C8" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Withdrawal provision requirement</header><text>The advice and consent of the Senate to the ratification of any agreement seeking membership in the United Nations or any organ, specialized agency, commission, or other formally affiliated body of the United Nations shall be subject to a reservation, which shall be included in the instrument of ratification, that reserves the right of the United States to withdraw from such agreement. </text></subsection></section>
<section id="HF06699FA416B4BF3BA0490FEAC0EF38E"><enum>10.</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall notify the United Nations and any organ, specialized agency, commission, or other formally affiliated body of the United Nations of the provisions of this Act.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

