<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25589-W7C-91-N53">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1677 IS: Ensuring Lasting Smiles Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 1677</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250508">May 8, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms.
                    Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr.
                    Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr.
                    Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr.
                    Booker</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>)
                introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the
                    <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and
                    Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To provide health insurance benefits for outpatient and inpatient items and
            services related to the diagnosis and treatment of a congenital anomaly or birth
            defect.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="H5D15B4DFE9224C1B970FA37A805F4384">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Lasting Smiles Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="H5DF514D53FCF46448CB49DB295CEA482">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Coverage of congenital anomaly or birth defect</header>
            <subsection id="H4F65E1659FF34F48A48F869BC557140D">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Public Health Service Act Amendments</header>
 <text>Part D of title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-111">42 U.S.C. 300gg–111 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
                <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C3F23D1CED54398A05D827195D62EB7">
                    <section id="HFF19EF1A55B440CC9650E87909926F84">
                        <enum>2799A–11.</enum>
                        <header>Coverage of congenital anomaly or birth defect</header>
                        <subsection id="id1069007d2dd148efa2f2c09597fa89bb">
                            <enum>(a)</enum>
                            <header>Requirements for care and reconstructive treatment</header>
                            <paragraph id="id9a8a981fa20e461ba9a7d8b39a696305">
                                <enum>(1)</enum>
                                <header>In general</header>
 <text>A group health plan, and a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage, shall provide coverage for outpatient and inpatient items and services related to the diagnosis and treatment of a congenital anomaly or birth defect that primarily impacts the appearance or function of the eyes, ears, teeth, mouth, or jaw, consistent with paragraphs (2) and (3).</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="ida910110b256849699e44000b8bdbdbc8">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
                                <header>Financial requirements</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any coverage provided under paragraph (1) under a group health plan or group or individual health insurance coverage may be subject to cost-sharing requirements (such as coinsurance, copayments, and deductibles), as required by the plan or issuer offering such coverage, that are no more restrictive than the predominant cost-sharing requirements applied to substantially all other medical and surgical benefits covered by the plan or coverage.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="ide70c1574c55e4c4ebfac52177f4ddbbe">
                                <enum>(3)</enum>
                                <header>Applicable items and services</header>
                                <subparagraph id="idd0c05bea2e3446deadafffcd6cd9ff34">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                                    <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the items and services required under paragraph (1) to be covered by a group health plan or group or individual health insurance coverage offered by a health insurance issuer include—</text>
                                    <clause id="id849e4c10c16b4f5aaef90fbd8d7649da">
                                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any item or service to improve, repair, or restore any body part to achieve normal body functioning or appearance, or performed to approximate a normal appearance, as determined medically necessary by the treating physician (as defined in section 1861(r) of the Social Security Act), on account of a congenital anomaly or birth defect that primarily impacts the appearance or function of the eyes, ears, teeth, mouth, or jaw; and</text>
                                    </clause>
                                    <clause id="id5c817a7383fa4e239af67178f9e66ede">
                                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any treatment or diagnostic service with respect to any and all missing or abnormal body parts (including teeth, the oral cavity, and their associated structures), as determined medically necessary by the treating physician (as defined in section 1861(r) of the Social Security Act), including—</text>
                                        <subclause id="idd7fca8c63a994ad5a17e761aef49e58d">
                                            <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reconstructive services and procedures, and items and services related to any complications arising from such services and procedures;</text>
                                        </subclause>
                                        <subclause id="id1b3fe05ec28740cfa84887b2c3423243">
                                            <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>adjunctive dental, orthodontic, or prosthodontic support from birth until the medical or surgical treatment of the defect or anomaly has been completed, including ongoing or subsequent treatment required to maintain function or approximate a normal appearance, notwithstanding any exclusions, limitations, or restrictions under the plan or health insurance coverage on coverage of dental, orthodontic, or prosthodontic items and services arising from other injuries or sicknesses; and</text>
                                        </subclause>
                                        <subclause id="id3de96e4999ec44e794e709d6a606e4a0">
                                            <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text>items and services related to secondary conditions and follow-up treatment associated with the underlying congenital anomaly or birth defect.</text>
                                        </subclause>
                                    </clause>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="id61cf6b92a6364ea39cc36b9bb0cf0565">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                                    <header>Exception</header>
 <text>The items and services required under this subsection to be covered by a group health plan or health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage shall not include cosmetic surgery performed to reshape normal structures of the body to improve appearance or self-esteem, if such items and services are not furnished as a result of a medical determination of a congenital anomaly or birth defect.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection commented="no" id="HD37C4492E4114CD0A9028B446ACF2C23">
                            <enum>(b)</enum>
                            <header>Notice</header>
 <text>Beginning not later January 1, 2026, a group health plan or health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage shall provide notice to each participant and beneficiary under such plan or coverage regarding the coverage required by this section in any documents describing services, in accordance with any regulations promulgated by the Secretary.</text>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="idFD4B1880002B47188104444389150422">
                            <enum>(c)</enum>
                            <header>Definition</header>
 <text>In this section, the term <term>congenital anomaly or birth defect</term> means a structural or functional anomaly that occurs during intrauterine life, develops prenatally, and may be identified before birth, at birth, or later in life, and which may—</text>
                            <paragraph id="idC24141997F9944A48F4BE00969A0B228">
                                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>be caused by genetic or chromosomal disorders, embryotoxic or teratogenic environmental factors, nutrient deficiency, multifactorial inheritance, or be of an unknown cause;</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="idE3F56E87FCA54099A6EB06C5F0B9EEA4">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>manifest as abnormal anatomical structures;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id71281605CFCF4E5DA6DFBA8499694503"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>manifest as physical, sensory, or cognitive functional disabilities;</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="id3C007E9C569144EF8E5AE24A3021CFF8">
                                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>manifest as syndromes, diseases, or other health problems; and</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="idC2F560B2DEFD44949BD660D7EC2DF233">
                                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>manifest as singular anomalies or in combination prenatally, at birth, or later in life.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection>
                    </section>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HD0DA142613E847EB99B4C90252C08F99">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>ERISA amendments</header>
                <paragraph id="H5B2208D6113F491AB58BACC9D6354DD1">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>Subpart B of part 7 of subtitle B of title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
                    <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73CEC333889F4F588F07AE8D23966664">
                        <section commented="no" id="H8735C43E75DA413FAFF71FA05188B570">
                            <enum>726.</enum>
                            <header>Coverage of congenital anomaly or birth defect</header>
                            <subsection id="ide4408724c6d646c0bebeb71462330774">
                                <enum>(a)</enum>
                                <header>Requirements for care and reconstructive treatment</header>
                                <paragraph id="id94aac59f9d8141dcb94804148b8b33bc">
                                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>A group health plan, and a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage, shall provide coverage for outpatient and inpatient items and services related to the diagnosis and treatment of a congenital anomaly or birth defect that primarily impacts the appearance or function of the eyes, ears, teeth, mouth, or jaw, consistent with paragraphs (2) and (3).</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="idbac6cf1a66c848c9a24d057514ce4249">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                                    <header>Financial requirements</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any coverage provided under paragraph (1) under a group health plan or group health insurance coverage offered by a health insurance issuer may be subject to cost-sharing requirements (such as coinsurance, copayments, and deductibles), as required by the plan or issuer offering such coverage, that are no more restrictive than the predominant cost-sharing requirements applied to substantially all other medical and surgical benefits covered by the plan or coverage.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="id0377ba0b53574d2980771848f7a78d7a">
                                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                                    <header>Applicable items and services</header>
                                    <subparagraph id="id041387b6a24f4a6b8f80ffe27ae77c41">
                                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                                        <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the items and services required under paragraph (1) to be covered by a group health plan or group health insurance coverage offered by a health insurance issuer include—</text>
                                        <clause id="idb3d6e5cc7afa4cf797cb04eec0b5b718">
                                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any item or service to improve, repair, or restore any body part to achieve normal body functioning or appearance, or performed to approximate a normal appearance, as determined medically necessary by the treating physician (as defined in section 1861(r) of the Social Security Act), on account of a congenital anomaly or birth defect that primarily impacts the appearance or function of the eyes, ears, teeth, mouth, or jaw; and </text>
                                        </clause>
                                        <clause id="id0f78bbde477040f394517590af50f0cf">
                                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any treatment or diagnostic service with respect to any and all missing or abnormal body parts (including teeth, the oral cavity, and their associated structures), as determined medically necessary by the treating physician (as defined in section 1861(r) of the Social Security Act), including—</text>
                                            <subclause id="idc773279324a748e3bf51195be05af3cf">
                                                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reconstructive services and procedures, and items and services related to any complications arising from such services and procedures;</text>
                                            </subclause>
                                            <subclause id="id76b6dec80e314565a39276a9bbe0dd94">
                                                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>adjunctive dental, orthodontic, or prosthodontic support from birth until the medical or surgical treatment of the defect or anomaly has been completed, including ongoing or subsequent treatment required to maintain function or approximate a normal appearance, notwithstanding any exclusions, limitations, or restrictions under the plan or health insurance coverage on coverage of dental, orthodontic, or prosthodontic items and services arising from other injuries or sicknesses; and</text>
                                            </subclause>
                                            <subclause id="id2b83550a0f444143b5e41dbac769f4a0">
                                                <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text>items and services related to secondary conditions and follow-up treatment associated with the underlying congenital anomaly or birth defect.</text>
                                            </subclause>
                                        </clause>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="id47d987ac95544845af840ec9ba140ad1">
                                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                                        <header>Exception</header>
 <text>The items and services required under this subsection to be covered by a group health plan or health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage shall not include cosmetic surgery performed to reshape normal structures of the body to improve appearance or self-esteem, if such items and services are not furnished as a result of a medical determination of a congenital anomaly or birth defect. </text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                </paragraph>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection commented="no" id="HF77320D0F17342ADBE401EBD8628EF8B">
                                <enum>(b)</enum>
                                <header>Notice</header>
 <text>Beginning not later than January 1, 2026, a group health plan or health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage shall provide notice to each participant and beneficiary under such plan or coverage regarding the coverage required by this section, in any documents describing services, in accordance with any regulations promulgated by the Secretary. </text>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="id2C9B4D9440794DDB90CFEC792A1E435A">
                                <enum>(c)</enum>
                                <header>Definition</header>
 <text>In this section, the term <term>congenital anomaly or birth defect</term> means a structural or functional anomaly that occurs during intrauterine life, develops prenatally, and may be identified before birth, at birth, or later in life, and which may—</text>
                                <paragraph id="idF2E7909EBEF74620B170524952EB38C9">
                                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>be caused by genetic or chromosomal disorders, embryotoxic or teratogenic environmental factors, nutrient deficiency, multifactorial inheritance, or be of an unknown cause;</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="id42A42ABC80064B0C8B45D3A89A27BF3B">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>manifest as abnormal anatomical structures;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idC6AB3F10879E4E89AB0908E358062E5A"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>manifest as physical, sensory, or cognitive functional disabilities;</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="id07ED60A5F24844B49E211A3538C9B461">
                                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>manifest as syndromes, diseases, or other health problems; and</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="id5AEF2DED05034BF19494A526934CF8DD">
                                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>manifest as singular anomalies or in combination prenatally, at birth, or later in life.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                            </subsection>
                        </section>
                        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                    </quoted-block>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HEEDD6B6150AD47999990DC9727CB5041">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Technical amendments</header>
                    <subparagraph id="HCB605CB76238433EBEB50F8A4DA1130F">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>Section 732(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1191a">29 U.S.C. 1191a(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 711</quote> and inserting <quote>sections 711 and 726</quote>.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H5DCADE00BEAA444E88EE5675FFB3E649">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>The table of contents in section 1 of such Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 725 the following new item:</text>
                        <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD1F8D72DA2EF4DF6B55018074594254C">
                            <toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
                                <toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 726. Coverage of
                                    congenital anomaly or birth defect.</toc-entry>
                            </toc>
                            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                        </quoted-block>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAEC8AFBF65CE41EDB8035C747C6573BD">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Internal Revenue Code amendments</header>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H468B1BBC64C847BF8ECDF3BEF082C5FA">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>Subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/100">chapter 100</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
                    <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93E52D52084845A5AA568192350B790F">
                        <section commented="no" id="HFA96D9754A8C4B74A39FB5BCD7FBD268">
                            <enum>9826.</enum>
                            <header>Coverage of congenital anomaly or birth defect</header>
                            <subsection id="HDB7F403250A347B59663D264FF8953DD">
                                <enum>(a)</enum>
                                <header>Requirements for care and reconstructive treatment</header>
                                <paragraph id="H2A57C076A7A144818217C056343D02E0">
                                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>A group health plan shall provide coverage for outpatient and inpatient items and services related to the diagnosis and treatment of a congenital anomaly or birth defect that primarily impacts the appearance or function of the eyes, ears, teeth, mouth, or jaw, consistent with paragraphs (2) and (3).</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="H456CE8A2E205429EBB2D1D7CF5559914">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                                    <header>Financial requirements</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any coverage provided under paragraph (1) under a group health plan may be subject to cost-sharing requirements (such as coinsurance, copayments, and deductibles), as required by the plan, that are no more restrictive than the predominant cost-sharing requirements applied to substantially all other medical and surgical benefits covered by the plan.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="H0764E16E48D2447A8FA77B4F833CB267">
                                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                                    <header>Applicable items and services</header>
                                    <subparagraph id="HE20DDFE553194EA6A2648A3690FEAE4A">
                                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                                        <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the items and services required under paragraph (1) to be covered by a group health plan include—</text>
                                        <clause id="idE6E8C3153F3343FF9145889381F2E0C1">
                                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any item or service to improve, repair, or restore any body part to achieve normal body functioning or appearance, or performed to approximate a normal appearance, as determined medically necessary by the treating physician (as defined in section 1861(r) of the Social Security Act), on account of a congenital anomaly or birth defect that primarily impacts the appearance or function of the eyes, ears, teeth, mouth, or jaw; and</text>
                                        </clause>
                                        <clause id="id7EB491A0DDDF46B096E852A4FDB64AB9">
                                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any treatment or diagnostic service with respect to any and all missing or abnormal body parts (including teeth, the oral cavity, and their associated structures), as determined medically necessary by the treating physician (as defined in section 1861(r) of the Social Security Act), including—</text>
                                            <subclause id="HD93F33C702C14BD6BE3B708B1AD2DD3A">
                                                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reconstructive services and procedures, and items and services related to any complications arising from such services and procedures;</text>
                                            </subclause>
                                            <subclause id="H4E63FBF0E06E436DBF5A3BA0CDBBA9A1">
                                                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>adjunctive dental, orthodontic, or prosthodontic support from birth until the medical or surgical treatment of the defect or anomaly has been completed, including ongoing or subsequent treatment required to maintain function or approximate a normal appearance, notwithstanding any exclusions, limitations, or restrictions under the plan on coverage of dental, orthodontic, or prosthodontic items and services arising from other injuries or sicknesses; and</text>
                                            </subclause>
                                            <subclause id="HA8849C46034A4E8C96E69CF2605C4A6E">
                                                <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text>items and services related to secondary conditions and follow-up treatment associated with the underlying congenital anomaly or birth defect.</text>
                                            </subclause>
                                        </clause>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="H1DFBE27B8D0447759A32713D4B30A8A0">
                                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                                        <header>Exception</header>
 <text>The items and services required under this subsection to be covered by a group health plan shall not include cosmetic surgery performed to reshape normal structures of the body to improve appearance or self-esteem, if such items and services are not furnished as a result of a medical determination of a congenital anomaly or birth defect.</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                </paragraph>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection commented="no" id="HC39FFABFB75A46AD904559109B8F4EF2">
                                <enum>(b)</enum>
                                <header>Notice</header>
 <text>Beginning not later January 1, 2026, a group health plan shall provide notice to each participant and beneficiary under such plan or coverage regarding the coverage required by this section in any documents describing services, in accordance with any regulations promulgated by the Secretary.</text>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="id04BCF72CBFD740958F9AE960FB8A1EFC">
                                <enum>(c)</enum>
                                <header>Definition</header>
 <text>In this section, the term <term>congenital anomaly or birth defect</term> means a structural or functional anomaly that occurs during intrauterine life, develops prenatally, and may be identified before birth, at birth, or later in life, and which may—</text>
                                <paragraph id="idB8DC44EFB3E74CD9A18B4C3588EDF699">
                                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>be caused by genetic or chromosomal disorders, embryotoxic or teratogenic environmental factors, nutrient deficiency, multifactorial inheritance, or be of an unknown cause;</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="id7DE561BE62534475A6B65AD392900E65">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>manifest as abnormal anatomical structures;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idBCAB708EB63A4901A9C862CB8F7B7D77"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>manifest as physical, sensory, or cognitive functional disabilities;</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="idD7458D808918472098936744A5C15A23">
                                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>manifest as syndromes, diseases, or other health problems; and</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="id9069D4D1BBC84137B39E4CFF94663806">
                                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>manifest as singular anomalies or in combination prenatally, at birth, or later in life.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                            </subsection>
                        </section>
                        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                    </quoted-block>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HECAAB9B13B074C3D92093F313FE20040">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Clerical amendment</header>
 <text>The table of sections for such subchapter is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
                    <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3EF19B4603FC4E60996B55ED0A62ADF8">
                        <toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
                            <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 9826. Coverage of congenital anomaly or
                                birth defect.</toc-entry>
                        </toc>
                        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                    </quoted-block>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id7df568e1dd7647de8aaafbf14673e30e">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Study and report on network adequacy</header>
 <text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall conduct a study, and not later than December 31, 2027, submit a report to Congress, on the matters relating to access of services for coverage of outpatient and inpatient items and services related to the diagnosis and treatment of a congenital anomaly or birth defect that primarily impacts the appearance or function of the eyes, ears, teeth, mouth, or jaw. Such study and report shall—</text>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb0ea321505d543b3a59c85d7c8f99a51">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate the sufficiency and accessibility of networks of providers that perform services related to the diagnosis and treatment of such congenital anomalies and birth defects under group health plans and group and individual health insurance coverage (as such terms are defined in section 2791 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-91">42 U.S.C. 300gg–91</external-xref>)); and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide3d243caef9645e0ba75ef336ed54a39">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess any change in out-of-pocket costs for patients, by procedure type, resulting from the coverage requirements under sections 2799A–11 of the Public Health Service Act, 726 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, and 9826 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as added by this section, and any change in the overall procedure cost for such services.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H54D86CD2DA384762A7CC8330922B0F29">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Effective date</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by subsections (a), (b), and (c) shall apply with respect to plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2026.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

