<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV25B72-DFX-HV-084"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2199 IS: To require the Secretary of Defense to issue regulations requiring that optional combat boots worn by members of the Armed Forces wear be made in the United States, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2199</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250626" legis-day="20250624">June 26 (legislative day, June 24), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Defense to issue regulations requiring that optional combat boots worn by members of the Armed Forces wear be made in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H579D86014807419294DC160999E93D7E"><section section-type="section-one" id="H60332628162E4A77B0225C64380E0B0E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Regulations applicable to combat footwear of members of all branches of the Armed
 Forces</header><subsection id="HE6C83E3CA8A1412ABF2943E4F3783F20"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall issue regulations prohibiting any member of the Armed Forces from wearing optional combat boots as part of a required uniform unless the optional combat boots are entirely manufactured in the United States and entirely made of—</text><paragraph id="H1C9A65F5A6E5437DBAAC0EB39419F544"><enum>(1)</enum><text>materials grown, reprocessed, reused, or produced in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE47DA778D354500B78AB5FB8A8211D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>components that are manufactured entirely in the United States and entirely made of materials described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H92F108E0614943BCB1309683072D214C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability exemption</header><paragraph id="HDA099A099F794932A1ECB2A1FAEFD5D2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Secretary concerned may make a determination described in subsection (c) of section 4862 of title 10, United States Code, with respect to optional combat boots designed for a specific use and a specific need of the Department of Defense in the same manner as an article or item under subsection (a) of such section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88F9D4FDD79F477482E2543842BF4C5B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a Secretary concerned makes a determination described in paragraph (1) with respect to optional combat boots designed for a specific use and a specific need of the Department of Defense, the Secretary concerned may waive the prohibition under subsection (a) with respect to such optional combat boots designed for a specific use to the extent necessary to meet such need.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE8DEDCF89077499E8768F33D77270B05"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Medical exemption</header><text>The prohibition under subsection (a) shall not apply to the wearing of optional combat boots by a member of the Armed Forces if such optional combat boots are medically necessary to meet a unique physiological need of such member of the Armed Forces.</text></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E1177724B7949CC8E9AB981536D5E60"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H5310AB754A4F4C9CAE20EAC2E3B74919"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Armed forces; Secretary concerned</header><text>The terms <term>Armed Forces</term> and <term>Secretary concerned</term> have the meanings given such terms, respectively, in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3096314FFE249868FBF23E7F7129864"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Optional combat boots</header><text>The term <term>optional combat boots</term>, with respect to a member of the Armed Forces, means combat boots not furnished to such member of the Armed Forces by the Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37D89C17B39E47C7A5017D67DBFC0B71"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Required uniform</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>required uniform</term> means a uniform a member of the Armed Forces is required to wear as a member of the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


