<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL25571-P6F-MP-1JY"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2590 IS: Fresh Start Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2590</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250731">July 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a grant program for States for purposes of modernizing criminal justice data infrastructure to facilitate automatic record expungement and sealing, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HF4E07FC91E7340FEA8D557B5FC930050"><section section-type="section-one" id="H204CDCCD8DE540A0A631E1A78E1D91C2"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fresh Start Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9174C6C61DCA4211B7C27BFA6A0E5CEF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H89F901683DA34FBD8D4AED1FBA4BDF49"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Terms defined in Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968</header><text>Terms defined in section 901 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10251">34 U.S.C. 10251</external-xref>) shall have the meanings given those terms in that section.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07ceef831aa9480aaf3a9de6895190bb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other terms</header><subparagraph id="H4CBAA8FD02C14073981315863A1EBAAD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Automatic</header><text>The term <term>automatic</term> means, with regard to the expungement or sealing of a criminal record, that the expungement or sealing occurs without the State requiring any action from the eligible individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04BD7C670354473B8EFE637DBBF56FD9" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered expungement law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered expungement law</term> means a law of a State providing for the automatic expungement or sealing, subject to such requirements as the State may impose, of a criminal record of an individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H8EDE585E602243ABA92A3E9B61FA65CA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of grant program</header><subsection id="HB935B9B83E894DEEAB07908C5DE0FEFC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may make not more than 1 grant under this Act to each eligible State.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id11511c4af2fc4b70a30e59de411967e5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant described in subsection (a) shall be in an amount of not more than $5,000,000.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBF6D950E75E34F4BA1FFBB8FE0BB548E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>A State shall be eligible for a grant under this Act if—</text><paragraph id="HC988A72DE267404CBD9ABCB581A3253C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the State has in effect a covered expungement law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H753C8AA95BFC4BD18A7258D974019CB4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the covered expungement law of the State provides that expungement or sealing of a criminal record shall not be delayed by reason of a failure to pay a fee or fine; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30A01B9930D14294AD92DA61AEA04A9B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the State submits an application to the Attorney General containing such information as the Attorney General may require, including, at a minimum—</text><subparagraph id="H65B0A560765E4AE9B571A2CA22CFAE79"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information identifying whether a system exists, as of the date of the application, for record expungement or sealing in the State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H351DC11C4F124CD3B969ABF417C09FC5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of how infrastructure created through grant funding will facilitate automatic record expungement or sealing for individuals eligible for record expungement or sealing; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFEE3886982649B4B148E79D38CF3695"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an identification of the anticipated number of individuals who would benefit from the implementation of automatic record expungement or sealing infrastructure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2F6FA39FFEB24805928F424E7EE3CDBD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Use of grant amounts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A State shall use a grant received under section 3 to implement a covered expungement law in accordance with the following requirements:</text><paragraph id="HC3F430E4C7AC4425ADDA649B367F101E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State shall use not more than 10 percent of the grant for research or planning for criminal record data infrastructure improvements that will make criminal record expungement or sealing automatic.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C2D9E8BCD79453A82A5B4B76483701B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The State shall use any remaining amounts to implement criminal record data infrastructure improvements that will make criminal record expungement or sealing automatic.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02E5791A65CB44B3B4E66E888DBFB624"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The portion of the costs of implementing the law provided by a grant under this section may not exceed 75 percent.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H51E60C627D6840BB806A26E3CB7273C2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><subsection id="H86B09A3AC80146D7A5D1738C126F364B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State receiving a grant under section 3 shall report to the Attorney General, each year of the grant term, pursuant to guidelines established by the Attorney General, information regarding the following:</text><paragraph id="H870059A0BE734189B2AEAE147E8E9077"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of individuals eligible for automatic expungement or sealing under the covered expungement law of the State, disaggregated by race, ethnicity, and gender.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67EBAB6AE8BD46A29815211F067F68E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of individuals whose records have been expunged or sealed annually since the enactment of the covered expungement law of the State, disaggregated by race, ethnicity, and gender.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D28486E0BE6470D89F25E72E4517DB2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of individuals who have submitted an application for expungement or sealing under the covered expungement law of the State that is still pending, disaggregated by race, ethnicity, and gender.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC6BE2DFDFDE24B7FA760F0DFC5B29E87"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inaccessibility of data for reporting</header><text>If a State is unable to compile and report elements of the data on expungement and sealing required to be reported under subsection (a) during any year of the grant term, the State shall develop and report, not later than the last day of that year, a comprehensive plan to obtain as much of the unavailable data as possible.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2211A67A02074BF98B536F1799267B7C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and each year thereafter, the Attorney General shall make available to the public a report containing the data reported to the Attorney General under this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA1B986205EF340FD9B485CBAF9290ED2"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030 to carry out this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

