<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H015BAA2B90F744EAA8CB2252BDD89269" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4441 IH: Patient Access to Innovative New Technologies Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4441</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250716">July 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001126">Mr. Carey</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve Medicare beneficiary access to new medical technologies that improve health care quality and outcomes by ensuring that breakthrough devices are eligible for conditional approval under the Medicare New Technology Add-On Payment (NTAP) Program, enabling these medical breakthroughs to be provided to Medicare beneficiaries without unnecessary delay.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H141143ADB1DC4353A502456CDF764BCE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD05F12B3328F4728A1DE2CE3C4FE8D56" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Patient Access to Innovative New Technologies Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H22F36A832FCD48DA9E672C628795ADE0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Increasing adoption of and access to breakthrough devices</header> <subsection id="H1DE33A53E4BB422CB4945304FEE97CEC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1886(d)(5)(K) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)(5)(K)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C27189714E242259A7BC0A8688E06C6">
<clause id="H8E922887FD104353B8010D94B005B162" indent="up3"><enum>(x)</enum>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H40F7480B2B574495980E0A7727D1DAF8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>A breakthrough device that is not approved, cleared, or authorized under section 510(k), 513(f)(2), or 515 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act by the deadline specified in section 412.87(f)(2) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation) may be conditionally approved for the new technology add-on payment under this subparagraph for a particular fiscal year, effective for discharges beginning in the first quarter after receiving such approval, clearance, or authorization, provided that the approval, clearance, or authorization is granted before July 1 of the fiscal year for which the applicant applied for new technology add-on payments.</text></subclause> <subclause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H53FC242BC1354E1291526E1F9D7F6BEA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>For purposes of this clause, the term <term>breakthrough device</term> means a medical device that—</text>
<item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7CE705EBE404650944BC2B60D836FE8"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is designated for expedited development and priority review under section 515B of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act; and</text></item> <item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC6006A15DD3E4501B9ED1C7F52953DCC"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been approved, cleared, or authorized under section 510(k), 513(f)(2), or 515 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act for the indication for which the designation described in item (aa) was made.</text></item></subclause>
<subclause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H25FF5149CD5145B287B9E46FD4CAA19C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>This clause shall not be considered an adjustment and shall be implemented in a budget neutral manner.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C35462AEDA14DB78FE33E5712C84AF7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section, and the amendments made by this section, shall take effect on the enactment of this Act and shall apply to a breakthrough device (as defined in section 1886(d)(5)(K)(x)(II) of the Social Security Act, as added by subsection (a)) that is approved, cleared, or authorized under section 510(k), 513(f)(2), or 515 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360">21 U.S.C. 360(k)</external-xref>, 360c(f)(2), 360e) on or after July 1, 2023.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

