<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9C5B1CE9BEE045E2937333554ADC0D26" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1240 IH: National Statistics on Deadly Force Transparency Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1240</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250212">February 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Attorney General to issue rules pertaining to the collection and compilation of data on the use of deadly force by law enforcement officers.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE8DC3354D62E45DCB82363E6565E7F68" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAF6121D336BD4193865C6916F1E4A353" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Statistics on Deadly Force Transparency Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC8225B9C458044C2839D071D878B5FF5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Attorney general to issue regulations</header> <subsection id="HF9FF1D812D61491D983B0C1F114E35D4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, in consultation with stakeholders, including Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies and community, professional, research, and civil rights organizations, shall issue regulations for the collection and compilation of data pertaining to the use of deadly force by Federal, State, or local law enforcement officers.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H5E5482BA1E82436EABEA364126D37C78"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The regulations issued under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H8E1BD22E6CA74254A319A2D8F7AF8560"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require the collection of data on all instances wherein deadly force was used by a Federal, State, or local law enforcement officer;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H46B8CFFD197D42CD94B57B71004D835F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require that the data collected shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H3EDB8ED4C8404D72BBE61E3DC90AAB22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include identifying characteristics of the person who was the target of the use of deadly force and the officer who used deadly force, including—</text>
<clause id="H437F25A3B19D4744B1971F4A0BCB28B9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>race or ethnicity;</text></clause> <clause id="H4278D41860CD4FD59BE8921BDFB813C2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>gender;</text></clause>
<clause id="H4DC658FDAB034DE1899C1CB36C7FED40"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>approximate age; and</text></clause> <clause id="H702C00E8282F49D89F39D92842DE3922"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the actual or perceived religious affiliation;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4E73C3958FFE4639BE3E1B19CB366C88"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include the date, time, and location of such use of deadly force;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8F8D3174126741BA8BD377FD6C6AF4DB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include the alleged criminal activity of the person who was the target of the use of deadly force;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2259C08A2C7F4B688E41471D9AA74B96"><enum>(D)</enum><text>include the nature of the deadly force used, including the use of a firearm;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H65B1741B83114C9699BE9FBF4C143D53"><enum>(E)</enum><text>include an explanation, if any, from the relevant law enforcement agency on why deadly force was used;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA09562045449454D8D4916260E082072"><enum>(F)</enum><text>include a copy of any use of deadly force guidelines in effect at the relevant law enforcement agency at the time deadly force was used;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC27267F556124330B20D7A857B99C1F9"><enum>(G)</enum><text>include a description of any non-lethal efforts employed to apprehend or subdue the person who was the target of the use of deadly force before deadly force was used; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE4D7AA86D1E04651A70BF501E500C54C"><enum>(H)</enum><text>not include personally identifiable information described in section 4;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H37B0E41B3DD747F9B9763E5F7E8D83AF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide that a standardized form shall be made available to law enforcement agencies for the submission of data collected pursuant to this Act to the Department of Justice;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB11ABBB93D1B42549E46D8C3CF959459"><enum>(4)</enum><text>require that law enforcement agencies compile data using the standardized form made available under paragraph (3), and submit the form to the Department of Justice Bureau of Justice Statistics and any other component of the Department of Justice that the Attorney General determines appropriate; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H01C08D95D5DF4D0BA5A4D636B6AE5560"><enum>(5)</enum><text>require that law enforcement agencies shall maintain all data collected under this Act for not less than 4 years.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H1740127CE982492E829615D19EE49399"><enum>3.</enum><header>Duties of the bureau of justice statistics</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Department of Justice Bureau of Justice Statistics shall provide to Congress and make available to the public the data collected pursuant to this Act, excluding any personally identifiable information described in section 4.</text></section> <section id="H8C26D7E780794A22BD35957A0F681F7A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Limitations on publication of data</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The name or identifying information of a law enforcement officer, person who was the target of the use of deadly force, or any other individual involved in any activity for which data is collected and compiled under this Act shall not be—</text>
<paragraph id="HF4E3905056F040C7A8E81EF3274181D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>released to the public;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1455985EEE4644BEBB9FC8DABAAD3B09"><enum>(2)</enum><text>disclosed to any person, except for—</text>
<subparagraph id="H48FE83CFAFDC4A0F83F226365B11BCCD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such disclosures as are necessary to comply with this Act;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H846BCAE22BB34DF0A312492F38DA4936"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disclosures of information regarding a particular person to that person; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H30293C876BEF466A8C576C1E996AE479"><enum>(C)</enum><text>disclosures pursuant to litigation; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F73022EAF5F4AF3A22EC00A82BB8B4B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>subject to disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the Freedom of Information Act), except for disclosures of information regarding a particular person to that person.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H6AF2A6ABC2AA421F91B0083FFE2098AC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Byrne JAG grant reduced for failure to report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In the case of a State or unit of local government that received a grant award under subpart 1 of part E of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3750">42 U.S.C. 3750 et seq.</external-xref>), if that State or unit of local government fails substantially to comply with the requirement under section 2 for a fiscal year, the Attorney General shall reduce the amount that would otherwise be awarded to that State or unit of local government under such grant program in the following fiscal year by 10 percent.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

