<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5BE2026458164484AEFD4DC8EE12B27D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4765 IH: Securing our Border Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4765</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250725">July 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reprogram all remaining unobligated funds from the IRS enforcement account.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDEDE26A8A164403381B5B99A2A18C880" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HDFBE42F30FAD4DA3BB0A4783D9A505AF"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing our Border Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0F5ACAA01BD64C3BA680120C3B671C4E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H01E4B619AB2742D39D89BA6C77BBC8A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>United States border security is paramount to the general welfare of our Nation and ensures the efficient and meaningful flow of goods and individuals through legal means.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB21C581DC18E4AC4AEA5965EE5649240"><enum>(2)</enum><text>During 2023, an estimated 105,007 drug overdose deaths occurred in the United States.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBB961E9BE40C47C48A6A830C2C61934F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Only 2 percent of passenger vehicles and 20 percent of commercial vehicles crossing the southern border are scanned by nonintrusive inspection technology through a radiation portal monitor.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC8F4114F3224A51A087E0A2E15E2D5F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>During fiscal year 2023, U.S. Customs and Border Protection agents processed more than 1,081,030 passengers and pedestrians.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD7038E88BA8C485BB7D603AACAC059FF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Limiting the amount of deadly illicit narcotics, including fentanyl, from entering the United States would reduce the number of Americans who die annually from the use of such narcotics.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6836D115EDA14A4E8A68340990C3420F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Because of the failure to update nonintrusive inspection technologies at land ports of entry along the southern border of the United States, there has been an increase in the amount of illicit narcotics, such as fentanyl, being trafficked across the southern border.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0A9C77E77A5745EAA1198832D70FB84D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The amount of illicit drugs seized by U.S. Customs and Border Protection along the southwest border was approximately—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86F1959CACF94CE09236D22DE5723970"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">241,000 pounds during fiscal year 2023; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H60D010801E7C495EA1109319B1922231"><enum>(B)</enum><text>275,000 pounds during fiscal year 2024.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB49001F8DB5D4CBF8B8759BD99F292A4"><enum>(8)</enum><text>U.S. Customs and Border Protection agents had 2,135,005 encounters along the southern border during fiscal year 2024, including—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC4247ADB69E5445586F9A8049DF0CA0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>1,218,880 single adults;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB40C1DAAB8F345609B1D29B84053E23E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>804,456 family units; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H397089FB1B7741629334D2D8C9813E68"><enum>(C)</enum><text>109,998 unaccompanied minors.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D23B27D0A8F4583A04A32388B9B7ED6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>According to the Department of Homeland Security, 750 migrants died attempting to cross the southern border during fiscal year 2022, which is—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC6CF129607A649BFA39DAD2D8057AC44"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">more migrant deaths than occurred in any previous fiscal year; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD5F140FC10D6457CAEBDBAD3E1D1ACBC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">more than 200 more migrant deaths than the number of such deaths during fiscal year 2021.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4D45A9E038704D459E01CC79C1A67FA0"><enum>(10)</enum><text>As of September 30, 2024, the immigration court backlog was 3,558,995 cases.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H521FA8ACC1534F60B012FC8997927297"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Since the end of fiscal year 2019, U.S. Customs and Border Protection has reported 2,371 encounters with potential terrorists at ports of entry along the southern and northern borders.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0627500661BA4B42B72BAAA8C5167E4E"><enum>(12)</enum><text>According to U.S. Customs and Border Protection onboard staffing data, approximately 2,700 additional U.S. Customs and Border Protection officers need to be stationed at United States ports of entry to fully staff such ports.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA8320A7981243B99C3E818F3BEFE97A"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Due to shifting priorities, construction delays, a lack of available technology solutions, and funding constraints, most southern U.S. Border Patrol sectors still rely on obsolete systems or technologies.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H3E901102BABE443996D721831C528716"><enum>3.</enum><header>Funding for nonintrusive border inspections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">One-third of the unobligated balances (as of the date of the enactment of this Act) from amounts made available under section 10301(1)(A)(ii) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/169">Public Law 117–169</external-xref> shall be transferred to U.S. Customs and Border Protection during the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and ending on February 6, 2034, for nonintrusive inspection systems to achieve a 100 percent nonintrusive inspection scanning rate at all northern border and southwest border land ports of entry by February 6, 2034.</text></section> <section id="HF90BD444487D4520851F39231709C8A7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Funding for border wall construction</header> <subsection id="H5AFCEB25650641D6AC29C875EDA8C4CF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two-thirds of the unobligated balances (as of the date of the enactment of this Act) from amounts made available under section 10301(1)(A)(ii) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/169">Public Law 117–169</external-xref> shall be transferred to the Department of Homeland Security during the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and ending on February 6, 2034, for activities related to the construction of a border wall system along the southwest international border of the United States.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HCFAEFE8A9B6741758A48A302854FC753"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Quarterly reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit quarterly reports to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that contains—</text> <paragraph id="HE8B86A1C1545446EB996DF3B7BCD1892"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an implementation plan with benchmarks related to stemming illegal immigration; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8C0C392E4BA74818BF72F54041825E23"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cost estimates associated with border wall system construction.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section commented="no" id="H1EB4C548363344E69E85FF9519DDDBC7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization to provide bonuses to U.S. Customs and Border Protection agents</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H499D6115EB584E2F832E6E5270D08F6F"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recruitment bonuses</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4FA11B9BBE1F48FEAD5342F58344A093"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the approval of the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection may pay a recruitment bonus, not to exceed $15,000, to each newly hired U.S. Customs and Border Protection agent after—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H79A6E7008BE3491C8BAB23821F9FFC57"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the agent completes initial basic training; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H66A1FAE349454F49A318D61A515AC9DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the execution of a written agreement described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9930031441C6404E8EF7A9AA8B8CB382"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Written agreement</header><text>A written agreement described in this paragraph is a legally binding agreement between a newly hired agent and U.S. Customs and Border Protection that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H34C50BE97D844E6E9130AFCE77DDD965"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specifies the amount of the bonus payment to be paid to such agent, including the timing of such payment;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE605E39917144C53B8A199C1431CEC65"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the length of the period of service required to be completed before such agent is entitled to retain such payment; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7605D1CA75F949A3AC7934EE65B744D6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other terms and conditions to which such payment is subject.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H160F6B68B11E4FBDA4BB7A8EAF8451CD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Retention bonuses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the approval of the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection may pay annual retention bonuses, not to exceed 15 percent of the agent's basic pay, to U.S. Border Patrol agents after the completion of each year of satisfactory service, as determined by the Commissioner.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E98320A52D04CBDBB82918E26E83112"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Relocation bonus</header><text>Subject to the approval of the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection may pay a relocation bonus, not to exceed 15 percent of the agent's annual basic pay, to a U.S. Customs and Border Protection agent who agrees to be transferred and to serve for not less than 3 years at the new duty station.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCAC46205380C42C1962133CF95B9C320"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Limitation</header><text>None of the bonuses paid to a U.S. Customs and Border Protection agent pursuant to subsections (a) through (c) may be considered part of the basic pay of such agent for any purpose, including for retirement or in computing a lump-sum payment to the agent for accumulated and accrued annual leave under section 5551 or 5552 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H4E495F422ECD4C64A522C6AB7D48A0B9"><enum>6.</enum><header>Treatment of aliens arriving from contiguous territory</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 235(b)(2)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1225">8 U.S.C. 1225(b)(2)(C)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>may return</quote> and all that follows and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB8F88B2F736D4B3DA95CD9F8196CD11A"><text>shall—</text> <clause id="H7A0FBA7A52DC41088972952D67AB9520"><enum>(i)</enum><text>return the alien to such territory, or to a safe third country (as described in section 208), pending the completion of a proceeding under section 240; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H1DBA31D21C684F04A51E92409DCFEEB2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>detain the alien for further consideration of an application for asylum, which shall include a determination of credible fear of persecution.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

