<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB92C87C3768D49BF95B70AD39742D288" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 403 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that public servants should be commended for their dedication and continued service to the United States during Public Service Recognition Week and throughout the year.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 403</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250509">May 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that public servants should be commended for their dedication and continued service to the United States during Public Service Recognition Week and throughout the year.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the week of May 4 through May 10, 2025, has been designated as <quote>Public Service Recognition Week</quote> to honor employees of the Federal, State, and local governments and members of the uniformed services for their contributions to the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Public Service Recognition Week provides an opportunity to recognize and promote the important contributions of public servants and to honor the Americans who serve their country, States, and communities at all levels of government and as members of the uniformed services;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas millions of individuals serve the public in government service and as members of the uniformed services in every State, county, and city across the United States and around the world;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public servants provide crucial services to the millions of Americans in their Nation, State, and communities, supporting local programs and contributing to local economies;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public service is a noble calling involving a variety of challenging and rewarding professions and highly skilled and trained individuals offering their knowledge, effort, and skills in support of the public;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States is a great and prosperous country, and public service employees contribute significantly to that greatness and prosperity;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public servants—</text><paragraph id="HC2B40F6823924D9388FD7FF69FB1692F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">defend the freedom of the people of the United States and advance the interests of the United States and the ideals of democracy around the world;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA601C6974FE4CEDA8081301488B2DFE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide vital strategic support functions to the Armed Forces and serve in the National Guard and Reserves;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE53B231D5C54814B0885E04FA35C423"><enum>(3)</enum><text>fight crime and fires;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D5F4D15281946ABA389C4A9D4F2E3A6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure equal access to secure, efficient, and affordable mail service;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6682C7684D46478C9497D477396C59F1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">deliver benefits under the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/301">42 U.S.C. 301 et seq.</external-xref>), including benefits under the Medicare program under title XVIII of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07485190C6D64D3AA795B8E0728ECB7A"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fight disease and promote better health;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H351466710B4B40E6BA0540737946C973"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">protect the environment and the parks of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47E660B003CB41C2993155C899673C7A"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enforce laws guaranteeing equal employment opportunity and healthy working conditions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC6993F2B12A451F929943FFBC5D22D5"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">defend and secure critical infrastructure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49D8FF97A1F14712A7C6A3527371825C"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">help the people of the United States recover from natural disasters, pandemics, and terrorist attacks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8CF1A556E9224B7DA2A27A526098D581"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">teach and work in schools and libraries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1EB5862850F4817A80F2A6BA3FF5AFC"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop new technologies and explore Earth, the moon, and space to improve knowledge on how the world changes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD14347661E3C4B36BF4FF4EEA307F396"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve and secure transportation systems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E144B2DA8E642FF8AA765E52F8C93C4"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promote economic stability and growth;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H399CF869EF8A4F4E8833D701F333879E"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist veterans of the Armed Forces; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEA1D8CD7E9E447EBBF6908803F5B319"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide critical support to our Nation, States, and communities in a variety of other efforts and endeavors.</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas members of the uniformed services and civilian employees at all levels of government—</text><paragraph id="H691D01685580472686536622FA1E4B2C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide a variety of services that make significant contributions to the general welfare of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98D44D749EB44682B746F24102B7E7B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are on the front lines in the fight to defeat terrorism and maintain homeland security; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H541FC52AA1524F37874D30C29C2D4992"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">bravely defend the United States and its ideals; and</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the week of May 4 through May 10, 2025, marks the 41st anniversary of Public Service Recognition Week: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HB478E14AE31B41F0951BFB5FDDA84B4E"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H64B488DAED8641EFB208E854757427B7"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H003B4F9844224F69811CBA522E72215C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commends public servants during Public Service Recognition Week for their outstanding contributions to this great country throughout the year;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H34F9E1BA143F42F6B8C99A804A916243"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">salutes government employees and members of the uniformed services for their unyielding dedication to, and enthusiasm for, the public whom they serve;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D5D018664714700A0C5DC20AAE75248"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">honors government employees and members of the uniformed services who have given their lives in service to their communities and their country;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H205A1AC4B985448983FA620F3B2C4F56"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages efforts to promote and celebrate public service careers at every level of government; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4409A7ECDBBB42098168E0A9C74BE1AF"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses gratitude to the public servants who have selflessly answered the call to serve their country, State, or communities.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

