<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE33FC2BB57B649E3A4B6A0B172B5CA2A" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 239 IH: Raising awareness of the racial disparities in the impact of colorectal cancer on the Black community.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 239</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250321">March 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Raising awareness of the racial disparities in the impact of colorectal cancer on the Black community.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas colorectal cancer, or CRC, is the third-most common cancer in the United States for men and women combined, and the second-leading cause of cancer death;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas this disease takes the lives of more than 50,000 people each year; </text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the rate of CRC is 20 percent higher among Black men and is 14 percent higher among Black women than compared to non-Hispanic Whites; </text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the rate of CRC death is 40 percent higher among Black men and is 25 percent higher among Black women than compared to non-Hispanic Whites; </text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas CRC is the third-leading cause of cancer death in both Black men and women in the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Black Americans have the lowest 5-year survival rate for CRC of any racial group in the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas deaths from colorectal cancer among people younger than 55 have increased 1.9 percent per year from 2011 to 2019;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the tragic death of 43-year-old actor Chadwick Boseman from colorectal cancer has catalyzed more conversation about CRC’s impact on the Black community;</text></whereas> 
<whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, by 2030, it is expected that CRC will be the leading cause of death among people ages 20 to 49; </text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas it is estimated that 19 percent of racial disparity in CRC death rates between White and Black Americans is due to lower screening rates alone; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas CRC has a 90-percent survival rate when caught at the earliest stage and there are many screening methods available: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HCAE566E7212842A58FB8585FC94BB06E"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H71AE728FB9394A2B9E62F06B107C4502"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H50FFA22741884AA8A96756157D29745C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the deadly impact colorectal cancer has to the American people;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA9FBCCF064F41BCA27BF1BAA75E6B68"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acknowledges the racial disparity that the Black community faces when dealing with colorectal cancer;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB14C99B223DF462EB5070672422205D7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to continue and expand their work to identify those factors that result in the colorectal racial screening disparity and develop effective strategies to reduce and ultimately eliminate racial disparities in colorectal screening;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9B02E89C45E499D976843BED9F91142"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages everyone get colorectal cancer screening when recommended by the United States Preventive Services Task Force;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0DEA00C7128F4F8BB7677BD9056AB7E4"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to conduct research to determine any environmental factors, and the National Institutes of Health to conduct research into any physiological factors that cause an elevated risk for colorectal cancer in young adults; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H374A486BEF704ADC90A1BFD0A2BB846F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>urges State health plans to quickly adopt new measures to cover colorectal screenings for individuals at a lower age, with special consideration for the Black community and all those at higher risk for colorectal cancer.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

