<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6DE323D458B041C98F554A33AC8367D2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5032 IH: Nitazene Control Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5032</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250822">August 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001322">Mr. Baumgartner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Controlled Substances Act to permanently schedule the class of benzimidazole-opioids known as nitazenes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H312B3FB95CAC4D348CAAC5E34C60698B" style="OLC"><section id="HD492955755934739B1698EB301BE4C27" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nitazene Control Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2D0C6DE6E0C14418A412EF017B478CDC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HA55245C7089E4E678D9BC86860385D3E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Nitazenes are a class of synthetic opioids first synthesized in the 1950s that exhibit extreme potency at the mu-opioid receptor, with some analogs exceeding the potency of fentanyl.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H006933CD76084B748D8CAB7A991712BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) has temporarily or permanently scheduled multiple nitazene compounds under Schedule I of the Controlled Substances Act due to their high abuse potential and lack of accepted medical use.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD696A5FA3E254E109688BD136331D962"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Nitazenes and nitazene analogues have emerged in the illicit drug supply as designer drugs and contribute to overdose and fatal poisonings in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E3C491D79BC483F8827F9DD6FDE2827"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A class-wide permanent scheduling of nitazenes is necessary to preemptively address the proliferation of new analogs, streamline enforcement, and protect public health.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H454001045C924923B402B421C608EF3F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Schedule I classification of nitazenes</header><subsection id="H57CE5D304FB6458F81C8960248037158"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text>Section 202(c) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/812">21 U.S.C. 812(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end of Schedule I the following:</text><quoted-block id="H203F88D634DA42D395BA7C0541B37BFE" style="OLC"><subsection id="H13720D25A0584A75B049989E6BEFF661"><enum>(f)</enum><text>Benzimidazole-opioids, commonly referred to as nitazenes, including any substance (including its salts, isomers, and salts of isomers) that has a chemical structure that is substantially similar to that of etonitazene or isotonitazene, including:</text><paragraph id="H0C2D81C5F2FB41D398EC2BDD395F1E5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A benzimidazole core substituted at the 2-position with a benzyl or substituted benzyl group; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E81DBCB9DF14403A2566433EC88D692"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A basic nitrogen-containing side chain at the 1-position; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99063056D45741769EFD988ADC9C0C84"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Exhibits agonist activity at the mu-opioid receptor.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">Such substances include, but are not limited to: etonitazene, clonitazene, metonitazene, isotonitazene, protonitazene, butonitazene, etodesnitazene, flunitazene, N-pyrrolidino etonitazene, N-desethyl isotonitazene, and N-piperidinyl etonitazene.</continuation-text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA7A114881FF1429F8436ECDA827EE11D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Removal of temporary status</header><text>Any substance included in the amendment to section 202(c) of the Controlled Substances Act made by this section that was temporarily scheduled under section 201(h) of the Controlled Substances Act shall be deemed permanently scheduled and subject to the requirements of Schedule I as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H72C462D8C27D40C3A30ECDC283A99592"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rulemaking authority</header><text>The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, may issue rules to clarify the scope of the nitazene class as necessary to enforce this section, provided such rules are consistent with the chemical definition in subsection (a)(1).</text></subsection><subsection id="H47158C0A8F6D47ABB1F3228B9BE665E7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Research exemption</header><paragraph id="H7C00126B712545F38B102ACD46D48BCB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Notwithstanding the amendments made by subsection (a), a researcher who, as of the date of enactment of this Act, is conducting research involving a substance described in subsection (a) that was not previously listed in Schedule I of section 202(c) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/812">21 U.S.C. 812(c)</external-xref>), shall not be required to obtain a registration under section 303(f) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823(f)</external-xref>) solely due to the inclusion of that substance in Schedule I, provided that:</text><subparagraph id="H3CDCEA89189B4F4C8885DDE66DEC379C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the research is being conducted pursuant to an active investigational new drug (IND) application or other applicable regulatory exemption recognized by the Food and Drug Administration or Drug Enforcement Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA67CBC52A954065B1DCA1E3D455F4A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the research was approved by an institutional review board (IRB) prior to the enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4776E9A7308940D98B1D12E352E8EE9A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the researcher notifies the Attorney General, in a manner determined by the Attorney General, within 90 days of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC92E5400746F4B928B9C8A655A7C0168"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The exemption under paragraph (1) shall remain in effect for a period not to exceed 18 months from the date of enactment, during which time the researcher may apply for a registration under section 303(f), and the Attorney General shall expedite such applications to ensure continuity of research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC667603EA40444C98CA768DC491A788B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to authorize the initiation of new research using substances described in subsection (a) without proper registration and scheduling compliance.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

