<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4066496F84C846DC85D6C5C7000B4652" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2476 IH: Stop Illegal Campaign Coordination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2476</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to treat expenditures as coordinated with a candidate, an authorized committee of a candidate, or a committee of a national, State, or local political party if the making of the expenditures is materially consistent with instructions, directions, guidance, and suggestions from such candidate or committee, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H766653CBEE35428CBAE060ACEA2CF14B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA056433046644BB181C35941C2D8A0EE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Illegal Campaign Coordination Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8E3EE309CC444ECAA8C11C796B1C976B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Treatment of certain expenditures as coordinated expenditures</header> <subsection id="HF03B89B726274FCB8A6850058F333CF6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 315(a) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30116">52 U.S.C. 30116(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1CB6816DB578403FBF0FC1BADEFD5111"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (7)(B)(i), by striking <quote>or their agents</quote> and inserting <quote>or their agents, including expenditures described in paragraph (10),</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71E4959498C0422CA7B69347B374EE7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (7)(B)(ii) by striking <quote>political party,</quote> and inserting <quote>political party, including expenditures described in paragraph (10),</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF370B84312F04729A3C3C570081397EF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="traditional" id="H8AF2780E35994FE4B9FF8BB6689017E2" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HB631444ABDF141F4BD3386590B4A5C6D" indent="up1"><enum>(10)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H81B7913DD9E5467880AB29BAA51586AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (7)(B)(i) and (ii), an expenditure is described in this paragraph if the making of the expenditure is materially consistent with instructions, directions, guidance, or suggestions from a candidate, an authorized committee of a candidate, or a national, State, or local committee of a political party, or from an agent of any such candidate or committee, regardless of whether the instructions, directions, guidance, or suggestions are made available to the general public or are communicated directly or indirectly to the person making the expenditure.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDE314B69958C490292C29D46306DFC04" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To determine whether the making of an expenditure is materially consistent with instructions, directions, guidance, or suggestions from a candidate or committee for purposes of this paragraph, the Commission shall consider each of the factors described in subparagraph (C), and if the Commission determines that one or more of such factors apply with respect to the making of the expenditure, the making of the expenditure shall be presumed to be materially consistent with instructions, directions, guidance, or suggestions from a candidate or committee for purposes of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF98A016CDCAA479293B22F76C52B0F5C" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The factors described in this subparagraph are the following:</text> 
<clause id="H2728D66E6ECD4235B69DC05440D9F803"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Whether the instructions, directions, guidance, or suggestions indicate that information regarding a clearly identified candidate or political party should be communicated or disseminated to voters or any subset of voters.</text></clause> <clause id="HE5DD7C68C766472C95C9855A8C3FBD69"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>In the case of an expenditure consisting of Federal election activity or a communication which disseminates to any person information about a candidate or political party, whether the instructions, directions, guidance, or suggestions include information regarding the target audience for the communication or the information, such as the demographics, location, or political party affiliation of recipients.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H882BCA24684246AA90308BD3377C7019"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Whether the instructions, directions, guidance, or suggestions include suggested methods of making a communication or disseminating information, such as references to the distribution or receipt of direct mail, audio, video, social media, digital, or other media.</text></clause> <clause id="HEE99DAA23A154D8AA5AE97EC7A70667B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>In the case of an expenditure consisting of Federal election activity or a communication which disseminates to any person information about a candidate or political party, whether the instructions, directions, guidance, or suggestions include or are accompanied by any phrase, image, video, or audio is subsequently used, in whole or in part, in communicating or disseminating the information.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9499BC4701EA48B5936D3E55C2E5D3D2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Whether the instructions, directions, guidance, or suggestions containing one or more other factors identified in this subparagraph are set apart using a signal or cue.</text></clause> <clause id="H482B8D48F6044CEE98FCFC1A3EF939EB"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Such other factors as the Commission considers appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0171DDD112794987A061207A0CCF9511"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to expenditures made on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

