<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H15926A3EEC8240FC9855DF5BEF66B39C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3316 IH: Stop Mental Health Stigma in Our Communities Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3316</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250509">May 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for a national
      outreach and education strategy and research to improve behavioral health among the Asian
      American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander population, while addressing stigma against
      behavioral health treatment among such population.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H03864171EA704A34B571B7B38580206E" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HE7A964EECFEC4342A31F405A2F2E8271"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Mental Health Stigma in Our Communities Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA4D17071B2344DBBB7A489516D3E5929"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="HE2A6C249EB5947EAAE301E228221A6AB">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>AANHPI</header>
 <text>The term <term>AANHPI</term> means Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8EA98769779F40549CF573E2CECEA737"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>Except as otherwise specified, the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H46B2DD60F78E4CA7B49CBBF2527EA54C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HC5411F71B48F41398107C68122F78B12"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The AANHPI community is among the fastest growing population groups in the United States. It is a diverse population representing more than 70 distinct ethnicities, and speaking more than 100 languages and dialects.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC974F0B8D7B40C289C4BFC51198C713"><enum>(2)</enum><text>There is a growing mental health crisis in the United States, particularly for AANHPI individuals. AANHPI individuals with mental health challenges have the lowest rates of mental health service utilization compared to other racial or ethnic populations. In 2023, only 35 percent of Asian adults with a mental health challenge received treatment in the past year. Although suicide is the eleventh leading cause of death, it is the leading cause of death for AANHPI youth. From 2018 to 2023, AANHPI youth between the ages of 10 to 24 years were the only racial or ethnic population in this age category where suicide was the leading cause of death.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFEB30A46903A482980F75731A9263179"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Such mental health disparities within the AANHPI community may be attributed to systemic barriers to accessing mental health services, including stigma attached to mental health, limited availability of and access to culturally and linguistically appropriate services, and insufficient research.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE51E810E419B46CE9AE6FCF1103CE4DC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Insufficient research on AANHPI communities often leads to an inaccurate representation of their experiences and needs. It is imperative to disaggregate AANHPI population data to better understand the range of mental health issues for each subpopulation so that specific culturally and linguistically appropriate solutions can be developed.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFBF1CC101E1042AA9E7AAA7BC1A48C5C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Critical investments are necessary to reduce stigma and improve mental health within AANHPI communities, including increasing culturally and linguistically appropriate outreach education and mental health services, improving representation of AANHPI individuals among the behavioral health workforce, and strengthening disaggregated data collection in research.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H4C12D4B0AAC44AF5B3DB3F0887ECD9FA"><enum>4.</enum><header>National AANHPI behavioral health outreach and education strategy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part D of title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290dd">42 U.S.C. 290dd et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF6EA347E5AB54D19AFD7E30A81A87D74">
<section id="HC76886CE123743C58665C79B8A66EFDF"><enum>554.</enum><header>National AANHPI behavioral health outreach and education strategy</header>
<subsection id="HA0F102DD75A04D9A85C8E64925BAC31C">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary, shall, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Minority Health, the Director of the National Institutes of Health, and the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and in consultation with advocacy and behavioral health organizations serving populations of Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander individuals or communities, develop and implement a national outreach and education strategy to promote behavioral health and reduce stigma associated with mental health and substance use disorders within the Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander population. Such strategy shall—</text>
            <paragraph id="H6E80395755D64D36A1DF9BF0912CEFEF">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>be designed to meet the diverse cultural and language needs and preferences of the various Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander populations;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H7D92261AFB49426AA41737A144F5F7DF">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>be developmentally and age appropriate;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H550F4E2364764EEF987C4787183A0CDE"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>increase awareness of symptoms of mental illnesses common within subgroups of such population, taking into account differences within subgroups, such as gender, gender identity, age, sexual orientation, culture, or ethnicity;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HB2B8D272392944C28E18B82E4C5BCD80">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>provide information, in a publicly accessible manner, on evidence-based, culturally and linguistically appropriate, and adapted interventions and treatments;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H819FF4D815A447BEB8D6831A0A7FBE3E">
              <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>ensure full participation of, and engage, both consumers and community members in the development and implementation of materials; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H0CA10F5CE185427084C27DFB7A07F824">
              <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>seek to broaden the perspective among both individuals in Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander communities and stakeholders serving such communities to use a comprehensive public health approach to promoting behavioral health that addresses a holistic view of health by focusing on the intersection between behavioral and physical health.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
<subsection id="HDD9555863AF1488FAD87E058AF1DB709">
            <enum>(b)</enum>
            <header>Reports</header>
 <text>Beginning not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Stop Mental Health Stigma in Our Communities Act of 2025</short-title> and annually thereafter, the Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary, shall submit to Congress, and make publicly available, a report on the extent to which the strategy developed and implemented under subsection (a) increased awareness among the Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander population of mental health and substance use disorders.</text>
          </subsection>
<subsection id="HDF3B1B34073D4DBF9967013711A7957D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HCA52A2AE8655455F9EC79D66CAC5310C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Systematic review of and report on the AANHPI youth behavioral health crisis</header> <subsection id="H6F29C5F204A642FAAB9CD84482F1DA08"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Systematic review</header> <paragraph id="HFABCA180E2CC4623A5B56F9773EB11C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, in coordination with the Director of the National Institutes of Health, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and the Director of the Office of Minority Health, shall conduct a systematic review of behavioral health among AANHPI youth.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7272327DD413436B967531F0FAC9B30B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Such systematic review required under paragraph (1) shall include an assessment of—</text> <subparagraph id="HBCEFEB672EC94494936F4490BE38C129"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the prevalence, risk factors, and root causes of mental health challenges, substance misuse, and mental health and substance use disorders among AANHPI youth;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H252B20B9C3014BE6978BE872858B8054"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the prevalence and methods of attempted suicide, nonfatal substance use overdose, and death by suicide or substance use overdose among AANHPI youth; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H584F3EF8DCEF4DD79ACA50403820FCFC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>AANHPI youth that received treatment for mental health and substance use disorders.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H3D0AD24075F4458185DB7FD412B20314"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and make publicly available, a report on the findings of the systematic review conducted under subsection (a), including—</text> <paragraph id="H91EF6540C7264AE6B02C60E6AD3C9D6F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identification of the barriers to accessing behavioral health prevention, treatment, and recovery services for AANHPI youth;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8C8A67F66CA542FBAE443168E9CC9F7D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identification of root causes of mental health challenges and substance misuse among AANHPI youth;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4046BB130DB44B6A226FAD6616C9086"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations for evidence-based actions to be taken by the Secretary to improve behavioral health among AANHPI youth;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD690CA81BB1043BD87A3B28D257BAE37"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations for legislative or administrative action to improve the behavioral health of AANHPI youth experiencing depression, suicide, and overdose, and to reduce the prevalence of depression, suicide, overdose, and other behavioral health conditions among AANHPI youth; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H12CFBF93F749433B9AD7EE002AEA6898"><enum>(5)</enum><text>such other recommendations as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H4A5DD540D6444AE783745F5E9960E64B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data</header><text>Any data included in the systematic review or report under this section shall be disaggregated by race, ethnicity, age, sex, gender identity, sexual orientation, geographic region, disability status, and other relevant factors, in a manner that protects personal privacy and that is consistent with applicable Federal and State privacy law.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H76B3C055222748DAB9F4DD9C2BBF4CDB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>For purposes of carrying out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $1,500,000 for fiscal year 2026.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HDDD079A8A770448ABC0DCE7BC92585F5"><enum>6.</enum><header>Systematic review of and report on strategies on the AANHPI behavioral health workforce shortage</header>
<subsection id="H09F142F8BD6D40A580606C7199C4ADC3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Systematic review</header>
<paragraph id="H7E6C198B71B54503AB3A4FC610E10373"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, in coordination with the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, the Secretary of Labor, and the Director of the Office of Minority Health, shall conduct a systematic review of strategies for increasing the behavioral health workforce that identify as AANHPI.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E3CAE37F579469B9C91ABBAA79F3875"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Such systematic review required under paragraph (1) shall include an assessment of—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1B6E0E0AB68D45898AD477628AA6A3D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total number of behavioral health workers in the United States who identify as AANHPI;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6F97255024E744CABDFC18FCB8745FB7"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>with respect to each such worker, information regarding the current type of license, geographic area of practice, and type of employer (such as hospital, Federally-qualified health center, school, or private practice);</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA9DD7BAFEB7F469FBB06670C860BD9D6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information regarding the cultural and linguistic capabilities of such workers, including languages spoken proficiently;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6AF93AD14EED4D73A38250ED3B0CF6CF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the relevant barriers to enrollment in behavioral health professional education programs and entering the behavioral health workforce for AANHPI individuals; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC9EDC12EEDB5417A8FA6C78939DFA3CB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the total number of behavioral health workers who identify as AANHPI and who participate in Federal programs that seek to increase, train, and support the behavioral health workforce.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEEBF40310DB249D98FC6143AFB237A49"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and make publicly available, a report on the findings of the systematic review conducted under subsection (a), including—</text>
<paragraph id="H8B526EF7FF564EB09ACB4623D0BC75E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identification of AANHPI behavioral health workers’ knowledge and awareness of the barriers to quality behavioral health care services faced by AANHPI individuals, including stigma, limited English proficiency, and lack of health insurance coverage;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB3D7C61C0F4D4F1EA6BDAD3BC47E1BB2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations for actions to be taken by the Secretary to increase the number of AANHPI behavioral health workers;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8AB4D032EAF4460CB773738EEC1224E4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations for legislative or administrative action to improve the enrollment of AANHPI individuals in behavioral health workforce education and training programs; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H623486FDFAF14830972F54A9621650B8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>such other recommendations as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HAC6FAB8ECFE04AEE9EDF951611BCB87C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data</header><text>Any data included in the systematic review or report under this section shall be disaggregated by race, ethnicity, age, sex, gender identity, sexual orientation, geographic region, disability status, and other relevant factors, in a manner that protects personal privacy and that is consistent with applicable Federal and State privacy law.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H89E41B9062E04359AD4BAFC5D59466EE"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definition</header><text>In this section the term <term>behavioral health worker</term> means any individual licensed or certified to provide mental health or substance use disorder services, including in the professions of social work, psychology, psychiatry, marriage and family therapy, mental health counseling, peer support, and substance use disorder counseling.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H685BE825A40B41E6BE7FAD3E0CCA2375"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>For purposes of carrying out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $1,500,000 for fiscal year 2026.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

