<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BUR25570-L7G-1G-K0C"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1947 IS: Opposing the Cultivation and Trade of Octopus Produced through Unethical Strategies Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1947</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250604">June 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</sponsor> (for himself and
                    <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>) introduced the following
                bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and
                Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce from
            authorizing commercial octopus aquaculture operations in the United States, the
            exclusive economic zone, and the waters of the United States, and for other
 purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Opposing the Cultivation and Trade of Octopus Produced through Unethical Strategies Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>OCTOPUS Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id288e0cb52d0540c0b1cfab611fb37054"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id5183b60d80c743a2b8916b664d795249"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commercial octopus aquaculture</header><text>The term <term>commercial octopus aquaculture</term> means the farming of octopuses to be slaughtered for human consumption or use and sold through marketplaces.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8b75c05ae3e4449eb9d4b09a3963df12"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusive economic zone</header><text>The term <term>exclusive economic zone</term> means the zone established by Presidential Proclamation Number 5030, dated March 10, 1983 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1453">16 U.S.C. 1453</external-xref> note; relating to the exclusive economic zone of the United States of America).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idEE4B1B1FBB224F629B859FFC79D0378A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Octopus</header><text>The term <term>octopus</term> means a member of the order Octopoda.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaf283d05a9cc405c99232721ad3e10ce"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reexport</header><text>The term <term>reexport</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1742 of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD6B9643A096E4AC9888CC8FAA7954DBD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>United States</header><text>The term <term>United States</term> means the 50 States, the District of Columbia, and the territories and possessions of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4f4efa0a38b7440c9d03047b6a51a310"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Waters of the United States</header><text>The term <term>waters of the United States</term> has the meaning given that term in section 120.2 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="id180A4E563CA043C5BB24D7FC93B15413"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on authorizing commercial octopus aquaculture</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id81fca89d61e74e1e92471d59f9284179"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not issue any permit or in any other way authorize any person to conduct commercial octopus aquaculture operations in the United States, the exclusive economic zone of the United States, or the waters of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida1e5dc678129425ab17716179836ace9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall coordinate with the Secretary of Interior to ensure commercial octopus aquaculture is not permitted or authorized through the United States Fish and Wildlife Service or any other department; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide0a2f9000e2949ccae2cd94b7526c31d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and jointly with the Secretary of the Interior, shall issue a final rule to prohibit commercial octopus aquaculture operations in the United States, the exclusive economic zone of the United States, and the waters of the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id3488A259933747359558DEA3C616E4A4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on importation and reexport of commercially farmed or aquacultured
 octopus</header><subsection id="idabdaabdc475545249975932af71e4277"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following are prohibited:</text><paragraph id="idC49A049FE3424A2094598ACD03D2981C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The importation into the United States of commercially aquacultured octopus, including any living or dead specimens, parts, or derivatives, or any product containing specimens, parts, or derivatives of such octopus.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3A4EF75D82BE44A6ABECCD46B3063F5E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The reexport of octopus described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id72BBFDE89D0A46C58E3E3370FD6271C8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) applies with respect to articles entered, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="id71f36ae678c54bae8a3cc64948c42841"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Any person who violates subsection (a) shall, for each violation, be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $100,000, or the fair market value of the octopus involved, whichever is greater.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideb8d85b692714607a16e0acfc9d981b0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce, in coordination with the Secretary of the Interior and in consultation with the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, shall issue a final rule to prohibit octopus described by subsection (a)(1) from being imported into or reexported from the United States.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id708C127AC5F64B85B67E3EA031002345"><enum>5.</enum><header>Certification upon importation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A person that imports into the United States an octopus, including any living or dead specimens, parts, or derivatives, or any product containing specimens, parts, or derivatives of such octopus, shall certify on the date of importation that such octopus is not a commercially aquacultured octopus.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="ida80e9652d0e142aeab97c1d89cb4870f"><enum>6.</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Sections 3, 4, and 5 shall not apply with respect to octopus that are used solely—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75DCB43ECA694B91BD359B6CEAF81F32"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for public display by an accredited or licensed aquarium or zoo;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2A985405B7044E75800F276579434754"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in a breeding program of an accredited or licensed aquarium or zoo; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9716A81D48604FB380DC52FB66696CDA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for research purposes carried out by an accredited or licensed aquarium or zoo, a museum, a college, a university, a Federal or State agency, or any other person under a State or Federal permit to conduct noncommercial scientific research.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id760D2C828EE1414F9B04DCE24F387850"><enum>7.</enum><header>Reporting of harvest methods for octopus imports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall ensure that one or more trade programs of the National Marine Fisheries Service require the reporting of harvest methods for imports of octopus, including any value-added product that is composed fully or partially of octopus.</text></section></legis-body></bill>


