<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB97ADB18CC624E2487C9049B4B05EBC1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4394 IH: the Compliant Operations of Decentralized Entities Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4394</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250715">July 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to develop a public-private partnership program to examine innovative anti-money laundering solutions for decentralized finance services, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4BAED7BFAF2C4D23BAF877280D2833D3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDFA6466B26BF4095957FB41A841C4631" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>the Compliant Operations of Decentralized Entities Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>the CODE Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HB4A4D7CEDB374575AB75F9C786994607"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HAA234016DDC24BE9A4C9825AB5247604"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2019, under the Trump Administration, the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network issued guidance (FIN–2019–G001) to clarify that decentralized finance applications may be required to register with the agency and comply with the Bank Secrecy Act, including anti-money laundering, recordkeeping, and reporting requirements.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8265F7239AA942E0B947C05864C215C7">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>In 2019, under the Trump Administration, the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network published an advisory (FIN–2019–A003) noting that the prevalence of unregistered cryptocurrency entities without sufficient anti-money laundering controls enables illicit activity that threatens national security.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H35412BF9A4DF46D09D683D8F2F775E7E">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>In 2022, under the Biden Administration, the Federal Bureau of Investigation published a public service announcement (I–082922–PSA) encouraging decentralized finance services to institute real-time analytics, monitoring, and rigorous testing of the computer code to more quickly identify vulnerabilities and respond to indicators of suspicious activity.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4F49031D4AB74330BFA13ECE17B060C9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In 2023, under the Biden Administration, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission issued a report (<quote>Decentralized Finance</quote>), advocating for building regulatory compliance into decentralized finance systems and noting that areas like illicit finance compliance and cybersecurity are ripe for this kind of near-term action by software developers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65F3AE81C988496A830C95E773822E88"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Decentralized finance services may be subject to Bank Secrecy Act requirements, but there is a lack of standardization across decentralized finance services and compliance processes.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE7E6CBD270E4184BFC6708B7DD1F49E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Decentralized finance services present unique cybersecurity risks and have been vulnerable to exploitation campaigns by North Korean threat actors.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF644ACBBC2F45EABEACBF2E34E296F4"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Decentralized finance services and the broader cryptocurrency ecosystem could benefit from a set of technological controls that are coherent, consistent, and capable of satisfying Bank Secrecy Act requirements.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HEFB3337AE72949E5BFF0416605DE12AC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Public-private partnership program for decentralized finance services</header> 
<subsection id="H15397CAF5D514DB099D3444A9F74703A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network, the Office of Foreign Assets Control, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the United States Secret Service, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, and such other relevant agencies as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, shall develop a public-private partnership program with decentralized finance services and relevant risk management experts to—</text> <paragraph id="HBCF58D8C8F6D40C199F8E391CDAF89D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">focus on decentralized finance applications and front-end user interfaces;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9BD657802D7B43BC8C90769728D2DBB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider integrating anti-money laundering, identity verification, sanctions, and cybersecurity controls and other technological solutions into decentralized smart contracts prior to deployment on a public blockchain network;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD10B58ECD49346C68831414BDCE87688"><enum>(3)</enum><text>test the capabilities of such integrated controls in decentralized smart contracts;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2B1585F0B5F0452D95D739147661B5A8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>consider establishing a regulatory gateway to external, verifiable data inputs and outputs that are capable of upgrading smart contract behavior after it has been deployed; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H210DA303B4E7446C8C0BCC132122A18C"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide legislative and regulatory recommendations related to integrated compliance mechanisms for decentralized finance services.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA10636FF57134717B9C58A6740CA2E31"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on certain participants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Participants selected for the public-private partnership program required under subsection (a) shall not include a decentralized finance service owned or controlled, directly or indirectly, by a covered person.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7489F35B402D40ADB202DDAD36445D2B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The public-private partnership program developed under subsection (a) shall terminate 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD39BED90838A4D749145BEC2423B95C3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in subsection (a) shall be construed to limit, impair, or otherwise affect the supervisory, regulatory, or enforcement authority or the jurisdiction of the agencies described in subsection (a) under any applicable law.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H607FF503FD2341E7A8421D9EF322A467"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Interagency coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall share the recommendations provided pursuant to subsection (a)(5) with other appropriate agencies, and such agencies shall take the recommendations into account when issuing rules or carrying out supervisory functions.</text> </subsection> </section> 
<section id="H2EAABEE249F040D49205502B5C85982E"><enum>4.</enum><header>FinCEN advisory</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network shall publish an advisory related to the responsible development, deployment, and ongoing operation of decentralized finance services on a public blockchain network for the purposes of strengthening compliance with the Bank Secrecy Act.</text></section> <section id="H19068A3154594D6891F7686578819C19"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rulemaking to modernize and strengthen Bank Secrecy Act requirements for decentralized finance services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall issue a rule to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H332C03BF014749F185C7B100F099D15C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>further define the terms <quote>decentralized finance service</quote> and <quote>decentralized smart contract</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF26FCBA10124A8481BA718A77D398DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expressly require that a decentralized finance service implements and maintains—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0CDB26D5FE3246AEAC424FD25CBB00B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a risk-based anti-money laundering program that meets the requirements under the Bank Secrecy Act; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9CFEE0478A8B4FFE857FA91AF4D043DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a risk-based sanctions compliance program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H30CDBAA16F8C4423B2D40D26AB98AED0"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H8B949034B4474867B73B03B43A41272F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bank Secrecy Act</header><text>The term <quote>Bank Secrecy Act</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD0DA88B98E17445282490951D26AFA14"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 21 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1829b">12 U.S.C. 1829b</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H42E589A32587409DA77FFDF094885A06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>chapter 2 of title I of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/91/508">Public Law 91–508</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1951">12 U.S.C. 1951 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2D3F5D3A77174130981C0F486EE3387C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73BD705E85284D88B576F54647BACC74" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered person</header><text>The term <quote>covered person</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H22090D2D76ED429A98449050BB1075F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the President;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2AC21B65BD4A4E13B1C2103D91F56121"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Vice President;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9EDB33E2799C43AF9C01E157699679AA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a Member of Congress;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H77AD7C3059F443F09C6F5A5952920A1D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a senior executive branch employee; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8F386435D3D44F918BFBA6CAB64E8A58"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the spouse, child, son-in-law, or daughter-in-law, as determined under applicable common law, of any individual described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H191A81F6B4F5413099354FF54000B388"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Decentralized finance service</header><text>The term <quote>decentralized finance service</quote> means a protocol, application, or service that, through the use of decentralized smart contracts deployed on a public blockchain network, facilitates digital asset transactions or the exchange of digital assets for other digital assets or fiat currency and may include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4D2891CC3A664B8AAD3224E7275E555D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a peer-to-peer digital asset trading platform;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD053D2B932C64BF2A4E3B73BD2D09D7C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a digital asset lending protocol;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H420162B876214B428C3266ED4A87A3D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a digital asset staking or liquidity service;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBB5011D2036841829D81775C51519EB7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a digital asset mixing service;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H88B47F62ADC34C5CBFB0A7B675049BFD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a cross-chain bridge service provider; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF3F3A1294410481595B4C76FF3F9FFEF"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other decentralized finance service determined by the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9C95ADA5432C4F829DB2CDF0AAA68E7A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Decentralized smart contract</header><text>The term <quote>decentralized smart contract</quote> means a digital contract or collections of computer code on a public blockchain network that are automatically executed if specific conditions are met.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD8ACFE0173454EFDB2AF2F0BDA3B42FC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Public blockchain network</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>public blockchain network</quote> means an open source, decentralized, permissionless distributed ledger system that records digital asset transactions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F601A231BB5471F86ADB3391DA0DCB0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Risk management expert</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>risk management expert</quote> means a person or entity with specialized knowledge or expertise in identifying, preventing, and managing illicit finance, cybersecurity, or compliance risks associated with decentralized finance services, and may include—</text> <subparagraph id="HFDEBA0693DF340CABE3E362C0D32B139"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an identity verification software provider;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8DE7BE8C364A460D8D13826D6A2FBB0A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a fraud detection service;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H828E31F68A584DAE92C9E35CA688F187"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a blockchain analytics firm;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA19287581D8249CEA5DBF9CDB9FF0BFA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a smart contract auditor;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9332324F961D477BB19F70E6BA8912F9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a blockchain oracle service;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAD4E1F13B91B475586A2885C0CF819FA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a blockchain cybersecurity service; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1D84BE7153324B96BB5C49D1FEF093C4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any other relevant risk management experts as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5E6E8414B5E14E82BB725EFE61446396"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Senior executive branch employee</header><text>The term <quote>senior executive branch employee</quote> means an executive branch employee—</text> <subparagraph id="H21712CD5F508430285B24F0E3C28EDAC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who is employed in a position listed in section 5312 of title 5, United States Code, or for which the rate of pay is equal to the rate of pay payable for level I of the Executive Schedule;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H73C0C42A912640C4862F6213B766DD3D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who is employed in a position—</text> <clause id="HC8190F9DACBC415F873752A6ADF32CA7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the Executive Office of the President; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBF5B081765724AA69C18FA948BD7A195"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">listed in section 5313 of title 5, United States Code, or for which the rate of pay is equal to the rate of pay payable for level II of the Executive Schedule;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBE0A94275488460094337D45264E08BF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>who is appointed by the President pursuant to section 105(a)(2)(A) of title 3, United States Code; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA2A0111D8AA84E8A96554E1D3002A707"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who is appointed by the Vice President pursuant to section 106(a)(1)(A) of title 3, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </section> </legis-body></bill>

