<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCC25A13-HX8-7M-X3C"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2277 IS: GPS Resiliency Report Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2277</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250715">July 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Defense to submit a report on risks to the Global Positioning System and associated positioning, navigation, and timing services.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>GPS Resiliency Report Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id35928345417E4A69A0E5082E5F261ACC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on risks to Global Positioning System and associated positioning, navigation, and timing services</header><subsection id="id25e6f00af71d4813976bbe6303edad2e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on risks to the Global Positioning System and associated positioning, navigation, and timing services.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id04dbfb39ee4c48389c78fea835c31203"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="ide9d737a8e5f348fd82bd0b7c1c87fe30"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of risks posed by a lack of access to the Global Positioning System and associated positioning, navigation, and timing services during a potential conflict in which the United States involved or in the case of an attack on a United States ally. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddfb4880d0abf4958b404a1e1a94bb27b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of risks to United States allies from a disruption of access to the Global Positioning System and associated positioning, navigation, and timing services provided by the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a8febeb4d094c7ea1d9a8eb728f5f6b"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of each of the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id93f47b4859c44fdca56ce3e4cef7491e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The capabilities of competitor countries, including the People's Republic of China, the Russian Federation, Iran, and the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea, to degrade or deny United States access to the Global Positioning System and associated positioning, navigation, and timing services during a potential conflict with the United States or in the case of an attack on a United States ally.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb885e872c6144387bae292c7706ddfe6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Current Department of Defense efforts to develop or procure technology or systems to provide redundant global positioning and positioning, navigation, and timing capabilities, including space-based and terrestrial-based (including quantum sensing technology) efforts.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id92405c176c4c403598c705fb71080424"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The ability of the Resilient Global Positioning System (R–GPS) program of the Space Force to achieve, not later than 10 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, full capacity to provide Global Positioning System resilience to existing United States satellites.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id10ff0b62b52247d1a7e20a69648eccbb"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A framework for developing a full-scale terrestrial-based Global Positioning System redundancy system that could be operational not later than 15 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddba28003ad0344b4970e92e7944f219c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3bd3df40e9684b37b94ef0c192004058"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcca5ab98924745d18ec234c4a9e5b388"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc15c6f7849ba4a53bb6352a1d901e15b"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services, the Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07ed71462ba44c7bacf000ba1e670b2c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7efa884350244804a16f72271c1814d6"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States ally</header><text>The term <term>United States ally</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id85a651900e5b4ebda71e9fefe5bec21b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a member country of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id50c7c6fd3e094864b6967a1cb1113712"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a major non-NATO ally (as defined in section 644(q) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2403">22 U.S.C. 2403(q)</external-xref>)); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id83dd27c257d1434398aba2262e02220c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Taiwan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

