<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF6EFE9FF33FF4F82A34829DBFD4CF2CB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4312 IH: Student Compensation and Opportunity through Rights and Endorsements Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4312</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250710">July 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000289">Mr. Jordan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001136">Mrs. McClain</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000471">Mr. Fitzgerald</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000478">Mr. Fry</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect the name, image, and likeness rights of student athletes and to promote fair competition with respect to intercollegiate athletics, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD049D9458EC54F9F8A65EF713C5CA1A4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H626894BD51604540A528A6DB787A9917" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Student Compensation and Opportunity through Rights and Endorsements Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SCORE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H284E1C19D1FF4B248999176A6EA0D2BA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H36878BA3ED6B48F997BAE2395737540C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agent</header><text>The term <term>agent</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H1E7294AE224246BBA14A20E20E49707A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an individual who represents a student athlete with respect to a name, image, and likeness agreement or another agreement for compensation related to the participation of such student athlete on a varsity sports team; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H41724C9F4F644317969CFC1534AB4C5F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include an immediate family member of a student athlete, unless the immediate family member receives payment for representation described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H55E32D2D88064F498F2DD906E582A33D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Antitrust laws</header><text>The term <term>antitrust laws</term> has the meaning given such term in the 1st section of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12</external-xref>) and section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>) to the extent that such section 5 applies to unfair methods of competition.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H535A6E0305124454B2C9BFAB7674020D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Associated entity or individual</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>associated entity or individual</term> means, with respect to an institution—</text> <subparagraph id="HA38C861BFFF24754BA1AB2588C435265"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an entity that is known or should be known to the employees of the athletic department of such institution to exist, in significant part, for the purpose of—</text> 
<clause id="H67160973E1BA45D68FABECD48E0A3BDC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>promoting or supporting the varsity sports teams or student athletes of such institution; or</text></clause> <clause id="H0A9E5A744A984E15930CFA16F42987D2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>creating or identifying opportunities relating to name, image, and likeness agreements solely for the student athletes of such institution;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB4270D13DBF740CEB555ED1524F26690"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an individual who is or has been a member, employee, director, officer, owner, or other representative of an entity described in subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9BCD00224AE9404EA5853465A328A43B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individual who directly or indirectly (including through contributions by an entity affiliated with such individual or an immediate family member of such individual) has contributed more than $50,000 (as adjusted on July 1 each year by the percentage increase (if any), during the preceding 12-month period, in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics) over the lifetime of the individual to the athletic programs of such institution or to an entity described in subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE5EC07594BEF49C3B5C06751F4B245C9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an individual or entity who—</text> <clause id="HDFE3510CD3EA408BAFACE9404402A4EA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is directed or requested by the employees of the athletic department of such institution to assist in the recruitment or retention of prospective student athletes or student athletes, respectively; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9A9C0EC8D228482980C2B40E71F2E0D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>otherwise assists in such recruitment or retention; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6C5DBC627A8F43D1ACF6A13C30E0275C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any entity (other than a publicly traded corporation) owned, controlled, operated by, or otherwise affiliated with an individual or entity described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1A5A68FA08FA455DA8629A721A271165"><enum>(4)</enum><header>College sports revenue</header><text>The term <term>college sports revenue</term> means any revenue (without regard to ownership or legal title to such revenue) received by an institution with respect to intercollegiate athletics—</text> <subparagraph id="HA3B44F45F87D486785C87A8DDF4CB5E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">from the sale of admission to intercollegiate athletic competitions or any other event involving a varsity sports team, including actual monetary revenue received by or for the benefit of such institution for a suite license (unless such suite license is associated with philanthropy or any purpose not related to intercollegiate athletic competitions, including a concert);</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3C5E775476214110BA9A90390A3D2302"><enum>(B)</enum><text>from participation by the varsity sports teams of such institution in intercollegiate athletic competitions held at other institutions, including payments received due to cancellations of such intercollegiate athletic competitions;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5BFB7762A4C549BEB0B2B5F96F44B015"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for radio, television, internet, digital, and e-commerce rights, including revenue relating to media rights distributed by a conference to members of the conference, if applicable;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEF63839A0D3A4FFB8A19176F2B4129D0"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">from an interstate intercollegiate athletic association, including any grant, distribution of revenue, reimbursement relating to travel with respect to a championship of such interstate intercollegiate athletic association, and payment for hosting such a championship;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3D7D3D8A97124E479123115AB8477DB4"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">generated by a post-season football bowl, including any distribution of revenue by a conference to members of the conference and any other payment related to the participation of such institution in such post-season football bowl, including for ticket sales and reimbursement of expenses;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H278D9B4CF0A3432E9F3797BC8887326E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>from a conference, other than any revenue otherwise described in this paragraph;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF196C805BA534E829569002FADE2DD09"><enum>(G)</enum><text>for sponsorships, licensing agreements, advertisements, royalties, and in-kind products and services as part of a sponsorship agreement; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H447E85C444CE49FE9714E19302033F86"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">relating to any additional form of revenue an interstate intercollegiate athletic association uses with respect to the pool limit of such interstate intercollegiate athletic association.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H16328DB22BDA46309820F112C66D8328"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The term <term>compensation</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE3CEDAC174374ED8A65092D95F91E2DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means, with respect to a student athlete or a prospective student athlete, any form of payment or remuneration, whether provided through cash, benefits, awards, or any other means, including payments for—</text> <clause id="H361E0CDE367C4294B9985498DFE6E000"><enum>(i)</enum><text>licenses relating to, or the use of, name, image, and likeness rights; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9215FFAE4AD44B8BA44D42B4FE26AABF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>licenses relating to, or the use of, any other Federal or State intellectual or intangible property right; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF555E3DC2E2C48808C53DFA4EDFB3777"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text> 
<clause id="H2B8837E5F4D3435F81BCFDD198E5CAF7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>grants-in-aid;</text></clause> <clause id="H9C244E9D8FE94BEB81AC94FCA6E24DD6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Federal Pell Grants and other Federal or State grants unrelated to and not awarded with regard to participation in intercollegiate athletics;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA098D207D8A14D92ADC0283371626F62"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">health insurance and payments for the costs of health care, including health insurance and payments for the costs of health care wholly or partly self-funded by an institution, conference, or interstate intercollegiate athletic association;</text></clause> <clause id="HE131A5533F344E7E95347185EE765E44"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>disability and loss-of-value insurance, including disability and loss-of-value insurance that is wholly or partly self-funded by an institution, conference, or interstate intercollegiate athletic association;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA2B950C195ED455CAF9B84F37379C34C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>career counseling, job placement services, and other guidance available to all students at an institution;</text></clause> <clause id="H2E66F07C995943FFBEDDC8E036B5CECB"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>payment of hourly wages and benefits for work actually performed (and not for participation in intercollegiate athletics) at a rate commensurate with the going rate in the locality of an institution for similar work;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H18D5228D2F8E4BC797CB9A65ACB0843F"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>academic awards paid to student athletes by institutions;</text></clause> <clause id="H6B11FDA5603C4B3CA8A90589F1D4F6E4"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>provision of financial literacy or tax education resources and guidance; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF788D88F64B34825866AF3A49111D123"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>any program to connect student athletes with employers and facilitate employment opportunities, if—</text> <subclause id="HFDA597B30CE74712B9286CD010FC1C5F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the financial terms of such employment opportunities are consistent with the terms offered to similarly situated employees who are not student athletes; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9FEC0B8E7D804FBF916B6CAF4E12E007"><enum>(II)</enum><text>such program is not used to induce a student athlete to attend a particular institution.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD9194944FF9C47D6AE7D268009B1C411"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Conference</header><text>The term <term>conference</term> means an entity that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1A860256DFAC4DAFAE714A31C980D19A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has as members 2 or more institutions;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H46A2FC3923EA4544951F4E3C4E89EFA9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>arranges regular season intercollegiate athletic competitions and championships for such members; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9B69095623A5453E87F45B5099C829EA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>sets rules with respect to such intercollegiate athletic competitions and championships.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H32791B4B8D4E46A1AD40A51D2852DBD4"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Cost of attendance</header><text>The term <term>cost of attendance</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H56B6FA24603741B1BF3849695F9204AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given such term in section 472 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087ll">20 U.S.C. 1087ll</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H91CE258BF5D847588EAFB6588B92A759"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is calculated by the financial aid office of an institution applying the same standards, policies, and procedures for all students.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H54A826E4572D4588971910185559DFEA"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Grant-in-aid</header><text>The term <term>grant-in-aid</term> means a scholarship, grant, stipend, or other form of financial assistance, including the provision of tuition, room, board, books, or funds for fees or personal expenses, that—</text> <subparagraph id="HE6A2EDD459D143088160FF134B738287"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is paid or provided by an institution to a student for the undergraduate or graduate course of study of the student; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF3CA23419FAF45A6B6AC968AF5F63C10"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is in an amount that does not exceed the cost of attendance at the institution for such student.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H731A4063EFF441BCA6893320646F0DDA"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Image</header><text>The term <term>image</term> means, with respect to a student athlete, a picture or a video that identifies, is linked to, or is reasonably linkable to such student athlete.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD9B6085B6B0343AB85B8026D48896DDD"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Institution</header><text>The term <term>institution</term> has the same meaning given the term <term>institution of higher education</term> in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H480D22F39AA44C3E992B8EFAC48EAA25"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Intercollegiate athletic competition</header><text>The term <term>intercollegiate athletic competition</term> means any contest, game, meet, match, tournament, regatta, or other event in which varsity sports teams of more than 1 institution compete.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H85D781DEBFD74C6097EBBB044A653D23" commented="no"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Intercollegiate athletics</header><text>The term <term>intercollegiate athletics</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H6D50E77FAD5C4365BC00CFCA549602E6" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means the varsity sports teams for which eligibility requirements for participation by student athletes are established by a conference or an interstate intercollegiate athletic association; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H622A62E721C448299267D2F2459A3AF5" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any recreational, intramural, or club teams.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H30F06CB9308242C3AEEF2C006A451B39"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Interstate intercollegiate athletic association</header><text>The term <term>interstate intercollegiate athletic association</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD1A69A6E7C9F4EBB93A5AC6C66D32A92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any entity incorporated in the United States that—</text> <clause id="H5211B601918646BEB61FFF7C6BD80F49"><enum>(i)</enum><text>sets common rules, standards, procedures, or guidelines for the administration and regulation of varsity sports teams and intercollegiate athletic competitions;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB11DD0EE94814E11AABF7A55061EF025" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is composed of 2 or more institutions or conferences located in more than 1 State; and</text> </clause> <clause id="HFBFFBD0E5DCC424DABED581E711D04A1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has rules or bylaws prohibiting the provision of prohibited compensation to student athletes and prospective student athletes; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0DE658C30FA6439C85DF2ABD4B5F17F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any entity affiliated with professional athletic competitions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDFCA5DB92B0F4438926565F07832DE1E"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Likeness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>likeness</term> means, with respect to a student athlete, a physical or digital depiction or representation that identifies, is linked to, or is reasonably linkable to such student athlete.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1489ADF4AE2347138BAC5103ADC6F416"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Name</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>name</term> means, with respect to a student athlete, the first, middle, or last name, or the nickname or former name, of such student athlete if used in a context that identifies, is linked to, or is reasonably linkable to such student athlete.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H97E56F7E856E416AAA2AA3E4512815C8"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Name, image, and likeness agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>name, image, and likeness agreement</term> means a contract or similar agreement under which a student athlete licenses or authorizes, or a contract or similar agreement that otherwise is in relation to, the commercial use of the name, image, or likeness of the student athlete.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEA7C95A0EA43424AB5A18251694EF67F"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Name, image, and likeness rights</header><text>The term <term>name, image, and likeness rights</term> means rights recognized under Federal or State law that allow an individual to control and profit from the commercial use of the name, image, and likeness of such individual, including all rights commonly referred to as <quote>publicity rights</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC3ED46822A1435C92388C70AE86532D"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Pool limit</header><text>The term <term>pool limit</term> means a dollar amount based on college sports revenue that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC005CEFC21374151A8A55FBE8B9D952C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is calculated and published by an interstate intercollegiate athletic association pursuant to the rules the interstate intercollegiate athletic association establishes under section 6; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE82F140B81C64D2E9D064328E612B189"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serves as the annual maximum amount that an institution that is a member of such interstate intercollegiate athletic association may provide, in total, to student athletes of such institution, including in the form of a name, image, and likeness agreement or direct payment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC63F336D2092441CA0DB3E38CF370B46"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Prohibited compensation</header><text>The term <term>prohibited compensation</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HB38EF09C1BA141F68304C056D4FCDCBD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>compensation (including an agreement for compensation) to a student athlete from an associated entity or individual of the institution at which the student athlete is enrolled (or to a prospective student athlete from an associated entity or individual of an institution for which the prospective student athlete is being recruited) for any license or use of the name, image, and likeness rights of such student athlete or prospective student athlete (or any other license or use), unless the license or use is for a valid business purpose related to the promotion or endorsement of goods or services provided to the general public for profit, with compensation at rates and terms commensurate with compensation paid to individuals with name, image, and likeness rights of comparable value who are not student athletes or prospective student athletes with respect to such institution; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H222051E5C42B45009852E5C1C43A1E61" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compensation to a student athlete (or a prospective student athlete) if such compensation is paid by or on behalf of the institution at which the student athlete is enrolled (or for which the prospective student athlete is being recruited) and results in the exceeding of the pool limit established by the interstate intercollegiate athletic association of which such institution is a member.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BEE5D95D3B54DA6A1BCC6869A01CC77"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Prospective student athlete</header><text>The term <term>prospective student athlete</term> means an individual who is solicited to enroll at an institution by, or at the direction of, an employee or an associated entity or individual of the institution in order for such individual to participate in a varsity sports team of such institution.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDE894362388744DD9346733CAE4BCAF2"><enum>(21)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each State of the United States, the District of Columbia, and each commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C1C58372B664DCE9C2F47152530C9CB"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Student athlete</header><text>The term <term>student athlete</term> means an individual who—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H91BE305C2C9E48FEA16EFC79A69137FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is enrolled or has agreed to enroll at an institution; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H30568E1E57E04955B2FDC1583F9802D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>participates in a varsity sports team of such institution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE5B5A67B5FB54E2D9ED52EA02AFC61F8"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Varsity sports team</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>varsity sports team</term> means an entity composed of an individual or group of individuals enrolled at an institution that is organized by such institution for the purpose of participation in intercollegiate athletic competitions.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HA44B7FEC817642C8B1C3EE018988D2E1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Protection of name, image, and likeness rights of student athletes</header> <subsection id="HA42A947DE62841F4BBB59BA8F6D072AF"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Right To enter into name, image, and likeness agreements</header> <paragraph id="HAAE4D3E579EB4669802D19ABD0403729"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>No institution, conference, or interstate intercollegiate athletic association may restrict the ability of a student athlete to enter into a name, image, and likeness agreement.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HDAE0B13854F5494F9EF2C622DC091953">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Exceptions</header>
          <subparagraph id="H87541832FFA74F82AEB28E56392D248C" commented="no">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>Prohibited compensation</header>
 <text>Paragraph (1) does not apply with respect to a name, image, and likeness agreement to the extent such agreement provides prohibited compensation.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HD89264E100324E1DA31B898794B581E8">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Codes of conduct and conflicting agreements</header>
 <text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), an institution may restrict the ability of a student athlete of such institution (including a prospective student athlete who has agreed to attend such institution) to enter into a name, image, and likeness agreement that—</text>
            <clause id="H3815593CA9AA409C880D5083A2C1B0B5">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>violates the code of conduct of such institution; or</text> </clause> <clause id="HC1932D62DACB44ADA9FCC3B65D91F0D5"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>conflicts with the terms of a contract or similar agreement to which such institution is a party.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9DC442614299415EA2E50A551ACA0A59"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Right to representation</header><text>Except as provided by this Act, no institution, conference, or interstate intercollegiate athletic association may restrict the ability of a student athlete to obtain an agent.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE9F99864C6D4405694C073A8985F58C0" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Right to privacy</header><text>Except as provided by this Act, no institution, conference, or interstate intercollegiate athletic association may release information disclosed to such entity by a student athlete with respect to a name, image, and likeness agreement without the express written consent of such student athlete.</text></subsection> </section> 
<section id="HEA6F46C1A7A449F794BFE656EAE49DF1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sports Agent Responsibility and Trust Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Sports Agent Responsibility and Trust Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/7801">15 U.S.C. 7801 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H7352D734CEA04AE29864E3FDFE6414C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 3(b)(3), by striking <quote>Warning to Student Athlete: If you agree orally or in writing to be represented by an agent now or in the future you may lose your eligibility to compete as a student athlete in your sport.</quote> and inserting <quote>Notice to Student Athlete:</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B998E6CAC2A41029C1AA52197E69B83"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDA426E9897214569BA1CFA88098E6737" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H6B63965D9711451181D754351B46F0BF"><enum>9.</enum><header>Disclosure and consent relating to name, image, and likeness agreements</header> <subsection id="H876832EC8C19489093F2E908719A2A0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An athlete agent who assists a student athlete with an endorsement contract shall disclose in writing to the student athlete—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCBF97FF5B9914A6A96AD80C904C2FAC4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>whether the athlete agent is registered with an interstate intercollegiate athletic association (as defined in section 2 of the SCORE Act); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H117C28D47B50495AA2AC0EECFBDD78B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the athlete agent is registered with an interstate intercollegiate athletic association, whether the athlete agent is registered with the interstate intercollegiate athletic association that has as a member the institution (as defined in section 2 of the SCORE Act) at which the student athlete is enrolled.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H362A63CA95824BECBD3AC18E1384273B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consent</header><text>In the case of an athlete agent who is not registered with an interstate intercollegiate athletic association, the athlete agent may only assist a student athlete with an endorsement contract if the student athlete (or, in the case of a student athlete who is under 18 years of age, the parent or guardian of the student athlete) provides to the athlete agent written consent for such assistance after receiving the disclosure under subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1B0D59D57D274EA190DC50279E6E3899"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <paragraph id="HD07EF8ACA50947BE88F4EEDAD36C15EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If an attorney general of a State has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of that State has been or is threatened or adversely affected by the engagement of any athlete agent in a practice that violates this section, the attorney general may bring a civil action pursuant to section 5 in the same manner as the attorney general may bring a civil action with respect to a violation of section 3.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC3FAA742FCD049A7ACF2F14B44E82BB1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sole authority</header><text>No individual or entity other than an attorney general of a State may enforce this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB4CE4D5DBD84A1299B3864C01D8312C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No Federal notice necessary</header><text>Subsections (a)(2), (b), and (d) of section 5 do not apply to an action brought by an attorney general of a State pursuant to this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H4788719E042541BA9EB7745355CB6347"><enum>5.</enum><header>Requirements applicable to certain institutions</header> 
<subsection id="HC42E63D143D74F31B6293AE98C8EC7FF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>An institution described in subsection (c) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H48169C597F0844CCA225CEBD963C3832"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide comprehensive academic support and career counseling services to student athletes that include life skills development programs with respect to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H93E0A4765B684A4ABBACFDED7A2A6A6E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>mental health, including alcohol and substance abuse;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H43A7D2494E78464DBCB9B6E7099B34C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>strength and conditioning;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H957F2FC783E64324916596B62D1B7773"><enum>(C)</enum><text>nutrition;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDE92A8FE961643858164DBD657900FC9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>name, image, and likeness rights, including related legal advice;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6DD42DC0076F4BCCA1AE674C77A44370"><enum>(E)</enum><text>financial literacy, including taxes;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD89C4F2CF6DB4079A81508870F107A5F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>career readiness and counseling;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8229D88174594784899841FBED1B2A0C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the process for transferring between institutions; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4D4FB841FC894C8C8C5FB50D7D68C105"><enum>(H)</enum><text>sexual violence prevention;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD2F427589A34442A9C0609D717C220CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide medical and health benefits to student athletes that include—</text> <subparagraph id="H87A4958C7D4D4160B58580FD54F56F19"><enum>(A)</enum><text>medical care, including payment of out-of-pocket expenses, for an injury of a student athlete incurred during the involvement of such student athlete in intercollegiate athletics for such institution that is available to the student athlete during the period of enrollment of the student athlete with such institution and a period of at least 3 years following graduation or separation from such institution (unless such separation is due to violation of a code of conduct);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H47DB679C63A94F2F98908D955206F89D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mental health services and support, including mental health educational materials and resources;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0C124EFE9622405ABFBA7B11DEA6A63D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an administrative structure that provides independent medical care, including with respect to decisions regarding return to play; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA1AC8620EAE34E389B3C56F1986C10F3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a certification of insurance coverage for medical expenses resulting from injuries of student athletes incurred during the involvement of such student athletes in intercollegiate athletics for such institution;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71E6D16350714FE4993AC56EBE0B2881"><enum>(3)</enum><text>maintain a grant-in-aid provided to a student athlete in relation to the involvement of such student athlete in intercollegiate athletics during the period of that grant-in-aid for such institution without regard to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H306C92556F924753AA2D1A69931A303E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>athletic performance;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAFCCBDBC34F249E8B4893A021F43D0ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>contribution to team success;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4684B2C73BB94412B8D98C38C9999AC8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>injury, illness, or physical or mental condition; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2178FB96EC9A4148A92481A28412C31B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>receipt of compensation pursuant to a name, image, and likeness agreement;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H415365268A254CCBA14D7793EDE903AD" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide a degree completion program—</text> <subparagraph id="H2BCE6D0ADFEE464680BA7EC4B3688F0D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for each former student athlete of such institution who received a grant-in-aid from such institution and did not graduate from such institution; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1448893AF93740AD93A551FFDBBE5E94" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that provides financial aid to such former student athlete in an amount that is based on the average annual grant-in-aid provided to such former student athlete during the period that such former student athlete participated on a varsity sports team of the institution; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC50549D1FE1A41F3A61671171222E91D" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>establish, not later than July 1, 2027, and thereafter maintain, at least 16 varsity sports teams.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCC644537F2304670B925C3593D23D130"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>An institution may carry out subsection (a) in conjunction with a conference or interstate intercollegiate athletic association.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H317AC046D35C463DA3BCFF80D798C2A1" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution is described in this subsection if any member of the coaching staff of a varsity sports team of such institution earns more than $250,000 in base salary annually (as adjusted on July 1 each year by the percentage increase (if any), during the preceding 12-month period, in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF0137E3FE2254994829FB94827DC2799"><enum>6.</enum><header>Roles of interstate intercollegiate athletic associations</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">An interstate intercollegiate athletic association is authorized to establish and enforce rules with respect to—</text> <paragraph id="H9E8F54041D4E44A6B1E2CF1A81B423E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>requiring a student athlete or prospective student athlete to disclose, in a timely manner, the terms of a name, image, and likeness agreement entered into by such student athlete;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6178A8F970FD40C0A1F0B61AE94C5947"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishing and implementing a process to collect and publicly share aggregated and anonymized data related to the name, image, and likeness agreements of student athletes;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53628D2317C849B2853FB4DB2416DDC2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>prohibited compensation, including processes for dispute resolution and penalties, if such rules provide that a student athlete does not lose eligibility to compete in intercollegiate athletic competitions while a process for dispute resolution is ongoing;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA76605163884C8497D15AF1062C38D3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>setting parameters for the manner in which and the time period during which student athletes and prospective student athletes may be recruited for intercollegiate athletics;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C4BAAEAD51146508861F000B8B6119C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>calculating a pool limit, if such rules provide that such pool limit is at least 22 percent of the average annual college sports revenue of the 70 highest earning (with respect to such revenue) member institutions of such interstate intercollegiate athletic association (or, if such interstate intercollegiate athletic association has fewer than 70 members, the average annual college sports revenue of all members), and monitoring payments of compensation related to such pool limit;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3B30AC77B36A4E4BACE31D4E3FB16AFA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>setting parameters for the manner in which a student athlete may transfer between institutions, if such rules provide that—</text> <subparagraph id="H27F14B7C197F49818B092ED53B1E4954"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on at least 1 occasion each student athlete may transfer between institutions and be immediately eligible; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF0753AC18A5342B4A79D41EFD3CBB4CC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an institution to which a student athlete is transferring or is considering transferring shall provide to such student athlete, at the request of such student athlete, in writing and at a reasonable time prior to completion of the transfer, a notice of the previously earned academic credits of such student athlete that such institution will accept, including with respect to the program of study of such student athlete;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DA133055A0C4B0ABAFD4A31ED31EF51"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the eligibility of a student athlete to participate in intercollegiate athletics, such as rules with respect to the length of time a student athlete is eligible to compete and academic standards for eligibility;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H33101CAF1DA940C286E25603F7C4517C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>establishing and implementing a process for agent registration, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H74596FDE0B0D40AB8168AC2304B116A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>setting parameters for the ability of member institutions to negotiate with agents who are not registered under such process; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H03AC0F5ED8074373959F876265A217E6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>limiting the amount of the compensation under a name, image, and likeness agreement between a student athlete and an institution that may be provided to the agent of such student athlete to not more than 5 percent of such compensation;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H52E99F3A009D4822B702F51608D8C352"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the membership of, and participation in, such interstate intercollegiate athletic association, including any championships administered by such interstate intercollegiate athletic association, under which such interstate intercollegiate athletic association may establish membership qualifications, remove members, and otherwise regulate participation; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9823C8E5D0B24CC5BB557AF6F9BFA962"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">intercollegiate athletic competitions and playing seasons, including rules with respect to season length, maximum number of contests, and student athlete time demands (whether during a playing season or outside of such season).</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H84C53323C9654A899B17556822B7C92C"><enum>7.</enum><header>Liability limitation</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Compliance with this Act and the adoption of, agreement to, compliance with, or enforcement of any rule, regulation, requirement, standard, or other provision established pursuant to, or in compliance with, this Act shall be treated as lawful under the antitrust laws and any similar State law, rule, regulation, requirement, standard, or other provision having the force and effect of law.</text></section> 
<section id="H1F9E170920B44ECA93B096B5AC6CEE44"><enum>8.</enum><header>Employment standing</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of Federal or State law, no individual may be considered an employee of an institution, a conference, or an interstate intercollegiate athletic association based on the participation of such individual on a varsity sports team or in an intercollegiate athletic competition as a student athlete, without regard to the existence of rules or requirements for being a member of such team or for participating in such competition.</text></section> <section id="H00DA0229D7374826BD53C3A1C43CF143"><enum>9.</enum><header>Student athletic fees</header> <subsection id="H4D0E7768617244589D4C042DF669AC04"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transparency requirements</header> <paragraph id="HA0A8C1AEE7B54E398AF082C2513E89F3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Information dissemination activities</header><text>Section 485(a)(1)(E) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092">20 U.S.C. 1092(a)(1)(E)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(including the amount of such fees used to support intercollegiate athletic programs)</quote> after <quote>and fees</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83DD786B943447CDBA8E7537DB696064"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Data required</header> 
<subparagraph id="HFADEBD41F021450FB62389EC0020DFBE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 485(g) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092">20 U.S.C. 1092(g)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="H4DA5E6452292405C90B3188BF2C2188F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF06A4CD62CB3414CAD6F405D925F38C5" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H8DE2522C5E7D4B4A91B55744B1EE832F"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to fees charged to students to support intercollegiate athletic programs—</text> <clause id="H54C972CE06A847348EE7AC085EC7F786"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total amount of such fees charged to students;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD817A09246464A4BB7791D789643AABD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the uses of such fees with respect to facilities, operating expenses, scholarships, payments to athletes, salaries of coaches and support staff, and any other expenses reported under this paragraph; and</text></clause> <clause id="H0DA9B7CEC435414C8BFC0E1C0E3E1933"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the percentage of the total cost of such programs covered by such fees.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> 
<clause id="H6F388C8D2586450885A2EB83C3008EBD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> <subclause id="H57B57E23C38045B2BD49DA80E0FFCB69"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HCE96B26173364439A04171E69E7A40A9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>that all students</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3CDB9F50C2C44B268497C2FFCAE2D85D" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA2E4030E782044209C4D4AECF69F80FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all students</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause> <subclause id="HBB2D3681722C42EA91E4E6F4E0CF6EAC"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCA40C35261604BEDB9FC4D6F4564BA21" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H3B562C59F03A422099E40DF04DB4C6E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the information described in paragraph (1)(K), the institution shall annually publish such information on a publicly available website of the institution not later than October 15 following the end of each fiscal year of the institution.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD4EB97ABBA6241178BCCA384AFEAD1AC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subparagraph (A) shall take effect and apply beginning on July 1, 2026.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4B978ACAEC1E47DE8402D7C5303DF3B7">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Restricting student fees for high-Media-Rights-Revenue institutions</header>
        <paragraph id="HA2E775BB8AEC4947B828E41D5D09C48E">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Media rights revenues</header>
 <text>Section 485(g)(1)(I)(ii) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092">20 U.S.C. 1092(a)(1)(I)(ii)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>broadcast revenues</quote> and inserting <quote>media rights revenues (including revenues from broadcasting, streaming, or digital distribution of intercollegiate athletic events)</quote>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H3A0E7AFCFEB247FB944A48DD50119FA7">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Program participation agreements</header>
 <text>Section 487(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
          <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9F4CD01D3395434AA1C3697CA57CFF72"
            display-inline="no-display-inline">
            <paragraph id="HB0EA0E6E7CC24C1D9007FFA4FCA86A9B">
              <enum>(30)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an institution that, for the most recently completed fiscal year, had annual media rights revenues (as described in section 485(g)(1)(I)(ii)) of $50,000,000 or more, the institution will not, for the fiscal year immediately following such fiscal year, use student fees to support intercollegiate athletic programs, including with respect to facilities, operating expenses (as defined in section 485(g)), scholarships, payments to athletes, salaries of coaches and support staff, and any other expenses reported under section 485(g)(1).</text>
            </paragraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD04F1EC4FD6645019312C4AF39DA1A69">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Effective date</header>
 <text>The amendments made by this subsection shall take effect and apply beginning on July 1, 2026.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection></section> 
<section id="H2EEEE8ABDAB64F2EAFA583D96807E3A7"><enum>10.</enum><header>Preemption</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">No State, or political subdivision of a State, may maintain, enforce, prescribe, or continue in effect any law, rule, regulation, requirement, standard, or other provision having the force and effect of law that—</text> <paragraph id="HF32FBD1B0B574F64B78DA363416B66D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>governs or regulates the compensation, payment, benefits, employment status, or eligibility of a student athlete (including a prospective student athlete) with respect to participation in intercollegiate athletics, including any law, rule, regulation, requirement, standard, or other provision that relates to the right of a student athlete to receive compensation or other payments or benefits directly or indirectly from any institution, associated entity or individual, conference, or interstate intercollegiate athletic association;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA4DAE620DFB7432D87853FF79F304E90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>limits or restricts a right provided to an institution, a conference, or an interstate intercollegiate athletic association under this Act;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H75E48663D5704218B98D926F50E56FA6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>requires a release of or license to use the name, image, and likeness rights of any individual participant, or group of participants, in an intercollegiate athletic competition (or an individual spectator or group of spectators at an intercollegiate athletic competition) for purposes of audio-visual, audio, or visual broadcasts or other distributions of such intercollegiate athletic competition; or</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4F910F1172FA41F1892E89C727D7836A" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>is otherwise related to this Act.</text> </paragraph> </section> </legis-body></bill>

