<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H41385999B3A84AE4870EB5D36A33710A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3435 IH: Federal Cyber Workforce Training Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3435</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250515">May 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the National Cyber Director to submit to Congress a plan to establish an institute within the Federal Government to serve as a centralized resource and training center for Federal cyber workforce development.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF36CEBEC5EB043378E52A388F0AFB1C0" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H800E4865E8D4437AB3BC85202FD87170"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Cyber Workforce Training Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2695AF93035D4BE0A45E1A2FA2BD5D78"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal cyber workforce development institute</header> <subsection id="HF8639BFA323C43DDB6B45A2C73D50CE7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA143EA464D324992B338C926B50C96A2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD602FA97E17D4D299BA42D9E85B2FC1B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H27D115B160FF49CAACF55BB274AEDF68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7AED91F238E448B69B54C8DB85EF476E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBBFCB3299628474D94E5668453224BD4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBF1ACAADA76943A8B13BD12300DD3B62"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1204E358B1E24013992564ACC45127D2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F6DB063F1CB4B4DA86B6DD212952123" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cyber work role</header><text>The term <term>cyber work role</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H593AF1E0630242A8AD1AB68A591CDFA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a role indicated in the NICE framework for new hires and personnel seeking transition to mid-career positions; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HD7FD2173A5E642A68EA00CBA74668EE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a role relating to work involving designing, building, securing, operating, defending, and protecting cyberspace resources.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H218EE65184034BD3BB3AB0A4D2451541"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the National Cyber Director.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1846812AFA9C44B89B9BF48E52A1E6F9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Federal institute</header><text>The term <term>Federal institute</term> means the Federal institute described in the plan required under subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA554973BAD1E4E919BD7432DB2E718AC"><enum>(6)</enum><header>NICE framework</header><text>The term <term>NICE framework</term> means Special Publication 800–181 of the National Institute of Standards and Technology entitled <quote>Workforce Framework for Cybersecurity (NICE Framework)</quote>, or any successor document.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H70108690F8724331BCC6D1567C0258FE"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Work-based learning</header><text>The term <term>work-based learning</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2302">20 U.S.C. 2302</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2BD9E282B6443829127179635A574E3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement</header> 
<paragraph id="HF5678D58578F44A3A83F6297355D2397"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Defense, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, and the head of any other agency the Director determines necessary, shall submit to Congress and make publicly available a plan for the establishment of a Federal institute to provide—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBEEA51166E804642954C41967158E49B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">training for personnel hired for cyber work roles in the Federal Government, including new hires and personnel seeking transition to mid-career positions, which may include upskilling and reskilling efforts; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30C2916AE7C047899ABF3239389FE98F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">training for personnel with responsibilities for human resource functions relating to cyber personnel.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H27F7B0E75FFF4D98B64E279B97564715"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institute functions</header><text>The plan required under paragraph (1) shall provide for the Federal institute to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3DA8B2A2B8894A7BBBE38B864AF10508"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide modularized cyber work role-specific training, including hands-on learning and skill-based assessments, to prepare newly hired Federal personnel from a wide variety of academic and professional backgrounds to perform effectively in Federal cyber work roles;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C89076EC74443C9B8444963F90BB816"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordinate with the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Defense, and the heads of other agencies determined necessary by the Director to develop a cyber work role-specific curriculum for the training provided under subparagraph (A)—</text> 
<clause id="H814EB422929E4E2FA3E6FB8CFC1DC624"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in accordance with the NICE framework; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC6BFE906474A4A58A87F028B9633839A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in consideration of other Federal cyber training programs;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9FA195EC83C34F8A881F31ACFFCD486A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>prioritize entry-level positions in the provision of curriculum development and training;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE500F390D4FE4A79A89849F7A73D7892"><enum>(D)</enum><text>address the training needs of—</text> 
<clause id="H4CFA2FC49FEC46FB96735620100E22C3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>personnel seeking transition to mid-career positions; and</text></clause> <clause id="HE8F3258B16B643DFB1CFDC862C9400BD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>personnel with responsibilities for human resources functions relating to cyber personnel;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9CCB0A9675D545D29F80B9F5CBEAC93C"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include curriculum development and training for Federal cyber workers seeking transition to mid-career positions, which may include upskilling and reskilling efforts;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4236F4D9D0A848C59DC2FB971A4D8771"> <enum>(F)</enum> <text>consider developing a specific module to familiarize and train appropriate Federal Government hiring managers and human resources staff in the unique challenges in recruiting and hiring personnel for Federal cyber workforce roles;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCEB8D70FBAD44166808BE42F0BE498EA"><enum>(G)</enum><text>incorporate work-based learning in personnel training;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBF1BBB5A3C214E8DA398571D1B14169F"><enum>(H)</enum><text>develop a badging system to communicate qualification and proficiency for individuals who successfully complete training through the Federal institute with consideration of systems used by the intelligence community;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE4497C0315FD48D1B4B5DA887D671EB4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>offer in-person and virtual options to accommodate various learning environments for individuals; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC289126B2874AE9A076FC93624F28DC"><enum>(J)</enum><text>provide training to individuals irrespective of whether an individual has a college degree or a college degree in a cyber-related discipline.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90A3F20443E345269708A18ADC902B97"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Plan elements</header><text>The plan required under paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HFFF850E533C8441391711852832C3A19"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recommend an organizational placement for the Federal institute, which may include a single agency or a combination of agencies;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H36D7A20E2ECA493AB6FEC2D1DF0A8727"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the greatest extent practicable, align training and tools, including cyber work roles and competencies and the associated tasks, knowledge, and skills from—</text> <clause id="HF9BEB795CCD949BABCB0B4802FA227C0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Special Publication 800–181, Revision 1, of the National Institute of Standards and Technology entitled <quote>National Initiative for Cybersecurity Education Workforce Framework for Cybersecurity</quote>, or any successor special publication; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H74BD7E12A8B94E9CB3372BC31D6E87FB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other applicable publications, studies, or guidance of the Federal Government;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD374D37AEB0F4E50B0F18571B394852E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify—</text> 
<clause id="H80AE5A12C7B64005A1C253A00F824289"><enum>(i)</enum><text>elements of the Federal institute and its functions that could use existing facilities, resources, and programs of the Federal Government; and</text></clause> <clause id="H97E3084872834099827A9B588765EA4A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>elements of the Federal institute and its functions that would require new facilities, resources, and programs of the Federal Government in order to implement the plan required under paragraph (1);</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF723670E880949329CEC8B5AE12CF6CA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommend a course curriculum, delivery method, and length of curriculum for the training provided under paragraph (1)(A) using Federal Government cyber training programs as models, including the Joint Cyber Analysis Course of the Department of Defense and the Federal Cyber Defense Skilling Academy of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H258F962310FA46F9A6F2821217105D0C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>recommend a policy for individuals who do not complete required training;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3D53B3F19413474DBD2CBAB425A8C699"><enum>(F)</enum><text>describe a security clearance process to complete some level of security clearance for appropriate individuals while individuals are enrolled in training;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H147DFF77CA0D41D18E119CC5A7A84164"><enum>(G)</enum><text>recommend a governance structure for the Federal institute that would ensure ongoing interagency coordination in the development of a curriculum, the provision of training, and other considerations the Director determines appropriate;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H32BDAEAB0EA4407495383194CE32509E"><enum>(H)</enum><text>provide an estimate of the funding and new authorities required to establish and operate the Federal institute;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H98F3945DA3A6449B9043AF0D03B3B396"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describe any requirements for the Federal institute to conduct work in a classified setting;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1D2AB2F4CD51446FB7B1A7F71C085C27"><enum>(J)</enum><text>identify how the Federal institute would—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5CD4ED70A6A34C9A92EB3F4C85AACA90"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide some or all of the training required by paragraph (1)(A) through 5 academic institutions from among academic institutions that—</text> 
<subclause id="H12DF21C56C4B4F9FBDEF060BF33B4C69"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are designated by the National Security Agency as a National Center of Academic Excellence in cybersecurity for cyber defense, cyber research, and cyber operations; and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C8E60F1AD544F59939502DB2DDD288C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>have an operational sensitive compartmented information facility; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3AEB35E2D1A1492AAB272E391215A0C8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>select the 5 academic institutions under clause (i);</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4355C4A6D60C4B6382C6838E73CF4A41"><enum>(K)</enum><text>identify how the instructors of the Federal institute will remain current with respect to cybersecurity knowledge, skills and abilities through scholarship or other means; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4D67C37B27AE4D24904A8445E11194B9" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(L)</enum><text>identify how the Federal institute will maintain the quality and longevity of instructors.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F4FA708A83F4BBCBF3DB089E9FEB0D2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing a plan for the Federal institute, the Director shall consult with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, the Chief Human Capital Officers Council, the Chief Information Officers Council, and the Chief Learning Officers Council to establish tools for human resources professionals of the Federal Government to develop the knowledge, skills and abilities required to manage the career life cycle of cyber professionals from recruitment to retirement.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H294BBE673FE742A796525BC308C9442A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a briefing on the plan required under subsection (b)(1), including an estimate of the funding and the authorities necessary to implement the plan.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H709FCA18EAF243278231127C2DDF0169"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No additional funds</header><text>No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of carrying out this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

