<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ARP25039-K5Y-GH-L1K"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S349 IS: Fire-Safe Electrical Corridors Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 349</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250130">January 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to permit removal of trees around electrical lines on National Forest System land without conducting a timber sale, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fire-Safe Electrical Corridors Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idbcec8abd03574d0c89925eaa9c10ded1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Permits and agreements with electrical utilities</header><subsection id="id5c3a7aa16c904709a956526bc1792f39"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any special use permit or easement on National Forest System land provided to an electrical utility, the Secretary of Agriculture may provide permission to cut and remove trees or other vegetation from within the vicinity of distribution lines or transmission lines without requiring a separate timber sale, if that cutting and removal is consistent with—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida051dfed181b4bf6984814b7fe37276a"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicable land and resource management plan; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf121a3a003c84ea0a9424fd56358f80b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other applicable environmental laws (including regulations).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id52594c23745d4abd96ed1234c44befbe"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of proceeds</header><text>A special use permit or easement that includes permission for cutting and removal described in subsection (a) shall include a requirement that, if the applicable electrical utility sells any portion of the material removed under the permit or easement, the electrical utility shall provide to the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, any proceeds received from the sale, less any transportation costs incurred in the sale.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide4fb1c08c79a431ea76ecd7d469aae8d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in subsection (b) shall require the sale of any material removed under a permit or easement that includes permission for cutting and removal described in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

