<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H85448BF6CA5E43E59D2E3CD14805F670" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 518 IH: Troops Before Politicians Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 518</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250116">January 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000598">Mr. LaLota</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To withhold the pay of Members of Congress in certain cases, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H160C815DD6FE468B91CB7CA82022BB63" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBB891D9E2C924B038FD9A8CDF8E53D49" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Troops Before Politicians Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HD8AB89A4928A47538F3419ADE98F03B2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Withholding of pay of Members of Congress in certain cases</header> <subsection id="HC20C7597517F4DEFA760ACC8B274D26A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Holding salaries in escrow</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If on any day during a pay period members of the Armed Forces, including the reserve components thereof, who perform active service during such period are not receiving amounts of pay due to such members, including as a result of a lapse in appropriations for a fiscal year, the payroll administrator of a House of Congress shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE3C6DE5A0DA9457EB3D6438AE554B213"><enum>(1)</enum><text>withhold the payments otherwise required to be made during the period for the compensation of each Member of Congress who serves in that House of Congress; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4BE7AB1BC58340E0892BF0E77DB457E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>deposit in an escrow account all amounts withheld under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA52252AAA9684CEAAEF75A1A86967925"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Release of amounts held in escrow</header> 
<paragraph id="H231115AD9FE14A48B8BA586C15970C39"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Release</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The payroll administrator of a House of Congress shall release for payments to Members of that House of Congress any amounts in any escrow account under this subsection as soon as practicable after the date that the lapse in pay described in subsection (a) terminates.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31189DDAC52F4A25AC3BFFDE9D571E72"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for One Hundred Nineteenth Congress</header><text>In order to ensure that this section is carried out in a manner that shall not vary the compensation of Senators or Representatives in violation of the twenty-seventh article of amendment to the Constitution of the United States, the payroll administrator of a House of Congress shall release for payments to Members of that House of Congress any amounts remaining in any escrow account under this subsection on the last day of the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H95E1AD3D16264ECE88CC1A078A28A0EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Role of Secretary of the Treasury</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall provide the payroll administrators of the Houses of Congress with such assistance as may be necessary to enable the payroll administrators to carry out this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9084FCB349CC4CAB84780D1808A49C20"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC23689A2083642EBA08B8B4472D421CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the terms <term>active service</term> and <term>Armed Forces</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 101 of title 10, United States Code;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H295AF80F889F4B62B1D946EE8260A82F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Member of Congress</term> means an individual serving in a position under subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of section 601(a) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1BDA767BA0C54442AA6A9E69104AB560"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the <quote>payroll administrator</quote> of a House of Congress means—</text> <subparagraph id="H485169D7FDF84292AD6122D1165DCA66"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of the House of Representatives, the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, or an employee of the Office of the Chief Administrative Officer who is designated by the Chief Administrative Officer to carry out this Act; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5EFDC95D6359481A8E5ACCA24A9E33E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of the Senate, the Secretary of the Senate, or an employee of the Office of the Secretary of the Senate who is designated by the Secretary to carry out this Act; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E439192A65B423D8AECFDE48EFB535F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>reserve components</term> means the components named in section 10101 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

