<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H09C19524B1C7406CB327AAC044D83CDC" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 478 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the month of July as “American Patriotism Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 478</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250604">June 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001239">Mr. McGuire</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the month of July as <quote>American Patriotism Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on July 4, 1776, in an act of patriotism, the 13 colonies declared independence from British rule and created the United States of America;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States was founded on the values of life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, throughout its rich history, many American patriots have demonstrated commitment to these founding principles through selfless service and sacrifice;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas following the unprecedented Japanese attack on Pearl Harbor on December 7, 1941, thousands of Americans rushed to enlist in the United States military to defend our country;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on June 6, 1944, over 73,000 Americans stormed the beaches of Normandy to protect democracy and liberty around the globe and here at home;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on January 20, 1961, President John F. Kennedy in his inaugural address said, <quote>And so, my fellow Americans, ask not what your country can do for you, ask what you can do for your country,</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on January 20, 1981, President Ronald Reagan in his inaugural address said, <quote>Above all, we must realize that no arsenal or no weapon in the arsenals of the world is so formidable as the will and moral courage of free men and women. It is a weapon our adversaries in today’s world do not have. It is a weapon that we as Americans do have.</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas through the leadership of United States Presidents and the American people, America was triumphant in the Cold War against the Soviet Union and emerged as the beacon of hope for the free world;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas when the United States of America was attacked on September 11, 2001, American patriots rushed to help one another, defend our country, and defend the values that as Americans we so deeply believe in;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on September 11, 2001, the American patriots aboard United Airlines flight 93 fought against the hijackers and saved thousands of American lives;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 181,510 Americans joined the ranks of Active Duty service and 72,908 enlisted in the reserves in the year following the September 11, 2001, attack;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on July 5, 2019, President Trump in his Salute to America said <quote>That same American spirit that emboldened our founders has kept us strong throughout our history. To this day, that spirit runs through the veins of every American patriot. It lives on in each and every one of you here today. It is the spirit of daring and defiance, excellence and adventure, courage and confidence, loyalty and love that built this country into the most exceptional nation in the history of the world, and our nation is stronger today than it ever was before. It is its strongest now.</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas July holds significance in American history as it includes Independence Day, the commemoration of the Declaration of Independence, a document that became an international beacon of freedom;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the millions of American citizens who have given their life in defense of the United States of America to protect the values and freedoms that our Founding Fathers declared on July 4, 1776, deserve the respect and gratitude of the American people; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the month of July would be an appropriate month to designate as <quote>American Patriotism Month</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H72C3938D1A344493A70D8CC54468F8EE"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HE71F29D0237346CEB47A5A09ECB4A55C"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H08FBF867E4CB45CB86A98ED0552EE7BC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of American patriotism and its examples throughout history;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C0BF35FFA2F435D964499375084C400"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the contributions of all Americans, past and present, who have preserved America’s patriotic principles through service and sacrifice; starting with our founding fathers declaration of independence from Great Britain on July 4, 1776;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7AF3DD09C16C4437A84257481A8654D5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages individuals, schools, organizations, and communities across the United States to observe the month with appropriate ceremonies, activities, and educational initiatives that celebrate American history, values, and civic responsibility;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E6B134924E347899EDC6823EF0D8D03"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>American Patriotism Month</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCA627ECA55AE4337ADAE9EC0085BEAFF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>requests that the President issue an annual proclamation designating <quote>American Patriotism Month</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

