<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2E076BCAEF3B4989A4E2F4B191B352B2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1750 IH: Health Equity and Rare Disease Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1750</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for greater investments in research on rare diseases and conditions disproportionately affecting minority populations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCE8EBA683F7845E5B456909C813DEE65" style="OLC"><section id="H9C0C7475D999439BB056172EB96040B4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Health Equity and Rare Disease Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HEARD Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HE5E994FD91E7419BB6C691E0EC199181"><enum>2.</enum><header>NIH expansion, intensification, and coordination of research on rare diseases health equity</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title IV of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/284">42 U.S.C. 284 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H078D6982C68E40C78ACEF1362D60C354" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H88691D935E4648A9BAD0F29531A81E8A" commented="no"><enum>409K.</enum><header>Rare diseases health equity</header><subsection id="H922C0887B94746BBAF17C9268EB8500F" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expansion, intensification, and coordination of activities</header><paragraph id="H575C9A3E8839449588778F3115B9BF9A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of NIH shall expand, intensify, and coordinate research and other activities of the National Institutes of Health with respect to rare diseases health equity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F12D9B214C44165B956DBA6E739AA84" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allocations by Director of NIH</header><text>With respect to amounts appropriated to carry out this section for a fiscal year, the Director of NIH shall allocate the amounts among the national research institutes that are carrying out paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAD350E197CE34371A568BA3CB4DA57FF" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordinating Committee</header><paragraph id="H83FE04D78CC64D44AE0CCE7FB381AEBB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall maintain a coordinating committee with respect to rare diseases health equity (referred to in this section as the <quote>Coordinating Committee</quote>) to coordinate activities across the National Institutes and with other Federal health programs and activities relating to rare diseases health equity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD619015F2BA343C2B3A4D562D0854239" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Composition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Coordinating Committee shall be composed of—</text><subparagraph id="H38BCFCE3B8264344A22E5C7C9E4659C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the directors (or their designees) of each of the national research institutes involved in research with respect to rare diseases and minority health or health equity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2309D13CA326492ABD2B1179203D5003"><enum>(B)</enum><text>representatives of all other Federal departments and agencies whose programs involve health functions or responsibilities relevant to such rare diseases, including the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the Food and Drug Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H02F81E2BBDF847329573E5CE39B6336A" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chair</header><subparagraph id="HBEC5B4703EC44E2382BDD85C525E81A8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to rare diseases health equity, the Chair of the Coordinating Committee shall serve as the principal advisor to the Secretary, the Assistant Secretary for Health, and the Director of NIH, and shall provide advice to the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, and other relevant agencies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE955147B4ADE4D9DA1962B0C0E8824F0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Director of NIH</header><text>The Chair of the Coordinating Committee shall be directly responsible to the Director of NIH.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H69F220235EBE4F53A079542CDAA7155F" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Plan for NIH Activities</header><paragraph id="H4761B6E7F1234DA885E6D25BF0100B61" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Coordinating Committee shall develop a plan for conducting and supporting research and education on rare diseases health equity, and rare diseases or conditions in minority populations, through the national research institutes. The Coordinating Committee shall periodically review and revise the plan. The plan shall—</text><subparagraph id="HB5891197030B4868B67FD3F10677F128" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide for a broad range of research and education activities relating to biomedical, psychosocial, and rehabilitative issues, including studies of the disproportionate impact of such diseases or conditions on minority populations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF792F6F4049E4C459ADA6FAC07C1C348" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify priorities among the programs and activities of the National Institutes of Health regarding such diseases or conditions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H194A98989B4E4139AED91175360E9CD1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reflect input from a broad range of scientists, patients, and advocacy groups.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H72172562C7774209B9EC0B0A27701BCE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certain elements of plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The plan under paragraph (1) shall, with respect to rare diseases or conditions in minority populations, provide for the following as appropriate:</text><subparagraph id="HFB386FD075F04E62B4D2968AB1BFA5C0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Research to determine the reasons underlying the incidence and prevalence of the diseases or conditions, including among subpopulations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D4F974EB8A44572B8F4FCF80AD5EC13" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Basic research concerning the etiology and causes of the diseases or conditions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E35714737B54212AFDD6526F7DAC391" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Epidemiological studies to address the frequency and natural history of the diseases or conditions, including any differences among the sexes and among racial and ethnic groups.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H907BE1B733204394828A50A9408086D6" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The development of improved screening techniques.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45ACC4E601C84AEFBF14F3AF166F76B5" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Clinical research for the development and evaluation of new treatments, including new biological agents.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78939EECF3F64769B2B952E638B6B67C" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Information and education programs for health care professionals and the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H030055D6458B431CB0E77C1D9F7C0360" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Implementation of plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of NIH shall ensure that programs and activities of the National Institutes of Health regarding rare diseases or conditions in minority populations are implemented in accordance with the plan under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA6948306BE414BE6A6FE09D4961B77D5" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H4AA0CE3622284571B09F85AA09E07085" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>minority</term> has the meaning given such term in section 464z–3.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA59DD6E59FC3475B837A10F917E381FE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>rare disease or condition</term> has the meaning given such term in section 526 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360bb">21 U.S.C. 360bb</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HBA76F6EF275F449B952370752F05E5E7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Collaborative comprehensive plan to address rare diseases and conditions in minority populations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart 20 of part C of title IV of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/285t">42 U.S.C. 285t et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDFFC1978AFA84AC0B6CD2C272EBCA052" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H29900DD298D44FB6BA843EAE34F1F37C"><enum>464z–7.</enum><header>Collaborative comprehensive plan to address rare diseases and conditions in minority populations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Director of NIH, the Director of the Institute, the Director of the National Center for Advancing Translational Sciences, the Director of the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, and the directors of the other agencies of the National Institutes of Health in collaboration (and in consultation with the advisory council for the Institute) shall—</text><paragraph id="H56FF013B59F84224B249D4A7DBE35B71"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop a comprehensive Federal plan to address rare diseases and conditions in minority populations (as those terms are defined in section 409K), including a strategy to increase diversity in genetic programs at the program for Therapeutics for Rare and Neglected Diseases at the National Institutes of Health;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC4B85BFD5914AFDACD31E7A6D025DFE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct or support through grants or cooperative agreements basic, clinical, and translational research on rare diseases and conditions in minority populations, including research on—</text><subparagraph id="H63BB1C05594E438CA01A6975E40E043A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>early detection, diagnosis, and treatment of such diseases and conditions in such populations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF32C1FC6039949329D1F5BAF0706A09D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving the quality of life for individuals with rare diseases or conditions and their families; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E2190F948DD4DC8AF28466566B80904"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conduct or support clinical training programs for physicians and other health care practitioners with respect to detecting, diagnosing, and treating such diseases and conditions in such populations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE87BC63ED2741A083B90C9F1E95C6AF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop guidance for increasing participation of health professionals who are members of minority groups (as defined in section 464z–3) in research conducted or supported by the National Institutes of Health on such diseases and conditions in such populations. </text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HA672781FAC5C4B1496460E6DD88F28E7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grants to collect and analyze data on rare diseases and conditions in minority populations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1707(b) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300u-6">42 U.S.C. 300u–6(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5FD5848355B348428FF3BC922CCE73E8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H0C41481287854515B120AF5551545E3F"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In coordination with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, award grants to public and private nonprofit entities to—</text><subparagraph id="H913823B36A2345AC8ABBFE77922CA638"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collect, analyze, and report data on rare diseases and conditions in minority populations, including on epidemiological data with respect to incidence of such diseases and conditions in such populations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F4E0FA456644A2F90911351A7FF627E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct outreach and engagement activities with the minority populations impacted by such rare diseases and conditions by—</text><clause id="H391B203A1C414F2895D5070CF2278FE4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>improving health literacy with respect to rare diseases and conditions;</text></clause><clause id="H4A3ABFFDBBE14E20A3DB4C9DB8B8F2CA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>disseminating information on health and community services related to rare diseases and conditions; and</text></clause><clause id="H74AEFF53EDCF4C46A762D3AF4D83E4F8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>providing information regarding the maintenance of rare diseases and conditions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB77D8D75AF304E9590A53699137C5BEF"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Submit to Congress, on a biannual basis (beginning not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>HEARD Act of 2025</short-title>), a report describing the activities carried out pursuant to paragraph (11). </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H52189D7356F2454382EAFB7A48163749"><enum>5.</enum><header>Physician training programs with respect to rare diseases</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart II of part C of title VII of the Public Health Service Act is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9BA952A69FFA46F881A910B09C1BC7BA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H61777B9BC2774FED905B28A99DAFB385"><enum>749C.</enum><header>Physician training programs with respect to rare diseases</header><subsection id="HB596390C6CB9454A981A156279199874"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a program to award grants to accredited schools of allopathic medicine, osteopathic medicine, and nursing, and other health professional training programs for the training of health care professionals—</text><paragraph id="H867578674E134CD4A2B7575B13BB81C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to improve the provision of care to individuals who have rare diseases or conditions (as defined in section 526 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360bb">21 U.S.C. 360bb</external-xref>));</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H990426F04A7247D0A6227F03964506AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to improve the provision of care to such individuals via telehealth; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9A79FD4D59A41D7B8D74EDD62F291A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to conduct research relevant to rare diseases and conditions.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H274ABF3C83B94B1BB52639C0FE27920A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under subsection (a), an entity described in such subsection shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE1C42DEBFC5744689D90AB7CBD7D6203"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><paragraph id="H7A69668CE500464DB1784F1C0809F9D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Periodic reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each entity awarded a grant under this section shall periodically submit to the Secretary a report on the status of activities conducted using the grant, including a description of the impact of such training on patient outcomes, as applicable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H414001E7C5594584B7AE56C3EA0368D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit a report to Congress on the activities conducted using grants under subsection (a) and any best practices identified and disseminated under subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H40FC6D91E4BF41278FB250A71479C007"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text>The Secretary may identify and disseminate best practices for the training described in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="HFEF0DDF87E1B4889A3BC623A01679099"><enum>749D.</enum><header>Health professionals education on rare diseases and conditions in minority populations</header><subsection id="HB819F044F0A047BA9BE70E8A965C570E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may award grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts to accredited schools of medicine and nursing, and other health professional training programs, for the development and implementation of programs to provide education and training to health care professionals on the causes and effects of rare diseases and conditions in minority populations.<italic></italic></text></subsection><subsection id="HB865DB21246940D9A38AF2C14E59A78E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HA961D787685B43B78E088EA47A5031FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>minority</term> has the meaning given such term in section 464z–3.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H967350740D43420283C1A5A52603BB65"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>rare disease or condition</term> has the meaning given such term in section 526 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360bb">21 U.S.C. 360bb</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD3E11237ED764E76B3BB1BB5BDF61718"><enum>749E.</enum><header>Mentoring program for health care professionals seeking to work in rare diseases and conditions<editorial></editorial></header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, may award grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to public and nonprofit private entities (including Tribal entities) for the establishment of a mentoring program for health care professionals seeking to treat patients with rare diseases and conditions.<italic></italic></text></section><section id="HBE61414DCA0A47CBAE5676989B1439B5"><enum>749F.</enum><header>Scholarship and loan repayment program for physicians and genetic counselors serving populations with rare diseases and conditions</header><subsection id="HD6A9DD68B34240A19D2DF46652D3A73A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Loan repayment program</header><paragraph id="H437ED52F6D0C4420868865ADDA32B460"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a program of entering into contracts with eligible individuals under which the individuals agree to serve as health care professionals serving populations with rare diseases or conditions in consideration of the Federal Government agreeing to pay, for each year of such service, up to $50,000 (plus an amount determined by the Secretary on an annual basis to reflect inflation) of the principal and interest of the educational loans of such individuals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A08F68CB00346D49869149DF28B9408"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making a determination of the amount to pay for a year of such service by an individual, the Secretary shall consider the extent to which each such determination—</text><subparagraph id="H386972730D994A598544F019452BD450"><enum>(A)</enum><text>affects the ability of the Secretary to maximize the number of contracts that can be provided under the program from the amounts appropriated for such contracts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C83A19365A6428A996D8534084031BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides an incentive to serve as health care professionals serving populations with rare diseases or conditions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDB359CA758043AC8AC7FAE057078BD0"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides an incentive with respect to the health professional involved to remain serving populations with rare diseases or conditions, including after the completion of the period of obligated service under the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H39BBD26773AB4B888E87074FCF6363F3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>eligible individual</term> means an individual who is enrolled or accepted for enrollment as a full-time or part-time student in a school of medicine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96DF4764C52542C5BAF2C65375260E4A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Applicability of certain provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the National Health Service Corps Loan Repayment Program established in subpart III of part D of title III of this Act, the provisions of such subpart shall, except as inconsistent with paragraph (1), apply to the program established in this section in the same manner and to the same extent as such provisions apply to the National Health Service Corps Loan Repayment Program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H06A45181A3B444228CDAD811373B3C60"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scholarship program</header><paragraph id="HAD4EBBB284714B8AA93D6AA168BBEC8F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out a program of entering into contracts with eligible individuals under which each such individual agrees to serve, for a period of not less than 5 years, as a health care professional primarily serving populations with rare diseases or conditions, in consideration of the Federal Government agreeing to provide to the individual a scholarship for attendance at a school of medicine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB116B7EC29DC470F8F033D2C47BF0A30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>eligible individual</term> means an individual who is enrolled or accepted for enrollment as a full-time or part-time student in a school of medicine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA853E5757524308BA4BE3CB884DCBCB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicability of certain provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of subpart III of part D of title III shall, except as inconsistent with this section, apply to the program established in paragraph (1) in the same manner and to the same extent as such provisions apply to the National Health Service Corps Scholarship Program established in such subpart.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HDCF0A092E15A48DEAE036294F491187C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Increasing minority representation in research on rare diseases and conditions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part G of title IV of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/288">42 U.S.C. 288 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H47B79693115D49BA99976D434D9567DA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H173F96FFCF644C0BA449F936E9E6C235"><enum>487E.</enum><header>Increasing minority representation in research on rare diseases and conditions</header><subsection id="H9FCD4BA23A034B0BAB8D473604CDCD04"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out section 487, the Secretary may award grants to eligible entities involved in research on rare diseases and minority health to establish programs to increase the recruitment and retention of members of minority groups to conduct research in matters relating to the cause, diagnosis, prevention, and treatment of rare diseases or conditions, including by expanding the number of internships and mentoring opportunities.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF40D0C6D59404C1680B81F98641A7462"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In subsection (a), the term <term>eligible entities</term> means accredited schools of allopathic medicine, osteopathic medicine, and nursing, and other health professional training programs. </text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H7075A0FD11074A5F885B3F6D96E11C61"><enum>7.</enum><header>Report to Congress on Federal efforts on rare diseases and conditions in minority populations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health and in consultation with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall submit to Congress—</text><paragraph id="HCC37A4F24E7B422887A0C5852755A388"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a report on research and public health activities carried out by the Federal Government with respect to rare diseases or conditions in minority populations (as those terms are defined in section 409K of the Public Health Service Act, as added by section 2 of this Act);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB77C5B8CB81470184842E2BD3B86A94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a comprehensive list of known rare diseases and conditions that impact minority populations heavily or disproportionately; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H789956C072284E1B90AFF8156B094973"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an analysis of data gaps with respect to rare diseases and conditions and the effect of such diseases and conditions on minority populations.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HBF2BD4363FE64B15A854B0E9AE72DCE9"><enum>8.</enum><header>Research and awareness campaigns with respect to rare diseases and conditions in minority populations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/243">42 U.S.C. 243 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 317V (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b-24">42 U.S.C. 247b–24</external-xref>) the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF701138D23C54F3F9EB0719379915008" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H9DF696266E86428BBD47937D2FCC87C9"><enum>317W.</enum><header>Research and awareness campaigns with respect to rare diseases and conditions in minority populations</header><subsection id="H1A1F884625AA4DC2A9309D0C5061A231"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Research</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall conduct or support research and carry out public health awareness campaigns with respect to rare diseases and conditions in minority populations (as defined in section 409K).</text></subsection><subsection id="H70688EE611E341EF818EA9E336900810"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Awareness campaign</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, directly or through grants or contracts, establish a public education program in cooperation with existing national public awareness campaigns to increase awareness about rare diseases and conditions in minority populations through culturally and linguistically appropriate information campaigns about prevention and management of rare diseases and conditions.<italic></italic></text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HCB1F0D10F89549BFA7B72DC0A02D7ECD"><enum>9.</enum><header>FDA survey and report on clinical trial diversity</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, shall—</text><paragraph id="H16F6F372AE8D4635A3F68CFEACC9EA72"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a survey of policies and programs of the Food and Drug Administration to support an increase the availability of clinical trial data on minority populations, with an emphasis on minority populations with rare diseases and conditions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89F21142565D49D6A831C39837628C9F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to Congress a report containing—</text><subparagraph id="H0836BF688FE84759BFAC8F445804AF36"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the findings of such survey;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9CAB1FA55394232875D95ADF4C3D68C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary’s recommendations for statutory or regulatory changes to increase the availability of such data;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H514F50C435FB44429CD4FBC34C47174F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary’s recommendations for strategies to encourage drug manufacturers to address racial equity and inclusion in research and development of treatments of rare diseases or conditions that disproportionately impact minority populations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20D6640E3F1648AB81807E62A41FC0EB"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary's recommendations for strategies to address research and development of treatments of rare diseases or conditions that disproportionately impact minority populations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H2EA9D6C0653A44859A2D1A58C45D15C0"><enum>10.</enum><header>Tribal epidemiology center grant program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title II of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1621">25 U.S.C. 1621 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H987DC69639BA4208848E43A6F41E2513" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H1FFCFB48CC834DCDA1F777F5C1874131"><enum>227.</enum><header>Tribal epidemiology center grant program</header><subsection id="H73DE3486091B48B59FE09C6FCDC1FF6B" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Service, shall award grants to Tribal Epidemiology Centers and Tribal and Urban Indian Health Centers to support clinically and culturally appropriate research and other activities with respect to rare diseases and conditions in Native American or Tribal communities.</text></subsection><subsection id="H124FA81CFB2044CF9A524F1F8B832BCF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Permissible activities</header><text>The activities funded through a grant under subsection (a) may include coordination of data collection on the prevention, diagnosis, treatment, and care of rare diseases and conditions by health care professionals serving American Indian and Alaska Native populations.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H49A8D2D55AF64B9D97D44DA15880D33F"><enum>11.</enum><header>Medicare review and report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Service shall conduct a review of and submit to Congress a report on the following:</text><paragraph id="HCF423E1E38E8418DB3391A59CCD5FF67"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Regulatory barriers under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>) that inhibit access to the treatment of rare diseases for Medicare beneficiaries of color, including barriers that inhibit health care providers from improving care related to such diseases for such beneficiaries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93564E47B142448AA6A50AD8DBE48304"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Requirements relating to the furnishing of telehealth services under such title insofar as such services relate to the treatment of rare diseases.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">Such report shall include any recommendations determined appropriate by the Secretary based on such review.</continuation-text></section></legis-body></bill> 

