<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEF4E27E9D9C44B98B790D2DF1FF4C622" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 883 IH: Countering Subversion and Negligence in Protecting Election Runners Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 883</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250131">January 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to provide candidates with a justification for candidate protection determinations, to require Senate confirmation of the Director of the United States Secret Service, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8C5F7456636041C3A259C96D351927A8" style="OLC"><section id="HBAD68E25153E4D16A99A0B8CF7D935EC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Countering Subversion and Negligence in Protecting Election Runners Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Counter SNIPER Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD10FD8514C7645B398BA11A8C1979E72"><enum>2.</enum><header>Presidential candidate protection; Senate confirmation of Director</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3056 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H99103FA3FA734FFE871DA5CE1694D235" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H0FFAB8F1CFFA4D09A24511B4006C7B3A"><enum>(h)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H23874F58468E40EFB51F5B2283F2D5F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case that the Secretary of Homeland Security determines that any Presidential or Vice Presidential candidate requesting a protective detail or an increase in assigned protective detail resources is not eligible for such detail or increased resources for the purpose of this section, the Secretary shall submit to the candidate and the advisory committee, within 14 days after such a request is made, a written notice of the Secretary’s determination, indicating the criteria that such candidate failed to meet for such purpose.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB023EBC31E07413191683F673BA89B8F" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any Presidential or Vice Presidential candidate may submit to the Secretary of Homeland Security a written request to reconsider the determination described in paragraph (1), which may include facts to support that the criteria specified by the Secretary of Homeland Security have been met for the purpose of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBDFCE5862D14DE2AF1F0C7E812D1267" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 14 days after a request for reconsideration is submitted under paragraph (2), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall review such request and submit to the Presidential or Vice Presidential candidate a written notice of the Secretary’s final determination on whether the criteria have been met for the purpose of this section, and provide a copy of such final determination to the advisory committee.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF2C759F12C9B43FE81903FC7A356AA2C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The United States Secret Service shall be headed by a Director, who shall be appointed by the President with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

