<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEA0AC487533843968A977545210A7A39" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 685 IH: Expressing support for testing for antiphospholipid syndrome (APS) as a standard part of prenatal screening, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 685</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250909">September 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001039">Mrs. Cammack</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for testing for antiphospholipid syndrome (APS) as a standard part of prenatal screening, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas antiphospholipid syndrome (APS) is a condition in which the immune system of an individual mistakenly produces antibodies that increase the risk of blood clots;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas APS can increase the risk of miscarriages, stillbirths, and pregnancy complications;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas professional medical associations and guideline-setting bodies do not recommend testing for APS as a standard part of prenatal screening;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas professional medical associations and guideline-setting bodies recommend testing for APS only if a woman has an unexplained fetal loss after 10 weeks or 3 or more unexplained embryonic losses (miscarriages);</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas APS is responsible for about 15 percent of recurrent pregnancy losses;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the total number of miscarriages caused by APS is unknown because it is not tested as part of normal prenatal screening;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas APS can be detected by a blood test and treated by blood thinners; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas testing for APS during normal prenatal screening can save babies and reduce grief for women and families: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HCAA0E50E045B4092901D7B95CAC7E613"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H10D038EF919E48EFB7A64F3A1FD54817"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H3FA5F702BE3640E69CEC645EF7A0C630"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports testing for antiphospholipid syndrome (APS) as a standard part of prenatal screening; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H93E9E570EDD0449FA41D121014F630E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls upon professional medical associations and guideline-setting bodies to update their recommendations to include testing for APS as a standard part of prenatal screening.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

