<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H628EFC5959CD48598B2CA8964E4179F7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 881 RH: DHS Restrictions on Confucius Institutes and Chinese Entities of Concern Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 62</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 881</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–87]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250131">January 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000300">Mr. Evans of Colorado</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001220">Mr. Strong</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250505">May 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="L000603">Mr. Luttrell</cosponsor> and <cosponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250505">May 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on January 31, 2025</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish Department of Homeland Security funding restrictions on institutions of higher education that have a relationship with Confucius Institutes, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HHM00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H51E018AD49E34764AB99A8309C41AD0E"><section id="HE5A10A10D942430687DECD3B6A5E8B82" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DHS Restrictions on Confucius Institutes and Chinese Entities of Concern Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2381FAEF629C47EA955C110A89FB0B8B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitations on Confucius Institutes’ host schools</header><subsection id="H5DAD19A6944F4064B7C9719D11F89B57"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HC362FE04499F480CA7C809A2F455EF63"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chinese entity of concern</header><text>The term <term>Chinese entity of concern</term> means any university or college in the People’s Republic of China that—</text><subparagraph id="H2C505CD4BFA3465ABA7291E3A8D98FC2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is involved in the implementation of military-civil fusion;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFBED720ADE14A108D42CEA4A6CD06C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>participates in the Chinese defense industrial base;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H607E8E41C85342D79C793CD216759A31"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is affiliated with the Chinese State Administration for Science, Technology and Industry for the National Defense;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9457C642D0E640229EC98B153FB05327"><enum>(D)</enum><text>receives funding from any organization subordinate to the Central Military Commission of the Chinese Communist Party; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48E7B19F662E4710B2245CF2DC9A26DE"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides support to any security, defense, police, or intelligence organization of the Government of the People’s Republic of China or the Chinese Communist Party;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H265FE0F334164E2D86FE0CE44001647B"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">purposefully undermines the United States’ relationship with Taiwan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5087D33E5A534CC58AC1B382B3D68375" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">aids, abets, or enables the detention, imprisonment, persecution, or forced labor of Uyghur Muslims in the People’s Republic of China;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0B2ED8A1CBA4706BCE8E326D217D267" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">willfully and knowingly engages in malicious activities, including online disinformation campaigns and propaganda, for the purpose of interfering with United States Federal, State, or local elections; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0740DCBD95A04974A7333CA393B66221"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is affiliated with the Chinese Academy of Sciences.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA87DACD41E140A69F8271F9DB9BE2FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Confucius Institute</header><text>The term <term>Confucius Institute</term> means a cultural institute funded by the Government of the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7964A70A9C2F4649B0BC30F4E497A50E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC246C4D911E4F47B6D11B5ED8DDCB2F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Relationship</header><text>The term <term>relationship</term> means, with respect to an institution of higher education, any contract awarded, or agreement entered into, as well as any in-kind donation or gift, received from a Confucius Institute or Chinese entity of concern.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H800007C031DC4E48A2030D29FEAF6625"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Thousand Talents Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Thousand Talents Program</quote> means any technological or educational program funded or administered by the Chinese Communist Party’s Ministry of Industry and Information Technology.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA12C525967EE4195A2871CC70507073E" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Restrictions on institutions of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning with the first fiscal year that begins after the date that is 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that an institution of higher education (referred to in this subsection as an “institution”) which has a relationship with a Confucius Institute, Thousand Talents Program, or Chinese entity of concern is ineligible to receive any funds from the Department of Homeland Security, unless the institution terminates the relationship between the institution and such Confucius Institute, Thousand Talents Program, or Chinese entity of concern, as the case may be. Upon termination of such a relationship, the institution at issue shall be eligible to receive funds from the Department of Homeland Security.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2A88B0350D6247329C527DE08C13315F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header><paragraph id="H73EAF4CA383A4A9A9322B072EE5E538F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security may, after consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, on a case-by-case basis and for a period not to exceed one year, waive the application of subsection (b) with respect to an institution of higher education if the Secretary determines the institution at issue maintains robust safeguards and enforcement protocols to monitor the relationship at issue, including active measures to detect and deter attempts by Chinese nationals affiliated with a Confucius Institute, Thousand Talents Program, or Chinese entity of concern that is the subject of such relationship to gain unauthorized access to sensitive research, data, or federally funded development activities conducted at or on the premises of, or by, such institution, and either of the following conditions is satisfied:</text><subparagraph id="H0BBED42ADFDF48B19C68562E21671C61" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The relationship at issue is in the national security interests of the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82A0B7B7BFEE403991D32C6EF68BAD2D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The relationship at issue does not present a direct or indirect national security risk to the United States or its allies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H92ADEABF92CF466B8D2D99C0B6107E8A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Renewal</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may, after consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, annually renew a waiver issued pursuant to paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines all of the conditions described in such paragraph continue to be satisfied.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD92F9C7541D49D3B9D07A4F216A4EE5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective dates</header><text>A waiver issued or renewed pursuant to paragraph (1) or (2), respectively, takes effect and applies beginning on the date that is 30 days after such issuance or renewal, as the case may be.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2156EFC638DA46CA8722DB46D0754222"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>If the Secretary of Homeland Security, after consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, issues or renews a waiver pursuant to paragraph (1) or (2), respectively, not later than 30 days before such issuance or renewal, as the case may be, takes effect, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate written notification regarding such issuance or renewal, including a justification relating thereto.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D58DA561CEB4CA2B4633FFC893FD2EA" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Assistance</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide outreach and, upon request, technical assistance to institutions of higher education relating to compliance with this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBCBFFC5C1E9C4C3AB92DE501F8671D70"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report regarding implementation of this section during the immediately preceding 12 month period. Each such report shall include information relating to the following:</text><paragraph id="H501C91E0445046EE86CE4FBEB75EDB2D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any institution of higher education that has a relationship with a Confucius Institute, Thousand Talents Program, or Chinese entity of concern and receives funds from the Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF577B37E61274E3993515963C10FEF43"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The implementation of subsections (b), (c), and (d).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20250505">May 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

