<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H241B39100D7449F3A338804232D8DE00" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1602 IH: Financial Privacy Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1602</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250226">February 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000626">Mr. Davidson</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to provide for greater transparency and protections with regard to Bank Secrecy Act reports, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="H7A891A5AE48244C8BB2942C8F309322F"> 
<section id="H2942FAFF541F4B46945B47356968C162" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Financial Privacy Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD7C0A7FB7D034BF29F3670F93020FBDF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H61AFA6230B974A85AE4915CAFBCCCC95"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuant to the Bank Secrecy Act (<quote>BSA</quote>), the Secretary of the Treasury, acting through the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (<quote>FinCEN</quote>), collects millions of reports annually on the economic activity of ordinary Americans.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF5438DCC59BE446BA56A03B77A431B03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Since 2001, FinCEN has applied the BSA to collect over 322,000,000 Currency Transaction Reports and more than 36,000,000 Suspicious Activity Reports, as well as nearly 5,000,000 Form 8300 Reports. In addition, FinCEN expects to amass beneficial ownership information (<quote>BOI</quote>) from 32,000,000 companies in its initial year of collection, plus 5,000,000 additional companies implicated each year thereafter.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE322C7051AAC4509AC7FF694B24AF35B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The mass of reporting collected by FinCEN suggests that, while certain BSA reports might prove useful to combat illicit finance, the bulk of BSA-related data may possess little to no nexus to legitimate law enforcement or intelligence purposes, even as it encompasses highly sensitive details on the everyday lives of Americans.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3F2CD3F0A83A4ABCADE9363B5DB1519D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>By law, the Secretary of the Treasury must ensure the security and confidentiality of BSA data. In a Notice of Proposed Rulemaking from December 2022, FinCEN acknowledged that <quote>BOI is highly sensitive information. FinCEN therefore views it as critical to mitigate the risk of unauthorized disclosure of BOI as much as possible.</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H423A119B4D9E4CEEAD79F739EA63579F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reports to Congress; Review of protocols for agency access to reports</header> 
<subsection id="H65170BB8966F431BB7BFFB2C879E6319"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/53">Chapter 53</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H39832B1DFB064718921F4E66E1AFC9C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subchapter II, by inserting after section 5326 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HDFBA9E793EDE46709ED41FF22886FED9" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HF5B285BEFB534200A8A7CA5D654DC32B"><enum>5327.</enum><header>Reports to Congress; Review of protocols for agency access to reports</header> 
<subsection id="H4602105DEC124C269F51DAAA5904D232"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days following the date of the enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate a report containing the following:</text> <paragraph id="H5CDED7B379F9468D9C34D9C4307EC332"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of reports, by type, filed each year with the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (<quote>FinCEN</quote>) under this subchapter since January 1, 2022.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H28E694B3F8E443D7B3D63D66ECAF928A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The total number of reports filed under this subchapter retained by FinCEN.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6263F7DBB60C45C1969E8FE910CC3451"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of any written protocols or guidance from the Secretary to national security, law enforcement, or intelligence agencies regarding agency access to, and retention or dissemination of, information held by FinCEN from reports filed under this subchapter, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H056DE059F0E9453EA40703CA52412348"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of any updates to the protocols or guidance during the reporting period;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD2BA59A0FA0E4EB59D56C00D4D56EE3B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of queries by such agencies to access the information during the reporting period; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8E1AEF6E702640ADA9900324254544EA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any denials of requests for, or revocations of, access by a national security, law enforcement, or intelligence agency, or by any employee thereof, with a description of the reasons for the denial or revocation, as the case may be.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HED77E562B43D4815A5F0B25E099F9249"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review and revision of protocols</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In consultation with the Director of National Intelligence and the Attorney General, the Secretary of the Treasury shall annually review and, as appropriate, revise any written protocols or guidance described under subsection (a) for the purposes of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3B628654B05D48C3BCFF9E72266EC63A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">better tailoring the collection, retention, and dissemination of information filed under this subchapter to authorized national security, law enforcement, or intelligence objectives;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1CC4993ACE4343608940C7A10DEC53AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enforcing prohibitions against unauthorized disclosure of such information; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEC50705DEBC740938163068CD266A40E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>protecting fully the legal rights of all United States persons, including freedoms, civil liberties, and privacy rights guaranteed by Federal law.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1F32E8F979994C5CAA41FFCA52F6963F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Congressional requests; notice of changes</header> <paragraph id="H17115D602C0E458CB4580ECDE5E46069"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requests for information</header><text>Upon request of the chair or ranking member of the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives or the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, the Secretary shall provide a copy of any written protocols or guidance described in subsection (a)(3).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE8A45DB044F9444BBED5D01E61150643"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice of changes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after revising any written protocols or guidance described in subsection (a)(3), the Secretary shall provide a copy of such revised written protocols or guidance to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC9C551150C374603B790A231A6E103C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the table of contents for such chapter, by inserting after the item relating to section 5326 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H50D8FF2C5647400E9AB3D9F72BD4AFC9" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">5327. Reports to Congress; Review of protocols for agency access to reports.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9A475DA544CC4DEE9D4A6EE1AE8E3939"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>On the date that is the end of the 7-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act—</text> <paragraph id="HC46E808D7C5C450EBA1B31B73DB10574"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 5327 of title 31, United States Code, is repealed; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A6223138C3849F087EE7A894CEF3EB3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the table of contents for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 5327.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

