<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6ADB4D3019DC41BF9CA8A45079E57054" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 508 IH: Bring American Companies Home Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 508</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250116">January 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000590">Mr. Green of Tennessee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To allow expensing of amounts paid to move business property from China to the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H59DFCC43BDD04E4E8383D8D58C3C4EFA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H910598F942D143449387C24177FF3A12" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bring American Companies Home Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H483FFAA6C5F94B89AA68512769DEF8E2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expensing of amounts paid to move business property from China to the United States</header> <subsection id="H1930ACBA9A2E47228E1F17FCCDC56D8C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate) shall establish a program under which amounts paid by a United States person (as defined in section 7701(a)(30)) to move inventory and equipment and supplies used in a trade or business of the taxpayer from China to the United States are allowed as a deduction in the taxable year in which paid by the taxpayer.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H07C2BD361AFF4A1198984BB3DC32B22F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate) shall issue regulations under the program carried out under subsection (a) that restrict the amounts that may be expensed under such program to business moving expenses (within the meaning of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the regulations and guidance issued thereunder).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE46CF5A3A606468183D17D09C283E0F7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expensing paid for with tariffs collected from China</header> <paragraph id="H6486C2614D9A4D99AD3A7EA2F5E5CAA5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment of trust fund</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund consisting of such amounts as are appropriated to such trust fund under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE0FE3867F98F4BA9B8B2A2272F654D36"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriations to trust fund</header><text>There are hereby appropriated to such trust fund amounts equivalent to the tariffs collected by the United States on goods manufactured in China.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC33AC3D374984A7ABAA0497F0B7F0A38"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriations from trust fund</header><text>There are hereby appropriated from such trust fund to the General Fund of the Treasury amounts equivalent to the reduction in revenue to such General Fund by reason of subsection (a).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEF64336D9A11412FAB0294A7729AFDDD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Timing of transfers, etc</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9601">section 9601</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall apply with respect to appropriations to and from such trust fund under paragraphs (2) and (3).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

