<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA866ACC7B5574B72A8A7F41B25B8BBEA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4000 IH: To prohibit persons who are not citizens of the United States, except for those from the “Five Eyes”, from accessing or entering Department of Energy sites and facilities.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4000</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit persons who are not citizens of the United States, except for those from the <quote>Five Eyes</quote>, from accessing or entering Department of Energy sites and facilities.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0E796B2BD01D48E095079059562F4529" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H24A721331A634A07BA16D4506804EBFF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibition on access or entrance to Department of Energy sites and facilities by non-U.S. citizens</header> 
<subsection id="HF1E60BC14A004513ADFC59971D189C07"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, except as provided in subsection (b), a person who is not a citizen of the United States may not access or enter any site or facility owned, operated, or leased by the Department of Energy.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H22C95E06792C45ECA10CDFAF84E2EF77"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The prohibition under subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to any person who is a citizen of Australia, Canada, New Zealand, or the United Kingdom.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBF9D3942B9BE4B66855275594835440C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prohibition under subsection (a) shall take effect on the date that is 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H263D13F5A6B1413EA9E42E473D8A86F1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy shall revise any regulations, guidelines, policies, and procedures as necessary to carry out this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

