<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HEN25357-8V6-R5-0G7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 108 IS: Affirming the rule of law and the legitimacy of judicial review.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 108</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S414">Mr. Ossoff</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Affirming the rule of law and the legitimacy of judicial review.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Constitution of the United States establishes 3 separate but equal branches of Government;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Article III of the Constitution of the United States vests the <quote>judicial Power of the United States . . . in one supreme Court, and in such inferior Courts as the Congress may from time to time ordain and establish</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Supreme Court of the United States, in Marbury v. Madison, established the principle of judicial review, which empowers Federal courts to hold that a legislative or executive act violates the Constitution of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Vice President Vance and other prominent elected officials have made remarks suggesting the President or the executive branch may ignore the constitutional authority of the Federal Judiciary and disregard a decision of a Federal court; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the President or the executive branch ignoring the constitutional authority of the Federal Judiciary and disregarding a decision of a Federal court would precipitate a constitutional crisis: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate affirms that—</text><paragraph id="id9c9687e70e27470dbab50b44bc01d0b6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Article III of the Constitution of the United States vests the <quote>judicial Power of the United States . . . in one supreme Court, and in such inferior Courts as the Congress may from time to time ordain and establish</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2f8f09062882419cb8616dbd959865ab"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as Chief Justice Marshall held in the Supreme Court’s landmark 1803 decision Marbury v. Madison, <quote>It is emphatically the province and duty of the judicial department to say what the law is</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida10ff7a417c545098b89fe8249d033d1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Constitution of the United States and established precedent require the executive branch to comply with all Federal court rulings. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

