<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H81B74FE6E6AF46CFBA6F738809910836" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3767 IH: Health Professionals Scholarship Program Improvement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3767</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250605">June 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001098">Mr. Hamadeh of Arizona</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor
          name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
        referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans'
          Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for a time frame for the employment in the Department of Veterans Affairs of participants in the Health Professionals Scholarship Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H17BA41EC7A3C4CB99924FD3C66FD72F7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HEF0F266EFC2E426097179010372DFAF5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Health Professionals Scholarship Program Improvement Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HPSP Improvement Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H8812DBC27C82402891E2FFCC7FFDB520"><enum>2.</enum><header>Time frame for employment of participants in Department of Veterans Affairs Health Professionals Scholarship Program</header> 
<subsection id="H5B779E5E7430453D89B80A4082A64F03"><enum>(a)</enum><header>in general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7616 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HD33E7EE975954167907EF8365EB13A1D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H6E71AA954B2646A7A3694D29D834F666"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the course completion date of a participant in the Scholarship Program, the Secretary shall ensure that the participant receives a contract for employment in the full-time clinical practice of such participant’s profession at a Department facility with the highest need, as determined by the Secretary. Such contract shall include a competitive salary and benefits package consistent with the employment standards of the Department.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H179805888FB44883A571C82CCB63BF5C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<paragraph id="HE14672BEDCC44F408D0018203F711F0D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter until the termination date specified in paragraph (2), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report on the implementation of subsection (d) of section 7616 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFCA3E088E0124FFFB67B59744180CF54"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination date</header><text>The termination date specified in this paragraph is September 30, 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

