<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H81C3696D1E5A4E1395F08227893E62C5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2747 IH: Healthy Affordable Housing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2747</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to establish a grant and loan program that provides amounts to eligible entities to use to develop, create, or preserve qualifying affordable dwelling units, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF981950D69B24DFEA16027020FB5D6A7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HEE26D7846C274A77A4AB183F164322D0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Healthy Affordable Housing Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF452D67D9CC2465CB3A160A762C3E8E7" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant and loan program for affordable dwelling units</header> <subsection id="H313F377A89DA425590F3231B81B8015D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall, not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, establish a grant and loan program that provides amounts to eligible entities to use to develop, create, or preserve qualifying affordable dwelling units in neighborhoods that the Secretary has determined have shortages of affordable housing.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3F0FA5B460C4432AADB574D86A8E07B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application and selection</header> 
<paragraph id="H9EC3D69F892E4A6EBE039CB99C9C3EFB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To apply for a grant or loan under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H789151A0147D492B98AEA0994BE13EC9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Location requirement</header> <subparagraph id="HCCA3D3A8F0C3427E983F7708AD0BED3B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Grants and loans may only be awarded to applicants that propose to develop, create, or preserve qualifying affordable dwelling units that are in a neighborhood with—</text> 
<clause id="HD0A1DE01CD2E4E8FBAF883BF6D50CF84" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a Federally qualified health center;</text></clause> <clause id="H6FB33911E71F405797DC7510C441FE15" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a health care provider who, as determined by the Secretary accepts Medicaid and provides primary care services;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H48818756C06A4F3CAE52509B602403D1" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a grocery store that accepts Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program, or the Nutrition Assistance Program, benefits and Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children benefits;</text></clause> <clause id="H426238C528C942A8BC83BFAC4DDA2E08" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a State licensed child care provider or an eligible child care provider under the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act that cares for at least one child to whom the provider is not related;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5985FC37E1FF46E898E8B6ABA3597C42" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a pharmacy; or</text></clause> <clause id="HC00D3112E14F401E8B8BB13C7969841D" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>public transportation, as such term is defined in paragraph (15) of section 5302 of title 49, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H248D306A54144505A9DE8775F4E2F1E5" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Preference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall give preference to applicants that are—</text> <clause id="H518C078E9B4A4BFBACC2FE135B2F5B35"><enum>(i)</enum><text>developing, creating, or preserving qualifying affordable dwelling units that are not more than a mile from 2 or more of the types of amenities listed in subparagraph (A); or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF1862990DCEE4EBFA20EAC3F3F500446"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing, creating, or preserving, with or without the assistance of a partnering entity, qualifying affordable dwelling units that are located in buildings that have or will contain any of the amenities listed in subparagraph (A). </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7DE79838678C47C884402AD8CC316BCE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in administering the grant and loan program, may establish selection criteria relating to—</text> 
<clause id="H5A7630FE20CC4D6992F8E9C85E69B455"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how many qualifying affordable housing units will be developed, created, or preserved;</text></clause> <clause id="H60183F54642B4D8CB172E7D7F9334CF1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the boundaries of the neighborhood in which the qualifying affordable dwelling units are to be developed, created, or preserved; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H734FD34BB215460796341DB6C1E36D31"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the area median income in the area in which the qualifying affordable housing units are to be developed, created, or preserved.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H24B97A2F5C7F4D018DA9137BEA193FDE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Survey</header> <paragraph id="HB2AA232204FB4D869591BC5BA59A2828"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header> <subparagraph id="HE9BAAF22112B4C21B2B7AA20B4A9DEFA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Two years after the date that any qualifying affordable dwelling unit is first occupied after being developed, created, or preserved using amounts provided under this section, and every 2 years thereafter for 10 years, the Secretary shall conduct a voluntary survey of residents in such dwelling unit about any benefits they perceive associated with being physically near the amenities listed in subsection (b)(2)(A).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF123E58F30174671A81C83483D0DDDB2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Control group permitted</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may, if the Secretary determines appropriate, survey persons who are not residents in a qualifying affordable dwelling unit that received amounts under this section as part of a control group for the survey required under subparagraph (A). </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H626ED6F1ECAC46F9A110BB1EA86CDD92"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header> <subparagraph id="H4A10BC3079964779B38C9A70B9959794"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall, not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary completes a survey required under paragraph (1), compile the results of each survey conducted under paragraph (1) and submit a report about such results to the Committees on Appropriations and Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Appropriations and Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8E5C1E38AECB41F384829F42688B4750"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall evaluate, with respect to each qualifying affordable dwelling unit developed, created, or preserved using amounts provided under this section, whether nearby the amenities identified in subsection (b)(2)(A) have closed or changed location in the time since the previous report submitted under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H97BEC4E696924CD38D55D65C0F0312ED"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header> <paragraph id="H4F630C375EB041D7A720B15BD11A778A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit the Secretary from awarding a grant or loan under this section to a person who has applied for another funding opportunity administered by the Secretary relating to the development, creation, or preservation of affordable housing units.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9207E3AF872E4B1893CF4AF6B359271E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rental assistance</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit a qualifying affordable dwelling unit that is developed, created, or preserved using amounts provided under this section from receiving tenant-based assistance or project-based assistance under section 8(o) of the United States Housing Act of 1937.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD94123443D0842979D2F4A020CBFA47B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $100,000,000 in each of fiscal years 2025 to 2029 carry out this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H15D4DDA95B194356B5BF880970DDA2D3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HF983FA99A38F4BC080A8167F71ED84B3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H92E470D35ADA4E66B1FBA26A21F2D4B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a unit of general local government, including county government;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1E4D9DD3D64E42A7B056CA4E6DA88BFB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a tribe, tribal entity or tribally designated housing entity;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBD9C92D0089E4B48B51882303A85843F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an owner or developer of a qualifying affordable dwelling unit;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9103851AB0504A7BA821E7E608F69440"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a public housing agency;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB0EB18EF025942C5998925326B85A2B1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an organization with a mission that involves the development, creation, preservation, renovation, operation, or maintenance of affordable housing; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H86D403A3F7234C2ABF6F130D758160C2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any combination of the entities described in subparagraphs (A) through (E).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE99A219368A84D0683124B09E2741809" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federally qualified health center</header><text>The term <term>Federally qualified health center</term> has the meaning given the term in section 1861(aa)(4) of the Social Security 22 Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(aa)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8186406E7D2D4BFCB4F44BB49D223C7F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualifying affordable dwelling unit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualifying affordable dwelling unit</term> means a dwelling unit that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB95D6A4BFB054E01A2491844FAE78ED5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>qualifies as affordable housing under 215(a) of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H19026D2AB365437E8BDB89650A606A88"><enum>(B)</enum><text>meets the income targeting requirements described in section 214(1) of such Act. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1382C0CBE15F45BDB505FB05E610D624"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

