<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HECA67B1B69294E1AAFCA03889CDF4DDA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2496 IH: Dairy Nutrition Incentive Program Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2496</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250331">March 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000600">Mr. Langworthy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001222">Mr. Miller of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000622">Mr. Riley of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000300">Mr. Evans of Colorado</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to establish a dairy nutrition incentive program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H11DC89B6390C4AD28D47A205F9C31952" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1F65E4687E4948E498CB1E927BECE779" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Dairy Nutrition Incentive Program Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H04A7AB840A884D13A27DD01E20DCAEF1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Dairy nutrition incentive program</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H11EAD36381674CDB99DE210352D02F45"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2011">7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H516A122165454D259585F2370D81BB41">
<section id="H87738BCEA19045AC9BE08D310AB84BFB"><enum>31.</enum><header>Dairy nutrition incentive program</header>
<subsection id="H6A87EC0DC88844FBA7927B8AAB2E2E0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H5307C257FCBF405488B787426A9AB3C6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Dairy product</header><text>The term <term>dairy product</term> means a product for which cow’s milk is listed as—</text>
<subparagraph id="H677B4B9ACBBE46D3B5ED6A44CCBCF1EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the first ingredient on the labeled ingredients list of the product; or </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H317434DB112E47F181896841ED32258F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the second ingredient on the labeled ingredients list of the product, if the first listed ingredient is water.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9C2706812D9A4076B94FE7C5995B32F4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H18D2EC76A4A740D98F9F0E3773D340A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State or local governmental entity; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5A24644C677D4EEDB53E67E95403CB38"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC7B944D95D5947E5B4FC0921D7A91653"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fluid milk</header><text>The term <term>fluid milk</term> means any variety of pasteurized cow’s milk that—</text>
<subparagraph id="HDC86B04632B245AD8FD3CB1C6592CD29"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is packaged in liquid form; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDDB96CF29C9D405086498A8DC1E064B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>contains vitamins A and D at levels consistent with the Food and Drug Administration standards, and applicable State and local standards, for fluid milk.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H94459C68DE984CB48D2982A643A158F1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Naturally nutrient-rich dairy</header><text>The term <term>naturally nutrient-rich dairy</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HE9F753FEA9EB4F22855C58920AEE96E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>fluid milk;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2769060A17F445DEA682325C1F2461F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>yogurt and other cultured cow’s milk dairy products; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB04D62D4FE1648A08CB7FEA796D66704"><enum>(C)</enum><text>cheese (including nonstandardized cheese) made from cow’s milk.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H980F08F223EF48629576A40A1133C281"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <quote>program</quote> means the dairy nutrition incentive program established under subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA62940AC73A641759354DF7CDBD911D0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall establish a dairy nutrition incentive program under which the Secretary shall develop and test methods to increase the purchase and consumption of naturally nutrient-rich dairy by members of households that receive benefits under the supplemental nutrition assistance program by providing an incentive for the purchase of naturally nutrient-rich dairy at the point of purchase to members of households purchasing food using those benefits.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HB29E6D115E8C4CB3B8B154C188950685"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grants or cooperative agreements</header>
<paragraph id="HE837264B8D8A460D928AE69E84B440D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To carry out the program, the Secretary shall enter into cooperative agreements with, or provide grants to, eligible entities, on a competitive basis, for projects that meet the purpose of the program described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6BE90003CA964D8A9210AFF637D32005"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible entity seeking to enter into a cooperative agreement or receive a grant under the program shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2ED03F6792984F0EA544584EF7721B7B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text>The Secretary shall develop and make public criteria for evaluating proposed projects in applications submitted under paragraph (2), which shall incorporate a scientifically based strategy designed to improve diet quality and nutritional outcomes through the increased purchase of naturally nutrient-rich dairy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD469B0E12B748888C36A0FF8459B502"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In entering into cooperative agreements and awarding grants under the program, the Secretary shall give priority to projects that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H126C4F8D1EED498A83333800E1B77FF5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>maximize the percentage of funds used for direct incentives for participants in the supplemental nutrition assistance program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H51433EAFC84E41F0896C9DA2746A4B85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include a project design—</text>
<clause id="HEB94EF15863C45C4B473FED3926E3F55" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that provides incentives when naturally nutrient-rich dairy is purchased using benefits under the supplemental nutrition assistance program; and</text></clause> <clause id="HE7C445C587AB41939D974708AEDF6468"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in which the incentives earned may be used only to purchase naturally nutrient-rich dairy;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H450F420FAA6A4EBB813535962EDA1437"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include project sites that serve members of households that participate in the supplemental nutrition assistance program; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD9D001C7908468C97625DCC826E9B1A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>incorporate the use of point-of-sale systems that can electronically issue incentives earned under the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB8FF9C0F17F74FA58DB141773FB720D9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Additional financial assistance</header><text>An eligible entity may request funds from the Secretary, pursuant to section 16, to offset initial costs to enable electronic benefits transfer technology for electronic point-of-sale systems described in paragraph (4)(D) for projects sites selected under the program.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H29D46A81C86F403A90D943D68F9E14B1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evaluation</header> <paragraph id="HCE001D72353F4E5BA2D2739706402457"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall provide for an independent evaluation of each project carried out under the program that measures, to the maximum extent practicable, the effect of incentives on purchases of naturally nutrient-rich dairy by members of households that receive benefits under the supplemental nutrition assistance program.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4E4F2E7DF19040269A231BCDC5665CED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Methodology requirement</header><text>The independent evaluation under paragraph (1) shall use rigorous methodologies, such as random assignment or other methods that are capable of producing scientifically valid information regarding activities that are effective.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD429DE95BFE444888FD12576FEB2D5A6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Discontinuance</header> <subparagraph id="HF66DB0B552CD4B589EB1F0F24B44DF75"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), subject to availability of funds, nothing in this section shall limit the continuation of a project carried out under the program. </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4CD5B17B028548BEB767D2390B5B43E7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Noncompliance</header><text>The Secretary may discontinue a project or close a project site under the program if the project—</text> <clause id="HED34D8A0B64843BA8929BE3EF5F5F4EF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>does not comply with the requirements under this section;</text></clause>
<clause id="H37D78EADB3E54B8D81E5B9627950E530"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not comply with the requirements of the grant awarded or cooperative agreement entered into under the program, as applicable; or</text></clause> <clause id="H0AE582C8171B4D2EA8409C47DD8CA22C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if the Secretary determines that the results of the independent evaluation of the project under paragraph (1) are not satisfactory.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H57D2E7F5F4384BDBAE541FE136D44B36"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public dissemination</header><text>The Secretary shall make publicly available the results of each independent evaluation carried out under paragraph (1). </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC3E55E257921434C9561D6EA5116638A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than December 31 of the first full calendar year following the date of establishment of the program, and biennially thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives a report that includes a description of—</text>
<paragraph id="HC7E4CD6FF85C4ABFB9EB4F8CF3867B9C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the status of each project carried out under the program; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H05B642B623EF4E95B533BAE35A26E765"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the results of each completed evaluation under paragraph (1) during the period covered by the report.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HABCC858C6CEA44E2A5B196A5A7B6F172"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding</header>
<paragraph id="H74CE68A60B604139B4789116C59A2682"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mandatory funding</header><text>There is appropriated to the Secretary, out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $10,000,000 for each fiscal year to carry out this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0A147270DA84C469D609FC635E95B21"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> <subparagraph id="H013A4FC6EF66498AA06B5A3D39B377C4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to the funds made available under paragraph (1), there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2026 and each fiscal year thereafter.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB093B7EAE51E404582B5DCB4E1F88D38"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appropriations in advance</header><text>With respect to any funds made available under subparagraph (A), only funds appropriated in advance specifically to carry out this section shall be available to carry out this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC1D84315B174439B73474D6ECFCD2F6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Evaluation costs</header><text>Of the funds made available to carry out this section for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall use not more than 7 percent to carry out subsection (d).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H75C73FFEFAE145FDB36839E9755B380F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation on use</header><text>Funds made available to carry out this section shall not be used for any project that limits the use of benefits under the supplemental nutrition assistance program.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC57E88575F9747A1A3AED51CC07BFDA0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transition from healthy fluid milk incentives projects</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H824CE9E6CDBC49BFBB3B77D33FEE41C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall transition projects carried out under section 4208 of the Agriculture Improvement Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2026a">7 U.S.C. 2026a</external-xref>) to be carried out as part of the dairy nutrition incentive program established under section 31 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6713CE5F90934FD48B310497DEE9199D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No interruption</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall ensure that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F1FEEF4430746ECADFB1F26F7890824"><enum>(A)</enum><text>there is no interruption in projects being carried out under section 4208 of the Agriculture Improvement Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2026a">7 U.S.C. 2026a</external-xref>) during the transition described in that paragraph; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6536A34E0A41444EAB062434018DB648"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any additional authorities or flexibilities under the dairy nutrition incentive program established under section 31 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 shall be applied to the projects described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6E6679FA74994DEA983602C60806B49A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text>Effective 1 year after the date on which the Secretary certifies that the Secretary has completed carrying out paragraph (1), section 4208 of the Agriculture Improvement Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2026a">7 U.S.C. 2026a</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

