<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCF7D6729B9B94381AC262D9C24AA07C6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4202 IH: Protect Honduran Democracy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4202</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250626">June 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000590">Mr. Green of Tennessee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of State to establish a strategy for monitoring the general elections in the Republic of Honduras to take place on November 30, 2025, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB5196EFD85AF45F8A656CE1F15C6CCA7" style="OLC"><section id="H5CD865C4591D4029AC885E106A11C137" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Honduran Democracy Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB45C2F12BAEF446EA061F97DEF39AD39" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H6F20599CE3FC4194B8396272E1ECD4AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the 2025 election process in the Republic of Honduras raises serious concerns about the fairness of the electoral process, including irregularities with the March 2025 primary election, violence against candidates and the actions undertaken by security and defense forces under the ongoing state of emergency, including serious human rights violations which undermine the conditions of the election;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H796E4BF7AE2D49419C5D0DB8D1428BEB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there is a need for the United States to support efforts to ensure elections in the Republic of Honduras to take place on November 30, 2025, are free and fair; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75E9B730F14549E9A89EC448B501C976"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Armed Forces of Honduras and other relevant institutions with a role in the electoral process should respect their role within the confines of the constitution of Honduras and protect the democratic process.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H6CDCBDF3E3204BF0BD7D9C26DA6B3C7D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Strategy</header><subsection id="H6BC2B6AD0CF74370A8D33880E37ABFA8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State shall establish a strategy to promote free and fair elections in Honduras to take place on November 30, 2025.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA9D3E2728B3048ED9F9E1E1E9726CA45"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The strategy required by subsection (a) shall include support for monitoring the elections by credible and internationally recognized elections monitoring bodies, such as the Organization of American States, the European Union, the United Nations, and experienced civil society observers and others to achieve the following:</text><paragraph id="HBF161D7D35DA48B6957EFE23970B571B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensure that candidates to public office are not subject to harassment, undue legal persecution or other efforts to misuse State resources to dissuade them or undermine their candidacies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6A90CA5C70B47DDBB661C83C4916B77"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Avoid the misuse of State resources aimed at influencing voter preferences.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC218CE3056F4414A7BB59FF9AE9C3D7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Avoid the use of violence and intimidation, including by transnational criminal organizations, local gangs, or political parties and their proxies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FB5F2742C3B4488BD0DB9366F254161"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Guarantee freedom of speech and assembly.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H54DB666FF0114DFCA428CF8269029F16"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensure transparent and credible transmission of elections results.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3381884A8DDE409AB9CF622C87FF3E9D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President, acting through the Secretary of State, is authorized to provide assistance on a grant basis to nongovernmental organizations for activities—</text><paragraph id="H13C34ACAE30B4F33948016F5A4A20B68"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to monitor the national elections in Honduras to take place on November 30, 2025; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53896DA680D446D0A8D27292F20B3FC1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to assess the extent to which these elections are held on a free and fair basis.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H20BD39FECDAE49D5BB7B8E96D9F54076"><enum>5.</enum><header>Sanctions</header><subsection id="H8A9A383F369449E7B1ADA19BFEE6DEB1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any foreign person, including any current or former official of the Government of Honduras or any person acting on behalf of that Government, that the President determines—</text><paragraph id="HFD8857EACC374EDF8C156FC834BA8840"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has unduly prevented, or is responsible for ordering or otherwise directing the undue prevention of, any candidate, or prospective candidate, in the general elections in Honduras to take place on November 30, 2025;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51A96CDD096E4C098FC391251A927367"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has knowingly materially assisted, sponsored, or provided significant financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services in support of, the commission of the acts described in paragraph (1); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD77866C0A42F4F239310577516B7E775"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has carried out acts of intimidation or harassment toward candidates, election officials, or election observers, including through the use of spurious legal action.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3A3B3FB3AD544CB28724AC2008F2D218"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><paragraph id="H8B8B8E71801B4E66BC0AD6215AC6B811"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are, in the case of an alien determined by the President to be subject to subsection (a), denial of a visa to, and exclusion from the United States of, the alien, and revocation in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>), of any visa or other documentation of the alien.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA4610C0813247A29F70F8808E1FBFB9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The sanctions described in paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to a foreign person that—</text><subparagraph id="HF84B6AE200BB47FB95694F5AF1E8D463"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the President determines is the subject of other sanctions equivalent to those described in paragraph (1); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB07F5B4694C54ED191C54C0E7629B66F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is an alien, if admitting the alien into the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC878247874BD42829E2FF8C69FA2E271"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of sanctions under subsection (b) with respect to a foreign person if the President—</text><paragraph id="HBF239596E7A74B52A49C13CBCADBA4AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determines that such a waiver is in the national interest of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD50931F8A7864771993AB77D08553646"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on or before the date on which the waiver takes effect, submits to the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a notice of and justification for the waiver.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4924578CC5374F5CAE1EB63BB93F2E25"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text>The President shall issue such regulations, licenses, and orders as are necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H802EA5A96FC14D7384227FE85537809A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Promotion of migrant participation in elections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress encourages the Secretary of State to promote the ability of citizens of Honduras residing in the United States to vote in the general elections in Honduras to take place on November 30, 2025.</text></section><section id="HA54091D85C214ED6AF432AFEDE201A3B"><enum>7.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the President should continue to seek to coordinate with other countries, particularly Central American countries, a comprehensive, multilateral strategy to further the purposes of this Act, including, as appropriate, encouraging other countries to take measures with respect to Honduras that are similar to measures described in this Act.</text></section><section id="HF5892E82EFCE411CB98F2DFE72806F19"><enum>8.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subsection id="H5B58C3885BA14A13B2D0599BAF46FC29"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $1,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2026 and 2027.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA75C16E46D9444CB9D7C388672E84078"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text>Amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under subsection (a) are authorized to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

