<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25517-0XM-7D-VVD"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1125 IS: Cultural Trade Promotion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1125</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250325">March 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To promote exports by creative industries and occupations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cultural Trade Promotion Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" id="id1f0ca39b65264f79b9522313018bf6fc"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="idB8111BF664BA441A9F42AAACA875B27D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Creative industry or occupation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>creative industry or occupation</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id3ff7a3b951224d37be18d3ce4b90f9f3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an industry that—</text><clause commented="no" id="id94826926A2C54EAF8980822C4FE83732"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has a substantial current or potential impact (including through positions that lead to economic self-sufficiency and opportunities for advancement) on a State, regional, or local economy or a Native American community's economy, as appropriate; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idF5FA056601DA478191F861F701A811EE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>contributes to the growth of businesses, nonprofit organizations, or self-employment opportunities that have their origin in individual creativity, skill, and talent, including such businesses, organizations, or opportunities focused on design, crafts, music, visual and media arts, performing arts, language, literature, or expressions of Native cultures or regional or local heritage culture; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id1c68fb21f2574458bf090b43918ed71a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an occupation that—</text><clause commented="no" id="id6E6AE615229B42C99D89E093DC2BD432"><enum>(i)</enum><text>currently has or is projected to have a number of positions (including positions that lead to economic self-sufficiency and opportunities for advancement) in an industry sector so as to have a substantial potential impact on a State, regional, or local economy or a Native American community's economy, as appropriate; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id4B09413B6BF640E7B37C26AB7BDAA047"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is comprised of—</text><subclause commented="no" id="id3FA964AEA1304709B23AD0801504A84D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>businesses or nonprofit organizations described in subparagraph (A)(ii); or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id8677FF56BA164C468BFF11A64AA36DF5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>individuals who are self-employed or sole proprietors and whose work has an origin in individual creativity, skill, and talent, including a focus on design, crafts, music, visual arts, media arts, performing arts, language, literature, or expressions of Native cultures or regional or local heritage culture.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id51843E6C7EB54E3CBC867678EC84B4D1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Native American</header><text>The term <term>Native American</term>, used with respect to culture, means the culture of a Native American, as defined in section 103 of the Native American Languages Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2902">25 U.S.C. 2902</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></section><section id="idC06E12B412E14BEB9150DA8E2A56AF13"><enum>3.</enum><header>Promotion of exports from microenterprises and creative industries and occupations</header><subsection id="id7096F7A18C1B4F50BB20EAE859A8F5EF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Promotion of exports by United States and Foreign Commercial Service</header><text>Section 2301(b) of the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/4721">15 U.S.C. 4721(b)</external-xref>) is amended, in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>small businesses and medium-sized businesses</quote> and inserting <quote>microentrepreneurs (as defined in section 172 of the Program for Investment in Microentrepreneurs Act of 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6901">15 U.S.C. 6901</external-xref>)), small businesses, and medium-sized businesses</quote>. </text></subsection><subsection id="id1D9866E43F2C4FE3B8CDCD81120FD13D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategic plan of Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee</header><text>Section 2312(c) of the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/4727">15 U.S.C. 4727(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idF54CD961E4E641CFA6F18F720A4FC283"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB58011FADA5149A790B4696651ED10AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (7)—</text><subparagraph id="idDC5AE99F6A394E7BBAD665991482FC5E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>microenterprises (as defined in section 172 of the Program for Investment in Microentrepreneurs Act of 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6901">15 U.S.C. 6901</external-xref>)) and</quote> after <quote>better assist</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id66FCDB1FFDE548DC9599F3E057B070EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id60340544EABE4B8E962875EEA6F9AEAA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id638EAE522D9940CB839BCF0020386BB3"><paragraph id="id08AB74C463B94EF5A63E863D2AA747CB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>consider how to promote exports of goods and services from creative industries and occupations (as defined in section 2 of the <short-title>Cultural Trade Promotion Act</short-title>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idC78A8132321D438D9AF2F5A6CF6E15BA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Promotion of exports of Native Hawaiian arts and crafts and exports from Native Hawaiian owned-Businesses</header><text>Section 2307 of the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/4726">15 U.S.C. 4726</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id6292006F13674397B93C50655706B3FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or Native Hawaiian</quote> after <quote>American Indian</quote> each place it appears; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id31207AC068974397ADA7B2C8E0411BBD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="id228C4CA0D3BC4841B2A4C5AAFECE32EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or Native Hawaiian</quote> after <quote>include Indian</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id42792934530D4668A554A2C5CCE379E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or Native Hawaiian-owned</quote> after <quote>Indian-owned</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5E1AB037C2F54BD3AA0F29C61F1B88BC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by striking <quote>hand made or hand crafted</quote> and inserting <quote>made</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id1548525939F740F6A4DBE0A64FA1C8A6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Collaboration to improve access to reliable international shipping services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Under Secretary of Commerce for International Trade, the Assistant Secretary of Commerce and Director General of the United States and Foreign Commercial Service appointed under section 2301(a)(2) of the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/4721">15 U.S.C. 4721(a)(2)</external-xref>), and the Postmaster General shall consult and collaborate with respect to how to better connect microenterprises (as defined in section 172 of the Program for Investment in Microentrepreneurs Act of 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6901">15 U.S.C. 6901</external-xref>)) and small businesses to fast, reliable international shipping services that meet the expectations of the modern consumer.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC8D2E26F5A004246B821FE4CC0CA7FE0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Focus on creative industries and occupations by Trade and Development Agency</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 661(a) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2421">22 U.S.C. 2421(a)</external-xref>) is amended in the second sentence by striking <quote>and environment</quote> and inserting <quote>environment, and creative industries and occupations (as defined in section 2 of the <short-title>Cultural Trade Promotion Act</short-title>)</quote>. </text></section><section id="idb9d86e348e8b4e65a2bca1f39a1e70c8"><enum>6.</enum><header>Travel and tourism advisory board</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including any regulation), the Secretary of Commerce shall appoint to serve as a permanent member of the United States Travel and Tourism Advisory Board established pursuant to section 3 of the Act of February 14, 1903 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1512">15 U.S.C. 1512</external-xref>; 32 Stat. 826, chapter 552), and <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, a representative of creative industries and occupations. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

