<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1D0F7F80ADA24B95BB7AABC5A384FE02" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4750 IH: Patawomeck Indian Tribe of Virginia Federal Recognition Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4750</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To extend Federal recognition to the Patawomeck Indian Tribe of Virginia, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H11B34C0D6C6A426098782325D400C595" style="OLC"><section id="HC9B3EFBCC8ED477FB71ADC607A3EE81C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Patawomeck Indian Tribe of Virginia Federal Recognition Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD659A011546E41CAB50D226C47AE2580"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text><paragraph id="H5B9DC3ADBB6E47D4929E0E2D1B603027"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Patawomeck, or Patawomeke, Tribe, also referred to as the Potomac Tribe, Potomac Band, Patamacks, and White Oakers was situated in and around Indian Point and Pasapatanzy in what are now Stafford and King George Counties, Virginia, and occupied a prominent place in the documented history of the first half-century of European contact with the Native Virginians.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H95C201092F5946E48A317FC94B621A1B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In 1608, Captain John Smith visited the village of Patawomeke between Potomac and Accokeek Creeks. The population of the Tribe was estimated at about 800, with 160 bowmen. Around this same time, Smith also visited and recorded the Patawomeck villages at Passapatanzy, Quiyough, and other small Patawomeck hamlets in the area.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB86056D5D3244AFF8D4FEB44A0B6F509"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 1610, Japazaw, brother of the Patawomeck weroance, related the Patawomeck creation story to Captain Samuel Argall, the only surviving Virginia Algonquian creation story recorded by the English.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4249DA7D53EE44228EAFFF256B079770"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In 1642, Patawomeck weroance, Wahanganoche, and his family were baptized into the Christian faith by Father Andrew White.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01C59B6807A2410CADEDEABA780F2623"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1662, Wahanganoche was issued a silver badge by the King of England to wear for safety when traveling across English lands and as an acknowledgement of Patawomeck sovereignty. The weroance was acquitted of charges of high treason and murder brought against him by Captain Giles Brent at the General Assembly in James City that year, but died on his way home, or shortly after his arrival.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB4F4A6ED7EF4821B9A4BFC5DF3B7997"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In July 1666, the General Council of Virginia declared war on the Patawomecks. Most of the men were killed and most of the women and children, who were not already living in English families, were captured as slaves. Others likely joined with nearby existing Indian groups such as the Doegs, Nanzaticos, and Portobagos.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF3510D74B5F4FAC87654D31FA5B2428"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In 1680, King Pattanochus signs the Treaty of Middle Plantation of behalf of the <quote>Nansatiocoes, Nanzemunds, and Portabacchoes</quote>. By this time, displaced Patawomecks are living among these groups of people.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C23AE47B2314B3288B723C67DCED4CE"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In 1692, A reference to payment for Rangers in Stafford County notes the presence of <quote>two Indians belonging to Stafford</quote> in the detachment, illustrating the continued presence within the area of Patawomeck ancestors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H00615AB2DE6D449795E7B633BADCCC10"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Through most of the 1700s the Patawomeck community lived in the Northern Neck, moving as necessary. Portions of the community settled near the area known as Indian Town in modern-day King George County.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD53FB5F927C84122BA712A3329779248"><enum>(10)</enum><text>In 1789, White Oak church was established. This church, which still stands, became a significant space that facilitated the continued interaction of members of the Patawomeck community who attended well into the 1900s and used the regular meeting opportunities as venues to pass down and maintain Tribal knowledge and traditions, meet suitable Patawomeck marriage partners, and conduct business in formal and informal ways. Generations of Patawomeck ancestors account for the vast majority of the interments in the cemetery, including members with the surnames of Newton, Green, Curtis, Jett, and Monteith.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B921236F3A84249B2B1758AFA762DCF"><enum>(11)</enum><text>By the early 1800s, the majority of the Patawomeck community had again coalesced in the area of Stafford County known as White Oak, with some members living in nearby Passapatanzy, in King George County, only a few miles from the locations of their ancestral villages, dating back to the 1300s.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87FDE482CCDE47F1AE5B0E1D5447B0A4"><enum>(12)</enum><text>In 1832, Wahanganoche’s badge was found at Camden, in Caroline County, a well-known location of coalescent Indian communities and the likely location of a portion of the Patawomeck community in the late 1600s.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EC2D8653E9D48E9B778C91B45841FE5"><enum>(13)</enum><text>During the United States Civil War, vandalism, courthouse fires, and other disasters destroyed many of the records within the Stafford and King George County courthouses, serving to reduce the archival footprint of the Patawomecks within their historic areas of habitation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H340C6EFC65AC4AD2B5B9453F96E62849"><enum>(14)</enum><text>In the late 1910s and 1920s, the anthropologist Frank Speck, visited the Patawomeck community to take photographs, conduct interviews, and collect objects related to Indigenous heritage, noting that the <quote>northern divisions of the [Powhatan] Confederacy are represented by descendants on Potomac Creek in King George county …</quote>. Since this time, partnerships have existed between the Tribe and researchers from institutions such as the Smithsonian Institution, the University of Pennsylvania, the College of William and Mary, American University, the University of Mary Washington, and Santa Clara University.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4344F9045504D40A4CDDCC493439101"><enum>(15)</enum><text>In 1924, Virginia passed the Racial Integrity Act which removed the category of Indian identity from official records. Instead, all people were required to be identified as White or colored. This law, in addition to other aspects of the racialized society that existed in Virginia starting in the late 1600s, effectively erased Virginia Indians from the official records of the Commonwealth until the middle of the 1900s, amounting to a paper genocide.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H335A8FE750B144B897D031B8997B76D2"><enum>(16)</enum><text>In the 1930s and 1940s, at least 722 Patawomeck ancestors were taken from their graves under the guise of archaeological research. Many of these ancestors were discarded by the excavators. The remainder, numbering well over 200 individuals, are currently held by the Smithsonian Institution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE6F49A1028948349CDAFA267208D4F5"><enum>(17)</enum><text>In 1954, Elizabeth Newton of the Patawomecks married O.T. Custalow, Chief of the Mattaponis.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69B8E16CC3C542F290FEB8BBC26C8F48"><enum>(18)</enum><text>In 1996, the contemporary and formal reorganization of the Patawomeck Tribe took place with the adoption of a written constitution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F910C094BE844C291C2BE7477B4A196"><enum>(19)</enum><text>In 2006, in partnership with linguists the Patawomecks began to work on reconstructing their native Algonquin language and sharing it with other Tribes and fellow Virginians. Since that time the Patawomecks have taught, transcribed, greatly enhanced the common Algonquin dictionary, and educated hundreds of Virginians in classroom settings.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5B778EFFDB24D2B8FFCB049DAF4573B"><enum>(20)</enum><text>In February 2010, The Patawomecks received official recognition from the Commonwealth of Virginia after years of hard work by Tribal members and anthropologists at the College of William and Mary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B3154DF68964BC68E66F1034B969A45" commented="no"><enum>(21)</enum><text>The Patawomeck Tribe resides in Spotsylvania County, Virginia.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HFF736A07CBA146A3B863EA79C002B5A0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H626853FED4144E21832BFA2E9411B928"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H151CDA1ECECC4AFCA5888DB9B4AE0B85"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Tribal member</header><text>The term <term>Tribal member</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H2E7B022E420547A481528694797A2F1F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual who is an enrolled member of the Tribe as of the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H972DB3BA4D824178A53F11AA864D6D25"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an individual who has been placed on the membership rolls of the Tribe in accordance with this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H40A24DFC00424136B5FFC35873E8ED40"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Tribe</term> means the Patawomeck Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H48D02B30A8E74B6FABB43EAFCD6F287F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Federal recognition</header><subsection id="H48F7C7487F4344E4BED2437F170823AB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal Recognition</header><paragraph id="H10E644984C5F4BA0A7870B0DBDA1C91C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Federal recognition is extended to the Tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB01D32D8C934A6EAE531C717B22094C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability of laws</header><text>All laws (including regulations) of the United States of general applicability to Indians or nations, Indian Tribes, or bands of Indians (including the Act of June 18, 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5101">25 U.S.C. 5101 et seq.</external-xref>)) that are not inconsistent with this title shall be applicable to the Tribe and Tribal members.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF5BF4ACFE2E04E9C960E67ADC6B02FC3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal services and benefits</header><paragraph id="H2F774846846840EF8B6BC532E678F421"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On and after the date of enactment of this Act, the Tribe and Tribal members shall be eligible for all services and benefits provided by the Federal Government to federally recognized Indian Tribes without the existence of a reservation for the Tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE331113325BE4646ACAE62D9F4601DF6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Service area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of the delivery of Federal services to Tribal members, the service area of the Tribe shall be considered to be the area comprised of King George County, Spotsylvania County, and Stafford County, Virginia.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4EE536D9523F47F189218A862BD893B6"><enum>5.</enum><header>Membership; governing documents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The membership roll and governing documents of the Tribe shall be the most recent membership roll and governing documents, respectively, submitted by the Tribe to the Secretary before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section><section id="HB58DAD3598964151B3E650A49356987C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Governing body</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The governing body of the Tribe shall be—</text><paragraph id="HC095AB075958410C9760CBD8E582410F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the governing body of the Tribe in place as of the date of enactment of this Act; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE64F4BC30DD44373BDAD6A900C0AB9F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any subsequent governing body elected in accordance with the election procedures specified in the governing documents of the Tribe.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H880D35F277DD4D81823037F23DA2688E"><enum>7.</enum><header>Reservation of the Tribe</header><subsection id="H080B8B6E942546738E633D5B573AAC8B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon the request of the Tribe, the Secretary of the Interior may take into trust for the benefit of the Tribe any land held in fee by the Tribe, if such lands are located within the boundaries of King George County, Spotsylvania County, or Stafford County, Virginia.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFB5C42659BC94C8B81226FF428761411"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deadline for determination</header><text>The Secretary shall make a final written determination not later than 3 years of the date which the Tribe submits a request for land to be taken into trust under subsection (a)(1) and shall immediately make that determination available to the Tribe.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAF79FFB08BCB4C28B19255457D085E82"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reservation status</header><text>Any land taken into trust for the benefit of the Tribe pursuant to this paragraph shall, upon request of the Tribe, be considered part of the reservation of the Tribe.</text></subsection><subsection id="H79AB00CCEA0A406BBA673610CA416241"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Gaming</header><text>The Tribe may not conduct gaming activities as a matter of claimed inherent authority or under the authority of any Federal law, including the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2701">25 U.S.C. 2701 et seq.</external-xref>) or under any regulations thereunder promulgated by the Secretary or the National Indian Gaming Commission.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC161132F76DD4200AE4A429501EDAC50"><enum>8.</enum><header>Hunting, fishing, trapping, gathering, and water rights</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act expands, reduces, or affects in any manner any hunting, fishing, trapping, gathering, or water rights of the Tribe and members of the Tribe.</text></section><section id="H69FEE108487B4E57A01983CFD5FD3724"><enum>9.</enum><header>Eminent domain</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Eminent domain may not be used to acquire lands for a Tribe recognized under this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

