<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4850954BB8684818B6F9F55844066046" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 257 IH: Expressing support for the designation of March 2025 as “Music in Our Schools Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 257</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250326">March 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Vel&#225;zquez</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001231">Mr. Mannion</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of March 2025 as <quote>Music in Our Schools Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas music has been present in every known human culture throughout history and modern times;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas music is one of the most important manifestations of the cultural heritage of the United States, as music embodies our national identity and illustrates our shared history;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas music education helps communities share ideas and values among cultures and generations, promoting a more cooperative and inclusive citizenry;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas singing has existed in classrooms in the United States since before the signing of the Declaration of Independence;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 1838, music as its own curriculum was first adopted by public authority in the public schools of Boston, Massachusetts;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the development of a musical people has been and remains dependent on a public commitment to the teaching of music in all schools;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas State legislatures and educational agencies have supported music as part of the regular school curriculum;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Every Student Succeeds Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/95">Public Law 114–95</external-xref>; 129 Stat. 1802) identified music as part of a well-rounded education;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas music is a means for exploring the emotional and aesthetic dimensions of the human experience;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas music holds intrinsic value as an art form, providing opportunity for self-expression, fellowship, and spiritual fulfillment;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas research has documented that participation in school music programs promotes student engagement, leading to improved social and academic outcomes, particularly for at-risk students;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas research has documented that participation in school music programs also promotes cognitive, social, and emotional development, exercising skills valuable to the workforce such as motivation, attentiveness, self-discipline, teamwork, persistence, empathy, respect, and leadership; and</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas a disproportionate number of students without access to music education attend schools in urban or rural communities, public schools with a high percentage of students from low-income families, and public schools that are majority Black, Hispanic, or Native American: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HC8572DBF69CA45B8807AD838517F0C8A"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H3B23E8604E304637AC891715FC4DE963"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="HDBC529C731724447B6A1A39AF2B4F312"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>Music in Our Schools Month</quote>; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H432F6326878E426297A989625545038E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes—</text>
<subparagraph id="H6DE8C8051355465BA92D11A7F7E440CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the fundamental importance of music to the culture of the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB23A0528CBCC4778BABA11834CDF82FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the long history of music as an integral part of the schools in the United States;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5E9C3650C1174884BF5AA6A0125BE6B0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the disparate access to high-quality music education that exists across the United States; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H23FACAC23FF141F89C7BF13697C12EE0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the need to do more to support the teaching and learning of music in public schools.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

