<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H66A79629995A4B63A9767D76C9576451" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1455 EH: Institute for Telecommunication Sciences Codification Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IB</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1455</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To codify the Institute for Telecommunication Sciences and to direct the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information to establish an initiative to support the development of emergency communication and tracking technologies, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H885BC56003924F4CBB26051A2FBD89D1" style="OLC">
<section id="HCDC0121179D541A885963B7FA29478DE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Institute for Telecommunication Sciences Codification Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ITS Codification Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H659EF34969114856A69ED0841DBEFD40"><enum>2.</enum><header>Institute for Telecommunication Sciences</header> <subsection id="HE11255EC6FF440CDA4A48E8A62DDEB37"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H5EB08724490E48F1AD466FB5DF8B56D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The test center within the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>NTIA</quote>) represents executive branch agencies on spectrum issues before the Federal Communications Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A7BC9C314BF4228AE3FCE30DB50E552"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Understanding radio frequency propagation characteristics and modeling is a critical component of making spectrum decisions.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H322B155C2C834FFCB814DE200E6E7334"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Federal agencies rely on expert engineering studies, simulations, and analyses to make determinations about how to make spectrum available for commercial use, including through system relocations and identifying spectrum sharing opportunities through the NTIA.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D66488794384F54BB296E2E6CDABFDD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Clearing of Federal spectrum, when feasible, is the priority action to take to make Federal spectrum available for commercial uses as required by section 113(j)(1) of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/923">47 U.S.C. 923(j)(1)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H604AA21D25334A9E8EEAB412F15B7A2A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Sharing of Federal spectrum between Federal entities and commercial entities provides access to Federal spectrum for commercial uses in circumstances where clearing is not feasible.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H16368345304A4FA4A9C9D0CD9E8C836F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The test center within the NTIA is the Government’s premier expert laboratory for spectrum research activities, spectrum sharing innovation and testing, spectrum interference studies, and all activities related to advancing next generation wireless technologies.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6F698408FBF84D3899E1DE54FA21525F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The test center within the NTIA is critical for undertaking engineering studies and analyses that inform clearing or sharing opportunities and facilitate policy decisions to maximize the efficient use of spectrum resources.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD7CA110E2129431586ED23469071608D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Operation of test center</header><text>Part A of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/901">47 U.S.C. 901 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H47954753FB754CD690620828BBCD0BF2" style="OLC">
<section id="HF2227AF5A97D434388474C37674DC20C"><enum>106.</enum><header>Institute for Telecommunication Sciences</header>
<subsection id="HF86EF52FD0EF4AFE8C2C827AFD015D6E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header>
<paragraph id="H47006DA82E804AC6A3A0A6C6508359BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Under the authority provided to the Assistant Secretary under section 103, the Assistant Secretary shall operate a test center to be known as the Institute for Telecommunication Sciences (in this section referred to as <quote>ITS</quote>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEBFBED9F04D24067913785165A791DB1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Functions</header> <subparagraph id="HFDB9A161A87C446F968A7F7057C26547"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to any functions delegated by the Assistant Secretary under subparagraph (B), ITS shall serve as the primary laboratory for the executive branch of the Federal Government to—</text>
<clause id="H74C9980D1D20441F93819BF5C7B9C73F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>study radio frequency emissions, including technologies and techniques to control such emissions and interference caused by such emissions;</text></clause> <clause id="HF9EF23E8E6D14EC3980B38AAB6B402D1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>determine spectrum propagation characteristics;</text></clause>
<clause id="H123329BFD5234F0487A809D661DCE038"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>conduct tests on technology that enhances the sharing of electromagnetic spectrum between Federal and non-Federal users;</text></clause> <clause id="H8209E8E9ACE84C03928276C1AFEA109B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>improve the interference tolerance of Federal systems operating with, or using, Federal spectrum;</text></clause>
<clause id="HBF585CB4F10040B8944F1317AAD2D55C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>promote activities relating to access to Federal spectrum by non-Federal users and the sharing of Federal spectrum between Federal and non-Federal users; and</text></clause> <clause id="H7AC20F2117714DDDB70A2441FCD22A6C"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>conduct such other activities as determined necessary by the Assistant Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3A40AD31301C43218C979EE740923872"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional functions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary may delegate to ITS any of the functions assigned to the Assistant Secretary under section 103(b)(1). </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85B258AFD59341E5A27C9ACAC8EDB2B4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Agreements and transactions</header><text>In carrying out the functions described in paragraph (2), the Assistant Secretary, acting through the head of ITS, may enter into agreements as provided under the following authorities:</text>
<subparagraph id="HABC005FDCA0342F5AD7A7A3F8F6EB5FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sections 11 and 12 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3710">15 U.S.C. 3710</external-xref>; 3710a).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H756579C82A3F42AB9236AD439164EABE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 1535 of title 31, United States Code.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB0A8119D79BD49CEB9394C8D37FCE4BD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Sections 207 and 209 of title 35, United States Code.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC056ABAB65524AAA8C8CC869D1A80C8A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Section 103(b)(2) of this Act.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3FC3C765751344DDA0F77F20226F77E3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Section 113(g) of this Act.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDB86919155B34899AD5C052A6A7A3F77"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The first undesignated section of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/91/412">Public Law 91–412</external-xref>.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H23142D26C7214077A35660070272E495" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any authorization in any other Federal statute.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC40AE3D3F66245D28DDBE18D89C3F672" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal spectrum defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>Federal spectrum</term> means frequencies assigned on a primary basis to a Federal entity (as defined in section 113(l)).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H025A276F32AF4003B261905BDA066E21"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Emergency communication and tracking technologies initiative</header>
<paragraph id="HFA377532F1454E01A43452E80927406D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Assistant Secretary, acting through the head of ITS, shall establish an initiative to support the development of emergency communication and tracking technologies for use in locating trapped individuals in confined spaces, such as underground mines, and other shielded environments, such as high-rise buildings or collapsed structures, where conventional radio communication is limited.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A383C65A09843C79CCB5488F1882381"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>In order to carry out this subsection, the Assistant Secretary, acting through the head of ITS, shall work with private sector entities and the heads of appropriate Federal agencies, to—</text>
<subparagraph id="HFE41976EA7EF459395539FE0BE4772F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>perform a needs assessment to identify and evaluate the measurement, technical specifications, and conformity assessment needs required to improve the operation and reliability of such emergency communication and tracking technologies; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD93002756115440482EDDA929477CEEF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>support the development of technical specifications and conformance architecture to improve the operation and reliability of such emergency communication and tracking technologies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H065BC74635B6464197062A49D7BB1AA7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Assistant Secretary shall submit to Congress, and make publicly available, a report on the assessment performed under paragraph (2)(A).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250714" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives July 14, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

