<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7F81CBBBB79C4FC5A3C81F23B7B28D87" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 861 IH: American Music Fairness Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 861</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250131">January 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000590">Mr. Green of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 17, United States Code, to provide fair treatment of radio stations and artists for the use of sound recordings, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC69B73B733A24B84BEE78976B31C5409" style="OLC"><section id="HABAFAEDA12724109BC0CA51D9FFCDEA5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H35A7BEA1177846ABA68A379369F2701B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Music Fairness Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9446CEDA4EE34D0095FCC0985C70DEA2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="HABAFAEDA12724109BC0CA51D9FFCDEA5" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7A728F9A5239421CA50CE89A45B08E7C" level="section">Sec. 2. Equitable treatment for terrestrial broadcasts and internet services.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H08B13D835A11480B92621984B3A4B39E" level="section">Sec. 3. Timing of proceedings under sections 112(e) and 114(f).</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA621502CB59947D48E094461752E36DD" level="section">Sec. 4. Special protection for small broadcasters.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H166C94BB245E48EC94444AFD0B8273D1" level="section">Sec. 5. Distribution of certain royalties.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HE987386EBB6148CEB94AEEBB317E3941" level="section">Sec. 6. No harmful effects on songwriters.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H818723F12430469DAEF7CC9DFB008D49" level="section">Sec. 7. Value of promotion taken into account.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="H7A728F9A5239421CA50CE89A45B08E7C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Equitable treatment for terrestrial broadcasts and internet services</header><subsection id="HD6BCCB777E0E43BF8EC5848FE45514FE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Performance right applicable to audio transmissions generally</header><text>Paragraph (6) of section 106 of title 17, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="HC0E4F5AAC4704F91BF49EF54DE94B3F9" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H1D0BA301E3094B099C12CF487BF35094"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in the case of sound recordings, to perform the copyrighted work publicly by means of an audio transmission.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H0D484357C2864EB1B86483DE9E2BDBE1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion of terrestrial broadcasts in existing performance right and statutory license</header><text>Section 114(d)(1) of title 17, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HC7C3335EA7B740248016FB11F0953E0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>a digital</quote> and inserting <quote>an</quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5631A0C60F340C4AA84DC9A9B45B397"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (A);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCED502FCB7944B097F0C450CE2D9FC7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (B) and (C) as (A) and (B), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4B4EAA788DE4DEA913A31218F642C03"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), as redesignated by paragraph (3), by striking <quote>nonsubscription</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>licensed nonsubscription</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1BE3D551931B4C04A533C330E16635BF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="H40DB3F15BB574E7E9880A7CD03566932"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 101 of title 17, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the definition of <quote>architectural work</quote> the following:</text><quoted-block id="H9924AABACDA94540890F91C33F84B60F" style="OLC"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">An <quote>audio transmission</quote> is a transmission of a sound recording, whether in a digital, analog, or other format. This term does not include the transmission of any audiovisual work.</text><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H73179DD86FA64B2E974CADE36C7A84DF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming removal of digital</header><text>Title 17, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H2CF8AD89D4A34AE4B4A7EA87373BE86B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 112(e)(8), by striking <quote>a digital audio transmission</quote> and inserting <quote>an audio transmission</quote>; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25A751AF846B4B36A0BD83E716F53F88"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 114—</text><clause id="HBE52D80FEEFD4D25AC47AEF2D35045C5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text><subclause id="H70B99FFF06144A58B0F92501A931E3F1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><item id="H6FD2592921A1468D8C0BAB36B602A3AE"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>subscription digital</quote> and inserting <quote>subscription</quote>; and</text></item><item id="HBF0DB41DAEF84DA6950C1DED45B8D1AF"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)(viii), by striking <quote>digital signal</quote> and inserting <quote>signal</quote>; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H4461AD6CBAF9442CB10E324D5ADE3BC6" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text><item id="H91381634EE0F4872AAEE95A178424232" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>a digital audio transmission</quote> and inserting <quote>an audio transmission</quote>; and</text></item><item id="HF42530A895A649678E5A6B6808038081" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(i), by striking <quote>a digital audio transmission</quote> and inserting <quote>an audio transmission</quote>;</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HB0AE238E76F94E09AE5478A8EB2E76E3" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(2)(A), by striking <quote>a digital</quote> and inserting <quote>an</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H1E0C79E725F1433A9FF7AA4014011BFA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subsection (j)—</text><subclause id="HE7C6A67BB31B4D04859B7859398D5FB6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in paragraph (6)—</text><item id="H9DF0F83AECD44C1CA328293B140E87C7"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>by striking <quote>digital</quote>; and</text></item><item id="H4FC64978BBAF4B49A8B7171992B86DC5"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>by striking <quote>retransmissions of broadcast transmissions</quote> and inserting <quote>broadcast transmissions and retransmissions of broadcast transmissions</quote>; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HF615421E90664C069D9C1E72ECCFE725"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking <quote>subscription digital</quote> and inserting <quote>subscription</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A9E78ED2FF24C07A88E366A98961B26"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in section 1401—</text><clause id="H1040952F009E42E097275B812D46B34C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>a digital audio</quote> and inserting <quote>an audio</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HC7E58964F954446E868DFCC5305746CC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text><subclause id="HFDF14AD287524C5081D0CB3727C483CC"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>a digital audio</quote> and inserting <quote>an audio</quote>;</text></subclause><subclause id="H665A02A60B124D13B4F68E2CE06D4285"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)(A), by striking <quote>a digital audio</quote> and inserting <quote>an audio</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H454B258E8A774177B4688C5CE73D34DE"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (4)(A), by striking <quote>a digital audio</quote> and inserting <quote>an audio</quote>.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H08B13D835A11480B92621984B3A4B39E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Timing of proceedings under sections 112(<enum-in-header>e</enum-in-header>) and 114(<enum-in-header>f</enum-in-header>)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (3) of section 804(b) of title 17, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block id="H24C8762B356743CEA671DAA86352A5EC" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HCAFA99D572AE407E8E8CD5C5B592122C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A proceeding under this chapter shall be commenced as soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this subparagraph to determine royalty rates and terms for nonsubscription broadcast transmissions, to be effective for the period beginning on such date of enactment, and ending on December 31, 2028. Any payment due under section 114(f)(1)(D) shall not be due until the due date of the first royalty payments for nonsubscription broadcast transmissions that are determined, after the date of the enactment of this subparagraph, by the Copyright Royalty Judges. Thereafter, such proceeding shall be repeated in each subsequent fifth calendar year.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HA621502CB59947D48E094461752E36DD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Special protection for small broadcasters</header><subsection id="H0FFF3CFE503341FE90FF511C909AE564"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Specified royalty fees</header><text>Section 114(f)(1) of title 17, United States Code, is amended by inserting at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block id="H9BFB6CA252A945CE93AB5EE95C91FB18" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H5AFD921717024B8EB52145AE6D7AC704"><enum>(D)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H98EE5C52BE7E45259B3039592C5AA4E0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Notwithstanding the provisions of subparagraphs (A) through (C), the royalty rate shall be as follows for nonsubscription broadcast transmissions by each individual terrestrial broadcast station licensed as such by the Federal Communications Commission that satisfies the conditions in clause (ii)—</text><subclause id="HF6F47C2A83C248C6A3668EB3221D8223" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>$10 per calendar year, in the case of nonsubscription broadcast transmissions by a broadcast station that generated revenue in the immediately preceding calendar year of less than $100,000;</text></subclause><subclause id="HDAF919725B894B4EAD1A553B4A833B95" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>$100 per calendar year, in the case of nonsubscription broadcast transmissions by a broadcast station that is a public broadcasting entity as defined in section 118(f) and generated revenue in the immediately preceding calendar year of $100,000 or more, but less than $1,500,000; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H4A4A0C37625748E1AE5977CF85D371E9" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>$500 per calendar year, in the case of nonsubscription broadcast transmissions by a broadcast station that is not a public broadcasting entity as defined in section 118(f) and generated revenue in the immediately preceding calendar year of $100,000 or more, but less than $1,500,000.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HB02004DD167D4AF8BAD10A5001B4A4BE" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An individual terrestrial broadcast station licensed as such by the Federal Communications Commission is eligible for a royalty rate set forth in clause (i) if—</text><subclause id="H657CBF6EAFF44DACAF1E87968BD99B34"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the revenue from the operation of that individual station was less than $1,500,000 during the immediately preceding calendar year;</text></subclause><subclause id="H566CD574A976428EBD09B1D1055DE692"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the aggregate revenue of the owner and operator of the broadcast station and any person directly or indirectly controlling, controlled by, or under common control with such owner or operator, from any source, was less than $10,000,000 during the immediately preceding calendar year; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H06EE103A8A3543E299B7BE927D4B6EF2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the owner or operator of the broadcast station provides to the nonprofit collective designated by the Copyright Royalty Judges to distribute receipts from the licensing of transmissions in accordance with subsection (f), by no later than January 31 of the relevant calendar year, a written and signed certification of the station’s eligibility under this clause and the applicable subclause of clause (i), in accordance with requirements the Copyright Royalty Judges shall prescribe by regulation.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HCC3C2B3C6B32461BA7535F8112EC8AEC" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>For purposes of clauses (i) and (ii)—</text><subclause id="HDE94D3FC6CB1479BAEC9D9D5FC525238"><enum>(I)</enum><text>revenue shall be calculated in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles;</text></subclause><subclause id="H77F44A69BEDA43BCBAF347B57266FF6A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>revenue generated by a terrestrial broadcast station shall include all revenue from the operation of the station, from any source; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H5B39E74AEFB340ECA0B8DD00960D10C8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in the case of affiliated broadcast stations, revenue shall be allocated reasonably to individual stations associated with the revenue.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HADD39DD36E094ABB9F85784F95739724" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The royalty rates specified in clause (i) shall not be admissible as evidence or otherwise taken into account in determining royalty rates in a proceeding under chapter 8, or in any other administrative, judicial, or other Federal Government proceeding involving the setting or adjustment of the royalties payable for the public performance or reproduction in ephemeral phonorecords or copies of sound recordings, the determination of terms or conditions related thereto, or the establishment of notice or recordkeeping requirements.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H9A36EFB5E277445996D1369030D86FF2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical correction</header><text>Section 118(f) of title 17, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 397 of title 47</quote> and inserting <quote>section 397 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/397">47 U.S.C. 397</external-xref>)</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="H166C94BB245E48EC94444AFD0B8273D1"><enum>5.</enum><header>Distribution of certain royalties</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> Section 114(g) of title 17, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H0329043C892C4912B152A9F790772527"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>or in the case of a transmission to which paragraph (5) applies</quote> after <quote>this section</quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6EB9A172C4B497289FB3A035DE0DABA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (5), (6), and (7) as (6), (7), and (8), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7916F4E0F79D4C2E9A743B4FCA0525DF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="H0C3BB925DAA14571857E2B03E4A1C8DE" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H490BFBCA933742DB9067B25E2D66EE59"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), to the extent that a license granted by the copyright owner of a sound recording to a transmitting entity eligible for a statutory license under subsection (d)(2) extends to such entity’s transmissions otherwise licensable under a statutory license in accordance with subsection (f), such entity shall pay to the collective designated to distribute statutory licensing receipts from the licensing of transmissions in accordance with subsection (f), 50 percent of the total royalties that such entity is required, pursuant to the applicable license agreement, to pay for such transmissions otherwise licensable under a statutory license in accordance with subsection (f). That collective shall distribute such payments in proportion to the distributions provided in subparagraphs (B) through (D) of paragraph (2), and such payments shall be the only payments to which featured and nonfeatured artists are entitled by virtue of such transmissions under the direct license with such entity.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HE987386EBB6148CEB94AEEBB317E3941"><enum>6.</enum><header>No harmful effects on songwriters</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or the amendments made by this Act, shall adversely affect in any respect the public performance rights of or royalties payable to songwriters or copyright owners of musical works.</text></section><section id="H818723F12430469DAEF7CC9DFB008D49"><enum>7.</enum><header>Value of promotion taken into account</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Pursuant to section 114(f)(1)(B) of title 17, United States Code, in determining rates and terms for terrestrial broadcast radio stations under this Act, and the amendments made by this Act, the Copyright Royalty Judges shall base their decision on economic, competitive, and programming information presented by the parties, including whether use of the station’s service may substitute for or may promote the sales of phonorecords or otherwise may interfere with or may enhance the sound recording copyright owner’s other streams of revenue from the copyright owner’s sound recordings.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

