<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-NEW25616-VNK-36-1YR"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 260 IS: Expressing support for the designation of June 6, 2025, as “National Gun Violence Awareness Day” and June 2025 as “National Gun Violence Awareness Month”. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 260</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250602">June 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of June 6, 2025, as <quote>National Gun Violence Awareness Day</quote> and June 2025 as <quote>National Gun Violence Awareness Month</quote>. </official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, each year in the United States—</text><paragraph id="ide05311d34240439dbb169fc716476f63"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">nearly 46,000 individuals are killed and nearly 97,000 individuals are wounded by gunfire; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb7b64cf6d46c478da2c5800e7b627ef4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">more than 19,000 individuals are killed in homicides involving guns; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd22f3cc32264628b121dccb1f937515"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">nearly 26,000 individuals die by suicide using a gun; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idad707c97747f4e0291123a3e6fc092c3"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">more than 500 individuals are killed in unintentional shootings; </text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since 1968, more individuals have died from guns in the United States than have died on the battlefields of all the wars in the history of the United States; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas 2024 was a deadly year for the United States, with an estimated 16,700 people killed in gun homicides or nonsuicide-related shootings; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, in 2024, more than 360 people were unintentionally shot by a child under 18;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, by 1 count, in 2024, there were 503 mass shooting incidents in the United States in which at least 4 people were killed or wounded by gunfire;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nationwide, more than 87,000 military veterans died by gun suicide from 2003 to 2022;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, every year in the United States, more than 4,300 children and teens are killed by gun violence and more than 17,000 children and teens are shot and wounded; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas more than 15,000 people in the United States under the age of 30 die because of gun violence annually, including Hadiya Pendleton, who, in 2013, was killed at 15 years of age in Chicago, Illinois, while standing in a park; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, on June 6, 2025, to recognize the 28th birthday of Hadiya Pendleton (born June 2, 1997), people across the United States will recognize National Gun Violence Awareness Day and wear orange in tribute to—</text><paragraph id="id1f5a84569d6d440aa3d90b520c098e8b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Hadiya Pendleton and other victims of gun violence; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idac7daecab5984fdfa14f1e2924e8ddad"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the loved ones of those victims; and </text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas June 2025 is an appropriate month to designate as <quote>National Gun Violence Awareness Month</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id18992be48ae74145a51bf71fa4c78a77"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports—</text><subparagraph id="idf000da7b5447452eb8ce52bace9be761"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the designation of <quote>National Gun Violence Awareness Month</quote> and the goals and ideals of that month; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb28c49db79024f7aace5e1b5b6928a78"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the designation of <quote>National Gun Violence Awareness Day</quote> in remembrance of the victims of gun violence; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9380a756d9eb4e5092df1e01fb923cb8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls on the people of the United States—</text><subparagraph id="idc4122de90cf649779278a310d9025175"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to promote greater awareness of gun violence and gun safety;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd5f57b9ecc1449b1bbe9775b41595b99"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to wear orange, the color that hunters wear to show that they are not targets, on National Gun Violence Awareness Day;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id62084a0646cc42c196701b4d1e40abcd"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to concentrate heightened attention on gun violence during the summer months, when gun violence typically increases; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8830e5e3f0c44e29b52f873654fb7893"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to bring community members and leaders together to discuss ways to make communities safer. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

