<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7E3206E09770430F96514172BAD8A210" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3590 IH: Securing Continued Healthcare for Our Operations and Logistics Professionals Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3590</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250523">May 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to clarify that determinations regarding whether an individual who is a contractor providing services to an educational organization is a full time employee for purposes of requirements relating to an employer’s responsibility to provide health coverage are subject to rules that apply to employees of educational organizations.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H09AFE380916647CEAEDB2F3EA02D63DC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H82CAE9C291044B94BE86A4A8AE9C4DEC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing Continued Healthcare for Our Operations and Logistics Professionals Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SCHOOL Professionals Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9AEFF0B750A343D1B68E6F5EE78BD274"><enum>2.</enum><header>Clarification regarding shared responsibility of employers of certain contractors of educational organizations relating to health coverage</header> <subsection id="H6798EABF563E40D29BD3E651255873A2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4980H">Section 4980H(c)(4)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>Such rules shall provide that individuals who primarily provide contract services to an educational organization shall be subject to rules similar to rules that apply to employees of an educational organization for purposes of determining whether such individual is a full-time employee for purposes of this section.</quote> after the period at the end.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H60E503AD82B549158A758E2679F5B17F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to months beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

