<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25398-LVV-XV-C4M"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1302 IS: Increasing Transparency in Generic Drug Applications Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1302</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250403">April 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for increased transparency in generic drug applications.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="idce2d9bc2ca2e48e69e889732f5fd4c9d" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Increasing Transparency in Generic Drug Applications Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="HB9F5C5B4BEFF4113B9E5353DB0122775" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Increasing transparency in generic drug applications</header><subsection id="HB68576D81AB84A59B17F93D1C005BDF5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 505(j)(3) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(j)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H386A40737BC141D193D2A11FCCD58012" changed="not-changed"><subparagraph id="H1D8B3E6E88764A73B4C4D4DD25750C6A" indent="up2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(H)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H46A59284AB01444C8C2304BA8C17453B" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Upon request (in controlled correspondence or an analogous process) by a person that has submitted or intends to submit an abbreviated application under this subsection for a drug that is required by regulation to contain one or more of the same inactive ingredients in the same concentrations as the listed drug referred to, or for which the Secretary determines there is a scientific justification for an approach that is in vitro, in whole or in part, to be used to demonstrate bioequivalence for a drug if such a drug contains one or more of the same inactive ingredients in the same concentrations as the listed drug referred to, the Secretary shall inform the person whether such drug is qualitatively and quantitatively the same as the listed drug. The Secretary may also provide such information to such a person on the Secretary’s own initiative during the review of an abbreviated application under this subsection for such drug.</text></clause><clause id="H46DB6DB6D44B4185872B6C3A93A73BD8" indent="up1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Notwithstanding section 301(j), if the Secretary determines that such drug is not qualitatively or quantitatively the same as the listed drug, the Secretary shall identify and disclose to the person—</text><subclause id="HFE48D62E31864FF286456AB49700FF1C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the ingredient or ingredients that cause such drug not to be qualitatively or quantitatively the same as the listed drug; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HC9D108B4AE7F4B7F9593089E8FBE6657" changed="not-changed"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for any ingredient for which there is an identified quantitative deviation, the amount of such deviation.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H843C57D4F4E1453389CED988E6B1562D" indent="up1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines that such drug is qualitatively and quantitatively the same as the listed drug, the Secretary shall not change or rescind such determination after the submission of an abbreviated application for such drug under this subsection unless—</text><subclause id="H6C0128F3941244E593F54048C05C69A7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the formulation of the listed drug has been changed and the Secretary has determined that the prior listed drug formulation was withdrawn for reasons of safety or effectiveness; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H22E4D811590D4E43B9587693A5FBCC09" changed="not-changed"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Secretary makes a written determination that the prior determination must be changed because an error has been identified. </text></subclause></clause><clause id="H228743AC56444F1F9D699B331C198E09" indent="up1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary makes a written determination described in clause (iii)(II), the Secretary shall provide notice and a copy of the written determination to the person making the request under clause (i).</text></clause><clause id="HDD55BCFB612C44169B931A9A2922C408" indent="up1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The disclosures authorized under clauses (i) and (ii) are disclosures authorized by law, including for purposes of section 1905 of title 18, United States Code. This subparagraph shall not otherwise be construed to authorize the disclosure of nonpublic qualitative or quantitative information about the ingredients in a listed drug, or to affect the status, if any, of such information as trade secret or confidential commercial information for purposes of section 301(j) of this Act, section 552 of title 5, United States Code, or section 1905 of title 18, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H1CF0B38E7AE246CA90F1B2AB934BD802" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance</header><paragraph id="HDD5E1B55F9A24041A8A11FD42891A347" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue draft guidance, or update guidance, describing how the Secretary will determine whether a drug is qualitatively and quantitatively the same as the listed drug (as such terms are used in section 505(j)(3)(H) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, as added by subsection (a)), including with respect to assessing pH adjusters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4B21B2F52654634A0681E79682A90FC" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In issuing guidance under this subsection, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall—</text><subparagraph id="H3E9ACDE7FAE74C02984FC084AF40A4C7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publish draft guidance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F978F0C6BB445F3844F4D7F841353F9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide a period of at least 60 days for comment on the draft guidance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9828E1A4A80841C58375BD90B2191378" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>after considering any comments received and not later than one year after the close of the comment period on the draft guidance, publish final guidance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD7F5EB5BE7B2476F9AFE246807F6BB55" changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Section 505(j)(3)(H) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, as added by subsection (a), applies beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, irrespective of the date on which the guidance required by subsection (b) is finalized. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

