<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9E05F967C35D47C4852AFB0176FA7594" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4592 IH: No Radioactive Roads Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4592</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250722">July 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to revise section 61.206 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, to approve certain distribution or use of phosphogypsum, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H23E4E2B07F564E6893AE38B02542CED6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H37B8C199552C42C3A8D7BABCA7D9DB06" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short Title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Radioactive Roads Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H230F8ECE12AE4484A1EB1A7DF882F2FF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2154ACD5397544439316C15BB88F2E7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Since 1992, the Environmental Protection Agency (hereinafter referred to as the <quote>EPA</quote>) has prohibited the use of phosphogypsum in road construction, citing numerous scenarios that would expose the public, and especially road construction workers, to an unacceptable risk of cancer.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E8B6D8E36324FC3BF8A6B8AC9A1081E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>EPA prohibited use of phosphogypsum in roads because it contains uranium and radium that produce radionuclides linked to higher risks of cancer and genetic damage. The Clean Air Act was amended in 1977 after finding that exposure to radioactive materials can cause serious harm to health, and that exposures to radioactivity are cumulative, which means each new or additional exposure increases the risk of serious illness.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9375169444354B94BAC5D126748CFEAE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>EPA found that phosphogypsum used in roads could contaminate nearby surface and groundwater quality through leaching, and that radioactive material could be resuspended into the air by wind and vehicle traffic.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBEB930ADC72245BA8288A63D4AECC4AF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>EPA found that stacking of phosphogypsum presented a lifetime cancer risk of 9.1 in 100,000, meaning that any alternative distribution of phosphogypsum must meet this same protective threshold.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD2D3D148F2A848C7A9CEBD6A049B1719"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Director of EPA’s Office of Radiation and Indoor Air has testified that use of phosphogysum as <quote>road building material could not meet the EPA’s risk criteria</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H260862D4B113453590B77C86134D8D9D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>EPA has further acknowledged it cannot authorize categorical approvals and requires case-by-case consideration of other uses.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H5D4D81FCEC9448C4AA98AED6F1DF2BF1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Clarification of Other Purpose</header> 
<subsection id="H786B5466DECC4BE1AE202F1C33EC9239"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall promulgate a final rule revising section 61.206 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, to ensure the following:</text> <paragraph id="H5F971BDFD3DB4F12ADBB6B33A583B287"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any request that Administrator approve distribution or use of phosphogypsum for any purpose not expressly specified in section 61.204 or 61.205 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2B3779B261B041EFB6C4481038E13060"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the maximum individual risk imposed on a person due to exposure to a pollutant;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H09014C7C45374C4E839A08F210A3807F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of measures to minimize, to the greatest extent possible, exposure to any individual who may be directly or indirectly exposed to phosphogypsum, in furtherance of the other purpose, including a—</text> 
<clause id="H0A8A10CCEED248629E0651FB75BAFB94"><enum>(i)</enum><text>construction worker;</text></clause> <clause id="HC9D6384B6070470A8D0C42419902CD8C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>utility worker;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE99696EF8B83428385E10312DD824C06"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>user of any final product that includes phosphogypsum; or</text></clause> <clause id="H476A4B0A8E5D4B37B88536F5C8C6CF70"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>nearby resident of an area of exposure to phosphogypsum; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC26BD6C4E2C24741AA3CF01F1282C366"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of both surfacewater and groundwater exposure pathways and a monitoring program to eliminate potential exposure to contaminants within the water pathways that includes—</text> <clause id="H7D3C2EB1D79741229D13886200E73381"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an estimate of the amount and composition of leachate from phosphogypsum expected from the phosphogypsum application throughout the product’s lifecycle;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H21A91FC3BB4E49F6875AFAC65E126CEC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an estimate of ecotoxicity impacts from potential leachate contamination of nearby or downstream environments (soil, vegetation, waterways, and aquatic life); and</text></clause> <clause id="H6B28880FFBD4462B96AB4D73A2D4BEC3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a written plan approved by the Administrator for quarterly leachate and ecotoxicity monitoring of the nearby and immediately downstream environments, including soil, vegetation, waterways, and aquatic life.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6825EDA62DCA46A0A57FD088C45D958C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any approval for distribution or use of phosphogypsum for any purpose not expressly specified in sections section 61.204 or 61.205 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations—</text> <subparagraph id="H7CD7D9F3A58846B08667A8EC04286099"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be determined on a case-by-case basis; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEB197DE8B88E4C1AAE3B3E6573B9F0F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not exceed a maximum individual risk of 9.1 in 100,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF054187C5A834648AA73AFCF865EC1CA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any request that the Administrator approves distribution or use of phosphogypsum for any purpose not expressly specified in section 61.204 or 61.205 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, including the results of any required testing specified in paragraph (1)(C) shall be made publicly available on the public website of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF2E0F76CE9DC4409910B6EC64BF4C6E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Maximum Individual Risk</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>maximum individual risk</term> means the highest increase in lifetime cancer risk an individual faces in a population that is exposed to the highest concentration of phosphogypsum over a 70-year period.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

