<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-RIL25382-XTR-KC-783"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 191 ATS: Supporting the designation of April 2025 as the “Month of the Military Child”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 191</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250430">April 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of April 2025 as the <quote>Month of the Military Child</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas millions of brave United States servicemembers and veterans have demonstrated their courage and commitment to freedom by serving the Armed Forces of the United States of America in active-duty posts around the world;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there are more than 1,600,000 children connected to the military across the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is only fitting that the people of the United States take time to recognize the contributions of servicemembers and veterans, celebrate their spirit, and let the men and women of the United States in uniform know that while they are taking care of us, the people of the United States are taking care of their children;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the recognition of a <quote>Month of the Military Child</quote> will allow the people of the United States to pay tribute to military children for their commitment, struggles, and unconditional support of United States troops;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, when a servicemember joins the military, it is a family commitment to the United States, and military children are heroes in their own way; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a month-long salute to military children will encourage the United States to provide direct support to military children and families: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H71BFA1357A794C7DA709B4B64082A49B"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H1378F16D1DC145A6911D6A103D83B661"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="H3213ED7C32E04717BCF9C0EC84C912A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of April 2025 as the <quote>Month of the Military Child</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16E66D45C2D747B7A5DCF8871C911BCA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>urges the people of the United States to observe the Month of the Military Child with appropriate ceremonies and activities that honor, support, and show appreciation for military children.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

