<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-HLA25746-XY1-M2-1PD"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 395 ATS: Recognizing and supporting the goals and ideals of National Forensic Science Week.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 395</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250916">September 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing and supporting the goals and ideals of National Forensic Science Week.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Senate is committed to the use of forensic science in the investigation of crimes, the prosecution and conviction of the correct perpetrators of crimes, and the exoneration of innocent individuals falsely accused of crimes in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas forensic science service providers address critical questions in civil and criminal investigations and trials in the United States, including by providing scientific conclusions relating to forensic evidence;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas forensic science service providers partner with—</text><paragraph id="id227B8588A8664464B715990585212CB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Federal agencies to build and maintain criminal databases relating to latent prints, DNA, and other information relevant to criminal cases; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id667C2376C5C24185A43A9ADDBDEB0C78"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Federal, State, and local agencies to ensure public safety;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas forensic science service providers serve a vital role in the criminal justice system by providing scientific information to investigators and officers of the court; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the week of September 14, 2025, to September 20, 2025, is recognized as <quote>National Forensic Science Week</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idAF1FC08915C5452EBB8B8D443DEDD2B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of National Forensic Science Week; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id48850EC866254139A889E18E200E62D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes that National Forensic Science Week provides a special opportunity for—</text><subparagraph id="id2ec17ddf3a874f1a90815db545921ff2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>forensic science service providers—</text><clause id="idee422b1c06264bbc88f53583506b9df4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to acknowledge the contributions of forensic scientists in the laboratories in which those individuals work;</text></clause><clause id="idd042e281a4c74bedb72082eb56de2aaa"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to organize community events to encourage a better understanding of forensic science;</text></clause><clause id="id159c880e80b248a7a48adda813c03465"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to provide tours to Federal, State, and local policymakers to assist those individuals in gaining better insight into the current capabilities of forensic science service providers and the future demands that forensic science service providers will face; and</text></clause><clause id="idb73b3ba17b7a4689815528244c506e4f"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to contact and invite local media outlets to cover events hosted during National Forensic Science Week;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id184903f24f614950b6710a1febe04fb0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>local policymakers—</text><clause id="id470fe7ec697d4c9f98ca698c49941d66"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to recognize, through formal commendation or resolution, the contributions of local forensic science laboratories to the communities of those policymakers;</text></clause><clause id="id2b05566b04724c4792e7e80ee0c7a79b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to formally declare the week of September 14, 2025, to September 20, 2025, to be <quote>National Forensic Science Week</quote> by proclamation;</text></clause><clause id="id61aa9db5c90b4c5a9945cfb97231acac"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to visit local forensic science laboratories to gain an understanding of the capabilities and needs of those laboratories; and</text></clause><clause id="id06fa460e3f5a4d068f759e826da49b97"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to discuss the operational needs of State and local forensic science laboratories;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7c1c9460d32d4725bc4d1c29a6b7a705"><enum>(C)</enum><text>individuals in the United States, including members of the media—</text><clause id="id108eec063c99413babd982f9cd39e0ba"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to attend community events sponsored by local forensic science laboratories;</text></clause><clause id="idf7e9b7bd9e80457facc4e7afd978d98f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to take tours of local forensic science laboratories; and</text></clause><clause id="idd44cdc7778ab4cacbfc20c62c23e4cd4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to ask local forensic science laboratories about the operational and legislative needs of those laboratories;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida3c58114783f47ff8d7da69d89847d01"><enum>(D)</enum><text>members of the media to highlight local news stories that focus on the work of local forensic science laboratories in the communities that those laboratories serve; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc497efcbf6e7470884b271984fc86c3b"><enum>(E)</enum><text>public safety officers, law enforcement officers, and officers of the court—</text><clause id="idce545dbabdc147698e01f9f3a3799be4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to attend community events sponsored by local forensic science laboratories;</text></clause><clause id="id37e7402b556d49aab22c89cfd7c66c32"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to take tours of local forensic science laboratories;</text></clause><clause id="id55204b3c49a64b09997513594990d32c"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to discuss the operational needs of State and local forensic science laboratories; and</text></clause><clause id="id66c899c5112949aba2017398d706490e"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to engage with local forensic science laboratories about working together more effectively.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

