<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5F7D83E245C4443A94E7FF6F9A904291" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 386 IH: Chinese Currency Accountability Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 386</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250114">January 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000626">Mr. Davidson</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the United States Governor of, and the United States Executive Director at, the International Monetary Fund to oppose an increase in the weight of the Chinese renminbi in the Special Drawing Rights basket of the Fund, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDC477A19F8514548A0F8B3F81D49A425" style="OLC"><section id="H38DD139603544D2F837AAE9B66319015" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Chinese Currency Accountability Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4580F1D08896427B8AE77FA8A179A147"><enum>2.</enum><header>Opposition of the United States to an increase in the weight of the Chinese renminbi in the Special Drawing Rights basket of the International Monetary Fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Governor of, and the United States Executive Director at, the International Monetary Fund to use the voice and vote of the United States to oppose any increase in the weight of the Chinese renminbi in the basket of currencies used to determine the value of Special Drawing Rights, unless the Secretary of the Treasury has submitted to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate a written report which includes a certification that—</text><paragraph id="H9E6EDC62F4F343B28679BE28BF9213D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the People’s Republic of China is in compliance with all its obligations under Article VIII of the Articles of Agreement of the Fund;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC6D7876E7C5415FA09BD7CCBA56CDED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the preceding 12 months, there has not been a report submitted under section 3005 of the Omnibus Trade and Competitiveness Act of 1988 or section 701 of the Trade Facilitation and Trade Enforcement Act of 2015 in which the People’s Republic of China has been found to have manipulated its currency; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA404BBFC3D84D68B32F50B967F9AA69"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the People’s Republic of China adheres to the rules and principles of the Paris Club and the OECD Arrangement on Officially Supported Export Credits.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC28D66E88F4C4EC2B86C6B2219B46F44"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2 shall have no force or effect beginning 10 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

