<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAD2FAAB4BF264F5E9887B6A91A4A4FBE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2030 IH: Maintaining Cooperative Permitting Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2030</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250311">March 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001314">Mr. Bean of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure that certain permit approvals by the Environmental Protection Agency have the force and effect of law, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD03363DC79CB4688B42DE56A2EE2B344" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H7FB0A55DF2764902871087A52FC344EB"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Maintaining Cooperative Permitting Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1334857C8C274344A65F7849D63020EA"><enum>2.</enum><header>State discharge of dredged or fill material programs</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H1CAACEC9ABEE47A4B9F2B8FB46578B9A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Withdrawal of approval without congressional authorization prohibited</header> <paragraph id="HE277AFC1A735471AAA4F2DF5F4B966E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The permit programs described in paragraph (2) are ratified, approved, and of full force and effect, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (referred to in this section as the <quote>Administrator</quote>) may not withdraw the approval of those permit programs, including through the process described in section 404(i) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344(i)</external-xref>), unless the withdrawal is expressly authorized by an Act of Congress enacted after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4630EFD62DD0429F8E8588F9D04B4FDC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Permit programs described</header><text>The permit programs referred to in paragraph (1) are the following State permit programs for the discharge of dredged or fill material approved under section 404 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>):</text> <subparagraph id="HF5B3E31921E74DB0BBEFBA002FFEDEA4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The program of the State of Michigan, approved in the notice of the Environmental Protection Agency entitled <quote>Michigan Department of Natural Resources Section 404 Permit Program Approval</quote> (49 Fed. Reg. 38947 (October 2, 1984)) and as described in section 233.70 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (including any updates to the program described in a successor Federal Register notice).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0342418F9BED426BA3096D8E16FFC193"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The program of the State of New Jersey, approved in the final rule and notice of the Environmental Protection Agency entitled <quote>New Jersey Department of Environmental Protection and Energy Section 404 Permit Program Approval</quote> (59 Fed. Reg. 9933 (March 2, 1994)) and as described in section 233.71 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (including any updates to the program described in a successor Federal Register notice).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBC7C810E327D4A9284CBDCE40DF5CA37"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The program of the State of Florida, as described in the notice of the Environmental Protection Agency entitled <quote>EPA’s Approval of Florida’s Clean Water Act Section 404 Assumption Request</quote> (85 Fed. Reg. 83553 (December 22, 2020)) (including any updates to the program described in a successor Federal Register notice), including the Programmatic Biological Opinion with Incidental Take Statement associated with the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H63FC680355144FDFBC6A8A6E1375415B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Program transition period</header><text>During the 90-day period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), and the State of Florida may both issue permits authorized under the program described in paragraph (2)(C) into navigable waters (as described in subsection 404(g)(1) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344(g)(1)</external-xref>)) within the jurisdiction of the State of Florida.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A7AEEF3D93442F4AA1A24F0016D5CA7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Approval of comparable state programs</header> <subparagraph id="H6098C921E77441FBB79F0973319FE366"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Administrator determines that a State program submitted under subsection (g)(1) of section 404 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>) is comparable to a State program described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (C) of paragraph (2), the Administrator shall make the determination described in subsection (h)(2)(A) of that section with respect to that program.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H66DEA22322B7487E9D7BF6201096D9F9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>On making the determination required under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall notify the Secretary and the applicable State of that determination.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4BCBCE24516A4ACF83BB80761A8952C1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Suspension</header><text>On notification from the Administrator under subparagraph (B) and from a State that the State has begun to administer a program approved pursuant to subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall suspend the issuance of permits under subsections (a) and (e) of section 404 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>) for activities with respect to which a permit may be issued by the State under that program. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H370CFE63D22E4356B5E8313D29BE49E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification of process</header><text>Section 404(h) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344(h)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4B493CCD101F475AB3F3CB66F963A9CD" act-name=""> <paragraph id="H7CB8F76DADF240A58CE227FED759688A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Not a rule or regulation</header><text>The approval of a State permit program under this section shall not be considered to be a rule or regulation.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

