<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEN25212-PXY-HK-JV3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S560 IS: EAGLES Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 560</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250213">February 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 18, United States Code, to reauthorize and expand the National Threat Assessment Center of the Department of Homeland Security.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H9BB53FD18A384071AB042C78B5D8F733"><section section-type="section-one" id="H8EDF5D61D79346A68FF0CD91C05BC2D5"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>EAGLES Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H38FAE27105764E1E8BFD60F4E44EC05D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header><subsection id="HD68CC988B8174741805056F9ABB10EDE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H209DB114979E4D60B3F7DB23B3624D23"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On February 14, 2018, 17 individuals were murdered in a senseless and violent attack on Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School in Parkland Florida, a school whose mascot is the eagle.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DE4F08C2075412180893EA3B7141F91"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">These individuals—Alaina Petty, Alex Schachter, Alyssa Alhadeff, Cara Loughran, Carmen Schentrup, Gina Montalto, Helena Ramsay, Jaime Guttenberg, Joaquin Oliver, Luke Hoyer, Martin Duque, Meadow Pollack, Nicholas Dworet, Peter Wang, Aaron Feis, Chris Hixon, and Scott Beigel—lived lives of warmth, joy, determination, service, and love, and their loss is mourned by the Nation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DA8824A0A0942FE9AAFB8655D972C2A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Like many attackers, the shooter in that attack exhibited patterns of threatening and concerning behavior prior to the massacre that were alarming and that should have alerted law enforcement and other Federal, State, and local officials about the potential for violence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BB9FFEBCA694400AC81D0917363437E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Acts of targeted violence, including the attack on Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School, are preventable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E7E8480EC9F4C4F8A0785536BCE1F14"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Lives were saved because of the brave and exemplary conduct of many students, teachers, and staff at Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School, including several of the victims of the attack.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12FF51BB811742418553AF8A0C0CC479"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Threat Assessment Center of the United States Secret Service (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Center</quote>) was established in 1998 to conduct research on all forms of targeted violence, including attacks targeting government officials, government facilities, workplaces, houses of worship, K–12 schools, universities, and mass attacks in public spaces.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99C6234CEAEA4E10826EA06CDB949BBB"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Research published by the Center on targeted violence has shown that—</text><subparagraph id="H4A7FB4D72AE647D983841D45B23151D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>most incidents were planned in advance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBFAB174D1AF46D19E909E8B0489D01C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the attackers’ behavior gave some indication that the individual was planning, or at least contemplating, an attack;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H758B3A3ECA5249D9811D119F951E90E8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>most attackers had already exhibited a pattern of behavior that elicited concern by other people in their lives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E346391A19645F7ADC6A15C6EF09DA1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>prior to the attack, someone associated with the attacker, such as a family member or peer, often knew the attack was to likely to occur.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1018D83AD4564C159B3C5F7A177239E0"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Through their research, the Center developed the behavioral threat assessment model of the United States Secret Service for preventing targeted violence, which includes a 3-step process—</text><subparagraph id="H80F59D903F7E4ADB98DF6042120CFB4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying individuals who are exhibiting threatening or concerning behaviors that indicate they may pose a risk of violence;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59C599EA208A4CF2A808FCB632C45427"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assessing whether the individual poses a risk, based on articulable facts; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33F0D119FD2B44F4A8C3EE186330616E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">risk posed by the individualized proactive and preventive measures.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA256A905DB1D4F5FAFFD1DDDE560C11A"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The behavioral threat assessment model works of the United States Secret Service most effectively when all the relevant parties, including local law enforcement, mental health professionals, workplace managers, school personnel, and members of the community, are part of a comprehensive protocol to identify, assess, and manage a potential threat.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F5BD6E8C5E64A789FD71B8022E43272"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The primary goal of behavioral threat assessment programs is to prevent targeted violence, with an emphasis on providing early intervention and connecting individuals exhibiting threatening or concerning behavior to existing community resources for support.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FD754E02EB1464EAA84AA84DDFEF1C7"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Early intervention is a proven and effective way to prevent violent conduct that would otherwise harm others and necessitate more punitive action, including criminal penalties.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H569B4F79098C4D31AFD189FA3FA27513"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The parties involved need the appropriate research, guidance, training, and tools to establish the appropriate mechanisms for implementing this type of preventative approach.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8011BC4A7C5C462A9E362C797156D790"><enum>(13)</enum><text>In K–12 schools, a behavioral threat assessment is a proactive approach to identify, assess, and provide age-appropriate interventions, resources, and supports for students who display behavior that elicits concerns for the safety of themselves or others.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H290B5437571E4E0CB39D3D4740A1A0BD"><enum>(14)</enum><text>There has been a 79 percent decline in juvenile arrests in K–12 school communities that have received training from the Center, thus successfully diverting youth away from the criminal justice system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC2DC7355437462EA755377DDF3EBF46"><enum>(15)</enum><text>The demand from local communities throughout the United States for behavioral threat assessment trainings has significantly increased. Since its inception, the Center has provided over 2,575 training sessions to over 273,000 attendees.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BF48EFADDD64EA4B056808D3299756A"><enum>(16)</enum><text>From fiscal year 2018 to fiscal year 2022, the Center has experienced a 117 percent increase in demand for training sessions, with 5 times as many participants.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H294922E92E3645868253C3E5D47CA012"><enum>(17)</enum><text>The Center additionally provides consultation and follow-up engagements with government agencies, law enforcement, schools, and other organizations with public safety responsibilities. From fiscal year 2018 to fiscal year 2022 the Center has seen a 553 percent increase in consultation activities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7203197701C64949BC2C9F24C89447F7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that a fact-based behavioral threat assessment approach, involving local law enforcement, mental health professionals, workplace managers, school personnel, other public safety officials, and members of the community, is one of the most effective ways to prevent targeted violence impacting communities across the country, and is a fitting memorial to those whose lives were taken in the February 14, 2018, attack on Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School and those who heroically acted to preserve the lives of their friends, students, and colleagues.</text></subsection></section><section id="H2858E131761145B98F87DCFD24AEC3EE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reauthorization and expansion of the national threat assessment center of the Department of Homeland Security</header><subsection id="HE2A3A881BCAD4A3CAB7684695814ADB0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/203">Chapter 203</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/3056A">section 3056A</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB4B128D471B426B99C02DB29224454A"><section id="HA3260B8D8EE442CFAC3A9AC8D237F3BB"><enum>3056B.</enum><header>Functions of the National Threat Assessment Center of the United States Secret Service</header><subsection id="H8086BBAFE3C64CFEA3E59AA3D82C4F74"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established a National Threat Assessment Center (in this section referred to as the <quote>Center</quote>), to be operated by the United States Secret Service, at the direction of the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBD1AC573A5C14F479C3CCB8A507B4A01"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The functions of the Center shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HC9E2B50AD1594D3E965154BD2CF141B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Training and education in the area of best practices on threat assessment and the prevention of targeted violence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5BC8FB0DD24445FA8C60D9C21298A12"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Consultation on complex threat assessment cases and programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC76E914E84544DB6AD0C596932812B8F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Research on threat assessment and the prevention of targeted violence, consistent with evidence-based standards and existing laws and regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE750E06D5E494A308365BB1AC70BC802"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Facilitation of information sharing on threat assessment and the prevention of targeted violence among agencies and organizations with protective or public safety responsibilities, as well as other public or private entities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H158819B77C7F4168A5EC6F58476E3D94"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Development of evidence-based programs to promote the standardization of Federal, State, and local threat assessments and best practices for the prevention of targeted violence.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD05B0AD389854C7382E16069C1E1D900"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Safe school initiative</header><text>In carrying out the functions described in subsection (b), the Center shall establish a national program on targeted school violence prevention, focusing on the following activities:</text><paragraph id="H6DC20EC4457B42C0B1CB47AB93140E34"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Research</header><text>The Center shall—</text><subparagraph id="H463C1905736C42018E1DE40CE2351B33"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct research into targeted school violence and evidence-based practices in targeted school violence prevention, including school threat assessment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H095BC50768124B81B05B61DDCACA08D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publish the findings of the Center on the public website of the United States Secret Service and on the School Safety Clearinghouse website, known as www.SchoolSafety.gov.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1BB13E52D124C8986C1F83949372CCC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Training</header><subparagraph id="HD0596D870E6C43C59743B5DAD8906119"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Center shall develop and offer training courses on targeted school violence prevention to agencies with protective or public safety responsibilities and other public or private entities, including local educational agencies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3ACA7D0051EC4249AE490E3792C9E5ED"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Plan</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Center shall establish a plan to offer its training and other educational resources to public or private entities within each State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0339BB37B3984FE2A1559EDE35CAD5CA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination with other Federal agencies</header><text>The Center shall develop research and training programs under this section in coordination with the Department of Justice, the Department of Education, and the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15FCC404EAC84872B57CE3BCDA48D1FC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation with entities outside the Federal Government</header><text>The Center is authorized to consult with State and local educational, law enforcement, and mental health officials and private entities in the development of research and training programs under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8A009447DCD4655B7B26C09FE853EC6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Interactive website</header><text>The Center may create an interactive website to disseminate information and data on evidence-based practices in targeted school violence prevention.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5F3077DD66344031AF690AA9C6322E03"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Hiring of additional personnel</header><text>The Director of the United States Secret Service may hire additional personnel to comply with the requirements of this section, which, if the Director exercises such authority, shall include—</text><paragraph id="H8480F8963A9741DE8008FB8A83426502"><enum>(1)</enum><text>at least 1 employee with expertise in child psychological development; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DB7A192D4224A55AACE94B81949C788"><enum>(2)</enum><text>at least 1 employee with expertise in school threat assessment. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB841B850F010485991B7843483390600"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of enactment of this section, the Director of the United States Secret Service shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Education and Workforce, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report on actions taken by the United States Secret Service to implement provisions of this section, which shall include information relating to the following:</text><paragraph id="H8E5769E25A844C06A434866880646E0F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of employees hired (on a full-time equivalent basis).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09C3CA3FFC064F6FB990D2F8BA7BB689"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of individuals in each State trained in threat assessment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD97049C8D3774CC6A5175B66799B6087"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of school districts in each State trained in school threat assessment or targeted school violence prevention.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC2FD7306CD3498CAEF20F5F3ED7CCDF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Information on Federal, State, and local agencies trained or otherwise assisted by the Center.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81F603EB089049749B2A1AAEC4E4DA38"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A formal evaluation indicating whether the training and other assistance provided by the Center is effective.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA39269C33CA84F6CB2CAA2620620D3DA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A formal evaluation indicating whether the training and other assistance provided by the Center was implemented by the school.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97BF19299F90406EAEF70A4A2A101EC1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A summary of the Center’s research activities and findings.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD3374F7DA21428AB11B5FA33664B671"><enum>(8)</enum><text>A strategic plan for disseminating the Center’s educational and training resources to each State.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H5937865B8EF446DDAA84FA6E7217E672"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1334D38CFD5246C6AEF39900AD012104"><enum>(g)</enum><header>No funds To provide firearms training</header><text>Amounts made available to carry out this section may not be used to train any person in the use of a firearm.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF9F7660E19F7433C8CE75A88AF0A537F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>No effect on other laws</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to preclude or contradict any other provision of law authorizing training in the use of firearms.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H2A18F1106CCC478B9C20DC54B3BAB347"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>This section shall terminate on September 30, 2030.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE9BC0F1A62834011AB39A15357F5B0C8"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HB54EEC16A5BA4EA595FD46D8662092EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Evidence-based</header><text>The term <term>evidence-based</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H4B5E38DBDC2643C18C9835EAA783C3D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>strong evidence from at least one well-designed and well-implemented experimental study;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E20D29A89FD410281B1117A172A6723"><enum>(B)</enum><text>moderate evidence from at least one well-designed and well-implemented quasi-experimental study; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0147AEA9C7DE4C6886E1EF171E5CA414"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promising evidence from at least one well-designed and well-implemented correlational study with statistical controls for selection bias.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFAB1F76D60A44D79184E86D74B0E822"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Local educational agency</header><text>The term <term>local educational agency</term> has the meaning given such term under section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDC443A3CE5644D49A16DB7BF4C09B6A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HE36EB5C28C874825AA74AD5B43BE0F78"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical, conforming, and clerical amendments</header><paragraph id="H123C2D91D886442E91909DBC6F3DA875"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>Section 4 of the Presidential Threat Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/3056">18 U.S.C. 3056</external-xref> note) is repealed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAACF76596E3646CA8C03B6547321C81A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/203">chapter 203</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/3056A">section 3056A</external-xref> the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8C32B576A5C47BA99B42923EACFAEC1"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">3056B. Functions of the National Threat Assessment Center of the United States Secret Service.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

