<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-RIL25200-2TG-2D-H65"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S939 IS: Medicare Dental, Hearing, and Vision Expansion Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 939</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250311" legis-day="20250310">March 11 (legislative day, March 10), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide coverage for dental and oral health care, hearing care, and vision care under the Medicare program.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicare Dental, Hearing, and Vision Expansion Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id9b2b2a841abb44c8881ff159c09f1f3a"><enum>2.</enum><header>Coverage of dental and oral health care</header><subsection id="idEA2700E07B0C4A9DBBB6D1D75531150B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coverage</header><text>Section 1861(s)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(s)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idBA5B268D55324DED99EB7858472936C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (JJ), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD1286278646A44C595F56BF3A0B9354B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4B103874FC5B4A5F8F054D14A41754FD"><subparagraph id="idEDF23B3D63C14C32815F89318D521227" indent="up1"><enum>(KK)</enum><text>dental and oral health services (as defined in subsection (nnn));</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida8be7f3518b4452680488a49141690bf"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Dental and oral health services defined</header><text>Section 1861 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7f9c25c8a6f3427c909d966c924a5f77"><subsection id="idfdba932be14346ff9b324332de1261df"><enum>(nnn)</enum><header>Dental and oral health services</header><paragraph id="id5afc2c99cf114a7cb01350e25a124034"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the term <quote>dental and oral health services</quote> means the following items and services that are furnished by a doctor of dental surgery or of dental medicine (as described in subsection (r)(2)) or an oral health professional (as defined in paragraph (3)) on or after January 1, 2027 (or January 1, 2026, in the case of dentures):</text><subparagraph id="ide699ad13c9494c169f9281a5930ce30a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Preventive and screening services</header><text>Preventive and screening services, including oral exams, dental cleanings, dental x-rays, and fluoride treatments.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8d5d06e3300b4c8e8f4a9b392b39aec5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Procedures and treatment services</header><text>Services to address oral disease, including services such as restorative services, prosthodontic and endodontic services, including fillings bridges, crowns, and root canals, periodontal maintenance, periodontal scaling and root planing, tooth extractions, therapeutic pulpotomy, and other related items and services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2ccdef12ddf84fac88b08f971ec4c5a9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Dentures and dental prosthetics</header><text>Complete dentures, partial dentures, and implants, including related items and services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcfc1550eff3147b7add532eb89e69edb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>Such term does not include items and services for which, as of the date of the enactment of this subsection, coverage was permissible under section 1862(a)(12) and cosmetic services not otherwise covered under section 1862(a)(10).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida1d6e53861ea49d5aaa0f8d5ad98eb48"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Oral health professional</header><text>The term <term>oral health professional</term> means, with respect to dental and oral health services, a health professional (other than a doctor of dental surgery or of dental medicine (as described in subsection (r)(2))) who is licensed to furnish such services, acting within the scope of such license, by the State in which such services are furnished.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idf2e4c92069364bac913c5f5ff044d6f7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Payment; coinsurance; and limitations</header><paragraph id="idaa78f61733a24593b0225027a5b2b1aa"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1833(a)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="id7685acf4a66f43bb8e85269de4ecc893"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (N), by inserting <quote>and dental and oral health services (as defined in section 1861(nnn))</quote> after <quote>section 1861(hhh)(1))</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc4d0caf49f7546fea8e62fcfd21865ee"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> before <quote>(HH)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c0fe5c9ebe6432eb4f394deb5e04ac0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>and (II) with respect to dental and oral health services (as defined in section 1861(nnn)), the amount paid shall be the payment amount specified under section 1834(aa)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0f854e0fb1d646a78c829db152c20d28"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payment and limits specified</header><text>Section 1834 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1AD9B9E6A0134172BDE028F4516B7464"><subsection id="id5114a3d853594b3a892d50a39f78a461"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Payment and limits for dental and oral health services</header><paragraph id="id7dbb608915004737abb3cef4cc1cc31c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payment</header><text>The payment amount under this part for dental and oral health services (as defined in section 1861(nnn)) shall be, subject to paragraphs (3) and (4), 80 percent (or 100 percent, in the case of preventive and screening services described in section 1861(nnn)(1)(A)) of the lesser of—</text><subparagraph id="id4b3f81b053d24eed91fe95c364ed8fc3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the actual charge for the service; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id06dab866ac914785bd7fe4ad535cf098"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idaaf565e803c54b0d97e1fced292160bb"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of such services furnished by a doctor of dental surgery or of dental medicine (as described in section 1861(r)(2)), the amount determined under the fee schedule established under paragraph (2); or</text></clause><clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id89997e49812c41d1b3cb0f34c7e2a977"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of such services furnished by an oral health professional (as defined in section 1861(nnn)(3)), 85 percent of the amount determined under the fee schedule established under paragraph (2).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2a7908f38fe242f9bc60888bf79fa619"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment of fee schedule for dental and oral health services</header><subparagraph id="idf20cd8f979574213b34325620c9b5396"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><clause id="id5d1c71ba046c4dbe93c04738471d801e"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a fee schedule for dental and oral health services furnished in 2027 (or 2026, in the case of dentures) and subsequent years. The fee schedule amount for a dental or oral health service shall be equal to 70 percent of the national median fee (as determined under subparagraph (B)) for the service or a similar service for the year (or, in the case of dentures, at the bundled payment amount under clause (iv) of such subparagraph), adjusted by the geographic adjustment factor established under section 1848(e)(2) for the area for the year.</text></clause><clause id="ida75ddd33286b4065a6b98c40cfee8a08"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out this paragraph, the Secretary shall consult annually with organizations representing dentists and other providers who furnish dental and oral health services and shall share with such providers the data and data analysis used to determine fee schedule amounts under this paragraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4e598e16dcaf4c3d8dadfe615f261dd1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determination of national median fee</header><clause id="idd864cd115f66489d9eae288130df7688"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall apply the national median fee for a dental or oral health service for 2027 (or 2026, in the case of dentures) and subsequent years in accordance with this subparagraph.</text></clause><clause id="id22f9596466f14c90aee1ecc2d91af628"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Use of 2020 dental fee survey</header><subclause id="idd00442f90a834090aacd2178ad46795c"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (iii) and clause (iv), the national median fee for a dental or oral health service shall be equal to—</text><item id="id2457389d0d71418bb3180ef151280320"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>for 2027 (or 2026, in the case of dentures), the median fee for the service in the table titled <quote>General Practitioners–National</quote> of the <quote>2020 Survey of Dental Fees</quote> published by the American Dental Association, increased by the applicable percent increase for the year determined under subclause (II), as reduced by the productivity adjustment under subclause (III); and</text></item><item id="id532befdbf9ae4e8c8d94f2031d9b0c90"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>for 2028 (or 2027, in the case of dentures) and subsequent years, the amount determined under this subclause for the preceding year, updated pursuant to subparagraph (C)(i).</text></item></subclause><subclause id="ide88ce25bef9949db999f4390d0ddf25d"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Applicable percent increase</header><text>The applicable percent increase determined under this subclause for a year is an amount equal to the percentage increase between—</text><item id="idbf72d3b9a9c54700a20c61779cf04e6f"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the consumer price index for all urban consumers (United States city average) ending with June of the previous year; and</text></item><item id="idd2fb92cfce864e6d80d08d6bc2e32f9d"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the consumer price index for all urban consumers (United States city average) ending with June of 2026 (or 2025, in the case of dentures).</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id30ca985a1758406ba8f86f8cd0a0e5b1"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Productivity adjustment</header><text>After determining the applicable percentage increase under subclause (II) for a year, the Secretary shall reduce such percentage increase by the productivity adjustment described in section 1886(b)(3)(B)(xi)(II).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id43ea8a60c10943a489b6dcd705ea14c8"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Determination if insufficient survey data</header><text>If the Secretary determines there is insufficient data under the Survey described in clause (ii) with respect to a dental or oral health service, the national median fee for the service for a year shall be equal to an amount established for the service using 1 or more of the following methods, as determined appropriate by the Secretary:</text><subclause id="id05b53a1550054c1a91b03a4aca6727fd"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The payment basis determined under section 1848.</text></subclause><subclause id="id225f5bb9b58f49adaf468baeb9f3fc0f"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Fee schedules for dental and oral health services which shall include, as practicable, fee schedules—</text><item id="id891c15bb08c84901a59aabc7ba46df27"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>under Medicare Advantage plans under part C;</text></item><item id="ida3dacd6df07f426fa2b0c962cd2437c0"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>under State plans (or waivers of such plans) under title XIX; and</text></item><item id="idb6dda3a4966947ee828a6e2f56bbc058"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>established by other health care payers.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="idbbea618c67cb4891a5c2778bc7df6729"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Special rule for dentures</header><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id897a0ffe79324040bae20437b6dc73bb"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make payment for dentures and associated professional services as a bundled payment as determined by the Secretary. </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id535381e316ad4672877e0e6afb2d0bb8"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Payment considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing such bundled payment, the Secretary shall consider the national median fee for the service for the year determined under clause (ii) or (iii) and the rate determined for such dentures under the Federal Supply Schedule of the General Services Administration, as published by such Administration in 2021, updated to the year involved using the applicable percent increase for the year determined under clause (ii)(II), as reduced by the productivity adjustment under clause (ii)(III), and shall ensure that the payment component for dentures under such bundled payment does not exceed the maximum rate determined for such dentures under the Federal Supply Schedule, as so published and updated to the year involved.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide5459a2548974677b54d42b10dc4b2c8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Annual update and adjustments</header><clause id="ida982a7940bd44f2fb4fc5bce5ad61e9a"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Annual update</header><text>The Secretary shall update payment amounts determined under the fee schedule from year to year beginning in 2028 (or 2027, in the case of dentures) by increasing such amounts from the prior year by the percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (United States city average) for the 12-month period ending with June of the preceding year, reduced by the productivity adjustment described in section 1886(b)(3)(B)(xi)(II).</text></clause><clause id="id7c3244408f274dfe825adaff102091ca"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Adjustments</header><subclause id="idcc6459db8e4f4550a319cb724bad4797"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall, to the extent the Secretary determines to be necessary and subject to subclause (II), adjust the amounts determined under the fee schedule established under this paragraph for 2028 (or 2027, in the case of dentures) and subsequent years to take into account changes in dental practice, coding changes, new data on work, practice, or malpractice expenses, or the addition of new procedures.</text></subclause><subclause id="id1415bec5ff2b4759acea30362a4c7a81"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Limitation on annual adjustments</header><text>The adjustments under subclause (I) for a year shall not cause the amount of expenditures under this part for the year to differ by more than $20,000,000 from the amount of expenditures under this part that would have been made if such adjustments had not been made.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc70bd6a347a447deba0f0cc6a2e75db7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>With respect to dental and oral health services that are preventive and screening services described in paragraph (1)(A) of section 1861(nnn)—</text><subparagraph id="id931320e3331a4190a068fcf24d537cc6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>payment shall be made under this part for—</text><clause id="id090fbc3a4cf344b5aa2d977a6320ec96"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not more than 2 oral exams in a year;</text></clause><clause id="iddbb9352070484f5ba452f82d5f73a6b9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not more than 2 dental cleanings in a year;</text></clause><clause id="idd0de191486614da18f900fbaa6d70566"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>not more than 1 fluoride treatment in a year; and</text></clause><clause id="id2e1dd225fc7b4d72ad06b280d0ac03a5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>not more than 1 full-mouth series of x-rays as part of a preventive and screening oral exam every 3 years; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9adbd53716564b47bbe833ce916b1c22"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of preventive and screening services not described in subparagraph (A), payment shall be made under this part only at such frequencies determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id25c7c2703c534b99ac0ecd05ff62ecc9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Incentives for rural providers</header><text>In the case of dental and oral health services furnished by a doctor of dental surgery or of dental medicine (as described in section 1861(r)(2)) or an oral health professional (as defined in section 1861(nnn)(3)) who predominantly furnishes such services under this part in an area that is designated by the Secretary (under section 332(a)(1)(A) of the Public Health Service Act) as a health professional shortage area, in addition to the amount of payment that would otherwise be made for such services under this subsection, there also shall be paid an amount equal to 10 percent of the payment amount for the service under this subsection for such doctor or professional.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6c2c9da32aa149fb876ca52d0c9cea8b"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitation on beneficiary liability</header><text>The provisions of section 1848(g) shall apply to a nonparticipating doctor of dental surgery or of dental medicine (as described in section 1861(r)(2)) who does not accept payment on an assignment-related basis for dental and oral health services furnished with respect to an individual enrolled under this part in the same manner as such provisions apply with respect to a physician's service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id303383770bd246899d02f8d46f39d545"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Establishment of dental administrator</header><text>The Secretary shall designate 1 or more (not to exceed 4) medicare administrative contractors under section 1874A to establish coverage policies and establish such policies and process claims for payment for dental and oral health services, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id986526eba295478a94e30634419a5214"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Inclusion of oral health professionals as certain practitioners</header><text>Section 1842(b)(18)(C) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395u">42 U.S.C. 1395u(b)(18)(C)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id620893de3471445db240820c8f718f08"><clause id="idf5c09acbc0344ef48403100980a2978d" indent="up2"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>With respect to 2028 and each subsequent year, an oral health professional (as defined in section 1861(nnn)(3)).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id70f07916a1b74dc597d4aa9cc697c21f"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exclusion modifications</header><text>Section 1862(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id10fc70e654f64e2fad56532f92d5e0ba"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="idc4d87ae4bb8d4a5d820fbdd33bb02c5a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (O), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfa673c5ce36a49879bfa0db9cef447f3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (P), by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting <quote>, and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id58e1c002dc7d4ab79860e484e78e1680"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96c46bc5bdc646d6b3a7fca814f52529"><subparagraph id="idc34be7a3ec2d42dfa9e9673fd533310c" indent="up1"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>in the case of dental and oral health services (as defined in section 1861(nnn)) for which a limitation is applicable under section 1834(aa)(3), which are furnished more frequently than is provided under such section;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4e829b8c44954209a2568d27c65fae72"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (12), by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>and except that payment shall be made under part B for dental and oral health services that are covered under section 1861(s)(2)(KK)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7c1a80b1e3be4984b2864fcf17d29a52" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Inclusion as excepted medical treatment</header><text>Section 1821(b)(5)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395i-5">42 U.S.C. 1395i–5(b)(5)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id81d045911ab341b7858a67aa87f7e9d6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (ii), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id500abb51c3d245a09183a73d2eadd6b2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (iii), by striking the period and inserting <quote>, or</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1645f7de29ef405abe71b9b00b721df1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6FF2258A2A7C4A5DBE16E00AFE895353"><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id00eec58045534713b0c5112613fadc06"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>consisting of dental and oral health services (as defined in subsection (mmm) of section 1861) that are payable under part B as a result of the amendments made by the <short-title>Medicare Dental, Hearing, and Vision Expansion Act of 2025</short-title>.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id98cb6499956b40f8960ffabf2798a493"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rural health clinics and federally qualified health centers</header><paragraph id="id646eac5214c24704bd31381217b54381"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Coverage of dental and oral health services</header><text>Section 1861(aa) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(aa)</external-xref>), is amended—</text><subparagraph id="idebdacef4e8254c65ad393157781bc328"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="id433dbeb979fa4729a4142436eeecd4ae"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></clause><clause id="id7c9d543cac7a45de94a44477effd8250"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by inserting <quote>and</quote> after the comma at the end; and</text></clause><clause id="idb9b65b283813440b909fdb2b23804992"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (D) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd423af404132476ead5b0b84719aefd8"><subparagraph id="id20e76131a63e4890bbe91add34cd4fb5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>dental and oral health services (as defined in subsection (nnn)) furnished by a doctor of dental surgery or of dental medicine (as described in subsection (r)(2)) or an oral health professional (as defined in subsection (nnn)(3)) who is employed by or working under contract with a rural health clinic if such rural health clinic furnishes such services,</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8ca14401c3954e87896ee174b893fa99"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(A), by striking <quote>(D)</quote> and inserting <quote>(E)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9dedec519d024052b441e0ce3eb0e5b2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Temporary payment rates for certain services under the RHC AIR and FQHC PPS</header><subparagraph id="id90fde02fe7c9442aa93621f733c4403a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>AIR</header><text>Section 1833 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l</external-xref>) is amended—</text><clause id="id87bbd4888d7044f5a1a70b04d9bbec43"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(3)(A), by inserting <quote>(which shall, in the case of dental and oral health services (as defined in section 1861(nnn)), in lieu of any limits on reasonable costs otherwise applicable, be based on the rates payable for such services under the payment basis determined under section 1848 until such time as the Secretary determines sufficient data has been collected to otherwise apply such limits (or January 1, 2031, if no such determination has been made as of such date))</quote> after <quote>may prescribe in regulations</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="id0ef861dc8203420bbc77ed286ae57c9c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id65abf49bf18d41d5817cd3478ac39a13"><subsection id="idc269cba97ada4091a032b6ee5aa0d3e7"><enum>(ee)</enum><header>Disregard of costs attributable to certain services from calculation of RHC AIR</header><text>Payments for rural health clinic services other than dental and oral health services (as defined in section 1861(nnn)) under the methodology for all-inclusive rates (established by the Secretary) under subsection (a)(3) shall not take into account the costs of such services while rates for such services are based on rates payable for such services under the payment basis established under section 1848.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf958c38a717d4371a277378e76c620aa"><enum>(B)</enum><header>PPS</header><text>Section 1834(o) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(o)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id856683169ffc4b58a06e189dba9ac720"><paragraph id="id402e87131f11439cae92501d96328faf"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Temporary payment rates based on pfs for certain services</header><text>The Secretary shall, in establishing payment rates for dental and oral health services (as defined in section 1861(nnn)) that are Federally qualified health center services under the prospective payment system established under this subsection, in lieu of the rates otherwise applicable under such system, base such rates on rates payable for such services under the payment basis established under section 1848 until such time as the Secretary determines sufficient data has been collected to otherwise establish rates for such services under such system (or January 1, 2031, if no such determination has been made as of such date). Payments for Federally qualified health center services other than such dental and oral health services under such system shall not take into account the costs of such services while rates for such services are based on rates payable for such services under the payment basis established under section 1848.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2894aaebe5354276ba203ddfb8b31185"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Secretary of Health and Human Services for fiscal year 2025, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $900,000,000, to remain available until expended, for purposes of implementing the amendments made by this section during the period beginning on January 1, 2025, and ending on September 30, 2034.</text></subsection></section><section id="idfddf097f89eb45dab815d595f399ab2c"><enum>3.</enum><header>Providing coverage for hearing care under the Medicare program</header><subsection id="idd90dc19e811e4fe5a07558c59184d5a0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Provision of audiology services by qualified audiologists and hearing aid examination services by qualified hearing aid professionals</header><paragraph id="idd316d92dd42b40679d293fe4ead6b4e2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1861(ll) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(ll)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="id0b66799feb3b453888a6bde902dfb467"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text><clause id="id5ea992846487485fa87c54e2f766dbd2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(A)</quote> after <quote>(3)</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="ida107792fc1454c39978d5c5e0f1c343e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), as added by clause (i) of this subparagraph—</text><subclause id="id8db6b88cd2354a8c83f20ef6fbadc7f5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>means such hearing and balance assessment services</quote> and inserting “means—</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaba3c5bbdc884970a0e36190bc55f2ac"><clause id="id4fa7b97cf2de48eeb2a9fe82c0fe2f65"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such hearing and balance assessment services and, beginning January 1, 2027, such hearing aid examination services and treatment services (including aural rehabilitation, vestibular rehabilitation, and cerumen management)</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause><subclause id="id63e5431da2d04361b6338724444029c1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in clause (i), as added by subclause (I) of this clause, by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="ida3e2de19c524455881b32e8dd261d8f5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida74cb401d49e49cea05efcfac4443cd2"><clause id="id04100d86479d4dcc8d2197c18ecc6091"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>beginning January 1, 2027, such hearing aid examination services furnished by a qualified hearing aid professional (as defined in paragraph (4)(C)) as the professional is legally authorized to perform under State law (or the State regulatory mechanism provided by State law), as would otherwise be covered if furnished by a physician.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause><clause id="idb6730de86ed84e60867a97a34bc04e88"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide5485621b9194fb999aad707d98ec685"><subparagraph id="id47ae1d44cd034c7ebbeee5305b1ec10f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Beginning January 1, 2027, audiology services described in subparagraph (A)(i) shall be furnished without a requirement for an order from a physician or practitioner.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9a96060d9ee4407b9fd40bfb890d6468"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id532c34b04afd4f49aa69725d18e78de5"><subparagraph id="id64b5b98ec1f1467e98263dc806875d12"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term <term>qualified hearing aid professional</term> means an individual who—</text><clause id="idbf63632e6ca340f3929022a2816a8d85"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is licensed or registered as a hearing aid dispenser, hearing aid specialist, hearing instrument dispenser, or related professional by the State in which the individual furnishes such services; and</text></clause><clause id="id5c9a007594744b1aa4762e8c9e9da600"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is accredited by the National Board for Certification in Hearing Instrument Sciences or meets such other requirements as the Secretary determines appropriate (including requirements relating to educational certifications or accreditations) taking into account any additional relevant requirements for hearing aid specialists, hearing aid dispensers, and hearing instrument dispensers established by Medicare Advantage organizations under part C, State plans (or waivers of such plans) under title XIX, and group health plans and health insurance issuers (as such terms are defined in section 2791 of the Public Health Service Act).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4b320ec429584bd4b2139d47cafdf9ac"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payment for qualified hearing aid professionals</header><text>Section 1833(a)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(a)(1)</external-xref>), as amended by section 2(c)(1), is amended—</text><subparagraph id="id7e553839929248e9a2c94f34bdd1eb42"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> before <quote>(II)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0485d2629c5a46f8ab6bf7883d47f1da"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>and (JJ) with respect to hearing aid examination services (as described in paragraph (3)(A)(ii) of section 1861(ll)) furnished by a qualified hearing aid professional (as defined in paragraph (4)(C) of such section), the amounts paid shall be equal to 80 percent of the lesser of the actual charge for such services or 85 percent of the amount for such services determined under the payment basis determined under section 1848</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc87e7bdf4d574d03877fc2593250688f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inclusion of qualified audiologists and qualified hearing aid professionals as certain practitioners to receive payment on an assignment-related basis</header><subparagraph id="id4555c1531f6c46c1b74e89c560446bd0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Qualified audiologists</header><text>Section 1842(b)(18)(C) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395u">42 U.S.C. 1395u(b)(18)(C)</external-xref>), as amended by section 2(d), is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id13b80639c3bb446fad98bb5c7a3391e7"><clause id="idf135074e147f4bf5abad11fd5387619a" indent="up2"><enum>(x)</enum><text>Beginning on January 1, 2027, a qualified audiologist (as defined in section 1861(ll)(4)(B)).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6a40d460973141a48e9af179dc7190bb"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified hearing aid professionals</header><text>Section 1842(b)(18) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395u">42 U.S.C. 1395u(b)(18)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><clause id="ide5636afcfb534f46b430fedd106e574c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in each of subparagraphs (A) and (B), by striking <quote>subparagraph (C)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (C) or, beginning on January 1, 2027, subparagraph (E)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="id1a9cfed1d791407cae79ea209e672f3c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE8B908C61E6C41D097BA27D425F5E7AC"><subparagraph id="id8a5538b261314f6cabb1a43d42e3bbbf" indent="up2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A practitioner described in this subparagraph is a qualified hearing aid professional (as defined in section 1861(ll)(4)(C)).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id366197c3293f4b7981aa153e5ffe9105"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coverage of hearing aids</header><paragraph id="idf91a9d72820d4820861669f531f5cf91"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inclusion of hearing aids as prosthetic devices</header><text>Section 1861(s)(8) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(s)(8)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, and including hearing aids (as described in section 1834(h)(7)) furnished on or after January 1, 2027, to individuals with moderately severe, severe, or profound hearing loss</quote> before the semicolon at the end.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3348a0eb8dd94daf9b069e8b290a3695"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payment limitations for hearing aids</header><text>Section 1834(h) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(h)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id41b999ea5a904d339915d59120da0eeb"><paragraph id="id76325bf816ab4680a51ec6044e0727fa"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Payment only on an assignment-related basis</header><text>Payment for hearing aids for which payment may be made under this part may be made only on an assignment-related basis. The provisions of subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 1842(b)(18) shall apply to hearing aids in the same manner as they apply to services furnished by a practitioner described in subparagraph (C) of such section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id519a71d0cfbe41f4bcb20057fad63d30"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Limitations for hearing aids</header><subparagraph id="id9f826d85963b4ec59c9033ae2b4a12fb"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Payment may be made under this part with respect to an individual, with respect to hearing aids furnished by a qualified hearing aid supplier (as defined in subparagraph (C)) on or after January 1, 2027—</text><clause id="idc689f7a93ed747a4b97c612db40f8ec4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not more than once per ear during a 5-year period;</text></clause><clause id="ida8f313b870d34c76b0a9e030ec6214b3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>only for types of such hearing aids that are determined appropriate by the Secretary; and</text></clause><clause id="ide15c8b3df0cd4f5da2e9b2e6b596cbd0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>only if furnished pursuant to a written order of a physician, qualified audiologist (as defined in section 1861(ll)(4)), qualified hearing aid professional (as defined in subparagraph (C) of such section), physician assistant, nurse practitioner, or clinical nurse specialist.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7231f9cc30f04f2bb3612363bc6b34e2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>The payment basis determined under this subsection (including after application of paragraph (1)(H), relating to application of competitive acquisition) for hearing aids furnished by a qualified hearing aid supplier on or after January 1, 2027, shall not exceed the rate determined for such hearing aids under the Federal Supply Schedule of the General Services Administration, as published by such Administration in 2021, updated to the year involved using the applicable percent increase for the year. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8527e24ca9c8458e9e17e4e642177dbf"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><clause id="id2067c8e766fa45e6bb38ebe0766cc46c"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Hearing aid</header><text>The term <term>hearing aid</term> means the item and related services including selection, fitting, adjustment, and patient education and training.</text></clause><clause id="id0d3bcc6841974213b3458df8bea0ca3f"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Qualified hearing aid supplier</header><text>The term <term>qualified hearing aid supplier</term> means—</text><subclause id="id4099d6905199405f8875eb873d22d5a9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a qualified audiologist;</text></subclause><subclause id="id0bb4adb55c99439995ad40f12e397401"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a physician (as defined in section 1861(r)(1));</text></subclause><subclause id="id924d45bd81ba4db08f19994eb4151601"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a physician assistant, nurse practitioner, or clinical nurse specialist;</text></subclause><subclause id="id5516308a34734562a5544bee26d08fb0"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a qualified hearing aid professional (as defined in section 1861(ll)(4)(C)); and</text></subclause><subclause id="idd85ea2ae869e4c18b35c7d14d70401e8"><enum>(V)</enum><text>other suppliers as determined by the Secretary.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id96a9f6250a264fe8b43325bf5ebd217d"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application of competitive acquisition</header><subparagraph id="id2b7169fee83945d69b17ee5b32bb7b9a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1834(h)(1)(H) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(h)(1)(H)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><clause id="id1e739b460eb14646b853b90ac6c818d7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the header, by inserting <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="subparagraph">and hearing aids</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="subparagraph">orthotics</header-in-text></quote>;</text></clause><clause id="id74dae195ce09492d89ff26956eacca03"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting <quote>or of hearing aids described in paragraph (2)(D) of such section,</quote> after <quote>2011,</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="idac0ab81ad37d4af38085f25f15b7cb27"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in clause (i), by inserting <quote>or such hearing aids</quote> after <quote>such orthotics</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0118c45d954c475c94bdabbec7493f5d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><clause id="id0fadf11247bb4efb8db9b3c636251e1a"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1847(a)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-3">42 U.S.C. 1395w–3(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9891C4BD2E9D494C8E921F0281FBE0C0"><subparagraph id="idd23671bd40ab465c9c2b0ea1925b09d2"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Hearing aids</header><text>Hearing aids described in section 1861(s)(8) for which payment would otherwise be made under section 1834(h).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="id987909f5ceef4abe80a26725f6c6a7f5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exemption of certain items from competitive acquisition</header><text>Section 1847(a)(7) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-3">42 U.S.C. 1395w–3(a)(7)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA1F04986013A48BB8A85D166FE5737B9"><subparagraph id="id34138b6d6af84aa78f472d1ac14d0b0d"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Certain hearing aids</header><text>Those items and services described in paragraph (2)(E) if furnished by a physician or other practitioner (as defined by the Secretary) to the physician's or practitioner's own patients as part of the physician's or practitioner's professional service.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="id4c54978d2e5141a59494bbb82612f67d"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Section 1847(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-3">42 U.S.C. 1395w–3(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7DE99C0E6E484FCF8DE23C31FEA50BA9"><paragraph id="id1f23a365f5774c948c1f9cc302c77ca2"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Competition with respect to hearing aids</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2031, the Secretary shall begin the competition with respect to the items and services described in paragraph (2)(E).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2883636cf9d34d20947f1ee600817944"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Physician self-referral law</header><text>Section 1877(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395nn">42 U.S.C. 1395nn(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9a57ba89d0c94c97a44adadee177a286"><paragraph id="id3932a08287d0485ab094e0860829756e"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Hearing aids and services</header><text>In the case of hearing aid examination services and hearing aids—</text><subparagraph id="id5b7d191ff57b4a07b7cc11c3e67b29cc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>furnished on or after January 1, 2027, and before January 1, 2029; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5a8235845bab42d7885d46ca40daac28"><enum>(B)</enum><text>furnished on or after January 1, 2029, if the financial relationship specified in subsection (a)(2) meets such requirements the Secretary imposes by regulation to protect against program or patient abuse.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0003c4d8c41e4753978e551de6003dbf"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exclusion modification</header><text>Section 1862(a)(7) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(a)(7)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(except such hearing aids or examinations therefor as described in and otherwise allowed under section 1861(s)(8))</quote> after <quote>hearing aids or examinations therefor</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="id90fbb7aa33f04a0ba3b05845c9b1ed8f" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Inclusion as excepted medical treatment</header><text>Section 1821(b)(5)(A)(iv) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395i-5">42 U.S.C. 1395i–5(b)(5)(A)(iv)</external-xref>), as added by section 2(f), is amended by inserting <quote>, audiology services described in subsection (ll)(3) of such section, or hearing aids described in subsection (s)(8) of such section</quote> after <quote>section 1861)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="idee6490acf6fa4654b2eacd6bd0f434c0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rural health clinics and federally qualified health centers</header><paragraph id="id2878b8c86b8b4dbb82184e3cf83c72b5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Clarifying coverage of audiology services as physicians' services</header><text>Section 1861(aa)(1)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(aa)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(including audiology services (as defined in subsection (ll)(3)))</quote> after <quote>physicians' services</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idac88042ca21a462f9ddef3929ed5d791"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion of qualified audiologists and qualified hearing aid professionals as RHC and FQHC practitioners</header><text>Section 1861(aa)(1)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(aa)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or by a qualified audiologist or a qualified hearing aid professional (as such terms are defined in subsection (ll)),</quote> after <quote>(as defined in subsection (hh)(1)),</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id395625d09fcf49b2b74befc80cfc0b02"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Temporary payment rates for certain services under the RHC AIR and FQHC PPS</header><subparagraph id="id13915a337f1d426db07af5e732594137"><enum>(A)</enum><header>AIR</header><text>Section 1833 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l</external-xref>), as amended by section 2(g)(2)(A), is amended—</text><clause id="id43a048cd023a4d10b2079a30b4f4589d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(3)(A), by inserting <quote>or audiology services (as defined in section 1861(ll)(3))</quote> after <quote>(as defined in section 1861(nnn)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="ida4ba5161e9764f87bd8eafdae48f3ef1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (ee), by inserting <quote>or audiology services (as defined in section 1861(ll)(3))</quote> after <quote>(as defined in section 1861(nnn)</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1d03851fc91e488e8e3b611cf134a272"><enum>(B)</enum><header>PPS</header><text>Section 1834(o)(6) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(o)(6)</external-xref>), as added by section 2(g)(2)(B), is amended—</text><clause id="iddd27a3fcca314c429be164e4c1aba089"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>or audiology services (as defined in section 1861(ll)(3))</quote> after <quote>(as defined in section 1861(nnn))</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="idec6467f923da4b7592ba9278e3354af3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by inserting <quote>or such audiology services</quote> after <quote>such dental and oral health services</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5b48969d0ec14f199ab5647a1c4fdd1e" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Expediting implementation</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall implement this section for 2027 and 2028 through program instruction or other forms of program guidance.</text></subsection><subsection id="id1b35a1d2f74f416491b5f19cf8ccc30d"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Secretary of Health and Human Services for fiscal year 2025, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $370,000,000, to remain available until expended, for purposes of implementing the amendments made by this section during the period beginning on January 1, 2026, and ending on September 30, 2035.</text></subsection></section><section id="id616e968d97ab4f7e842d1e442c2af780"><enum>4.</enum><header>Providing coverage for vision care under the Medicare program</header><subsection id="ida84f7314c1e3411b80d91c8638405fbe"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coverage</header><text>Section 1861(s)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(s)(2)</external-xref>), as amended by section 2(a), is amended—</text><paragraph id="id03aab37803f7427fa67e23a1a985ae04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (JJ), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb0dd5446ff34437e827d1c2ca5c7e817"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (KK), by striking the period at the end and adding <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id192b6d98620543a4a401d36b665fe2fc"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDAECECDD8D9242D98579A0B1D17DFFF1"><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc2ec5c9c7866451e834f321c6aa234d0" indent="up1"><enum>(LL)</enum><text>vision services (as defined in subsection (ooo));</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id47c34a8287ed4be1a64cc61f0211146a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Vision services defined</header><text>Section 1861 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x</external-xref>), as amended by section 2(b), is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6564878B3A174B9F9F7EF0E9222BA7D7"><subsection id="id3959513e80ea41df871f02fe3849ebdb"><enum>(ooo)</enum><header>Vision services</header><text>The term <term>vision services</term> means routine eye examinations to determine the refractive state of the eyes, including procedures performed during the course of such examination, furnished on or after January 1, 2027, by or under the direct supervision of an ophthalmologist or optometrist who is legally authorized to furnish such examinations or procedures (as applicable) under State law (or the State regulatory mechanism provided by State law) of the State in which the examinations or procedures are furnished.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idb3f53dd0e38e445e93fa1a27e4b25c4a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Payment limitations</header><text>Section 1834 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m</external-xref>), as amended by section 2(c)(2), is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD60599E90D5346FB9E382B5F43F412CD"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8fdf95df93f14df19f12c253eb59a56e"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Limitation for vision services</header><text>With respect to vision services (as defined in section 1861(ooo)) and an individual, payment shall be made under this part for only 1 routine eye examination described in such subsection during a 2-year period.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id253b440c2ade450a9e29ac77dd6a60ab"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Payment under physician fee schedule</header><text>Section 1848(j)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(j)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(2)(LL),</quote> before <quote>(3)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide76b5a3ed36f40ef9564ff82462947f7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coverage of conventional eyeglasses</header><text>Section 1861(s)(8) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(s)(8)</external-xref>), as amended by section 3(b)(1), is amended by striking <quote>, and including one pair of conventional eyeglasses or contact lenses furnished subsequent to each cataract surgery with insertion of an intraocular lens</quote> and inserting <quote>, including 1 pair of conventional eyeglasses or contact lenses furnished subsequent to each cataract surgery with insertion of an intraocular lens, if furnished before January 1, 2027, and including conventional eyeglasses (as described in section 1834(h)(8)), whether or not furnished subsequent to such a surgery, if furnished on or after January 1, 2027</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="id9676c7f23ac44af2b21936a1182ac9ff"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Special payment rules for eyeglasses</header><paragraph id="idfbe4d47458bf4c9d915aff11cb326583"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>Section 1834(h) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(h)</external-xref>), as amended by section 3(b)(2), is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3dc4666d63354a58818494a5523e279d"><paragraph id="id5a942404389a4fbe800f2c0661852156"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Payment limitations for eyeglasses</header><subparagraph id="id4dc73c3b117e4a61a95f654338716152"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to conventional eyeglasses furnished to an individual on or after January 1, 2027, subject to subparagraph (B), payment shall be made under this part only during a 2-year period, for 1 pair of eyeglasses (including lenses and the frame).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8f0c58a9e2924955b088dbbfe5f72691"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>With respect to a 2-year period described in subparagraph (A), in the case of an individual who receives cataract surgery with insertion of an intraocular lens, payment shall be made under this part for 1 pair of conventional eyeglasses furnished subsequent to such cataract surgery during such period.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9332f57caba947e2933296304accf300"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>The payment basis determined under this subsection (including after application of paragraph (1)(H), relating to application of competitive acquisition) for conventional eyeglasses furnished to an individual on or after January 1, 2027, shall not exceed the rate determined for such eyeglasses under the Federal Supply Schedule of the General Services Administration, as published by such Administration in 2021, updated to the year involved using the applicable percent increase for the year. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id89310d2100b7480d82113ae64ca9c0a4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>No coverage of certain items</header><text>Payment shall not be made under this part for deluxe eyeglasses or conventional reading glasses.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id1fb7d0bcf2074cf0b0e4cb5eeb33171f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application of competitive acquisition</header><subparagraph id="id9703e409097f4cfe9970f01801664b6a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1834(h)(1)(H) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(h)(1)(H)</external-xref>), as amended by section 3(b)(3)(A), is amended—</text><clause id="id625372e42b2f4e239f407f2404bf254a" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="paragraph">and hearing aids</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="subparagraph">hearing aids, and eyeglasses</header-in-text></quote>;</text></clause><clause id="id2d406ae1a20b4488a4f5f963d62490ae" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i)—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08776ff0834f4f4fb98e85a9e407d1fd"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>or of hearing aids</quote> and inserting <quote>of hearing aids</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id201024231b28408783e8eeffbe874065"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or of eyeglasses described in paragraph (2)(E) of such section,</quote> after <quote>paragraph (2)(D) of such section,</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id90ed1009e95048f09c1e6fda814e9397"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>or such hearing aids</quote> and inserting <quote>, such hearing aids, or such eyeglasses</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5756acc604c3408197d4d5314d48a6f3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 1847(a)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-3">42 U.S.C. 1395w–3(a)(2)</external-xref>), as amended by section 3(b)(3)(B)(i), is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id415fbcf826b34550bdc975e0db95e034"><subparagraph id="idc826c43633e64289b34853fa3c2cace6"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Eyeglasses</header><text>Eyeglasses described in section 1861(s)(8) for which payment would otherwise be made under section 1834(h).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ff2539d769843058fecc53ec896ac06"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Section 1847(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-3">42 U.S.C. 1395w–3(a)</external-xref>), as amended by section 3(b)(3)(B)(iii), is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2512a2bd3dc249d3a7cf18e7c0e061ae"><paragraph id="id94d86c25ff6d4202bd796b94ea4f0823"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Competition with respect to eyeglasses</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2030, the Secretary shall begin the competition with respect to the items and services described in paragraph (2)(F).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4dd1ba7c5ffe484abdff13c141a51a90"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exclusion modifications</header><text>Section 1862(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(a)</external-xref>), as amended by section 2(e), is amended—</text><paragraph id="id3edd8fba3e5e4a1a8b70ff6c67b10ac7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="id70152ce0abad4f50a2d4edd3dd266707"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (P), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id194b9da5e54f4c3ab4b8acbd378978b5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (Q), by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting <quote>, and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7f23bde3435d40c8b172b6a2644c4fa0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC840F2119DB543609026DA09FD182204"><subparagraph id="id9bd872103d3943e6a9d1da81011ad39a" indent="up1"><enum>(R)</enum><text>in the case of vision services (as defined in section 1861(ooo)) that are routine eye examinations as described in such section, which are furnished more frequently than once during a 2-year period;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida1d206d0f50b4608831ba1017f01bffe"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (7)—</text><subparagraph id="id3a85f6ffd1854f49a19636642be648c5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(other than such an examination that is a vision service that is covered under section 1861(s)(2)(LL))</quote> after <quote>eye examinations</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbbdeda38b1a94d74bf31b5707979c4a2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(other than such a procedure that is a vision service that is covered under section 1861(s)(2)(LL))</quote> after <quote>refractive state of the eyes</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id19e27783153f4c3dbe9d8ba5d7b4b0aa" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Inclusion as excepted medical treatment</header><text>Section 1821(b)(5)(A)(iv) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395i-5">42 U.S.C. 1395i–5(b)(5)(A)(iv)</external-xref>), as added by section 2(f) and amended by section 3(d), is amended—</text><paragraph id="id59acefaacb244511bb525c0a738c34a2" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or hearing aids</quote> and inserting <quote>hearing aids</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id66afad16a47f479ea2f385bf0fae448a" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, or vision services (as defined in subsection (ooo) of such section)</quote> after <quote>subsection (s)(8) of such section</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf966c309436544d8b8f15341179ab83a"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rural Health Clinics and Federally Qualified Health Centers</header><paragraph id="idc315ec3f570c4c8d82ab76c138e84d01"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Clarifying coverage of vision services as physicians' services</header><text>Section 1861(aa)(1)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(aa)(1)(A)</external-xref>), as amended by section 3(e)(1), is amended by inserting <quote>and vision services (as defined in subsection (ooo))</quote> after <quote>(as defined in subsection (ll)(3))</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id348f69f6259243019954f3ddf9d7bf74"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Temporary payment rates for certain services under the RHC AIR and FQHC PPS</header><subparagraph id="ideb5e38bec3ac4e4fa7c67b7875eb0ced"><enum>(A)</enum><header>AIR</header><text>Section 1833 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l</external-xref>), as amended by sections 2(g)(2)(A) and 3(e)(3)(A), is amended—</text><clause id="id3d605127a0ad4d19aa2d4e0e159218a6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(3)(A)—</text><subclause id="idddc20b19d96f4ee2b47c47835aecff54"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or audiology</quote> and inserting <quote>, audiology</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id49f5fe0db2a1472386e418240f6ef394"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, or vision services (as defined in section 1861(ooo))</quote> after <quote>(as defined in section 1861(ll)(3))</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idbc7bfb340f6747758f3f702fd8f295f7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (ee)—</text><subclause id="id4984ca99fbe44512b95651b83aa0b144"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or audiology</quote> and inserting <quote>, audiology</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id6518074722fb40bd98def6ccc844816a"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, or vision services (as defined in section 1861(ooo))</quote> after <quote>(as defined in section 1861(ll)(3))</quote>.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd05953a0f2144a6993e46244aa5ff2f3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>PPS</header><text>Section 1834(o)(6) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(o)(6)</external-xref>), as added by section 2(g)(2)(B) and amended by section 3(e)(3)(B), is amended—</text><clause id="idac619d6ca5d540e5a1721d4a305fdb8c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the first sentence—</text><subclause id="id31621bad39194904b41ef4b7e71b05c4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or audiology</quote> and inserting <quote>, audiology</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id686fe218611547f1949a2d7165d8931f"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, or vision services (as defined in section 1861(ooo))</quote> after <quote>(as defined in section 1861(ll)(3))</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id737d5310e6b94e10bcbdc4afe6afb4ff"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by striking <quote>or such audiology services</quote> and inserting <quote>, such audiology services, or such vision services</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc790a62424aa4d1cb30eb99ef37beb9a"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Expediting implementation</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall implement this section for 2027 and 2028 through program instruction or other forms of program guidance.</text></subsection><subsection id="id09303ec18b0f4e50b7c4791765a406cd"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Secretary of Health and Human Services for fiscal year 2025, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $500,000,000, to remain available until expended, for purposes of implementing the amendments made by this section during the period beginning on January 1, 2026, and ending on September 30, 2034.</text></subsection></section><section id="idae77b85389f24bacbb80c69d1825956c"><enum>5.</enum><header>Phase-in of impact of dental and oral health coverage on part B premiums</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1839(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395r">42 U.S.C. 1395r(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idbd96d970ebc94e828344141b9accf48a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the second sentence of paragraph (1), by striking <quote>and (7)</quote> and inserting <quote>(7), and (8)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id02856c7945b841e799123c4c0e78fd0f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (8)(C), the Secretary</quote>; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8e7d1d48bf3045f9b5e7eb938d67126d"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="id996b6c7f45094b64b84cf7038bfbe1d0" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><paragraph id="idc65700203a0243d58faf497c2b41ef7b"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Special rule for 2026 through 2030</header><subparagraph id="id2c149dff31f74bbdb9fd157235fddeeb"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Determination of alternative monthly actuarial rate for each of 2026 through 2030</header><text>For each of 2026 through 2030, the Secretary shall, at the same time as and in addition to the determination of the monthly actuarial rate for enrollees age 65 and over determined in each of 2025 through 2029 for the succeeding calendar year according to paragraph (1), determine an alternative monthly actuarial rate for enrollees age 65 and over for the year as described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcbb654439cf44f97b3129747dfaf2e59"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Alternative monthly actuarial rate described</header><clause id="id25ec612c45f6484090e675604b586f32"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The alternative monthly actuarial rate described in this subparagraph is—</text><subclause id="idad9e554a02f74b70ae6591af4fb6860e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for 2026 and 2027, the monthly actuarial rate for enrollees age 65 and over for the year, determined as if the amendments made by section 2 of the <short-title>Medicare Dental, Hearing, and Vision Expansion Act of 2025</short-title> did not apply; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idbd41ce77c894441fafff543d92cba725"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for 2028, 2029, and 2030, the monthly actuarial rate for enrollees age 65 and over for the year, determined as if the amendments made by such section 2 did not apply, plus the applicable percent of the amount by which—</text><item id="id29b625ba75d74ac38d18e7070fc0ef83"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the monthly actuarial rate for enrollees age 65 and over for the year determined according to paragraph (1); exceeds</text></item><item id="id062062f666d040c2a580b4e50d4ed39a"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the monthly actuarial rate for enrollees age 65 and over for the year, determined as if the amendments made by such section 2 did not apply.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="iddf74535c25e14e4ca86331eb6948954e"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Definition of applicable percent</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <term>applicable percent</term> means—</text><subclause id="ide258ad20c3014b36b32bb971bc6f20be"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for 2028, 25 percent;</text></subclause><subclause id="idf8c1305ae7a946eca658de4c7a77526e"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for 2029, 50 percent; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id7feb3b019e114bbca37668874af5084e"><enum>(III)</enum><text>for 2030, 75 percent.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4526ee4a309d47148af970b433de6145" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Application to part b premium and other provisions of this part</header><text>For each of 2026 through 2030, the Secretary shall use the alternative monthly actuarial rate for enrollees age 65 and over for the year determined under subparagraph (A), in lieu of the monthly actuarial rate for such enrollees for the year determined according to paragraph (1), when determining the monthly premium rate for the year under paragraph (3) and subsection (j), the part B deductible under section 1833(b), and the premium subsidy and monthly adjustment amount under subsection (i).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

