<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H746D8DD0323D4DDABBB15A4DE7D0B390" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 350 IH: Expressing support for the designation of April 24, 2025, as “Remanufacturing Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 350</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250424">April 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of April 24, 2025, as <quote>Remanufacturing Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas remanufacturing is a comprehensive and rigorous industrial process by which a previously sold, leased, used, worn, remanufactured, or nonfunctional product or part is returned to a like-new, same-as-when-new, or better-than-when-new condition, from both a quality and performance perspective, through a controlled, reproducible, and sustainable process; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a 2012 United States International Trade Commission (ITC) report found that remanufacturers support at least 180,000 full-time jobs in the United States, and the ITC report states that production of remanufactured goods in the United States increased by 15 percent from 2009 to 2011 and exports totaled $11,200,000,000 annually; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas remanufacturing has been recognized by leading universities, research institutions, and manufacturers in the United States as good for the environment for its ability to divert end-of-life products from landfills; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, by encouraging businesses, State agencies, nonprofit organizations, schools, and individuals to celebrate <quote>Remanufacturing Day</quote> on April 24, 2025, Congress can further promote remanufacturing as environmentally friendly and economically smart; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, to focus the attention of the United States on the benefits of remanufacturing, businesses, educational institutions, and nonprofit organizations have joined together to celebrate <quote>Remanufacturing Day</quote> and are encouraging their colleagues, friends and families, and their communities to learn more about the benefits of remanufactured products: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H7D781346707044DCB471C6F86470716B"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA0C71EC3318749A9A37BBCD18AD23401"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives supports the designation of <quote>Remanufacturing Day</quote>.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

