<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Considered-and-Passed-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1077 : District of Columbia Local Funds Act, 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1077</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was considered, read the third time, and passed</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To approve local funds for the District of Columbia for fiscal year 2025, in accordance with the Fiscal Year 2025 Local Budget Act of 2024, and to establish provisions for the use of such funds.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>District of Columbia Local Funds Act, 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id79ce3694f4f04ff3b0476573bb1f521c"><enum>2.</enum><header>District of Columbia Local Funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Local funds are appropriated for the District of Columbia for the current fiscal year out of the General Fund of the District of Columbia (<quote>General Fund</quote>) for programs and activities set forth in the Fiscal Year 2025 Local Budget Act of 2024 (D.C. Law 25–218) and at rates set forth under such Act, as amended as of the date of enactment of this Act: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That notwithstanding any other provision of law, except as provided in section 450A of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act (section 1–204.50a, D.C. Official Code), sections 816 and 817 of the Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2009 (secs. 47–369.01 and 47–369.02, D.C. Official Code), and provisions of this Act, the total amount appropriated in this Act for operating expenses for the District of Columbia for fiscal year 2025 by this section shall not exceed the estimates included in the Fiscal Year 2025 Local Budget Act of 2024, as amended as of the date of enactment of this Act or the sum of the total revenues of the District of Columbia for such fiscal year: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That the amount appropriated may be increased by proceeds of one-time transactions, which are expended for emergency or unanticipated operating or capital needs: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That such increases shall be approved by enactment of local District law and shall comply with all reserve requirements contained in the District of Columbia Home Rule Act: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia shall take such steps as are necessary to assure that the District of Columbia meets these requirements, including the apportioning by the Chief Financial Officer of the appropriations and funds made available to the District during fiscal year 2025, except that the Chief Financial Officer may not reprogram for operating expenses any funds derived from bonds, notes, or other obligations issued for capital projects. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

