<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2568368556A34B5493449CD3B1DBAFF0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2948 IH: Safer Neighborhoods Gun Buyback Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2948</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250417">April 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance to make grants to States, units of local government, and gun dealers to conduct gun buyback programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBF5E832A2C2248BCA4BBF8BEBD26FB14" style="OLC"><section id="HDB1231304C944630BB2D74DF3E4B19A5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H6A183609C0974467A784D1ED6C799A4A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safer Neighborhoods Gun Buyback Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></subsection><subsection id="H19261FFED9424A949F0E38187DFEAD11"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"><toc-entry idref="HDB1231304C944630BB2D74DF3E4B19A5" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H4B346BD3089C4370875D80F3C26D67AE" level="title">Title I—Gun Buyback Grant Program</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7EF9593C4EEA489F891428BF034158CF" level="section">Sec. 101. Program authorized.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H0EE5DCC537BB46359C5B867D1E71BDE2" level="section">Sec. 102. Applications.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HFB9AA6710BF04E5E9373974D3E847D53" level="section">Sec. 103. Term of grant.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7F93D05B022D4587A4800E6078BDCD22" level="section">Sec. 104. Smart prepaid cards.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6E412B891FC24F01B7EE21D255C7AD89" level="section">Sec. 105. Uses of funds.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7B16705A2B524E8A89705CD8E57F5D8D" level="section">Sec. 106. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H21649FC12A364A3986CEBDA6928B35E8" level="section">Sec. 107. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H52556090D6D64627A3068E9A344F8E73" level="title">Title II—Criminal Provision</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H46919AE32D1E427F870698B620C550AE" level="section">Sec. 201. Use of smart prepaid card in the acquisition or transfer of a firearm.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><title id="H4B346BD3089C4370875D80F3C26D67AE"><enum>I</enum><header>Gun buyback grant program</header><section id="H7EF9593C4EEA489F891428BF034158CF"><enum>101.</enum><header>Program authorized</header><subsection id="H0AF4FB262144466AB26DD81FA611CF84"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance (referred to in this title as the <quote>Director</quote>) may make grants to eligible entities to conduct gun buyback programs.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF8E91F7CD79E416F92F7A6C5819F3FD9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entity defined</header><text>In this title, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><paragraph id="HB15B853ADAC4491CA7B7EA6AA4CA0F4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a State;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5ABFF7F289E4AD1B5EF3131CC842100"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a unit of local government;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BAAF32740AA4C5F8CF1E481542C8B5F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Tribal government; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E456175D5F54D76BA59C990B363020E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a covered gun dealer. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0EE5DCC537BB46359C5B867D1E71BDE2"><enum>102.</enum><header>Applications</header><subsection id="H57CC0534063A4AEF981E52C34FE0271A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The chief executive of an eligible entity seeking a grant under this title shall submit an application to the Director at such time and containing such information as the Director may reasonably require.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD2E0B4274837410088C18A89DE9A1CBB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Subgrants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered gun dealer seeking a subgrant shall submit an application to the chief executive of such unit of local government or State at such time and containing such information as the chief executive may reasonably require, including proof of such dealer’s license under section 923 of title 18, United States Code.</text></subsection></section><section id="HFB9AA6710BF04E5E9373974D3E847D53"><enum>103.</enum><header>Term of grant</header><subsection id="H03B014100BD94F258DEB6C732531F1B9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Term</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term of a grant awarded under this title shall be two years.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4B57100951C74BB78BE577C75AEE177A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability of grant funds</header><paragraph id="H23E7327AA5FF4A2CAA34BC6AC7983DEC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>States or units of local government</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or unit of local government that receives a grant under this title shall return to the Director any remaining smart prepaid cards and any unused portion of such grant at the end of the two-year and 270-day period beginning on the date that the grant was awarded.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2421E818996447828BF7C73C817230F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Gun dealers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A gun dealer that receives a grant or subgrant under this title shall return to the Director any remaining smart prepaid cards and any unused portion of such grant or subgrant that was allocated to be used to buy back guns—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H70ECC31835954B29AC94C6551F443B6A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a gun dealer receiving a grant, at the end of the two-year period beginning on the date that the grant was awarded; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H523130419ABF4EB19B1D645672E945AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a gun dealer receiving a subgrant, at the end of the two-year period beginning on the date that the grant was awarded to the State or unit of local government from which the gun dealer received a subgrant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED461DB53BB34C3A9CD6E4D317A2DD72"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amounts returned</header><text>The Director shall return to the general fund of the Treasury any amounts returned under subsection (b).</text></subsection></section><section id="H7F93D05B022D4587A4800E6078BDCD22"><enum>104.</enum><header>Smart prepaid cards</header><subsection id="H1E747612C6DC428A8F33E4F310A50C3C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the grant program authorized under section 101, the Director may reserve such funds as may be necessary to acquire and distribute smart prepaid cards to eligible entities that receive grants under this title. The Director shall distribute the smart prepaid cards without any funds loaded onto the cards.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD3FB96BC0A7A43789AF437EC77323EAB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Market value of guns</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall determine the market value of each gun that the Director determines should be included in the gun buyback program and make such information publicly available.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7D385A3CB1C04EF9BE2BB7D7DB341333"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of cards To buy guns</header><paragraph id="H39D7EBEBD85E4263B6214195239BF2F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person may not use a smart prepaid card in the acquisition of a gun or ammunition, and a person may not accept a smart prepaid card in the transfer (including a loan) of a gun or ammunition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63EAFC68368843AD89C07625D5F7B982"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>A person that violates paragraph (1) shall pay to the Director an amount that is equal to the value of the prohibited sale.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6E412B891FC24F01B7EE21D255C7AD89"><enum>105.</enum><header>Uses of funds</header><subsection id="H687ED4FFE5D14CAC8640DC70D3E47982"><enum>(a)</enum><header>States and units of local government</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or unit of local government receiving a grant under this title shall use such funds to do the following:</text><paragraph id="H41C87F6A53574D0093EB11F22594BA9D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Gun buyback program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Use such funds to—</text><subparagraph id="H4AD37D08251C49B594DBD26821CC5B93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct a gun buyback program; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2433273E9304B4F9517D5662D2E72CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make subgrants to gun dealers in such State or unit of local government to conduct gun buyback programs, and distribute the smart prepaid cards such State or unit of local government receives to gun dealers receiving subgrants.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE855B6DBF2D41B7B75CC02B559AF819"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Gun and ammunition recycling program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Use not less than 5 percent of such funds to destroy the guns, including all parts, components, and accessories, and ammunition that such State or unit of local government collects or receives from gun dealers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H278C48D433774F5E8AB4E53911D4FA53"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>Use not more than 15 percent of such funds for the administrative costs of carrying out the grant program under this title, including the criminal database checks under subsection (f).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2A20FB7BAD174D789F8CEBE610B73756"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Gun dealers</header><paragraph id="HD7250220B0EF44A883948011AD1315D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A gun dealer receiving a grant or subgrant under this title shall use such funds to conduct a gun buyback program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAECC384047BC47B29F82F65D8A89D174"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Smart prepaid card amounts</header><subparagraph id="H056C595F605F40E9BC5FCC1C16269C1E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to purchase a gun through a gun buyback program, a gun dealer shall load onto a smart prepaid card 125 percent of the market value of the gun that the individual wishes to dispose of (as determined by the Director under section 104(b)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H278C4F29F54942B29FD33FD0159451D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A gun dealer may increase the purchase price of a gun and load an amount onto a smart prepaid card that is greater than 125 percent of the market value of the gun if the gun dealer determines that the gun has been altered in a way that would increase the market value of the gun (such as an altered grip, or the addition of a scope).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C7C854EFFF8431187656542A3567E37"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Guns received</header><subparagraph id="HCD1E6F3D48CA48C4BC0DF70D3E11960C"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H362541BD3E5E4544BE7FD018F9D784A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a gun dealer receiving a grant under this title, the gun dealer shall verify, pursuant to section 534(a)(5) of title 28, United States Code, that each firearm received under this program has not been reported stolen. </text></clause><clause id="H8887337BE1F94388956A68B4286AEFFA" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If such firearm has been reported stolen, such gun dealer shall notify the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives within 24 hours. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B31F753735F4E9DABBD54FF781E230E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the case of a gun dealer receiving a grant under this title, the gun dealer shall deliver a gun, as received including all parts, components, and accessories, or ammunition the dealer receives under the gun buyback program to the closest office of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives not later than 30 days after receiving such gun.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2520ABC53209431EA4AD9E20883A1CAB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>In the case of a gun dealer receiving a subgrant under this title, the gun dealer shall deliver a gun, as received including all parts, components, and accessories, or ammunition the dealer receives under the gun buyback program to the State or unit of local government from which it receives the subgrant not later than 30 days after receiving such gun.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H09D25CF0D917496AAC41E06AB4162F3A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ammunition collection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State, unit of local government, or gun dealer conducting a gun buyback program under this title may accept ammunition from individuals wishing to dispose of it, which shall be destroyed in accordance with the recycling program in subsection (a)(2), but may not use smart prepaid cards to purchase ammunition under the gun buyback program.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3A3DD28F0EE24E83BC1330EF7F130EEF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Incentives for gun dealer participation</header><text>To the extent that the Director determines necessary to facilitate participation of gun dealers in the gun buyback program, grant funds may be used to provide monetary or other incentives to gun dealers to participate in such program. For purposes of subsection (a), any such incentives shall be treated as part of the subgrant to the gun dealer described in paragraph (1)(B) thereof.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFF22980E95764FE48D3A11DB0413DF91"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Resale of guns prohibited</header><text>A State, unit of local government, or gun dealer conducting a gun buyback program under this title may not sell a gun, or any of the parts, components, or accessories of the gun as received, or ammunition received under such program.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC89864579C314CEB8B4EAEE9E086F17B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Criminal database check</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State, unit of local government, or office of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives that receives a gun under a gun buyback program under this title shall, not later than 21 days after receiving the gun, use any database accessible to the State, unit of local government, or office of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, as applicable, in order to determine whether the gun was used in the commission of a crime. If such a gun was used in the commission of a crime, the gun shall be delivered to the appropriate prosecuting authority.</text></subsection></section><section id="H7B16705A2B524E8A89705CD8E57F5D8D"><enum>106.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text><paragraph id="HE64BB86F01EC4AF99FFB0FE1B05A1B69"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Ammunition</header><text>The term <term>ammunition</term> has the meaning given such term in section 921(a)(17)(A) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H108FB992E2704470BC9684FD6DD02B2F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered gun dealer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered gun dealer</term> means a gun dealer—</text><subparagraph id="HE84AABAE70254CCFA0D120E73D585304"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not subject to a warning letter or warning conference pursuant to violations of Federal law by the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives in the 5 years prior to the date on which the dealer receives a grant under this title; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H251DD7DF558042B8A21E4234ABE1F4FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not located in a unit of local government or State that receives a grant under this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H728D5CD4AE81456F88E199C66BF93808"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Gun</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>gun</term> means <term>firearm</term> as defined in section 921(a)(3) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5746A33F3BE425EAB8DAB2D82B1D81E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Gun buyback program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>gun buyback program</term> means a program under which a State, a unit of local government, or a gun dealer, using smart prepaid cards as described in section 105(b)(2), purchases back from individuals wishing to dispose of them, a gun identified by the Director under section 104(b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14FFD0DCD9AA4406BFCA3564D0CA7170"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Gun dealer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>gun dealer</term> means a dealer of firearms licensed under section 923 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87C1B1E037104D7D8D313B9D7415E1E7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Smart prepaid card</header><text>The term <term>smart prepaid card</term> means a card issued by the Director that—</text><subparagraph id="H0CBCD142FB464D2797975942E21BE2FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is redeemable at multiple, unaffiliated merchants or service providers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H39001EAD06A746A882E6B900A342BB43"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contains a mechanism, for the purpose of preventing the cardholder from using it to purchase a gun or ammunition, that recognizes the merchant category code of a merchant and prohibits the use of such card at a place of business subject to a license to deal in firearms under section 923 of title 18, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A1DDD56FB07458EBEDF5683BC71790D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is honored, upon presentation, by merchants solely for goods or services, except for merchants described in subparagraph (B);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H718D188196354633A5166CBC1B4B4BD6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is loaded on a prepaid basis by a State, unit of local government, or gun dealer for use in a gun buyback program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21680BF3B7AC46EAB2DB4F45A1CB8A2F"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">clearly and conspicuously bears the words <quote>THIS CARD MAY NOT BE USED TO PURCHASE A GUN OR AMMUNITION</quote> in capital and raised letters on the card; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EF86176557C4673852031DE7310E603"><enum>(F)</enum><text>may not redeemed for coins or currency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB98F5C1EAAD4806BE9BFED1EE10EF62"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, or any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60C95946141045A5AB1A0DA5D0740833"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Tribal government</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>tribal government</term> means any Indian tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or community, including any Alaska Native village or regional or village corporation as defined in or established pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (85 Stat. 688; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1601">43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>) which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their special status as Indians.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H21649FC12A364A3986CEBDA6928B35E8"><enum>107.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $360,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2027 to carry out this title.</text></section></title><title id="H52556090D6D64627A3068E9A344F8E73"><enum>II</enum><header>Criminal provision</header><section id="H46919AE32D1E427F870698B620C550AE"><enum>201.</enum><header>Use of smart prepaid card in the acquisition or transfer of a firearm</header><subsection id="HD2FEF498FDA84DCABA07C05BD6433DBF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">Chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4D42A4B365E4811AA65F095F5B6BF46" style="USC"><section id="H9B3CCA7DB00748419C664BC5D6963203"><enum>932.</enum><header>Use of smart prepaid card in the acquisition or transfer of a firearm</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Whoever, in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce, uses a smart prepaid card (as such term is defined in section 106 of the Safer Neighborhoods Gun Buyback Act of 2017) in connection with the acquisition of, or accepts a smart prepaid card in connection with the transfer (including a loan) of a firearm or ammunition shall be fined not more than $100,000.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H470589CEA2A544B7944533F85929AABC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><paragraph id="H9B79DD10A50E4FA6A12A636529C06540"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 924(a)(1) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <quote>section 929</quote> the following: <quote>or section 932</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC9A8AD6A88A4C00BF61AA0015D5C22F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/931">section 931</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H32A056DB37934801AFF5981A988FE193" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">932. Use of smart prepaid card in the acquisition or transfer of a firearm. </toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

