<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="G">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 229 ATS: To authorize the production of records by the Committee on Foreign Relations.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num>S. RES. 229</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250514">May 14, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To authorize the production of records by the Committee on Foreign Relations.</official-title>
</form>
<preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas, the Committee on Foreign Relations has received a request from the Department of Justice for access to records relating to a panel discussion attended by committee staff that may be relevant to a case, <italic>United States v. Peter Biar Ajak</italic>, CR-24-00394-PHX-SPL, now pending in the United States District Court for the District of Arizona;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, by the privileges of the Senate of the United States and Rule XI of the Standing Rules of the Senate, no evidence under the control or in the possession of the Senate can, by administrative or judicial process, be taken from such control or possession but by permission of the Senate;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, when it appears that evidence under the control or in the possession of the Senate is needed for the promotion of justice, the Senate will take such action as will promote the ends of justice consistent with the privileges of the Senate: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body id="H92F419957CA6455EA23BFA633DFFF7BF"> <section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Chairman and Ranking Minority Member of the Committee on Foreign Relations, acting jointly, are authorized to provide to the Department of Justice for use in connection with <italic>United States v. Peter Biar Ajak</italic> committee records relating to a panel discussion attended by committee staff.</text></section>
</resolution-body>
</resolution> 


