<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25649-CJL-DM-GF5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S848 IS: Reporting Efficiently to Proper Officials in Response to Terrorism Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 848</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for joint reports by relevant Federal agencies to Congress regarding incidents of terrorism, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id28eeede8f53e465c92a19f9578217205"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short titles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reporting Efficiently to Proper Officials in Response to Terrorism Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>REPORT Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idfe9a1366a59c44d38e693e6d14cb80f1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Duty to report</header><subsection id="id3ae2feeeee7b46c6a401b2664352e7dc"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id368dfdab81b8427eaae77feb5c1670b0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Act of terrorism</header><text>The term <term>act of terrorism</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3077(1) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id571efac728ee4ed5aaac8804b090a2fc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id22491bb2bf82406cafbb166a3d9f5dd6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6fd3c6278e1f4bdf9458a618ef3b0474"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id266d71edc2c34e039a5ebd616c0a96b2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SLIN00">Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idda28140355934b0ebb9be7e782cc8118"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id52fbbd4b3cba462f9e25936eb640124a"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc92bf9d1916a42059ffb1f78e4758163"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id017c8d664ea946dfbb1af50514f04a5d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4650432ba1504712a1e79aa09ae35316"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Whenever an act of terrorism occurs in the United States, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and, as appropriate, the head of the National Counterterrorism Center shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7096c878a061469faebe1137a2ade9e8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to the appropriate congressional committees, by not later than 1 year after the completion of the investigation concerning such act by the primary Government agency conducting such investigation, an unclassified report (which may be accompanied by a classified annex) concerning such act of terrorism; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79020b91f9da49bfbc4a708484bf85e3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make the report required under subparagraph (A) available on a publicly accessible website.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49cdcd60c646402e936701311a2432ce"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reports required under this subsection may be combined into a quarterly report submitted to Congress.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idabf6081b115d45bc9ac108143e55cfc4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Each unclassified report and classified annex described in paragraph (1)(A) shall be made available upon request by any Member of Congress. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6de52d70a78d47318f25516b78ead53d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Content of reports</header><text>Each report submitted pursuant to subsection (b) shall—</text><paragraph id="id15322c2bba7044a9a8bcae25303d455b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include a statement of the facts of each act of terrorism covered by the report, to the extent such facts are known at the time the report is submitted to the appropriate congressional committees;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfbf2d14e445e439e8a5b2d14677ba8ab"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify any gaps in homeland or national security that could be addressed to prevent similar future acts of terrorism; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8e612d3b35954a4aa53fda2a4fb3e639"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include any recommendations for additional measures that could be taken to improve homeland or national security, including recommendations relating to potential changes in law enforcement practices or changes in law, with particular attention to changes that could help prevent future acts of terrorism.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id980b63f87cfd4e8c8e68f2eeedb8ca9d"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exception</header><paragraph id="id0067e7417c6f4a5d82b361696b0aaa0e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, or the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation determines any information described in subsection (c) that is required to be included in the report required under subsection (b) could jeopardize an ongoing investigation or prosecution, the Secretary, Attorney General, or Director, as the case may be—</text><subparagraph id="ida1f414d94aa84445a3d57f1c39cfb836"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may withhold from reporting such information; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7e233d9cd9ab4bacbfc422df611ce24e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall notify the appropriate congressional committees of such determination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id78e1299a3c1b450399b91df2229c4543"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Withholding of information pursuant to a determination described in paragraph (1) shall not affect, in any manner, the responsibility of the appropriate Federal official to submit a report required under subsection (b) containing other information described in subsection (c) that is not subject to such determination.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd07476d65d52478a9a81bcb613109ea0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></subsection><subsection id="id7ec10599b36447569ac0cfa04ab1cc92" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to provide the National Counterterrorism Center with prosecutorial or investigatory authority. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

