<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB8372B1B7C3E40E4BEA71A75D0191D05" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5770 IH: National Security Biotechnology Workforce Training Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5770</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251017">October 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish biotechnology workforce training programs for Department of Defense personnel, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5A60607857564A52982E474660759566" style="OLC">
<section id="HC93E1B68E2C54193809366885F061E92" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Security Biotechnology Workforce Training Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H989253BB3B494C10B0A28C1066D378A1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Defense biotechnology workforce training</header> <subsection id="H8A4A6F88F18F483C8C39691D20A1024E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall establish and carry out a training program—</text>
<paragraph id="HBDF2CC068DFA4A4297E0211F9AEBD8EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for members of the covered Armed Forces, civilian employees of the Department of Defense, and contractors of such Department whose duties the Secretary determines include—</text> <subparagraph id="H64CC7030B79048249EC57EB84992306C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>creating or deploying novel biotechnologies; </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE50EC49C97B44072AB113B18BA0C5B42"><enum>(B)</enum><text>analyzing, preparing for, or responding to biological threats; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2E5846715BD6439F82E18015EE5605D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">planning, research and development, engineering, or testing and evaluation of systems (including quality control and assurance, procurement and contracting, logistics, and cost estimating) regarding biotechnology; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBA7BFC7098184AF5AF8BA40907550715"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on biotechnology and other relevant critical and emerging technologies.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD9AF5BCEB0DF4F9D9FD9C5D7AD86ADBC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header> <paragraph id="HCC0EB93698C5496286698D6250E9FED9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall consult with leadership and workforce training managers in the Department to develop and implement such training program and identify the individuals described in subsection (a) based on—</text>
<subparagraph id="H3627A43582B94AFEBDF0025F7C63CBC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the needs and priorities of the Department; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFB71D710991E41D983F08F4F581EF906"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the relevance of the training to the individuals’ positions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H62FAE28CBD304B858498BB27706CC39F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Material</header><text>The material covered in the training programs shall be customized by Department leadership to align with specific needs and mission requirements.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC5D170725BB1495EA4FAD751D905C8E0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Skills</header><text>The Secretary shall define the essential skills for biotechnology personnel to better understand what Federal personnel should undergo training and how to customize training for groups.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H95F6277E102E40D7B31A5C00C6ACD7A8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header>
<paragraph id="H5D362762FF8C4FC3923C0B7C342D7A90"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The training program established under this section shall, at a minimum, include information on—</text> <subparagraph id="HB5D3104AE2FE4092BD3B2157158D8CF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the fundamental science underlying biotechnology, artificial intelligence and other relevant critical and emerging technologies;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H25172AB4831A448680651F00A879E08B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>concepts relating to the technological features of biotechnology systems;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39F7726E9E744165A62A4C9DF5F132F0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>applications of biotechnology in defense, health, agriculture, energy, environment, and other relevant areas;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC1693B1D9D9046A89EE089F02A84AAA6"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ways in which artificial intelligence, quantum computing, and other technologies are leveraged to advance biotechnology;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9CC666025FFA4391BCCE18FAAF622561"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">mechanisms by which the Federal Government supports, funds, purchases, and deploys biotechnology and its applications;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H904BF72FE17743C3BFC1F17A39155C10"><enum>(F)</enum><text>ways in which the Federal Government can benefit from biotechnology;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCDF7EDDF23A7469F88A3F579100E306A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>ethical, social, and legal aspects of biotechnology including ways of incorporating a wide range of stakeholder perspectives throughout research and innovation cycles;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H20DD623E965A4A588A877CF497BDCD6B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>ways to mitigate the risks described in previous subparagraphs, including efforts to create and identify biotechnologies that are reliable, safe, and trustworthy; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1708DBB0A6634758A604F18600A80909"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">future trends in biotechnology, including intersections with artificial intelligence, quantum computing, autonomous systems, robotics, advanced manufacturing, and other relevant technologies, as well as trends for economic and national security, and innovation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6B962E70EA5B4342A968B4EDFF8B4C1B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Participation</header><text>Any individual described under subsection (b)(1) shall complete training under this section annually.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7DDFE7048AB74047BF5A8827C5C9D2F3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Interactive</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure interactive learning with scholars and experts from private, public and nonprofit sectors is included under the training programs. The Secretary shall provide access to courses through institutions of professional military education, such as the National Defense University.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H28D4369D786F4088A49F31537D8AE9D8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The training programs established under this section shall be updated each year to review and cover advances in biotechnology and its convergence with other critical and emerging technologies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEFD43DE646E74DA3BE3E5D5536E0988E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Continuing education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall update the training programs established under this section to provide continuing technology education for individuals described in subsection (a) and include requirements for refresher training on the latest advances in biotechnology science, laboratory work, equipment and software.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H405EAFA00FD041BFA2B2324BEAF897A6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Performance measurements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish mechanisms to measure participation in training programs required under this section, and to receive and consider feedback from program participants to improve training.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H774D277C3B974AFDB2B3FA6896119B13"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a report that includes a plan to establish and implement the training programs required under this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H15EC88F9DF7942CF9400EC0C1E79CCA4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section and the training programs required to be carried out by this section shall terminate on the date that is five years after such programs are established under subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H12B2763F6E684E71B12D986317BBDA45"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="HD21DCCB87A87464295DC294EB4852F65"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given that term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (division E of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E4840C7943442639E8F03F5E465E272"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>covered Armed Force</term> means the Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Air Force, or Space Force.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

