<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA25392-FW8-JC-KS5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 254 ATS: Designating June 12, 2025, as “National Seersucker Day”, designating every Thursday after National Seersucker Day through the last Thursday in August 2025 as “Seersucker Thursday”, and designating June 2025 as “Seersucker Appreciation Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 254</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250522">May 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating June 12, 2025, as <quote>National Seersucker Day</quote>, designating every Thursday after National Seersucker Day through the last Thursday in August 2025 as <quote>Seersucker Thursday</quote>, and designating June 2025 as <quote>Seersucker Appreciation Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas seersucker was introduced to the United States in the South in the middle of the 19th century;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas seersucker suits were popularized in the United States in the early 1900s by New Orleans businessman Joseph Haspel at his Broad Street facility in New Orleans, Louisiana;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as a lightweight, hard-wearing fabric, seersucker is mostly worn and enjoyed by the people of the United States during hot summer months;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas former Senator Trent Lott of Mississippi brought Seersucker Thursday to Congress in 1996, and after the day went unobserved in 2012 and 2013, then-Representative Bill Cassidy, with the help of the late Senator Dianne Feinstein, revived the tradition in 2014;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the Senate will remember the historic service of the late Senator Dianne Feinstein, who shall forever remain a part of this tradition, which Senator Raphael Warnock will continue in her stead; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the name <quote>seersucker</quote> originates from the Persian phrase <quote>shir-o-shakar</quote>, meaning <quote>milk and sugar</quote>, alluding to the alternating textures of the fabric;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the seersucker textile is made of cotton, linen, or silk (or combinations thereof), woven on a loom with threads at different tensions, creating alternating stripes of smooth and puckered textures that do not lay flat on one’s skin, which is what makes the fabric so breathable;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas cotton is an important crop that producers in the United States, including 3,500 family farms in Georgia, strive to cultivate in the highest quality; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas one of the alternating stripes in seersucker is frequently in a color, typically blue, but sometimes gray, green, tan, red, pink, or another color, which, in combination with the white stripes, creates the iconic pattern so well known today: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id0bbb34992b284e99a96b3a9773cf4b13"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates June 12, 2025, as <quote>National Seersucker Day</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide9da4097585942fcac1ed4d2a54cbb36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>designates every Thursday after National Seersucker Day through the last Thursday in August 2025 as <quote>Seersucker Thursday</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id060d70216f924912b91af61de4ebdbab"><enum>(3)</enum><text>designates June 2025 as <quote>Seersucker Appreciation Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0463ec9fe9f44c4089e98a8390e31238"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recognizes the contributions of the hard-working people of the United States through the wearing of seersucker, the unique warm weather clothing known as the working person’s uniform;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id50bde1d6379d49539964ffa02051b4e8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages Senators to support the objective of National Seersucker Day and Seersucker Thursday;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9be4f25112344d3cb037b10a7f874d87"><enum>(6)</enum><text>encourages local governments in the United States to build partnerships with local organizations and other members of the clothing industries and enthusiasts to promote the wearing of seersucker; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb325b57e92d8447082cbf2ee136f1c31"><enum>(7)</enum><text>invites the people of the United States to don their warm weather finest on National Seersucker Day and every Seersucker Thursday. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

