<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5B90B7AB4F6D4946BF845CA219871867" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1215 IH: Semiconductor Supply Chain Security and Diversification Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1215</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250211">February 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="J000301">Mr. Johnson of South Dakota</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To support efforts of the governments of Western Hemisphere countries to increase the diversity of their upstream supply chains and downstream supply chains.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4D7F3C4A3C8F4AE4977CB4994C3E6EED" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDD8B5F10AED44BE3894BA1C0B041AC7D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Semiconductor Supply Chain Security and Diversification Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC965D4BE92304133A4420A990D6F1C77"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF6C59E1E839048DD90E15C395A9CB2D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>upstream supply chain</term> includes mining, production, or processing of critical minerals used in semiconductor manufacturing, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HC75871D7076D416D8BC60ECBFD83F1F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>zinc;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H17E96D491FED476AAC2843EC1C15C265"><enum>(B)</enum><text>gallium;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5B901F6D9F8642589222E875A4AD756A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>germanium;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC5A41495547D412EAD6BA31BA439C882"><enum>(D)</enum><text>silicon;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0E1B27D5CD694F4A8AAE6A06D4B617E5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>lithium; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA086CCC9DB004E49B199DDE36D67CC84"><enum>(F)</enum><text>cobalt; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2645629FC540408AA56D6D594350D852"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>downstream supply chain</term> includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD6455C61C45B4ADE85D02C73E957C8C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">testing and packaging facilities for semiconductors; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5D635F218F1A458C99A18FC8DC3D6D43"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advanced testing and packaging facilities for semiconductors.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HCC858797759A45AB9D90C2DDB1102959"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress; statement of policy</header> 
<subsection id="H48964AC0B0AE422C919D01889C9A9837"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the United States has an economic and national security interest in diversifying the semiconductor supply chain, specifically by encouraging the development of a regionally-based semiconductor ecosystems in the Western Hemisphere to compliment the investments in the United States under the CHIPS and Science Act. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H90F4B7223E1846AE90DED9C36FB2F35D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDE82E9B0C14E462B8376CD5F3F55CCE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to promote the security of allies and partners of the United States by encouraging the development of accessible, transparent, competitive, and robust semiconductor markets that provide diversified sources, types, and parts of the semiconductor chip; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89B113273C824232B7D6A040B53FFD98"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to encourage United States public and private sector investment in Latin American semiconductor infrastructure projects to bridge the gap between national security needs and commercial demand in a way that is consistent with the region’s absorptive capacity. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H9D274C786B394D3597CBD70B6FD5E5F6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Supporting efforts of the governments of Western Hemisphere countries to increase the diversity of their upstream supply chains and downstream supply chains</header> 
<subsection id="HC96910F7E3D9498AB05E1D3899E2921D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the policy described in section 3(b), the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and the heads of other relevant United States agencies, shall, as appropriate, focus the efforts of the Department of State and those agencies in supporting the efforts of the governments of Western Hemisphere countries to increase the diversity of their upstream supply chains and downstream supply chains, including through—</text> <paragraph id="HA92FCD723CB645828C5E0C4CC2E0E55B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>providing diplomatic and political support to the Organization of American States and Western Hemisphere governments, as necessary—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCFB9111F00A045C0A0C494A6E5B08191"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to facilitate international negotiations concerning cross-border infrastructure;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE9EBD697A8C49A2A92DC9A3C510D3AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to enhance the Western Hemisphere’s regulatory environment with respect to semiconductors; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBF02938247BA44CF9E59B1FCF7037CF8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop accessible, transparent, and competitive supply chain markets and downstream supply chain markets that are supplied by diverse sources, types, and routes of energy; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D1D53ADE4F64FA1835F5669E1275B44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing support to improve Western Hemisphere upstream supply chains and downstream supply chains for semiconductors, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7E9F2941BE9C427BAF19D4F3D79D6B47"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to diversify the sources and supply routes of Western Hemisphere countries; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAEA5F65B734F4ACC8E86E57CFE1D14C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to enhance semiconductor market integration across the regions. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFE7F0EA914554812878B780526379D39"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text>For the purposes of providing support for projects under this section, the following terms and conditions shall apply:</text> <paragraph id="H7DACC2C5CC384A49A2C8C3A91FAEB9AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States International Development Finance Corporation may provide support for upstream supply chain and downstream supply chain projects in countries in the Western Hemisphere with upper-middle-income economies or high-income economies (as those terms are defined by the World Bank).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDEAA1DF548A44A7D851EAB8281922307"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The restrictions under section 1412(c)(2) of the Better Utilization of Investments Leading to Development Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9612">22 U.S.C. 9612(c)(2)</external-xref>) shall not apply.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H98210199735D4980A297AA1FD7E4EB0A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Corporation shall restrict the provision of such support in a country described in paragraph (1) unless—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H040D562AA8A3449C97F72A728EE562DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that such support furthers the national economic or foreign policy interests of the United States; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9A13F02CA3C643DD9AA9EF4DAD5629DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such support is—</text> 
<clause id="HA387D3626F3A4C4E8175E91077405859"><enum>(i)</enum><text>designed to produce significant developmental outcomes or provide developmental benefits to the poorest population of that country; or</text></clause> <clause id="H4BD0466E6CBE40B49EAC98B5E57D9AAB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>necessary to preempt or counter efforts by a strategic competitor of the United States to secure significant political or economic leverage or acquire national security-sensitive technologies or infrastructure in a country that is an ally or partner of the United States. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE31EEA0CA51341D3B1DFAD963EF60969"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1402 of the Better Utilization of Investments Leading to Development Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9601">22 U.S.C. 9601</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

