<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H48E2538765EA46AEA29F02EBB4065BA2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1902 IH: Helping Emergency Responders Overcome Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1902</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250306">March 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to improve the detection, prevention, and treatment of mental health issues among public safety officers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H25150C60F888451FA8DDF7AF1CC90EFB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H531404476D844B93AB68E6BD1CB50DAA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Helping Emergency Responders Overcome Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HERO Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4FAAC2F556244B6DBDF74F95AF09E977"><enum>2.</enum><header>Data system to capture national public safety officer suicide incidence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 317V of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b-24">42 U.S.C. 247b–24</external-xref>) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H70F3A0B34F0A4596B7C6BE42898CB9E3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3D0E609ED690400D93BBFA167B070063"><enum>317W.</enum><header>Data system to capture national public safety officer suicide incidence</header> 
<subsection id="H67150333AA2D40808097328F30D3B127"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and other agencies as the Secretary determines appropriate, may—</text> <paragraph id="H1BC001CFF3954A9C9227718ECC597529"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop and maintain a data system, to be known as the Public Safety Officer Suicide Reporting System, for the purposes of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFFA2AA8A51BB49219651E09FBCD2E067"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collecting data on the suicide incidence among public safety officers; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4AB180FDA31B4B37BD164AB4049226CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitating the study of successful interventions to reduce suicide among public safety officers; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0D496C63FC3C45A48021BA049542AEB1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>integrate such system into the National Violent Death Reporting System, so long as the Secretary determines such integration to be consistent with the purposes described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H329AC9F4E25641CC88B1AD2986E60AE5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Data collection</header><text>In collecting data for the Public Safety Officer Suicide Reporting System, the Secretary shall, at a minimum, collect the following information:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5DA2E5B1EF264A4594741A6395A9435E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The total number of suicides in the United States among all public safety officers in a given calendar year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB33679E254354C879E7755883A846B8F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Suicide rates for public safety officers in a given calendar year, disaggregated by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2E47C7911E46432ABD7FE40072D5E500"><enum>(A)</enum><text>age and gender of the public safety officer;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8B29BF0F149B49DFBDE2211FB8D0B137"><enum>(B)</enum><text>State;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1D2A97603EEF4087ADF1C827B7FE8542"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">occupation; including both the individual’s role in their public safety agency and their primary occupation in the case of volunteer public safety officers;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC8D6D91C814840498315F5A75AAD4022"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">where available, the status of the public safety officer as volunteer, paid-on-call, or career; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1088B24BC4074E8697E6DA1410AC857B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>status of the public safety officer as active or retired.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA055D54DD8BE4CD8AD60550E5E86FECD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation during development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the Public Safety Officer Suicide Reporting System, the Secretary shall consult with non-Federal experts to determine the best means to collect data regarding suicide incidence in a safe, sensitive, anonymous, and effective manner. Such non-Federal experts shall include, as appropriate, the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3A07FAED7EB94AD49E724CBF0077B6A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Public health experts with experience in developing and maintaining suicide registries.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H079A9C67473F4E9D9109FC3447D1D0ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Organizations that track suicide among public safety officers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEA2CC016F53447079A12E98E59D7185B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Mental health experts with experience in studying suicide and other profession-related traumatic stress.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFD52A36578544401BED009D3E53E1489"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Clinicians with experience in diagnosing and treating mental health issues.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H05ABB80477AD40AAAF78F2CDFA54479D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Active and retired volunteer, paid-on-call, and career public safety officers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7CC261022394599B02058F27F5B708C"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Relevant national police, and fire and emergency medical services, organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9FA2D191A52A428F8A68A4BAC61DDDFD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Data privacy and security</header><text>In developing and maintaining the Public Safety Officer Suicide Reporting System, the Secretary shall ensure that all applicable Federal privacy and security protections are followed to ensure that—</text> <paragraph id="H82E5A50C3AA4440296DAE196EDDFE1B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the confidentiality and anonymity of suicide victims and their families are protected, including so as to ensure that data cannot be used to deny benefits; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8E400D2C9E5646A99F483EB2A7632ABB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>data is sufficiently secure to prevent unauthorized access.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H350DDB39777C4A6896AB9D8E865ED1D1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting</header> <paragraph id="H9730495B5EB54E95B2FA5701D783DD56"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Helping Emergency Responders Overcome Act</short-title>, and biannually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Congress on the suicide incidence among public safety officers. Each such report shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF5780E5F894D4A2F94591187AD9AFB39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include the number and rate of such suicide incidence, disaggregated by age, gender, and State of employment;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H17E859FC0BD6454BB9AC51856EFC5EBE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify characteristics and contributing circumstances for suicide among public safety officers;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H318036277F00447EB85F7BE9490B8B7F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>disaggregate rates of suicide by—</text> <clause id="H18CBBE70C1E84AAB939A15AA28BA59C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>occupation;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7A36241B0C564C41A76DD2BCBFD66060"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>status as volunteer, paid-on-call, or career; and</text></clause> <clause id="H1DC47103BA914EEDA1F70EA85AF52098"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>status as active or retired;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEC7FE20E74994AA58A141F29A4338C11"><enum>(D)</enum><text>include recommendations for further study regarding the suicide incidence among public safety officers;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8A4EEF3A85E8407DAA6169366982D675"><enum>(E)</enum><text>specify in detail, if found, any obstacles in collecting suicide rates for volunteers and include recommended improvements to overcome such obstacles;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFE15621895A541FCA3D8E3C822C05EE3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>identify options for interventions to reduce suicide among public safety officers; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H56CF90861F76465FAEF18F29B0AFC238"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describe procedures to ensure the confidentiality and anonymity of suicide victims and their families, as described in subsection (d)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H012B3244BDB7466B9DB655523457496D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>Upon the submission of each report to the Congress under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall make the full report publicly available on the website of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0E8FD40A48224F4DAD627F170C5F3430"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>public safety officer</term> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0013FD311A044E5BB1E5957421695414"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a public safety officer, as defined in section 1204 of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC4916553C44D4DDFA9C0693F8DAE9ACC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a public safety telecommunicator, as described in detailed occupation 43–5031 in the Standard Occupational Classification Manual of the Office of Management and Budget (2018).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFBAABB9959904C218D8898DE094FC1F9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Prohibited use of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if an individual is identified as deceased based on information contained in the Public Safety Officer Suicide Reporting System, such information may not be used to deny or rescind life insurance payments or other benefits to a survivor of the deceased individual.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H4DFF7B7A62044785975AE16D865816A7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Peer-support behavioral health and wellness programs within fire departments and emergency medical service agencies</header> <subsection id="HECF9AF637AD341F38330C305AF069D72"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part B of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/243">42 U.S.C. 243 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HA1397A91293F4D10A8FD17AB077E3537" style="OLC"> 
<section commented="no" id="HA7FAD058B44246708E478F4AD4C00C74"><enum>320C.</enum><header>Peer-support behavioral health and wellness programs within fire departments and emergency medical service agencies</header> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H0EEA98C600914EC2B818C530C9C57ADD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may award grants to eligible entities for the purpose of establishing or enhancing peer-support behavioral health and wellness programs within fire departments and emergency medical services agencies.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H0AE5471B9694490E8B7FFCB1F748FD04"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program description</header><text>A peer-support behavioral health and wellness program funded under this section shall—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H0AA43F034CEA4212906ADA5DD3DA3C40"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use career and volunteer members of fire departments or emergency medical services agencies to serve as peer counselors;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HCC725CCC964741E1B3E69ACDE455D62F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide training to members of career, volunteer, and combination fire departments or emergency medical service agencies to serve as such peer counselors;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HB8FB281ABF124A99AA1EFE7E5F524D9C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>purchase materials to be used exclusively to provide such training; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HB8A4B4A5BC4A480AB9C2041A36D068B9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>disseminate such information and materials as are necessary to conduct the program.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H9CA4906C9C424B108585E791CBC3CC53"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HA830EF15E8B7454D80FF5B6165595C11"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a nonprofit organization with expertise and experience with respect to the health and life safety of members of fire and emergency medical services agencies.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA35CF1A12B2D4F619FF8D933F179071A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>member</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H5F9B5128A95D4EB993A49E0A49FD6A8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to an emergency medical services agency, means an employee, regardless of rank or whether the employee receives compensation (as defined in section 1204(7) of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H081CC8600F704D4DB48B6CC34D304955"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a fire department, means any employee, regardless of rank or whether the employee receives compensation, of a Federal, State, Tribal, or local fire department who is responsible for responding to calls for emergency service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H0A02E6F54EF44AE194D8A5BA64C9E6FD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical correction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective as if included in the enactment of the Children’s Health Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/310">Public Law 106–310</external-xref>), the amendment instruction in section 1603 of such Act is amended by striking <quote>Part B of the Public Health Service Act</quote> and inserting <quote>Part B of title III of the Public Health Service Act</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD4EF6FAB482249918A1F82F6267925B1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Health care provider behavioral health and wellness programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/243">42 U.S.C. 243 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by section 3, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3998D9EC7C124237913E9FC855892F28" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="HCFCCCC848E6849BBA3AE4C6C35AB6374"><enum>320D.</enum><header>Health care provider behavioral health and wellness programs</header> <subsection id="H1B827A491D314D8A896289E7F7EC7ECA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may award grants to eligible entities for the purpose of establishing or enhancing behavioral health and wellness programs for health care providers.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H16C3C5EF505047028877C28CB90C130E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program description</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A behavioral health and wellness program funded under this section shall—</text> <paragraph id="HAA1CA3F4DA0648009622D3B47C7DBED8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide confidential support services for health care providers to help handle stressful or traumatic patient-related events, including counseling services and wellness seminars; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7A8B504D1CA54A28ADB9426CAB3DEB8B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide training to health care providers to serve as peer counselors to other health care providers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H992D71268D9349CA8E5E09B585F53CAB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>purchase materials to be used exclusively to provide such training; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H471B4DBF30DD45E6AD271CD38589B7A2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>disseminate such information and materials as are necessary to conduct such training and provide such peer counseling.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0DA9E430D2A247B1819986D49DEFFDB1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means a hospital, including a critical access hospital (as defined in section 1861(mm)(1) of the Social Security Act) or a disproportionate share hospital (as defined in section 1923(a)(1)(A) of such Act), a Federally-qualified health center (as defined in section 1905(1)(2)(B) of such Act), or any other health care facility.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H576EB05E457A4D39B3DDD1F1FEAAE53E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Development of resources for educating mental health professionals about treating fire fighters and emergency medical services personnel</header> 
<subsection id="H084FF5A59C16466A9B4B7B76EE4419FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the United States Fire Administration, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall develop and make publicly available resources that may be used by the Federal Government and other entities to educate mental health professionals about—</text> <paragraph id="H8809545280A742A9BF47B2599A9EB9F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the culture of Federal, State, Tribal, and local career, volunteer, and combination fire departments and emergency medical services agencies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H65F1F56F11464883AA8A47FB0FFA0A31"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the different stressors experienced by firefighters and emergency medical services personnel, supervisory firefighters and emergency medical services personnel, and chief officers of fire departments and emergency medical services agencies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B96EDA77C71478D8DD622723DFCE309"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">challenges encountered by retired firefighters and emergency medical services personnel; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H232B6278AA9D44F69B23904F5DB52794"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evidence-based therapies for mental health issues common to firefighters and emergency medical services personnel within such departments and agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB68C607573834655A373D18762AD8B2A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing resources under subsection (a), the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration and the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall consult with national fire and emergency medical services organizations.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF82ED869639C4F36BE2F908F396EB909"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H06D9B76DEF2E44EF844AE3230978A16A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chief officer</header><text>The term <term>chief officer</term> means any individual who is responsible for the overall operation of a fire department or an emergency medical services agency, irrespective of whether such individual also serves as a firefighter or emergency medical services personnel.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4857CE27A6404828B388B67BCF231F0D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Emergency medical services personnel</header><text>The term <term>emergency medical services personnel</term> means any employee, regardless of rank or whether the employee receives compensation, as defined in section 1204(7) of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10284">34 U.S.C. 10284(7)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2639811FAD714772A1263982849B6AEA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Firefighter</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>firefighter</term> means any employee, regardless of rank or whether the employee receives compensation, of a Federal, State, Tribal, or local fire department who is responsible for responding to calls for emergency service.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H3581235E9E2549AFA72177EDB0594911"><enum>6.</enum><header>Best practices and other resources for addressing posttraumatic stress disorder in public safety officers</header> 
<subsection id="H3E560545485540F58C3F81B3B81164F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Development; updates</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall—</text> <paragraph id="HC2D56E8594C84D59AEB4088C7BBDB505"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop and assemble evidence-based best practices and other resources to identify, prevent, and treat posttraumatic stress disorder and co-occurring disorders in public safety officers; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCEE3A9EDD51348F0A76CE3699BF15014"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reassess and update, as the Secretary determines necessary, such best practices and resources, including based upon the options for interventions to reduce suicide among public safety officers identified in the annual reports required by section 317W(e)(1)(F) of the Public Health Service Act, as added by section 2 of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0098F9F9043B415DA7C33F1447B96FD3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing, assembling, and updating the best practices and resources under subsection (a), the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall consult with, at a minimum, the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H408DB48FE438412A94D31E75C5090DDF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Public health experts.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89E3A1ACA8174428B95FFACB9FB8150C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Mental health experts with experience in studying suicide and other profession-related traumatic stress.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF6BC0B68A8E14A50A1315CF6003FB6A5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Clinicians with experience in diagnosing and treating mental health issues.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73B62CBDC35F44419FD14A89E5CF7D6F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Relevant national police, fire, and emergency medical services organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H697EA81A63E243539085A0FD0417D910"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall make the best practices and resources under subsection (a) available to Federal, State, and local fire, law enforcement, and emergency medical services agencies.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H864DDB2FBADD46F39D5461AF9C66CA4E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Federal training and development programs</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall work with Federal departments and agencies, including the United States Fire Administration, to incorporate education and training on the best practices and resources under subsection (a) into Federal training and development programs for public safety officers.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE8FD599070AB41258BFB6846CC124C45"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>public safety officer</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="HC0AB0034273C4464A10725D9FEC27A13"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a public safety officer, as defined in section 1204 of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10284">34 U.S.C. 10284</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H377158A62EDB4073B564C6020804036E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a public safety telecommunicator, as described in detailed occupation 43–5031 in the Standard Occupational Classification Manual of the Office of Management and Budget (2018).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

