<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H91F530BAC6054906A450F1D889A9655C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5786 IH: White House National Official Trust: Forbidding Official Recognition, Sponsorships, Ads, Logos, and Endorsements Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5786</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251017">October 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the display of names at the White House without approval, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB7071587E04E485FBF94E7C5E9DA33F0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAFB1667F587542CDB55494C80A4FEE90" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>White House National Official Trust: Forbidding Official Recognition, Sponsorships, Ads, Logos, and Endorsements Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>White House NOT FOR SALE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3EB162424F4E439FAEFF1BE68078DB5D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on display of names at White House without approval</header> <subsection id="H655A9F53EFEF454095BBB5647568A5B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), a permanent or semi-permanent inscription, engraving, advertisement, or other display of the name of an individual, corporation, or other entity may only be exhibited or placed within the White House, on the White House Grounds, or within any structure on the White House Grounds with the express approval of the Speaker and the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives and the Curator of the White House, in consultation with the Committee for the Preservation of the White House.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA9D0C10500E345EA956B79FE9177FDFD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Commemorative Works Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/89">Chapter 89</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Commemorative Works Act</quote>), shall apply to an inscription, engraving, advertisement, or other display described in subsection (a) that meets the criteria for a <quote>commemorative work</quote> under section 8902 of such chapter.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

