<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H453A28850B5F4FD5AB0B22ADC773AF4D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5793 IH: Eastern Flank Strategic Partnership Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5793</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251017">October 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To strengthen strategic defense cooperation between the United States and NATO allies on the Eastern Flank, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H27AC202DA8C4460A83EB533330CBB9A9" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H700FD72D611141AE8FAC340DBAAED332"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Eastern Flank Strategic Partnership Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H237DA7173F1443D990FEBC0F772B934E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="HCA0FA51AFF464835A8D187719A7DA70C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The frontline North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) allies of Bulgaria, Estonia, Finland, Hungary, Latvia, Lithuania, Poland, Romania, and Slovakia play a critical role in regional and transatlantic security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD5221F09C6AE448EAA83FE522F96CCD4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Those NATO allies have demonstrated consistent commitments to NATO defense spending targets, support for Ukraine, and forward deployments to deter Russian aggression.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H544F847D64454596B2C6E3A15E8A82B3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Those NATO allies are on the front line of deterring and defending against threats from Russia and Belarus, and require continued United States coordination, defense cooperation, and security assistance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCCF246E24E7A470F81CD015543CC44E6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Ukraine is on the front line of United States and NATO security, fighting to defend itself against Russian aggression that could also be turned upon those same NATO allies.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9EB65A94DBC44BDFB0067791E9E9A3D0" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The United States possesses existing authorities and tools, including assistance under the Foreign Military Financing program under section 23 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2763">22 U.S.C. 2763</external-xref>), assistance under section 333 of title 10, United States Code, transfer of excess defense articles under section 516 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321j">22 U.S.C. 2321j</external-xref>), and the War Reserve Stocks for Allies program administered under section 514 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321h">22 U.S.C. 2321h</external-xref>), that can be used to enhance resilience, logistics, and interoperability with those NATO allies.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HBB582D624C4E453E95190D09FC3F1849" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3940E1324B69476497E72AD62B2045C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3926BEAFC4484DD8A3B2E53C700302B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF2F70D8A5E8145E6BEA3849FA5802703"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0CF1C3B0A3E94F8CAFB917587FD536E7"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eastern Flank strategic defense partner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Eastern Flank strategic defense partner</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F8CEFA069E94B2F9F3E8F666DBAD9C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a NATO member state that—</text> <clause id="H41F7280AEA9E44CFB5EAC7AF718B81EA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shares a border with, or is in direct geographic proximity to, the Russian Federation, the Republic of Belarus, or Ukraine, and plays a role in the defense of NATO’s Eastern Flank due to its geographic proximity to those countries;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H992679B7337E4BFDB62131D1C91A9B94"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has committed to allocating 5 percent of its gross domestic product annually to defense by 2035, including at least 3.5 percent for meeting core defense requirements and NATO capability targets and 1.5 percent for other defense- and security-related investments;</text></clause> <clause id="HC872CDEEFC8F4D09A293248251E452FC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>hosts or supports the forward deployment of NATO military forces, including rotational deployments; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5C3E597FCCB344C3B4DA4D2F9C124B4E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>faces persistent threats from hostile state actors; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFDF369D1DF7F4131875F04FD8C6C9BD5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes Bulgaria, Estonia, Finland, Hungary, Latvia, Lithuania, Poland, Romania, and Slovakia.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HF801903F349A4477BD71324326B3C38B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Policy and priority for strategic defense cooperation</header> 
<subsection id="H0028DE3E67DC45BEB7CCAC2421C88178"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H498C71EA9EEB49898A330E351068D779"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to recognize the critical role of Eastern Flank strategic defense partners in defending NATO’s Eastern Flank, deterring aggression from hostile state actors, and advancing transatlantic security;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF235B897FD734A74B7FCDC843515A39F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to prioritize cooperation with Eastern Flank strategic defense partners in the implementation of defense cooperation authorities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9420746875C1459781587AF17B5DD1D1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to treat Eastern Flank strategic defense partners as priority recipients of security assistance under security assistance authorities; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H31D9EA63B7D84E50BBFEFDA29EA64625"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to support Ukraine, including with the security assistance necessary to deter Russian aggression against allies along NATO’s Eastern Flank.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA9AA4CAF0ECE4DAFB482DCC6275EFDBF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Defense shall, as appropriate and consistent with law, give priority to Eastern Flank strategic defense partners for the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9E30BC1C61EE4D149512150923636556"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Assistance under the Foreign Military Financing program under section 23 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2763">22 U.S.C. 2763</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA598216E9FC4389A87965603A434384"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Assistance under section 333 of title 10, United States Code (relating to authority to build the capacity of foreign security forces).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB40EC4CCC03F46B0BD75F5CFB3D2D733"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Transfer of excess defense articles under section 516 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321j">22 U.S.C. 2321j</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCAEE2833107340B1B2D8C6E1CB3480C1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Participation in bilateral and multilateral military exercises, interoperability training, logistics, and forward mobility planning.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H850D3FFFDA394F5A9928BD755AA2B6C3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The policy established by subsection (a) and the priority established by subsection (b) shall be implemented to reinforce bilateral defense cooperation arrangements, including defense cooperation agreements, status of forces agreements, and other bilateral or multilateral agreements.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H3DFA24D910334D12BA0232B33256B247"><enum>5.</enum><header>Stockpiling and pre-positioning of defense articles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Consistent with operational requirements and in consultation with NATO allies, and with the goal of increasing regional deterrence and reducing strategic response time, the Secretary of Defense shall—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94EFC01EC6DE414B89F7F4163E9DF382"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prioritize Eastern Flank strategic defense partners under the War Reserve Stocks for Allies program administered under section 514 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321h">22 U.S.C. 2321h</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC9C726FB28264BA78C8BBA9AAA54FF3A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider expanding stockpiles under such program in additional Eastern Flank strategic defense partner countries, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HA3D38742260F41449E8E5A7122E48364"><enum>6.</enum><header>Congressional briefing</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall brief the appropriate congressional committees on the implementation of sections 3 and 4, including timelines, goals, and cooperative mechanisms.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

