<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG25E08-0XH-HR-4WJ">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2501 IS: Veterans Scam And Fraud Evasion Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2501</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250729">July 29, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr.
                    Boozman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>)
                introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the
                    <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans'
                    Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to establish in the Department of
            Veterans Affairs a Veterans Scam and Fraud Evasion Officer, and for other
            purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Scam And Fraud Evasion Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>VSAFE Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="H1694F42E8D274C7E94679EFC1A449D20">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Veterans Scam and Fraud Evasion Officer</header>
            <subsection id="H09E7E8EFC1984C218D799140AC618ACC">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/3">Chapter 3</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
                <quoted-block style="USC" id="HB13BADBF9E174C14BE7680010A1EF68D" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <section id="HB38440E0AA33472AADD5F5189A83DC7A">
                        <enum>325.</enum>
                        <header>Veterans Scam and Fraud Evasion Officer</header>
                        <subsection id="H12577F585645499D8F16CBF042CA8192">
                            <enum>(a)</enum>
                            <header>Establishment</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is in the Department a Veterans Scam and Fraud Evasion Officer, who shall—</text>
                            <paragraph id="HE11037829FDB41C2AFC2D3594A845F2C">
                                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>be responsible for fraud and scam prevention, reporting, and incident response plans at the Department; and</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H324518BEC677407D91332275997FE48C">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>serve as a central point of contact to direct veterans to resources to prevent and mitigate fraud and scams.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="HF53CDE30B560463986B9C5826728E4CF">
                            <enum>(b)</enum>
                            <header>Responsibilities</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Veterans Scam and Fraud Evasion Officer shall carry out the following responsibilities:</text>
                            <paragraph id="H124CE26532F7404597ABC70497FE490F">
                                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing comprehensive communication from the Secretary to employees of the Department and veterans, their families, caregivers, and survivors during strategic and time-sensitive fraud and scam incidents.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H37AA978D89554AC185B113160C0B5D72">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Establishing consistent guidance across the enterprise for employees as well as veterans, their families, caregivers, and survivors on how to identify, report, and avoid fraud and scam attempts.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="HFA087C6C07F542298B748D11D3697201">
                                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>Promoting the VSAFE Fraud Hotline and VSAFE.gov website of the Department (and any successor resources) and identifying other identity theft resources available to veterans, their families, caregivers, and survivors, including with respect to actions made by the Secretary to protect the identities of veterans and their beneficiaries.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H26C19F3AD243405B860A0B4EE6AAB13E">
                                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>Developing methods to monitor fraud and scam metrics within the Department—</text>
                                <subparagraph id="H2F1D04BEA38D4248A6FB341E20779E73">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>to provide internal and external reporting;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7E6A2435637A430B9B8E639535B8C965"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>to enable advanced data analytics; and</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H3E85DA0C31DE49E098447867E6F1F66F">
                                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>to facilitate proactive and robust fraud and scam trend identification.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H68E61C7C6E894DDE8F9D8B6686B7DCE8">
                                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>Developing comprehensive training plans for Department employees fielding fraud and scam inquiries and reports.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="HAB17775744484F128FDF9719AF618EEF">
                                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>Coordinating with the Inspector General of the Department and other Federal departments and agencies, including the Executive Office of the President, the Office of Management and Budget, the Internal Revenue Service, the Department of Justice, the Department of State, the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, the Department of Defense, the Department of Education, the Social Security Administration, and other relevant agencies—</text>
                                <subparagraph id="H92AE7211F7624DFA89D54FEEB1698EEF">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>to develop a whole-of-government view within the Department to improve fraud prevention efforts within the Department;</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="HE28E5E74510F4ACEB9C8D616854E0B07">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>to identify the proper avenues for veterans to report fraud attempts and receive assistance; and</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="HD96C514CB63D4901A00DB2A76BE882DF">
                                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>to identify opportunities for coordination with such departments and agencies.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H0205E59843654454B12DA36E727304E7">
                                <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>Consulting with veterans service organizations and State, local, and tribal governments, as necessary, to improve understanding of potential fraud and scam risks to veterans.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="HC1C5A3396436427B835E624E4EFEF6C9">
                            <enum>(c)</enum>
                            <header>Full-Time employees</header>
 <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize an increase in the number of full-time employees otherwise authorized for the Department.</text>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="HE3F1BDB070CD4E94856F5E26ED37F8E0">
                            <enum>(d)</enum>
                            <header>Rule of construction</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Office of Inspector General of the Department as otherwise provided in this title or in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/4">chapter 4</external-xref> of title 5 (commonly referred to as the Inspector General Act of 1978).</text>
                        </subsection>
                    </section>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HE9AF11DE462344F490DF3B5108EC2402">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Clerical amendment</header>
 <text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
                <quoted-block style="USC" id="H0E9C0E4D68F147CB82173C6499313706" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
                        <toc-entry level="section">325. Veterans Scam and Fraud Evasion
                            Officer.</toc-entry>
                    </toc>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="H81C927C12AEA4032822A3690E68DAEB3">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Extension of certain limits on payments of pension</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5503(d)(7) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>November 30, 2031</quote> and inserting <quote>January 30, 2032</quote>.</text>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

