<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFEC41CD45C0647AAB78131C9A32120DE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5794 IH: FEMA Operations Continuity Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5794</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251021">October 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to continue disaster relief, recovery, and mitigation operations funded through the Disaster Relief Fund in the event of a lapse in appropriations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H051D28BD71A846D8AE3ECC88602808B7" style="OLC">
<section id="HD8F99D8A73414897B153147A42EB6883" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>FEMA Operations Continuity Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE16CCF9E350F41268078688EC6BDB89F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Continuation of FEMA operations during a lapse in appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in the event of a lapse in appropriations, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall be authorized to—</text>
<paragraph id="HC7052B8A48594C09B145435DD1EAA0BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>continue all disaster relief, recovery, and mitigation operations funded through the Disaster Relief Fund;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA512573418D84ED3BF17FCD0C9F47403"><enum>(2)</enum><text>obligate and disburse Disaster Relief Fund balances for all existing and future disaster declarations, including individual and public assistance under sections 403, 406, 407, 408, and 502 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170b">42 U.S.C. 5170b</external-xref>, 5172, 5173, 5174, and 5192); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEC8CC2EEE5D74AF1832F7757C3CEFC36"><enum>(3)</enum><text>maintain personnel and contract support necessary to ensure uninterrupted processing of claims and payments.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H2182D1C0691C4333AD7EFB3AEFB86FC5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Use of Disaster Relief Fund</header> <subsection id="H4CAA43EF07684B37B71B843CB747A710"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All unobligated balances in the Disaster Relief Fund shall remain available to the Administrator for expenditure during a lapse in appropriations.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HFC76B71881BE40BB90C7D0C004F7AEA2">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Prohibition on diversion</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds from the Disaster Relief Fund may be withheld, sequestered, or reprogrammed during a lapse in appropriations, except as necessary to comply with section 1341 of title 31, United States Code (commonly referred to as the ‘Anti-Deficiency Act’).</text>
            </subsection></section>
<section id="H1DF55BCB7EAB452D975CA260067BBA31"><enum>4.</enum><header>Exception from government shutdown restrictions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of section 1341 of title 31, United States Code (commonly referred to as the ‘Anti-Deficiency Act’), operations of the Federal Emergency Management Agency authorized under this Act shall be considered essential to protect human life and property, and therefore exempt from shutdown restrictions.</text> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

