<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25132-8GG-7C-CJN"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S604 IS: Safe Home Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 604</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250213">February 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the adoption opportunities program to define unregulated custody transfers of children and to improve awareness and prevention of such transfers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H66B5907C33EE4931BA0E59CBCEA195C5"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe Home Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id5b64f3d6-4842-4f23-b18f-741d0e232dff" changed="not-changed"><enum>2</enum><header>Unregulated custody transfers</header><subsection changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf609e08a8ca845b08dc91f086d40c765"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title II of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment and Adoption Reform Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5111">42 U.S.C. 5111 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id847d6a2c-f858-4ed4-bf53-cb66725394b1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 205 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5115">42 U.S.C. 5115</external-xref>) as section 206; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id076cf62d-f848-4561-a396-066669f1d40d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 204 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc66f8eef-16e5-44b5-b746-76bf0d0d84ba" changed="not-changed"><section id="id7a838b31-ae17-4bcb-8b1e-922692734552" changed="not-changed"><enum>205.</enum><header>Sense of Congress, technical assistance, and report on unregulated custody transfers</header><subsection id="idaf743098-96ef-43ed-a675-91b3f3309b34" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="id9fa900fa-97af-49d5-bef3-88eb798cbf60" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>there are challenges associated with some adoptions (including the child’s mental health needs and the difficulties many families face in accessing support services) and some families may seek out an unregulated transfer of physical custody of an adoptive child without any formal supervision by child welfare agencies or courts; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2876c2c8-1ead-4564-9364-afaeca1967ba" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>some adopted children experience trauma, and the disruption and placement in another home due to such a transfer may contribute to additional trauma and instability for such children;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7261aa12-705b-4fb3-a611-0145bdefcc35" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>unregulated custody transfers may not include certain safety measures that are required as part of formal adoption proceedings, such as required child welfare or criminal background checks or clearances;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9d3ed4c8-4f27-4970-b442-a647b4fe4435" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>child welfare agencies and courts may be unaware of the placement of children through unregulated custody transfers and, as a result, may not conduct assessments on children’s safety and well-being in such subsequent placements;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcd5c110e-ba10-4a6d-bdd5-e372c6015231" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the lack of such assessments may result in the placement of children in homes in which the children may be exposed to unsafe environments;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8ec67ef2-ec76-4296-93bf-8a654d0b4575" changed="not-changed"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the caregivers with whom a child is placed through an unregulated custody transfer may have no legal responsibility with respect to such child and may not have complete records, including the child’s birth, medical, or other records, with respect to such child;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id79d6ee73-f8d6-4d00-9728-506e1c5fa1e2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a child adopted through intercountry adoption may be at risk of not acquiring United States citizenship if an unregulated custody transfer occurs before the adoptive parents complete all necessary steps to finalize the adoption of such child; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9b533788-205f-43f4-8c15-805c85690365" commented="no" changed="not-changed"><enum>(8)</enum><text>unregulated custody transfers pose significant challenges for children who experience such transfers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9d15e909b70e4e089079cc45199e0672" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For the purpose of this section, the term <term>unregulated custody transfer</term>—</text><paragraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id71bc43f351704498a94ea57f55465a33"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means the abandonment of a child, by the child’s parent or legal guardian, or a person or entity acting on behalf, and with the consent, of such parent or guardian—</text><subparagraph id="idf27dfceef62e420ba86d3658c67a696d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by placing the child with a person who is not—</text><clause id="id61cb707b1fd24baea893b2493a8632db" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the child’s parent, stepparent, grandparent, adult sibling, legal guardian, or other adult relative;</text></clause><clause id="id6ed462a0c64d4467b0d3c09044704e80" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a friend of the family who is an adult and with whom the child is familiar; or</text></clause><clause id="id06a9dab5528e4e2a97698b3cf66a4c8b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a member of the federally recognized Indian Tribe of which the child is also a member or eligible to be a member;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6d2bdf1a9467434ab9866347ba290370" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with the intent of severing the relationship between the child and the parent or guardian of such child; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id65c792e46d5e4fb887029f7516238a45" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>without—</text><clause id="id293d71940c7d4a6ea455d779beb66697" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reasonably ensuring the safety of the child and permanency of the placement of the child, including by conducting an official home study, background check, and supervision; and</text></clause><clause id="idaf3216591ff647d0b977fd8f39bb6f52" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>transferring the legal rights and responsibilities of parenthood or guardianship under applicable Federal and State law to a person described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) of subparagraph (A); and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id523b6afee989480785ccdc1990a9ac65"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not include the surrender of an infant to a safe haven by the parent or guardian of such infant, if such surrender is consistent with the safe haven law of the applicable State. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddbf92f7a-2f9f-4e05-85af-0a86a2cb7ce4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical assistance and public awareness</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies—</text><paragraph id="id2aaacfae-f751-4871-8359-4d4a6bfdc1e5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall improve public awareness related to preventing adoption disruption and dissolution, including preventing unregulated custody transfers of adopted children; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaedbe90c-24bd-45d6-8db4-5d99f6189334" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in carrying out paragraph (1), shall update Federal resources, including internet websites, to provide—</text><subparagraph id="id1e08fed7-db06-4d3e-a986-eebd9a650e94" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>employees of State, local, and Tribal agencies that provide child welfare services with education materials related to preventing, identifying, and responding to unregulated custody transfers, including such materials containing information on adoption support and stability services for adoptive families and prospective adoptive families; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5fd79f0b-dea6-4056-8d13-6b08eaf685f1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prospective adoptive families with information on accessing pre-adoption education and post-adoption services from State, local, and private resources to promote child permanency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id54001e62-56e4-4c3e-8abb-3888b158aa72" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><paragraph id="idcdc21a57-30dd-41a1-ada7-ac89f9f7b923" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Safe Home Act of 2025</short-title>, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions and the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Education and Workforce and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives a report on unregulated custody transfers of children, including of adopted children.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id90ad0027-856a-4540-8e1d-174a55c28384" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="idf1de302d-f419-468d-bc34-0372fe5594a5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information on the causes, methods, and characteristics of unregulated custody transfers, including the use of social media and the internet;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8df1b3b8-ada2-470b-8c1d-cddc35e32b3c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information on the effects of unregulated custody transfer on children, including the effects of the lack of assessment of a child’s safety and well-being by social services agencies and courts due to such unregulated custody transfer;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcf6b7ccd-90ab-42a2-92d4-1b46a664a7ca" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>data on the prevalence of unregulated custody transfers within each State and across all States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id390763b1-4749-4a02-b769-521d108fd072" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommended policies for preventing, identifying, and responding to unregulated custody transfers, including of adopted children, that include—</text><clause id="id5ff56bee-563d-41e3-aa2f-f1bd50563d83" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>suggested changes or updates to Federal and State law to address unregulated custody transfers;</text></clause><clause id="id8c422312-1e0f-4fcb-95dd-d1727dd870e0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>suggested changes or updates to child protection practices to address unregulated custody transfers; and</text></clause><clause id="id4854e1c4-b168-48cc-bfdf-00606de0d344" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>methods of providing to the public information regarding adoption and child protection; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id236810e827eb43b48742bfbb596029ec" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of the activities carried out under subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10146f2b63ea461098e4cf67a42e80fa"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 203(d)(3)(A) of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment and Adoption Reform Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5113">42 U.S.C. 5113(d)(3)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 205(a)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 206(a)</quote>.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

