<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4A66ADC7DED0476F9039E9AC1B21DE36" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1911 IH: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide that certain payments to foreign related parties subject to sufficient foreign tax are not treated as base erosion payments.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1911</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250306">March 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001136">Mr. Conaway</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide that certain payments to foreign related parties subject to sufficient foreign tax are not treated as base erosion payments.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H60FA16A15467442EBB822D804F9910FC" style="OLC"><section id="H261D3153F382425B9138F1ECDB434AAB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Certain payments to foreign related parties subject to sufficient foreign tax not treated as base erosion payments</header><subsection id="H80EFEBE711684767B06CB9169E51C686"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/59A">Section 59A</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating subsection (i) as subsection (j) and by inserting after subsection (h) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA44A1DF538C2427CA3CAF0304392BEE1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HDFFAC5D6AD504273912A33F9FBAC9AF1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Certain payments to foreign related parties subject to sufficient foreign tax not treated as base erosion payments</header><paragraph id="H4517299C33834F41AFCF5A32971F2281"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An amount shall not be treated as a base erosion payment if the taxpayer establishes to the satisfaction of the Secretary that—</text><subparagraph id="H9590915ED0764DD3B97D58A4E1B793AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the foreign person to whom such amount is paid or incurred is subject to an effective rate of foreign income tax of at least 15 percent, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADE447334804465CB307DD8447EB0211"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such amount is subject to an effective rate of foreign income tax of at least 15 percent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H75031F0BACDC4A79AFEDCC24302C3703"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of effective rate on basis of applicable financial statements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, the effective rate of foreign income tax may be established on the basis of applicable financial statements (as defined in section 451(b)(3)) with appropriate adjustments (as determined by the Secretary) for excluded dividends, net tax expense, excluded equity gain or loss, included revaluation method gain or loss, gain or loss from intragroup transfers of assets and liabilities, asymmetric foreign currency gains or losses, bribes, illegal payments, large penalties, prior period errors and changes in accounting methods, accrued pension expenses, and such other items as the Secretary may provide.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8A1D1F384CA492E86177975925DE8C5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign income tax</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term “foreign income taxes” means any income, war profits, or excess profits taxes paid or accrued to any foreign country or to any possession of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HDB7641B65EB54C7A814E50808BAA5E50"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Section 59A(j) of such Code, as redesignated by subsection (a), is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (1), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (2) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H55E480D6F6474BFB8A10742BD11FA1AA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H67CA2B39EC724000B5B04002B5F03F3B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the application of subsection (i), including—</text><subparagraph id="HF16663B69D6F4B0B8A0D0C61AFC6CFB1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>procedures for determining the effective rate of foreign income tax, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF425E843B09A41CBB476E35E4E559ACB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rules to the prevent tax avoidance or abuse, including rules for recharacterizing a transaction or series of transactions among related parties.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HCB3263AC657842D7BF88EFFBC74AFA9A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

