<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H629D0D26679A4B6C93761DF89EFD6683" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3012 IH: Improving Reentry for District of Columbia Residents in the Bureau of Prisons Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3012</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250424">April 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to place certain individuals in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons within 250 miles of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H34A234F8BEE2406E820EA52C2B438FE6" style="OLC"><section id="H5592E9B1BEF7480B92A3744DCA5C9906" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Reentry for District of Columbia Residents in the Bureau of Prisons Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H057D11E3488D474D9F6A08FEAB80B083"><enum>2.</enum><header>Placement near District of Columbia for certain individuals in custody of Bureau of Prisons</header><subsection id="HDC4454D6310A40FCB89AEFFAC21E78D3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than two years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall not place a covered individual in a Bureau of Prisons facility that is located more than 250 miles from the District of Columbia, unless such individual requests or consents to such a placement. </text></subsection><subsection id="H62E25A3EE9F54396A83056F2450F50A2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Extraordinary circumstances</header><paragraph id="HE2B24646A89243B3963B4131CD91F0ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (a), the Director may place a covered individual in a Bureau of Prisons facility that is more than 250 miles from the District of Columbia if the Director determines that extraordinary circumstances warrant such a placement. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H925ACAD94C98487E90C01F6290BFF144"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not longer than 30 days after a placement under paragraph (1), the Director shall provide a written explanation to the covered congressional committees on the extraordinary circumstances warranting such a placement.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF0005E7EF0484598B825D9412537B623"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be constructed to prohibit the Director from placing a covered individual in prerelease custody pursuant to section 3624(g)(2) of title 18, United States Code, or on transferring an individual to begin a term of supervised release pursuant to section 3624(g)(3) of title 18, United States Code. </text></subsection><subsection id="HEFAB2EB044BF4EB1817ACA114E054198"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H72FA5D0B78124AE2901199598A07EC97"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered Congressional Committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered congressional committees</term> means the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDC4D245926B4F279F536B9CE0D4CF94"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered individual</header><text>The term <term>covered individual</term> means an individual committed to the custody of the Bureau of Prisons pursuant to chapter 1 of subtitle C of title XI of the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997 (sec. 24–101 et seq., D.C. Official Code) who is a resident of the District of Columbia at the time at which the individual was sentenced. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

