<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE682FB6DE6334173BA8B5D29BB57D752" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5002 IH: Protect Americans from Climate Disasters Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5002</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250819">August 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001094">Ms. Hoyle of Oregon</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reinstate all employees and programs at the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration that help communities prepare for and mitigate damage from extreme weather events.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBBD07BCAF97047AFB85760EE1690BA4E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD0027F5A41CF4043AE3D779BD80848D8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Americans from Climate Disasters Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2BFBBE63332740878756615669EADC3F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF949FD9B54524EF4BF4F62E7D0E15F2B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Fifth United States National Climate Assessment reported that human-caused climate variability such as extended droughts, longer wildfire seasons, heavy rainfall, and sea level rise affects the frequency and intensity of extreme weather events.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCA3424EC27934BD29F95137B744437CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), the number and cost of extreme weather and climate disasters have increased over time and will continue to increase in the United States due to climate change, increased urbanization, and development in weather prone areas.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H61E8BB4AEF54493F8EE23923EB57C789"><enum>(3)</enum><text>According to the National Centers for Environmental Information, from 2020 to 2024 alone, weather and climate disasters cost the United States over $746,700,000,000 and led to 2,520 deaths.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H539DD792A2BF493E8B79B76E48539F7E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Americans rely on weather information provided by NOAA every day for emergency disaster alerts, forecasting, data collection, and more.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA0FEA42085A643718503260CE2743427"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Staffing reductions at the National Weather Service and NOAA have resulted in decreased capacity to forecast extreme weather events, the elimination of some products and services, and the deterioration of environmental scientific research, which poses a threat to public safety.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC7ED992D79C74BDBB44D1B0A2B2BBCDE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The 5 former living National Weather Service leaders wrote an open letter expressing their deep concern that the staff and program cuts at NOAA may result in the loss of life.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2E94845014F456092D18BD7ABB79CFE"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">NOAA’s Billion-Dollar Weather and Climate Disasters product has been eliminated, reducing publicly available data that tracked the economic impact of United States weather and climate trends since 1980.</text></paragraph> </section> <section id="HE833CF2A10E44C60A1CE1239E3656880"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>NOAA</quote> means the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text> </section> 
<section id="H56047CA33E1545009011A7A297D43A8B"><enum>4.</enum><header>NOAA staffing and personnel</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, using funds previously appropriated for such purposes, the Secretary of Commerce shall—</text> <paragraph id="HFF878A7EEC0B43F596E4C895FB2A9D0B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>take such actions as are necessary to ensure that NOAA, including the National Weather Service, is fully staffed to ensure timely and accurate data, forecasts, weather alerts, and resiliency resources are available to prepare for extreme weather events; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8C2B3E88E67346DE9976FDCA4C1B25FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reinstate any individuals who—</text> <subparagraph id="H30FC562454AC483BB5C5686C6B13E7D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>were involuntarily removed or otherwise terminated from employment with NOAA during the period beginning on January 20, 2025, and ending on the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6B6B2C8047EE4C2AA2DD7E62FDAA8AA6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>elect to be reinstated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H108F92CF472040A7B2BF0C476F7EFF70"><enum>5.</enum><header>Continuation of authorized NOAA programs</header> <subsection id="H371FBB688E114C70BE9C529150D17C8E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE53DEF91C728409A86A8AE5329DDADAC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall continue to carry out any programs for which funds have been appropriated that support State and local efforts to prepare for and respond to extreme weather events; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6AA10EFDFDF3491981F9B169A7CCC0A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may not make any changes to existing congressionally mandated programs that will reduce access to extreme weather resources.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCC58DABED9934955A81E5CFC88B33329"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Actions required</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="H2545CF77BD254FF9B738D09F55EEEF0D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Commerce shall immediately reinstate the Billion-Dollar Weather and Climate Disasters product and carry out any project for which funds have been made available under such program;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H67CFB655C6CD42C0A37BAC81DE9276F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Commerce shall immediately reinstate the NOAA Marine Environmental Buoy Database and carry out any project for which funds have been made available under such program; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9105908B1D148C088D465EFB816469D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Commerce shall immediately reinstate the NOAA Global Ocean Currents Database and carry out any project for which funds have been made available under such program.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H3DC2D9C97719412AACC8836045B2198E"><enum>6.</enum><header>National Oceanic And Atmospheric Administration funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is appropriated to the Department of Commerce, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the fiscal year ending on September 30, 2026, $6,756,300,000 for the necessary expenses of National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

