<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-GOE25118-Y42-09-MSR"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S750 IS: Protecting Rural Seniors’ Access to Care Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 750</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250226">February 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit the Secretary of Health and Human Services from implementing, enforcing, or otherwise giving effect to a final rule regarding minimum staffing for nursing facilities, and to establish an advisory panel on the nursing home workforce.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HD903691106B041F4B15F947D2DCB017D"><section section-type="section-one" id="HE79D339485064A0FBFBD1FF553AC2E20"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Rural Seniors’ Access to Care Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC27EBC7A59DB41208F880B80188D0AEC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on implementing, enforcing, or otherwise giving effect to the final staffing rule</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services may not implement, enforce, or otherwise give effect to the final rule entitled <quote>Medicare and Medicaid Programs; Minimum Staffing Standards for Long-Term Care Facilities and Medicaid Institutional Payment Transparency Reporting</quote> published by the Department of Health and Human Services on May 10, 2024 (89 Fed. Reg. 40976–41000), and may not promulgate any substantially similar rule.</text></section><section id="HFC81CDD677A24F27B285B4F353A87863"><enum>3.</enum><header>Advisory panel on nursing home workforce</header><subsection id="HCAA3E452220645EEBAB9AA066DAA21A0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall establish the Advisory Panel on the Nursing Home Workforce (in this section referred to as the <quote>Panel</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HAAE3CE7C1ACD43EDABC3B532E3AD2B32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="H7555442E9EF44D6DB6D70276155032E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Number and appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Panel shall be composed of 17 members representing various geographic areas, appointed by the Secretary as follows:</text><subparagraph id="HA47FBF33095B42D985C05040689C01BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>1 representative of the Secretary, who shall serve as the chair of the Panel.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25DB4496E5F5413EBEC3A2639A14A8F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>2 registered nurses who actively furnish services in a skilled nursing facility or nursing facility, one of whom shall represent a rural area.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58DA11D1BD3142348C4BA60AF8E7FD95"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 licensed professional nurses who actively furnish services in a skilled nursing facility or nursing facility, one of whom shall represent a rural area.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD3C10306D764B0AAF55067C5BC4355D"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 nurse aides who actively furnish services in a skilled nursing facility or nursing facility, one of whom shall represent a rural area.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96F7463D85F040CD9662CA793C5FF849"><enum>(E)</enum><text>2 physicians who actively furnish services in a skilled nursing facility or nursing facility, one of whom shall represent a rural area.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19EB79CAC8EA40D0ABC81472C9064D5D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>1 representative of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF97C0662DA440BF8189EF412654930A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>1 representative of the Health Resources and Services Administration.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H797614F5E92041B3A334BDA69B5709B3"><enum>(H)</enum><text>2 individuals with professional expertise related to the nursing home workforce, one of whom shall have experience with respect to the nursing home workforce in rural and underserved areas.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA03AD5F3096D4D8B87CC525CCCAAEAF0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>1 licensed administrator or representative of a rural not-for-profit skilled nursing facility. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43C91C46DA1C4F06B1FB3407350ECB92"><enum>(J)</enum><text>1 licensed administrator or representative of a rural for-profit skilled nursing facility.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida8fe214e543142c9af980c91703697a4"><enum>(K)</enum><text>2 representatives of State boards of nursing. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A618A1BC92B4BEA9F896C12D01BB561"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing of appointments</header><text>Each of the appointments under <internal-xref idref="H7555442E9EF44D6DB6D70276155032E9" legis-path="4.(b)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref> shall be made not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3527862F2374CE0A8075B2B6E33B2A2" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Terms; vacancies</header><text>Each member shall be appointed for a term not to exceed 2 years, and a vacancy in the Panel shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06A8537BAA8C4EAE8892A8B29E197659" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>13 members of the Panel shall constitute a quorum.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6FD75A8A84C494099CF53FE8357055B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Federal Advisory Committee Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall apply to the Panel.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H869F0321C2DA4A08B56C800A6B7B1B24"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><paragraph id="HE126B973BBF145FEA469B9C2990E42AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Meetings</header><subparagraph id="H188CB935AB9040CEBD260FEBE5168EE5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Panel shall meet not later than 180 days after the date on which the appointments described in <internal-xref idref="HAAE3CE7C1ACD43EDABC3B532E3AD2B32" legis-path="4.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref> are made, and not less frequently than twice per year thereafter.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BBA5E4E61EC4D9DA3F60940118C5088" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public access</header><text>The Panel shall make available on a public website of the Department of Health and Human Services—</text><clause id="H1710F51FF6134290950F5646A9BFFE8F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>real-time virtual access to each meeting of the Panel; and</text></clause><clause id="H34C8D2390FB04E55849A9696FCDF34CC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after each such meeting, a recording and transcript of the meeting.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2A7C9BB483C4167A98E286B856BFF8B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports</header><subparagraph id="H4D9DAAB8A6674ABF94C55A7F5915A7DD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the initial meeting of the Panel under <internal-xref idref="H188CB935AB9040CEBD260FEBE5168EE5" legis-path="4.(c)(1)(A)">paragraph (1)(A)</internal-xref>, the Panel shall submit to the Secretary, the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Finance of the Senate, and shall publish on a public website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, a report on the state of the nursing home workforce, which shall include—</text><clause id="H323BA5DDEC954D798172AE27555AC445"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the state of the nursing home workforce in rural and underserved areas, including an analysis of—</text><subclause id="H137CB5939DDD4159AB9C5773F36FA29E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>workforce shortages; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H460FD1D199364669AA0479E10828E3AD"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to individuals entitled to benefits under part A of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>) and individuals entitled to medical assistance under title XIX of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>), barriers to access to skilled nursing facilities and nursing facilities caused by such shortages;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF54D9C081B6D45BA85E8627B0D0C7CF0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an analysis of regulations, sub-regulatory guidance, and guidance to State survey agencies issued by the Secretary with respect to skilled nursing facilities and nursing facilities, and the effects of such regulations and guidance on the nursing home workforce;</text></clause><clause id="H7C8CD106C7164959B89E919F496A1A1A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>recommendations for the Secretary to strengthen the nursing home workforce, including recommendations for decreasing regulatory burdens for skilled nursing facilities and nursing facilities and making financial investments in training for health professionals; and</text></clause><clause id="HFE44C66EDAFB494BA87DE951FFA4D0F5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>other information as the Panel determines necessary.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H044E565F3FD74971BA84C46A0F2A868E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subsequent reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after submitting the initial report under <internal-xref idref="H4D9DAAB8A6674ABF94C55A7F5915A7DD" legis-path="4.(c)(2)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref>, and annually thereafter, the Panel shall submit and publish an updated report in the same manner as required under such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H920FF752FA3044D783BCE4BC52DAC112"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the following definitions apply:</text><paragraph id="H15E842A1FB14486EAFABB7EF4BEAA9ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Nursing facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>nursing facility</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1919(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r">42 U.S.C. 1396r(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A8CBFA962AE48239F10ED12EED0A235"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nursing home workforce</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>nursing home workforce</term> means the workforce of health professionals that provide direct resident care in skilled nursing facilities and nursing facilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66041436448845949021B782A841D22F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rural area</header><text>The term <term>rural area</term> means any area outside a metropolitan statistical area.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F5B9EB802204C4E98314328F6E4FC63"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Skilled nursing facility</header><text>The term <term>skilled nursing facility</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1819(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395i-3">42 U.S.C. 1395i–3(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7F9CC342EAA435199EA5E676136564E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Underserved area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>underserved area</term> means an area that is—</text><subparagraph id="H1ED3F9B122F8498F8D3503E361FAFB13" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a health professional shortage area, as such term is defined in section 332(a)(1)(A) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254e">42 U.S.C. 254e(a)(1)(A)</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BAEFC51EDFB4771A27E9CCE70170038" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designated as a medically underserved area pursuant to section 330(b)(3)(A) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254b">42 U.S.C. 254b(b)(3)(A)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

