<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA80D5160AB384F74A5D1DCA10B73A4FF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>118 HR 2327 IH: Air National Guard Squadron Preservation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2327</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250325">March 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000307">Mr. James</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Air Force to take steps to ensure the continued production and procurement of advanced capability fighter aircraft and fifth generation fighter aircraft until the fighter units of the Air National Guard are fully recapitalized, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA43C1EE9EB734A7E91B0B3814269DF65" style="OLC"><section id="H8104811EEC4843F2A247B0028F7EEC93" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Air National Guard Squadron Preservation Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDED64B76E8CE4C1DB7DE86B693F3BAE4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to maintain the capabilities, experience, and strength of the Total Fighter Force needed to confront any threats by ensuring that the service retain force structure through the fighter aircraft squadrons across the Air National Guard are fully recapitalized.</text></section><section id="H75B466EE8687415D98AC0DF159DFBBEB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Recapitalization of Air National Guard fighter fleet</header><subsection id="HDC08FBC7EE574CB9B3C670030E60B99B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Plan for sustainment and recapitalization of Air National Guard fighter fleet</header><text>Section 154(b)(2) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/159">Public Law 118–159</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, fifth generation fighter aircraft,</quote> after <quote>legacy capability fighter aircraft</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA2E070F3EAD246118683E9ACBCD12DF5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procurement of fighter aircraft</header><paragraph id="HD18442B0461D44A1B054F1CBE06453B9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Air Force shall take such steps as may be necessary to ensure the continued production and procurement of at least one model of advanced capability fighter aircraft and at least one model of fifth generation fighter aircraft until the date on which the Secretary certifies to the congressional defense committees that the Secretary has replaced all legacy capability fighter aircraft within each covered Air National Guard fighter unit with an advanced capability fighter aircraft or fifth generation fighter aircraft.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99BBD5C51EA34C1C97437C0CE37F61AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contracts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of fulfilling the requirements of paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H4BC3D928AA80493DA38362ED5FFD2212"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seek to enter into a contract for the procurement of advanced capability fighter aircraft and fifth generation fighter aircraft; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE1EBFEEFB09432698DE196CB9E141E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">modify a contract to provide for the procurement of additional advanced capability fighter aircraft and fifth generation fighter aircraft.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EEF863DEC74481A94BE31A4FF52A211"><enum>(3)</enum><header>GAO review and report</header><subparagraph id="H56A990696C7D40548D6C4206C5F00FF0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a review of advanced capability fighter aircraft. Such review shall include—</text><clause id="HACA932C2317B43ACB5498F73930C5C2B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an assessment of any challenges to the procurement of such aircraft by the Secretary; and</text></clause><clause id="H3A4C96BBCB88445EB01F2908FAC7FD74"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recommendations on how to solve such challenges.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H319A48076C224ECA92C925678949B617"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall provide to the congressional defense committees a briefing on the preliminary findings of the review conducted under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86929509BA1D4368AA4D71DF96CC8DF0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the Comptroller General provides a briefing under subparagraph (B), the Comptroller General shall submit to the congressional defense committees a final report on the review conducted under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BBB1019CDCD4D69B794713EBD62B6D1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report on progress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the Comptroller General provides a report under paragraph (3)(C) and on an annual basis thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the progress of the Secretary in—</text><subparagraph id="HF75F36E778B84F129E316D4C78587D8A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>implementing the recommendations of the Comptroller General issued pursuant to paragraph (3); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0D321B3B5E74A1D933CA29DFA812086"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">replacing the legacy capability fighter aircraft within each covered Air National Guard fighter unit with an advanced capability fighter aircraft, fifth generation fighter aircraft, or next-generation air dominance fighter aircraft.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD8C14B35CBB54BEE8E5AD514F592D4B6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Feasibility study on advanced capability fighter aircraft</header><paragraph id="HC42AFEC7BA234FD9B5A5A23F84F181FF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the Air National Guard, shall conduct a study to determine the need for procuring advanced capability fighter aircraft for use by the active and reserve components of the Air Force.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FD607F2A19C46D6940AB58CA3EDCD55"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The study under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H19C844AFD42B4D67A8177939353070F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>take into account any plans of the Secretary to implement unmanned or autonomous capabilities in any fighter aircraft of the active or reserve components of the Air Force;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8A44DEFBFD746EFBCAF0A206278065D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calculate any cost savings in long-lead time, supply chain acquisition, and labor attributed to any sales of the Block 70/72 variant or later variant of the F–16 fighter aircraft by the military of a foreign country;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30EEA40B8F164BCD8286F8D6B4EA437B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify which reserve and active fighter units of the Air Force would be eligible for recapitalization with advanced capability fighter aircraft;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E1D0CE1679F41C79F439ACFE49B5D01"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify how advanced capability fighter aircraft would meet steady state and contingency force presentation and mission requirements of combatant commanders; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9EB118D382F942E09AEB7973906DA7B2"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify whether a multiyear contract would be the best method for acquiring advanced capability fighter aircraft.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H23EE8246B4F545B79010415A645A8650"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees the findings of the study conducted pursuant to this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H15C98E73A5C6460FAF183D5871047755"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H823FD59D7DC84DA5ABC1BE1BB010DA93"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>advanced capability fighter aircraft</term> means a Block 70/72 variant or later variant of the F–16 fighter aircraft, an F–15EX fighter aircraft, any future variant of such fighter aircraft, or any other more advanced capability fighter aircraft (other than a fifth generation fighter aircraft) identified by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF697C5CDAE77497B89E99503A5C081AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>congressional defense committees</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a)(16) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39EA6CE414CB4C08886C33022552B744"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered Air National Guard fighter unit</term> means any fighter unit of the Air National Guard with respect to which the Secretary has not commenced or completed the process of replacing the legacy capability fighter aircraft of such unit with advanced capability fighter aircraft or fifth generation fighter aircraft as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE413DD803CB4199ADFAE5D91113AA2D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fifth generation</term> has the meaning given such term in section 154(d)(2) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/159">Public Law 118–159</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96BDBF8E77274295898EB56F9131C3FE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>fighter aircraft</term> has the meaning given such term in section 9062(i)(2) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB8785E4B19E4A44885E2F03460FD3C2"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>legacy capability fighter aircraft</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H2D3C416FA0CE4745A510E3AF0333FE58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given such term in section 154(d)(4) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/159">Public Law 118–159</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF309001D145D4F39A0D381FD3A142830"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include the Block 70/72 variant of the F–16 fighter aircraft.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

