<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA26758D7CDF5425B80884CDC83F281EB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2884 IH: Anti-Racism in Public Health Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2884</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for public health research and investment into understanding and eliminating structural racism and police violence.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H95249DB3FFBE4056B504F2548F94C55F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H581DD0D8F9A14616ACFE554233FAE466" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Anti-Racism in Public Health Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE0517B3890A24418987B49DDEC3A2143"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H88562734FF5A4CDCA2F1146B0524956C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Antiracism</header><text>The term <term>antiracism</term> is a collection of antiracist policies that lead to racial equity, and are substantiated by antiracist ideas.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31516922B025486AAD3E9F1B779A430D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Antiracist</header><text>The term <term>antiracist</term> is any measure that produces or sustains racial equity between racial groups.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H6196BEE9F9DA4B8BA2E8188F159CE49E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Public health research and investment in dismantling structural racism</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/243">42 U.S.C. 243 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H97874C87D0604A0296E1A3BC244F5E02"> <section id="HC258EA94C8974386B0277C3DB7B85463"><enum>320C.</enum><header>National center on Antiracism and Health</header> <subsection id="HE71EB13EA52249B5B969F811CEE00584"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="H954E45A361704C8A8E4EC74E8481778C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National center</header><text>There is established within the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention a center to be known as the <quote>National Center on Antiracism and Health</quote> (referred to in this section as the <quote>Center</quote>). The Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall appoint a director to head the Center who has experience living in and working with racial and ethnic minority communities. The Center shall promote public health by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCE13F22DE85A4B5C8A17EBFB9902922F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>declaring racism a public health crisis and naming racism as an historical and present threat to the physical and mental health and well-being of the United States and world;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCA94C2E3A6C54EA2A5F73345CD31C421"><enum>(B)</enum><text>aiming to develop new knowledge in the science and practice of antiracism, including by identifying the mechanisms by which racism operates in the provision of health care and in systems that impact health and well-being;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFA491B4815FD4269A3D4428A9F14D0B0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>transferring that knowledge into practice, including by developing interventions that dismantle the mechanisms of racism and replace such mechanisms with equitable structures, policies, practices, norms, and values so that a healthy society can be realized; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6112DDCF55A94913B11977879FF2AB23"><enum>(D)</enum><text>contributing to a national and global conversation regarding the impacts of racism on the health and well-being of the United States and world. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC6CF5A37B4224BE5BD2F97F2F5974F3F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>General duties</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Center, shall undertake activities to carry out the mission of the Center as described in paragraph (1), such as the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HD931FC9C42554F1F8C7DD95B30C9B234" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Conduct research into, collect, analyze and make publicly available data on, and provide leadership and coordination for the science and practice of antiracism, the public health impacts of structural racism, and the effectiveness of intervention strategies to address these impacts. Topics of research and data collection under this subparagraph may include identifying and understanding—</text> 
<clause id="HBAF133B90BED49659BB937D3E57F77EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>policies and practices that have a disparate impact on the health and well-being of communities of color;</text></clause> <clause id="H17EBE96442E84A2CA94B05B3494AF580"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the public health impacts of implicit racial bias, White supremacy, weathering, xenophobia, discrimination, and prejudice;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4BF143B677A54E399D463286EFE6912A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the social determinants of health resulting from structural racism, including poverty, housing, employment, political participation, and environmental factors; and</text></clause> <clause id="H4170A07EB1154A20B174A3E64BB1DAC3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the intersection of racism and other systems of oppression, including as related to age, sexual orientation, gender identity, and disability status.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4DD3ACEDED844BADB3B7D68B9236CB11"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Award noncompetitive grants and cooperative agreements to eligible public and nonprofit private entities, including State, local, territorial, and Tribal health agencies and organizations, for the research and collection, analysis, and reporting of data on the topics described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H966D5A117B9C41A8B85A1B7BECBE762F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Establish, through grants or cooperative agreements, at least 3 regional centers of excellence, located in racial and ethnic minority communities, in antiracism for the purpose of developing new knowledge in the science and practice of antiracism in health by researching, understanding, and identifying the mechanisms by which racism operates in the health space, racial and ethnic inequities in health care access and outcomes, the history of successful antiracist movements in health, and other antiracist public health work.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB2E63B5214854CFE84400CD9D9F9B9E4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Establish a clearinghouse within the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention for the collection and storage of data generated under the programs implemented under this section for which there is not an otherwise existing surveillance system at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Such data shall—</text> <clause id="H6593CBFFA63D413EA2F08A53779BC7B0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be comprehensive and disaggregated, to the extent practicable, by including racial, ethnic, primary language, sex, gender identity, sexual orientation, age, socioeconomic status, and disability disparities;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9D81C0177E1B4C0F93B14EA9587DFF2A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be made publicly available;</text></clause> <clause id="HC6305B9D5BA04E09BB4B8C5029B65A66"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>protect the privacy of individuals whose information is included in such data; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H835DE389FA364B4D87E6BB05749CA04E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>comply with privacy protections under the regulations promulgated under section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD4E59F9712FF4054AFB9014550AF7034"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Provide information and education to the public on the public health impacts of structural racism and on antiracist public health interventions.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC95B409D55344D62AC24A645E89FB33B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Consult with other Centers and National Institutes within the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, including the Office of Minority Health and Health Equity and the Center for State, Tribal, Local, and Territorial Support, to ensure that scientific and programmatic activities initiated by the agency consider structural racism in their designs, conceptualizations, and executions, which shall include—</text> <clause id="HFB7A3D6B9835443CA6D2D7CFB8E9B3F8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>putting measures of racism in population-based surveys;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD0E5280D74DE4F0A9F9C2F755593F6D6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establishing a Federal Advisory Committee on racism and health for the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention;</text></clause> <clause id="H1BC4CBF014DC4B339CDDEFEBFD99022E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>developing training programs, curricula, and seminars for the purposes of training public health professionals and researchers around issues of race, racism, and antiracism;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB910E119CAA04F01A460C04B6D2C5891"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>providing standards and best practices for programming and grant recipient compliance with Federal data collection standards, including section 4302 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA5C86AE7F4794ECDAC69411BF1969740"><enum>(v)</enum><text>establishing leadership and stakeholder councils with experts and leaders in racism and public health disparities.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8255C7A53ED94746B0598D439E275235"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Coordinate with the Indian Health Service and with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention’s Tribal Advisory Committee to ensure meaningful Tribal consultation, the gathering of information from Tribal authorities, and respect for Tribal data sovereignty.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H696E557703E342FC8381D8400838F1B8"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Engage in government to government consultation with Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H100378DCF4E94B1EA5F67F77382FFA83"><enum>(I)</enum><text>At least every 2 years, produce and publicly post on the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention’s website a report on antiracist activities completed by the Center, which may include newly identified antiracist public health practices.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H53B75B239BEA43AC94B2F85C47872530"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HDB3E954091C24C759B988EDBD92B84D9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Public health research and investment in police violence</header> 
<subsection id="H945FB0FF00BC4FF88E5514AEFAE86922"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall establish within the National Center for Injury Prevention and Control of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (referred to in this section as the <quote>Center</quote>) a law enforcement violence prevention program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H952215FF1B434EDABE950E4F909BAE6B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>General duties</header><text>In implementing the program under subsection (a), the Center shall conduct research into, and provide leadership and coordination for—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA53BAB0562C044D9A7A8A151293358CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the understanding and promotion of knowledge about the public health impacts of uses of force by law enforcement, including police brutality and violence;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3EC33DA3C0474E1CB22A2CEA4A3B68F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>developing public health interventions and perspectives for eliminating deaths, injury, trauma, and negative mental health effects from police presence and interactions, including police brutality and violence; and </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H900DC328855244EB96D9CE063AC8517A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensuring comprehensive data collection, analysis, and reporting regarding police violence and misconduct in consultation with the Department of Justice and independent researchers.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H59487BF0684F406F9728F070499BBC34"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>Under the program under subsection (a), the Center shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H32A83C8F05D84E469950161FAC1FDAB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>summarize and enhance the knowledge of the distribution, status, and characteristics of law enforcement-related death, trauma, and injury;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H14CFFCAD6C2942B5B2322D4AAA0377F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conduct research and prepare, with the assistance of State public health departments—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H21D11433A2BE4EC7B7B077B7D5688A40"><enum>(A)</enum><text>statistics on law enforcement-related death, injury, and brutality;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H99846236AA8C4636B8870B4965E9B4C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>studies of the factors, including legal, socioeconomic, discrimination, and other factors that correlate with or influence police brutality;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6CE49F06808142EFA80B84F559E491A3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>public information about uses of force by law enforcement, including police brutality and violence, for the practical use of the public health community, including publications that synthesize information relevant to the national goal of understanding police violence and methods for its control;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H72E86DD8881040828D5CF805D3D33BE1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>information to identify socioeconomic groups, communities, and geographic areas in need of study, and a strategic plan for research necessary to comprehend the extent and nature of police uses of force by law enforcement, including police brutality and violence, and determine what options exist to reduce or eradicate death and injury that result; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB4BEC79A18ED47EDA6DBE6EE369543CD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>best practices in police violence prevention in other countries;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H453CE1C8CD814929AFC1CBD54AE2B9A9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>award grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements to provide for the conduct of epidemiologic research on uses of force by law enforcement, including police brutality and violence, by Federal, State, local, and private agencies, institutions, organizations, and individuals;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE23898CB2D3247FCB96FD2CC5B81C8F7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>award grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements to community groups, independent research organizations, academic institutions, and other entities to support, execute, or conduct research on interventions to reduce or eliminate uses of force by law enforcement, including police brutality and violence; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H180D8E3A7F2E4EBC8A0E4F78079DA161"><enum>(5)</enum><text>coordinate with the Department of Justice, and other Federal, State, and local agencies on the standardization of data collection, storage, and retrieval necessary to collect, evaluate, analyze, and disseminate information about the extent and nature of uses of force by law enforcement, including police brutality and violence, as well as options for the eradication of such practices;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8FD95EED436C43EF98FEA3997B4F5E20"><enum>(6)</enum><text>submit an annual report to Congress on research findings with recommendations to improve data collection and standardization and to disrupt processes in policing that preserve and reinforce racism and racial disparities in public health;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEBF4FB8F7A1341A4BC4AF98EDBFB824F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>conduct primary research and explore uses of force by law enforcement, including police brutality and violence, and options for its control; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD293BCF6896547349E7DD1480E7E1F15"><enum>(8)</enum><text>study alternatives to law enforcement response as a method of reducing police violence.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD5EB233045354723B49C19BDDEA881B3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated, such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section. </text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

