<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H830FE5B827A54570B6579A5437C1684F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5001 IH: SBIR/STTR Oversight Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5001</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250819">August 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the reporting requirements for the SBIR and STTR programs, and for other purpose.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H89327088F7984BF1BD1FC9698D788D7A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H895F70BD69724041A8FF87347706C5B4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>SBIR/STTR Oversight Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HCAA32664431C4BA8B792308DDD0F8455"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual reports to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 9 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2D7C4D263FC34F949EB2587BFCF8C18F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(9)—</text> <subparagraph id="HB5D51F68B73A4E8893B50D86F1F43805"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>the House Committee on Small Business, Senate Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship,</quote> after <quote>SBIR program to</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB44037C4AEC94CF2968ABA4F1B89AE48"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting a comma after <quote>Administration</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6AC31D13E4F74496BC8D48B6456EE33C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>Technology Policy</quote> the following: <quote>and publish such report on the website of such Federal agency as soon as practicable</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB8ED3AF224334DD8B214FBCD7047999F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (o)(10)—</text> <subparagraph id="H9F5A5C91765F4184A844F39B6CC5C4FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>House Committee on Small Business, Senate Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship,</quote> after <quote>STTR program to</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H84B09990B34240AF9AFD05589CF911DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting a comma after <quote>Administration</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H74DF6D9827904A0D990835C733DD402A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>Technology Policy</quote> the following: <quote>and publish such report on the website of such Federal agency as soon as practicable</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD895114E31534794A278A2749B427C19"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (gg)(6), by inserting <quote>Congress and</quote> after <quote>agency to</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HF23D1ECC206E4C1AB73961AC26FC6C3B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Comptroller General report on diversification and commercialization</header> <subsection id="H3623316C0F4D451F8EEBCEF8AEA2752A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than three years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives a report on the effectiveness of the SBIR and STTR programs with respect to diversification of participants and commercialization.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1F2BCD19BC4F47F5A7FBC8661DEAF6FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report shall include, to the extent practicable, an assessment of—</text> <paragraph id="HD39C96AECEE54BB3B6B1AF39214BBB5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the demographics of small business concerns receiving SBIR or STTR awards, including new entrants and underrepresented groups;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81D6650FF3B940599ADB2D8228C77C6C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the efforts of participating agencies to broaden representation and participation of new entrants and underrepresented groups in the SBIR and STTR programs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3755E1785C3401A8DE70C7686C82F4E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>how participating agencies develop solicitation topics and attract applicants;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H43A86297D91745AAA80674BDBD00FFF1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the efforts of participating agencies to support technology commercialization;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA82D9934EF3B49B7BEE5C50498B770D6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the extent to which the SBIR and STTR awards made by each participating agency align with the research priorities and technology needs of that participating agency; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H651408A38E2643A1914E65DA8E22596D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>such other matters as the Comptroller General, in consultation with the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives, determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1699EEEA5AC649F69EC200487BB11DB7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA9920BC1B31C4524AFEC746A963E34B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal agency; sbir; sttr</header><text>The terms <term>Federal agency</term>, <term>SBIR</term>, and <term>STTR</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 9(e) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638(e)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A3A0EA5425F49578153A475BF8C74CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>New entrant</header><text>The term <term>new entrant</term> means a small business concern that has not previously received an SBIR or STTR award.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAF633DDF17214CF1B8E824AC01B26EC0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Underrepresented groups</header><text>The term <term>underrepresented groups</term> means small business concerns located in States with respect to which a low level of SBIR and STTR awards have historically been awarded, small business concerns owned and controlled by women, and small business concerns owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE60E6025E5354B21B9663D7F6AAD3F64"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Participating agency</header><text>The term <term>participating agency</term> means a Federal agency carrying out an SBIR or STTR program under section 9 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC6B0DC4347EB4E249A4C0A40DCCA39DF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Small business concern</header><text>The term <term>small business concern</term> has the meaning given such term under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06BA5CA554824E20B3338D9487AE5A9F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Small business concern owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals; small business concern owned and controlled by women</header><text>The terms <term>small business concern owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals</term> and <term>small business concern owned and controlled by women</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 8(d) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/637">15 U.S.C. 637(d)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB5544B03961647FB815104539FFB63A0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Extend the report on award timeliness</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 9(ii)(2)(A) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638(ii)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H304E2DB52DCA42B98F0258A5B70E3113"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>3 years</quote> and inserting <quote>11 years</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBE53AE465A7E422E97BEBBC785BB5106"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5B19DA2C3F694486BB4CEA41AAF59D70"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (ii) as clause (iii); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H97C2335990834A6DAEF7B941A1B511F9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (i) the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block id="H28E05ADC72A845B394232DAF7D40C27D" style="OLC"> <clause id="H5AD34A5EB9D94C2ABF29F3BE620E0B8D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides the average and median amount of time that each Federal agency with an SBIR or STTR program takes to review and make a final decision on proposals submitted under the program; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HA1AE2E3F740C412F91D455C38A80E3A6"><enum>5.</enum><header>Pilot program to accelerate National Institutes of Health evaluation process</header> 
<subsection id="H967404B2A63C48A9A14B3392EB30747E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 9(hh) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638(hh)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="HDF3F5FEEC49E48129AEDE7FFBF8254F9" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H151FC9A059B84087B3F3ECB0FFA903D9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Pilot program to accelerate the national institutes of health sbir and sttr awards</header> <subparagraph id="HB5BF0438E6954E5FA6609F1FC0D9E0E0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall establish a pilot program to reduce the time for awards under the SBIR and STTR programs of the National Institutes of Health.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H082444478EF544F5ADDCE5DE746CAF7A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Award procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the pilot program under subparagraph (A), the Director shall develop simplified and standardized procedures across all relevant awarding offices at the National Institutes of Health and reduce the amount of time between the provision of notice of such awards and the subsequent release of funding with respect to the awards to be as close to 90 days as possible.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCF13D955F03441BB9E5681CB93DD9E70"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Merit review</header> <clause id="H363E8358F8F1410FAE47165F465FC61C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Under the pilot program under subparagraph (A), the Director of the National Institutes of Health may, with respect to awards under the SBIR and STTR programs of the National Institute of Health, use such peer review procedures (including consultation with appropriate scientific experts) as the Director determines to be appropriate to obtain assessments of scientific and technical merit and potential for commercialization.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA06A6E4000F8429AA30FB4A243ED930E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Deemed</header><text>The use of peer review procedures under clause (i) shall be deemed to fulfill any requirements applicable to the award under the SBIR or STTR program of the National Institute of Health under sections 406(a)(3)(A) and 492 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/284a">42 U.S.C. 284a(a)(3)(A)</external-xref>; 289a).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4D24219FEAF4CC1855E75F6C53468F8"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The pilot program under subparagraph (A) shall terminate on September 30, 2030.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEDDC1AE2D22F44CAAE22197703462491"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Evaluation report</header><text>Not later than three years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall submit to the Committees on Small Business and Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate an evaluation of the pilot program established under paragraph (3) of section 9(hh) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638(hh)</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a), including an analysis of the peer review procedures used under subparagraph (C) of such paragraph and the effects on award times.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

