<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-WIL25212-FY2-CJ-2F2"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2031 IS: Workforce Mobility Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code> 
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>S. 2031</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20250611">June 11, 2025</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To prohibit certain noncompete agreements, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H2B22458199094946AFD2BC2B57787247"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="S1"> <enum>1.</enum> <header>Short title</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Workforce Mobility Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="id7ADCE34C4A8C4CB79FB402BAFF44414C"> <enum>2.</enum> <header>Findings</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="id5ebe799d0c8348679f92f979ea63caef"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>The proliferation of noncompete agreements throughout sectors, occupational categories, and income brackets is contrary to the commitment of Congress to foster stronger wage growth for workers in the United States. Economists now estimate that 1 in 5 workers is covered by a noncompete agreement.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id1416bc3f29be40a3870955051688b1c5"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>Noncompete agreements are blunt instruments that crudely protect employer interests and place a drag on national productivity by forcing covered workers to either idle for long periods of time or leave the industries in which the workers have honed their skills altogether.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id3035142cb29d4152823eff76aed9c170"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>Enforceable noncompete agreements also reduce wages, restrict worker mobility, impinge on the freedom of a worker to maximize labor market potential, and slow the pace of innovation in the United States.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idef87bd2e2f464a7f84db34780534dea2"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>Employers have access to legal recourses to protect their legitimate interests and property, including trade secret protections, intellectual property protections, and nondisclosure agreements that do not inflict broad collateral harm on the labor market prospects for workers.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id7a1c83b821da4775b6f62881d00d2061"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text>Employers that rely on a list or lists of vendors, customers, or clients that are not easily obtained by an individual through means other than the work relationship have adequate legal protection through the use of trade secret protections and nondisclosure agreements.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id96233F7C886549428992399FCD6E6620"> <enum>(6)</enum> <text>Noncompete agreements broadly restrict employment options for workers in the United States when more narrowly targeted remedies are readily available to employers.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="ida4414fedf7fa46eeba7987d16c09aff3"> <enum>(7)</enum> <text>Fostering an environment where employers can flourish is necessary to promote vitality and prosperity in the economy.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id5C193FF9EC914E3F93F0EBDC3F1943FC"> <enum>(8)</enum> <text>Employers may retain critical skilled employees while ensuring that disincentives affecting mobility, including noncompete agreements, do not negatively impact the workforce in the United States.</text> </paragraph> </section> 
<section id="id6721ad09bd9d462bb36ae653242ee20b"> <enum>3.</enum> <header>Prohibiting noncompete agreements</header> 
<subsection id="idF521A4B822744780BE29759F233CE679"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Prohibition</header> 
<paragraph id="id2006ADA114174E25844637D7288DABF5"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), no person shall enter into, enforce, or attempt to enforce a noncompete agreement with any individual who is employed by, or performs work under contract with, such person with respect to the activities of such person in or affecting commerce.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id47B6C564D83D40FFBA9B301D50BB0E81"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Effect of agreements</header> <text>Except as provided in subsection (b), a noncompete agreement described in paragraph (1) shall have no force or effect.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="idCD5B33A80BE044CA96800C686B900C8F"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Exceptions</header> 
<paragraph id="id31808BC4AFB94484986096448BDD985E"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Sale of goodwill or ownership interest</header> 
<subparagraph id="id3C5494D9CF9F41DE9431DBB383488FDC"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>A seller of a business entity may enter into an agreement with the buyer to refrain from carrying on a like business within a specified geographic area described in subparagraph (C), if the buyer, or any person deriving title to the goodwill of the business entity or an ownership interest in the business entity from the buyer, carries on a like business in such specified geographic area.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34F9327EE4CD4237A43B92D5697142CC"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Senior executive officials with severance agreements</header> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD8A6F4BE9D124A37AD7A86C248F693BC"> <enum>(i)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>Subject to clause (ii), a buyer or seller of a business entity may enter into a noncompete agreement with a senior executive official who has a severance agreement described in clause (iii) that restricts the senior executive official from performing, within a specified geographic area described in subparagraph (C), any work that is similar to the work that the senior executive official performed for the buyer or seller, if the buyer, or any person deriving title to the goodwill of the business entity or an ownership interest in the business entity from the buyer, carries on a like business in such specified geographic area.</text> </clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id850384B932B1473D8AD156D028DFD1AF"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <header>Time-limited agreement</header> <text>A noncompete agreement described in clause (i) may not restrict the senior executive official as described in such clause for a period that is more than one year.</text> </clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCA2CBC3A197748E680888E252EFE0782"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <header>Severance agreement</header> <text>A severance agreement described in this clause is an agreement between the buyer or seller of a business entity and a senior executive official that—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id27A65CB06AD149A1B2C1EF472C47E182"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>is part of the terms and conditions of the sale; and</text> </subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD134DF733A5A4ECE8D2123AA992F080C"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text>requires monetary compensation for the senior executive official in the event of termination of the employment of the senior executive official at an amount that is not less than the compensation that the senior executive official is or would be reasonably expected to receive from the buyer during the 1-year period following the sale.</text> </subclause> </clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id967361D368764694B5CDEDE67502C56C"> <enum>(C)</enum> <header>Specified geographic area</header> <text>A specified geographic area described in this subparagraph is a geographic area—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10049216db5545078e10a001c178595e"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is specified in an agreement described in subparagraph (A), or a noncompete agreement described in subparagraph (B), regarding a business entity; and</text> </clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2136eb88f8ac4587a8f7c4270a70b42b"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in which such business entity, including any division or subsidiary of such business entity, conducted business prior to the agreement or noncompete agreement.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idACA4D50B98AB427EAF01E85C6D9E1BA6"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Partnership dissolution or disassociation</header> <subparagraph id="id2E4790BC195A4886B8F1DF199A823CB0"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>Any partner of a partnership may enter into an agreement with any other member of the partnership that, upon the dissolution of the partnership or dissociation of the partner from such partnership, the partner will refrain from carrying on a like business within a specified geographic area described in subparagraph (B), if any other member of the partnership, or any person deriving title to the partnership or the goodwill of the partnership from any other member of the partnership, carries on a like business in such specified geographic area.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id501B1A81145545F2BF182831628635F3"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Specified geographic area</header> <text>A specified geographic area described in this subparagraph is a geographic area—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0438575a7289450898196fe34987b61d"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is specified in an agreement described in subparagraph (A); and</text> </clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id122031e6429347c7a5ee0e9d2de8dcab"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in which any business of the partnership has been transacted prior to the agreement.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> </section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBFFEE2788DED43129E48E32572B0F42D"> <enum>4.</enum> <header>Trade secrets</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall preclude a person from entering into an agreement with an individual who is employed by, or performs work under contract with, such person with respect to the activities of such person in or affecting commerce to not disclose any information (including after the individual is no longer employed or performing work for the person) regarding the person, or the work performed by the individual for the person, that is a trade secret.</text> </section> 
<section id="idAC919CC93F2644AF93964AB76F3D74E8"> <enum>5.</enum> <header>Notice; public awareness campaign</header> 
<subsection id="idFBAB5AE01FB748C1815377FE96E632B3"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Notice</header> <text>Any person who engages an individual who is employed by, or performs work under contract with, such person with respect to the activities of such person in or affecting commerce shall post and maintain notice of the provisions of this Act—</text> <paragraph id="id17CB50B80B6044D6B996E89B63FBA1DB"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>in a conspicuous place on the premises of such person; or</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="ide535c03c82db433d92c0e063cdeb81aa"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>in a conspicuous place where notices to employees and applicants for employment are customarily posted physically or electronically by such person.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="idF83FE265968849E891F1444171CE67B7"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Public awareness campaign</header> <text>The Secretary of Labor may carry out activities to make the public aware of the provisions of this Act.</text> </subsection> </section> 
<section id="id6e005dabdcee4c739e56815f2d1a33fd"> <enum>6.</enum> <header>Enforcement</header> 
<subsection id="id57DC0A7AAD2F43B8BE2B5C0F01985DAA"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Federal Trade Commission</header> 
<paragraph id="idBADF55300A4943D3A0329D0EA729F1C9"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header> <text>A violation of section 3 or 5(a) shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id6815c1970a53442c86d68536724994ab"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Powers of Commission</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="id668f0d6aff56491695990c410c5e1dd3"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce sections 3 and 5(a) in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id97098537092743ac9b1c027c78f0bc29"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Privileges and immunities</header> <text>Any person who violates section 3 or 5(a) shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb4ad5a332ffb48f297734113a28a3668"> <enum>(C)</enum> <header>Authority preserved</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the authority of the Federal Trade Commission under any other provision of law.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="id515C2AA2676E4D25A2CD5145B6B92EC4"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Department of Labor</header> 
<paragraph id="idfa0f1289f1d648c6b3557763fd090c1f"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>The Secretary of Labor—</text> <subparagraph id="id6D454FC5CEC74D48B76C3A06A79B4696"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>shall investigate as the Secretary determines necessary to determine violations of section 3 or 5(a) by an employer; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id9CC127798DF3463286DD5E8A9EDBA884"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>may, subject to paragraph (2), bring an action in any court of competent jurisdiction to obtain the legal or equitable relief against an employer on behalf of an individual aggrieved by the violation as may be appropriate to effectuate the purposes of such sections.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEDE07C7FDF8343838F1DFABEF7D16A08"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Statute of limitations</header> <text>An action described in paragraph (1)(B) may not be commenced later than 4 years after the date on which the violation occurred.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2169CD9F04B14FFE90C58E6B47C8C067"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Regulations</header> <text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Chair of the Federal Trade Commission, shall issue regulations as necessary to carry out this Act, including with respect to the authority of the Secretary of Labor to enforce violations of section 3 or 5(a) in accordance with paragraph (1).</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7C57950BE8E84732BB357B814727534B"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Standards for dual enforcement</header> <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Federal Trade Commission and the Secretary of Labor shall, for the purposes of enforcing this Act—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id71B990EB0A8F40D8896622B0949EF44B"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>develop shared standards for consistent enforcement; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCB68B374DADA428789F5448FD559F090"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>identify the scope of responsibility of the Federal Trade Commission and such scope of the Secretary of Labor to ensure complementary enforcement of this Act.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id46FAA29451EA48C78057E3D5F7738CC7"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Reporting violations</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAE9F93CBD6234617902B63AF34DC1B08"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>The Federal Trade Commission and the Secretary of Labor shall each establish a system to receive complaints by individuals regarding alleged violations of section 3.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="ide3aee2e8cfe8491b92fd51e1f19bb89f"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Confidentiality</header> <text>Except as otherwise required by law, the Federal Trade Commission and the Secretary of Labor may not disclose the identity or identifying information of any individual providing a complaint under paragraph (1), without explicit consent from the individual.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="id3E128D81363B4278B6E175A92F170AB2"> <enum>(e)</enum> <header>Private right of action</header> 
<paragraph id="id273bc86d27b849ee83173b43c56132ce"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>An individual who is aggrieved by a violation of this Act may bring a civil action in any appropriate district court of the United States.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idAB35A3334DCF450DBE9DEB16E7290E3B"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Relief</header> <text>In a civil action under paragraph (1), a court may award—</text> 
<subparagraph id="idf536614afbfb40f4abaa3a4c089058c7"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>any actual damages sustained by the individual as a result of the violation; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idcc2dd3d8e2b1419ebe7c4f5d6a2f9578"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>in the case of any successful action, the costs of the action and reasonable attorney’s fees, as determined by the court.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="id37837AFFABD241C49CD0CA3003121B96"> <enum>(f)</enum> <header>Enforcement by States</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="id799C094792C54E55817D3789A9F46D64"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>In any case in which the attorney general of a State has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of the State has been or is threatened or adversely affected by any person who violates any provision of section 3 or 5(a) or any rule promulgated under this Act to carry out such section, the attorney general of the State, as parens patriae, may bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate State court or an appropriate district court of the United States to—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="id0C2F053EF4484D3AAB2FFA3886A22145"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>enjoin any further such violation by the person;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="idDA304EF31DDD4071B2034F686296BE1E"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>compel compliance with section 3 or 5(a) or any such rule;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="id2429456b55354bffb2aa20113d7a0284"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>obtain a permanent, temporary, or preliminary injunction;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="id3FD46807E91E4EDF863E98E3F822586B"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>obtain damages, restitution, or other compensation on behalf of the residents of the State; or</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="id51e27772f4644a579aefafd04f194cc3"> <enum>(E)</enum> <text>obtain any other appropriate equitable relief.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="id584AF26C07AE445C92100D87DFEC9017"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Preservation of state powers</header> <text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as altering, limiting, or affecting the authority of the attorney general of a State to—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="id048903109A6A40D28293CDBDA5CDECEF"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>bring an action or other regulatory proceeding arising solely under the laws in effect in that State; or</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62975B6E00A74E2ABA1B93B464C1B30D"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>exercise the powers conferred on the attorney general by the laws of the State, including the ability to conduct investigations, administer oaths or affirmations, or compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary or other evidence.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="idC52EEF4F91BB45859CE3C331E252822A"> <enum>(g)</enum> <header>Arbitration and class action</header> <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no predispute arbitration agreement or predispute joint-action waiver shall be valid or enforceable with respect to any alleged violation of section 3 or 5(a).</text> </subsection> </section> 
<section id="id6FE8701353D0457CA669A4E048310198"> <enum>7.</enum> <header>Reports</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary of Labor issues any regulations under section 6(b)(3), the Federal Trade Commission and the Secretary of Labor shall each submit to Congress a report on any actions taken by the Federal Trade Commission or Secretary, respectively, to enforce the provisions of this Act.</text> </section> <section id="idf1490257226c40df9070e741f9da9500"> <enum>8.</enum> <header>Definitions</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="id15CA5DC743994F02BF69189276C35B0A"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Business entity</header> <text>The term <term>business entity</term> means any partnership (including a limited partnership or a limited liability partnership), limited liability company (including a series of a limited liability company formed under the laws of a jurisdiction that recognizes such a series), or corporation.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id552572D17FB145D082A511EA128D8961"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Buyer</header> <text>The term <term>buyer</term>, with respect to a business entity, means any person who buys the goodwill of the business entity, buys or otherwise acquires ownership interest in the business entity, or buys a qualified asset or interest with regard to the business entity.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id63bbcdb4a5d94313a750c1121527e1ae"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Class action</header> <text>The term <term>class action</term> means a lawsuit in which 1 or more parties seek or obtain class treatment pursuant to rule 23 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure or a comparable rule or provision of State law.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id9F0A2405949D4E63AF9337197D3816E0"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Commerce</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>commerce</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA4429F851F6B4C8CAC5F6BB1204C7D51"> <enum>(5)</enum> <header>Employ; Employee; employer</header> <text>The terms <term>employ</term>, <term>employee</term>, and <term>employer</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 3 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idbffa1153c3a44747b04bcaa4031d2e67"> <enum>(6)</enum> <header>Noncompete agreement</header> <text>The term <term>noncompete agreement</term> means an agreement, entered into after the date of enactment of this Act between a person and an individual performing work for the person, that restricts such individual, after the working relationship between the person and individual terminates, from performing—</text> 
<subparagraph id="id076bcdae0bdd4f049f60ec0be3579fef"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>any work for another person for a specified period of time;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id2c1004e3ecb245d5be140033034c0d54"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>any work in a specified geographical area; or</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id956a781de3364696be0de12cc9f9b192"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>any work for another person that is similar to such individual’s work for the person that is a party to such agreement.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id29d3c2ea162b483db1c70ad69ec9b790"> <enum>(7)</enum> <header>Owner of a business entity</header> <text>The term <term>owner of a business entity</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="id75AFEB895D1447D59FED019538235710"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>in the case of a business entity that is a partnership (including a limited partnership or a limited liability partnership), any partner;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id2B0F5FB8DF0D4588AADA9423365760FA"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>in the case of a business entity that is a limited liability company (including a series of a limited liability company formed under the laws of a jurisdiction that recognizes such a series), any member of such company; or</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idCC7842CFDF0B4DBE873447FDAA3B87C9"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>in the case of a business entity that is a corporation, a capital stockholder of the business entity who owns not less than 5 percent of the capital stock.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id8d831852b64c439aa2d6cf94c9632430"> <enum>(8)</enum> <header>Ownership interest</header> <text>The term <term>ownership interest</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="id03F89CA80B5A41B5B1EEF2117029346B"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>in the case of a business entity that is a partnership (including a limited partnership or a limited liability partnership), a partnership interest;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idBF3093574E8D462FAEFBB1FECE9E16A4"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>in the case of a business entity that is a limited liability company (including a series of a limited liability company formed under the laws of a jurisdiction that recognizes such a series), a membership interest; or</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3B622A010368443198F5B7EFA47E88BE"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>in the case of a business entity that is a corporation, not less than 5 percent of the capital stock of the business entity or, as applicable, a subsidiary of the business entity.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb71321724406471f92f691318aec39f2"> <enum>(9)</enum> <header>Person</header> <text>The term <term>person</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id1F47028BBAEA494DAD3110D34D92A4B6"> <enum>(10)</enum> <header>Predispute arbitration agreement</header> <text>The term <term>predispute arbitration agreement</term> means an agreement to arbitrate a dispute that has not yet arisen at the time of the making of the agreement.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idB87FFCF78F1A4A31BCFCB7846325B8E4"> <enum>(11)</enum> <header>Predispute joint-action waiver</header> <text>The term <term>predispute joint-action waiver</term> means an agreement, whether or not part of a predispute arbitration agreement, that would prohibit, or waive the right of, one of the parties to the agreement to participate in a joint, class, or collective action in a judicial, arbitral, administrative, or other forum, concerning a dispute that has not yet arisen at the time of the making of the agreement.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idA140CB3CD18A4C2A871F73FBA5AC595A"> <enum>(12)</enum> <header>Qualified asset or interest</header> <text>The term <term>qualified asset or interest</term>, with respect to a business entity, means an asset or interest that is—</text> <subparagraph id="id2E508AC297C643EE864F8212072F4C89"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>all or substantially all of the operating assets and the goodwill of the business entity;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id993C9CBF6E81490AB6522C47DA39C702"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>all or substantially all of the operating assets of a division, or a subsidiary, of the business entity and the goodwill of that division or subsidiary; or</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id85E1FBF3FE4D4D3FB70666C5A2A7D2A1"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>all of the ownership interest of any subsidiary of the business entity.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id09CF65E34606488385ADCF33F691C66A"> <enum>(13)</enum> <header>Sale</header> <text>The term <term>sale</term>, with respect to a business entity, means the sale of the goodwill of the business entity, the sale or other disposal of all of the ownership interest of a seller in the business entity, or the sale of a qualified asset or interest with regard to the business entity.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD56F86CBEA034419BBE12A620EC1C8D3"> <enum>(14)</enum> <header>Seller</header> <text>The term <term>seller</term>, with respect to a business entity, means any person who sells the goodwill of the business entity, any owner of the business entity selling or otherwise disposing of all of his or her ownership interest in the business entity, or any owner of the business entity that sells a qualified asset or interest with regard to the business entity.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2B0B639D2D774F43AD4E57AB5082E988"> <enum>(15)</enum> <header>Senior executive official</header> <text>The term <term>senior executive official</term>, with respect to a sale, means an official who was acquired as an employee of the buyer in such sale through the terms and conditions of the sale, and, on the day before the date of such sale—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id070C27FAC8B74250BC611777ECB518DF"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>who was employed by the seller in such sale;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD151F4C1491B47BE88FD1C417D176904"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>who was responsible for making or directing major decisions of the seller; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8CE21207BD85410CAD5B4CBC8EC54C54"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>whose rate of compensation was in the highest 10 percent of the compensation rates for all employees of the seller.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id998DD1287BFC48A79076AF1A7358D0ED"> <enum>(16)</enum> <header>Trade secret</header> <text>The term <term>trade secret</term> has the meaning given the term in section 1839 of title 18, United States Code.</text> </paragraph> </section> </legis-body> </bill> 

