<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1E3474A8B7F745BDAB63F56D4C09305A" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 19 IH: Providing the sense of the House of Representatives that the House should not adjourn until the annual appropriation bills within the jurisdiction of all the subcommittees of the Committee on Appropriations for the current fiscal year are enacted into law.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 19</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250107">January 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001116">Mr. Clyde</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing the sense of the House of Representatives that the House should not adjourn until the annual appropriation bills within the jurisdiction of all the subcommittees of the Committee on Appropriations for the current fiscal year are enacted into law.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H4E331A43B7BB4B1593ED22DB8538F509"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA4CF9C21542942A9A1B5FC157C2E7D3A"><enum/><text>That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that the House should not adjourn until the annual appropriation bills within the jurisdiction of all the subcommittees of the Committee on Appropriations for the current fiscal year are enacted into law.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

