<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9FC7935D93EF4FFC8FB17213C7759660" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>109 HR 3030 IH: Highway Formula Fairness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3030</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250428">April 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 23, United States Code, to provide for a discretionary increase in certain highway funding to take into account population growth of a State, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1DF2876EB90A448A9F4CE51FB48A84BF" style="OLC"><section id="H375ECFE9409C499C8B4E663EA3742F77" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Highway Formula Fairness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC25C4ED8E5184E619DFCFDD8366E1FBD" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Discretionary increase in certain highway funding for population growth</header><subsection id="H22E8F7A403394BA0B54E70A2B8DC69EF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 104(c)(1) of title 23, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H0F401B6DBDB44860B3F39E8E453A3EB1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><subparagraph id="H3CE1C789C2874E49AE691E590F6FDA76"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking clause (i); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7F3FF373373445CA9D00E276D128F37"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (ii) and (iii) as clauses (i) and (ii), respectively; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E9924E70DF440B2B385196249E61784"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H76B1E18E776A4CFC812C64AF4CBC82D7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H21DC07AD1E1143B79FED296FE877922C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Discretionary increase in amounts for population growth</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the amounts described in subparagraphs (A) and (B), the Secretary may provide an additional amount to each State that has increased in population since the previous decennial census conducted under section 141(a) of title 13, United States Code, in a proportion based on the relative increase in each such population, as determined appropriate by the Secretary .</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0E9A786A27D24E919F677935124567D7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply beginning with the first fiscal year beginning after the date of enactment of this Act. </text></subsection></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H50D3138EB8A44B25ABFB08B1146C0986" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Highway formula modernization study</header><subsection id="H5EB0C1B7CDA44C58B173321650BF8583" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the State departments of transportation and representatives of local governments (including metropolitan planning organizations), shall conduct a highway formula modernization study to assess the method and data used to apportion Federal-aid highway funds under subsections (b) and (c) of section 104 of title 23, United States Code, and issue recommendations relating to such method and data.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC360344E6596415DA1C9B49239666257" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>The highway formula modernization study required under subsection (a) shall include an assessment of, based on the latest available data, whether the apportionment method described in such subsection results in—</text><paragraph id="HE1279B379EDB4080A2D3895D091B8129" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an equitable distribution of funds based on the estimated tax payments attributable to—</text><subparagraph id="HF11CCD0AB18F4BFD97138CDB2425825C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>highway users in the State that are paid into the Highway Trust Fund; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD849BE5514E94FC9B2E13D5448934DC7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>individuals in the State that are paid to the Treasury, based on contributions to the Highway Trust Fund from the general fund of the Treasury; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F5E27C7889A470AADB775D645C9A553" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the achievement of the goals described in section 101(b)(3) of title 23, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H58F36686DBF84D4383B63A5D7162F0E0" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In the assessment under subsection (b), the Secretary shall consider the following:</text><paragraph id="H9005EFB54362453AB9E8B1DA8B16AF57" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The factors described in sections 104(b), 104(f)(2), 104(h)(2), 130(f), and 144(e) of title 23, United States Code, as in effect on the date of enactment of SAFETEA–LU (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/59">Public Law 109–59</external-xref>; 119 Stat. 1144).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF81AE0B349F24CC3937B885D3EFC7DC0" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The availability and accuracy of data necessary to calculate formula apportionments under the factors described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H54966285BD624998B9262B91C79A0471" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The measures established under section 150 of title 23, United States Code, and whether those measures are appropriate for consideration as formula apportionment factors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B172C61AFD04AD18B55BA3CE78EE8A2" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any other factors that the Secretary determines are appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC6BA020884174CE2AF45CE3A6598CF30" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the State departments of transportation and representatives of local governments (including metropolitan planning organizations), shall develop recommendations on a new apportionment method, including—</text><paragraph id="H07F21945EFDE4154BEA6AE9FF301B0BA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the factors recommended to be included in the new apportionment method;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59BD9452F666478A8B6FBD362C02DD46" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the weighting recommended to be applied to the factors recommended under paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7D31669E9F941BEAD6EED9C00062F97" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any other recommendations to ensure that the new apportionment method best achieves an equitable distribution of funds described under subsection (b)(1) and the goals described in subsection (b)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF6FD85F574854BF3AB66642578EE0FD0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report containing the study conducted under subsection (a) and the recommendations developed under subsection (d). </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

