<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE27D97863D2C4E4E87F98E7B0B1D197E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 596 IH: Report on Grant Consolidation Authority for Puerto Rico Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 596</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250121">January 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hernández</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a study relating to the consolidation of certain grant programs currently available to insular areas and the suitability of such consolidation for Puerto Rico, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD46B71CAFC314D49BFE809C429511A3F" style="OLC"><section id="H0C290844B8A745DF9189989FB9953044" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Report on Grant Consolidation Authority for Puerto Rico Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H972388CE846A44FBAA7C8729D3CEA6EC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional findings and statement of purpose</header><subsection id="H6A58038FC9484A3DAD84DAA8A7568A41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Increased burden on the public sector of Puerto Rico</header><text>The Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="H505B5B90BBF74B3EB325A178F9B4377A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Puerto Rico faces a severe economic crisis, characterized by the largest municipal bankruptcy in the United States history, higher levels of poverty and socioeconomic inequality when compared to the rest of the United States, and a reduced labor force.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C4496ED399C4971A7A1DF91D00AA8EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Puerto Rico is managing a large recovery and reconstruction process prompted by hurricanes Irma, María, and Fiona, the 2020 earthquakes, and the COVID pandemic.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BAD6A4C857B4D7C9B5016DEC996EB02"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The set of post-disaster conditions has exerted a great burden on the public sector of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico. Public employees have had to comply with new fiscal requirements imposed by the Financial Oversight and Management Board under the Puerto Rico Oversight, Management, and Economic Stability Act (<quote>PROMESA</quote>), handle historic allocations of Federal funds, which involves engaging with new agencies, programs, and requirements over time, and balance fiscal constraints with the urgency to recruit specialized and full-time workforce for the best use of disaster funding.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4AEDF29178C34BE8A512E83647CF7601"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Statement of Purpose</header><text>It is the purpose of this Act to study the suitability of grant consolidation to minimize the burden upon the public sector of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and maximize its available resources to access Federal funding.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA095412ADF7D49EA99B1E394D846002E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study required</header><subsection id="H212C94933B5140C5A2FAC1FD415B9913"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report containing the results of a study on the process by which grants made available by the Federal Government are consolidated for insular areas pursuant to part 97 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations. Such report shall also contain the following:</text><paragraph id="H602247BCC4014BEC9099558B4B9538D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis, in consultation with appropriate officials of local agencies in Puerto Rico, about the manner in which such agencies currently access funding from programs that are listed in section 97.12 of such part 97.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBC97D6CBDA94EAE84E0F40A4420D057"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A list of each grant or other program that such officials would recommend adding to the list of programs under such section 97.12.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04F825BEF9044800AF6248DF1AAF4EAA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any challenges noted by the Comptroller General or by such officials relating to meeting the existing requirements for obtaining funding for Puerto Rico from such listed programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE804B9527C5A43BCB86B376230782D35"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment by the Comptroller General whether any of the challenges described pursuant to paragraph (3) with respect to existing requirements for obtaining funding would be partially or wholly addressed by extending access to the consolidation of such funding to Puerto Rico in the same manner and to the same extent as the insular areas.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFDF49C61C304A2BBD73069C95E0BF9B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any recommendations of such officials regarding the manner in which that current process for access to such funding should change, including recommendations relating to extending access to the consolidation of such funding to Puerto Rico.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5B937B7E43884836B35F68E66D0EA580"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Access to prompt and complete information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any official of Puerto Rico from whom the Comptroller General seeks information for purposes of the report required by subsection (a) shall promptly and comprehensively respond to such request for information, and in no case later than 90 days after the receipt of such a request. To the extent appropriate, the Comptroller General may interpret a lack of response, or a partial or incomplete response, to any such request for information adversely in compiling the report required by such subsection.</text></subsection><subsection id="H07812505F5874F4DB4C7386987119878"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H8B6443BE656B42EAAD03069B7B157047"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources, the Committee on Education and Labor, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BC974F2E1D0466DA9AF28E87AA0F1EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

