<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD8C8FA65137048E8BF17A324A13EA0ED" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 206 IH: Recognizing the importance of stepped-up basis under section 1014 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 in preserving family-owned farms and small businesses.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 206</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250310">March 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000446">Mr. Feenstra</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000491">Mr. Lucas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the importance of stepped-up basis under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1014">section 1014</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 in preserving family-owned farms and small businesses.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the stepped-up basis under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1014">section 1014</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 allows recipients of inherited assets such as land, equipment, or buildings to adjust the cost basis of the asset to reflect its fair market value;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 98 percent of farms are family-owned according to the Department of Agriculture, and 19 percent of all businesses are family-owned according to the Small Business Administration;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a study conducted by the Economic Research Service of the Department of Agriculture determined that 66 percent of all midsized farms would see an increased tax liability if the stepped-up basis were eliminated;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the stepped-up basis is a crucial component of many family farms and small business succession plans; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the elimination of the stepped-up basis would threaten the ability of farmers, ranchers, agribusinesses, and small business owners to make generational transfers of their operations: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H7A268F9A456F4411B0C49BE4CC702354"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HF97FEC0F212946CC918BBB789734190D"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H1367A7AD3A2B47DB8B8FF58A04C4961B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the preservation of the stepped-up basis;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF349CED057284BDA84E9F4B4872F91A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>opposes any efforts to impose new taxes on family farms or small businesses; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7034F9970F6D4707BC212E65555339D7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of generational transfers of farm and family-owned business operations.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

