<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H592087DA65F748E7B5E8A3D5F9810940" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1267 IH: Water Systems PFAS Liability Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1267</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250212">February 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000600">Ms. Perez</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001228">Ms. Maloy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To exempt certain entities from liability under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 with respect to releases of perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2CBC4FD8E8EF41EBB0FB55AE7C8D2834" style="OLC"><section id="H2987A5E5359248178707C9A8E3A5BDD8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Water Systems PFAS Liability Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H949DD9A65CFE4A47ADDD156D2977677E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exemption of water and wastewater treatment facilities from CERCLA liability for releases of PFAS</header><subsection id="HA5A1053CBAEE4CD081200DEC127CA3BD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HD8A0DEBD180A4E8390F2CCD4E93BDB1A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered perfluoroalkyl or polyfluoroalkyl substance</header><text>The term <term>covered perfluoroalkyl or polyfluoroalkyl substance</term> means a non-polymeric perfluoroalkyl or polyfluoroalkyl substance that contains at least 2 sequential fully fluorinated carbon atoms, excluding gases and volatile liquids, that is a hazardous substance (as defined in section 101 of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0D12693D84B42FE9673970CAF153AE8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB565DEA01A27463A99E4AA3D04E3FBBD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Protected entity</header><text>The term <term>protected entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HB867F6B4D9324BE4A4877E110D23F954"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a public water system (as defined in section 1401 of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300f">42 U.S.C. 300f</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04FAA49761DE4D809768AAA3EB0D382A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a publicly or privately owned or operated treatment works (as defined in section 212 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1292">33 U.S.C. 1292</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H95374C9052A149E790868CA64FB1DD12"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a municipality to which a permit under section 402 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1342">33 U.S.C. 1342</external-xref>) is issued for stormwater discharges;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95932A66AC8448F5B024D36F15E51C93"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a political subdivision of a State or a special district of a State acting as a wholesale water agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98B3BD9CA06C4F49B9A164D34CBEDB7C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a contractor performing the management or disposal activities described in subsection (c) for an entity described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H41C29E0C6FA245C08BAC0E1089450B0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>Subject to subsection (c), no person (including the United States, any State, or an Indian Tribe) may recover costs or damages from a protected entity under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601 et seq.</external-xref>) for costs arising from a release to the environment of a covered perfluoroalkyl or polyfluoroalkyl substance.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3331941DDE8746FEB87E50E480782A00"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Subsection (b) shall only apply if a protected entity transports, treats, disposes of, or arranges for the transport, treatment, or disposal of a covered perfluoroalkyl or polyfluoroalkyl substance—</text><paragraph id="H7E6EE5D4161E437FA739A0FA19A627F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in a manner consistent with all applicable laws at the time the activity is carried out; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88332F91668342FDA9514183445216ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>during and following the conveyance or treatment of water under Federal or State law, including through—</text><subparagraph id="H0BF017174C6040ECBE6B77E2A9C95FCD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the management or disposal of biosolids consistent with section 405 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1345">33 U.S.C. 1345</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA9B254D175C47BF9B1B17333CEEA89F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the discharge of effluent in accordance with a permit issued under section 402 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1342">33 U.S.C. 1342</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC2007E0CE654565B4A91B48C90807FF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the release or disposal of water treatment residuals or any other byproduct of drinking water or wastewater treatment activities, such as granulated activated carbon, filter media, and processed waste streams; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99C0CE1EA7864A9DB555AB66AE434B40"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the conveyance or storage of water for the purpose of conserving or reclaiming the water for water supply.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C65E518BFFE42ADAC8FF0AB2EE98E9E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this section precludes liability for damages or costs associated with the release of a covered perfluoroalkyl or polyfluoroalkyl substance by a protected entity if that protected entity acted with gross negligence or willful misconduct in the discharge, disposal, management, conveyance, or storage of the covered perfluoroalkyl or polyfluoroalkyl substance.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

