<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H882943074CB44B47AC75C12C52A6F19D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3925 IH: Yuhaaviatam of San Manuel Nation Land Exchange Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3925</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250611">June 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for a land exchange in San Bernardino County, California, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC54774D015CC4BF1BC3D392A2E5C95F6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H86C5FE3632F345259EF6A7AB1D2D8CE5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Yuhaaviatam of San Manuel Nation Land Exchange Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE19266A0A03C4B6A8F1D8EDEFCFF1B14"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exchange of land</header> <subsection id="HBA5945E360304C2F8143D57683FF12E3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA6F6C2F257BE4AF1A15F7709058658D6">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Federal Land</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal Land</term> means the approximately 1,475 acres of National Forest System land (including any and all privileges, easements, subsurface rights, hereditaments, improvements and appurtenances thereon and thereto) depicted as F–1 and F–2 on the Federal Land Maps.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB96554583EB844C3BD1E852208B57EDE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal Land Maps</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal Land Maps</term> means the maps entitled—</text> <subparagraph id="H15C517B2E9414E389187F5278198CB43"><enum>(A)</enum><text><quote>San Manuel Ancestral Land Exchange, San Bernardino National Forest, San Bernardino County, California, Federal Lands Proposed for Exchange (map 1 of 2)</quote>, created July 8, 2022, revised January 10, 2023; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA23A6345332A4CBE9D6B42671A75AB90"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><quote>San Manuel Ancestral Land Exchange, San Bernardino National Forest, San Bernardino County, California, Federal Lands Proposed for Exchange (map 2 of 2)</quote>, created July 8, 2022, revised January 10, 2023.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HD07D5698D2B8457EA62E8A5F4E99EC4A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Nation</term> means the Yuhaaviatam of San Manuel Nation, a federally recognized tribe, also recognized as the San Manuel Band of Mission Indians.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3AA16A763B3847E4B60A4A0BA8ED2021">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Non-Federal Land</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Non-Federal Land</term> means the approximately 1,460 acres of land (including any and all privileges, easements, subsurface rights, hereditaments, improvements and appurtenances thereon and thereto) owned by the Nation and depicted on the Non-Federal Land Maps as NF–1, NF–2, NF–3, NF–4a, and NF–5.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCAAAE1D0553C4FDAAA1027C54517899D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Non-Federal Land Maps</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Non-Federal Land Maps</term> means the maps entitled—</text> <subparagraph id="HCC52D5BC758649509ABE6AA1E31AC6CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text><quote>San Manuel Ancestral Land Exchange San Bernardino National Forest, San Bernardino County, California, Non-Federal Lands Proposed for Exchange (map 1 of 4)</quote>, created March 8, 2022, revised January 9, 2023;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3F308C810E46490A9B67CA70A2B5B9A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text><quote>San Manuel Ancestral Land Exchange San Bernardino National Forest, San Bernardino County, California, Non-Federal Lands Proposed for Exchange (map 2 of 4)</quote>, created March 8, 2022, revised January 9, 2023;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H20CDEFF10F114D629C490634F608F6E7"><enum>(C)</enum><text><quote>San Manuel Ancestral Land Exchange San Bernardino National Forest, San Bernardino County, California, Non-Federal Lands Proposed for Exchange (map 3 of 4)</quote>, created March 8, 2022, revised January 9, 2023; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3502C0E47E6E43D88B7CC7C27A1EE8EA"><enum>(D)</enum><text><quote>San Manuel Ancestral Land Exchange San Bernardino National Forest, San Bernardino County, California, Non-Federal Lands Proposed for Exchange (map 4 of 4)</quote>, created July 8, 2022, revised January 9, 2023.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H99B48DF1AD7E481BA0DA7271EF0C1A3B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3E5D0797E3154AE8A5CC513992F6950B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Land exchange</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the provisions of this section, if the Nation offers to convey to the United States all right, title, and interest of the Nation in and to the Non-Federal Land, the Secretary shall, as soon as practicable within the 120-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary receives such offer—</text> <paragraph id="HEE070CEFF09F4FCE8072E7B3BC72F1D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>accept the offer; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9EA9FD1FBB5447A497F31525420D84EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>convey to the Nation all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Federal Land, excepting and reserving an easement for access and use by the Forest Service any portion of Forest Service roads 1N22, 1N24, and 1N25 located on the Federal Land.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC5DCC42F9965489CA2B556F44E241ECE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Survey</header> <paragraph id="H2FB01339594645389CE5444432018ACE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The exact acreage and legal description of the Federal Land to be conveyed under subsection (b) shall be determined by a survey reasonably satisfactory to the Secretary and the Nation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7691E9D8FA2048E6B7C33C704E5CBB8B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-Federal land</header> 
<subparagraph id="H46D3D807ADBB4E2FB59D86389286A249"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The exact acreage and legal description of the Non-Federal Land to be conveyed under subsection (b) shall be determined by a survey reasonably satisfactory to the Secretary and the Nation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H18C9301D67804F9DA7D37BFD89C5511C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Cost</header><text>The cost of the survey in subparagraph (A) shall be borne by the Nation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2EAD2D31F1E949FD87715E340CDEDEA4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Maps, estimates, and descriptions</header> 
<paragraph id="HF17589E32A6D47B8A5150B5F82AAE83A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Minor error</header><text>The Secretary and the Nation may, by mutual agreement—</text> <subparagraph id="H1EA6DB265BF7497AA1769063A9DEFA9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make minor boundary adjustments to the lands to be exchanged under subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H79C7C0757BD04FC29BC5882C035665F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>correct any minor errors in any map, acreage estimate, or description of the land to be exchanged under subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9733BB9B803F44A9B01FA58E7A5E646B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conflict</header><text>If there is a conflict between a map, acreage estimate, or description of any land to be exchanged under subsection (b), the map shall control unless the Secretary and the Nation mutually agree otherwise.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H946C5C4B53CC4B51AEC6B88606A66C17"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability of maps</header><text>The Federal Land Map and the Non-Federal Land Map shall be kept on file and available for public inspection in the office of the Regional Forester, Pacific Southwest Region, United States Forest Service, or any other appropriate office of the Forest Service, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEFE73F8A4C834DC292093554581CC2F8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Arrowhead Landmark preservation</header> <paragraph id="HE7058D60837A4128914323B34FF62373"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of the conveyance under subsection (b), not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Nation shall enter into an agreement with the Secretary under which the Nation agrees to preserve, to an extent mutually agreed upon, the historical and cultural integrity of the Arrowhead landmark site denoted on the Federal Land Maps as <quote>Arrowhead Landmark GA</quote>.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H53CF5F9D556A462CB2B41C22CCBF009E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Records</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The agreement entered into under paragraph (1) shall be recorded in the official records of the County of San Bernardino, California, and an in an appropriate records system of the Forest Service, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H291CF69347FC42039C6327EB07BF6877"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Management of land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Land acquired by the Secretary under this section shall become part of the San Bernardino National Forest and be managed in accordance with the laws, rules, and regulations applicable to such National Forest.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0A0D125018164871B1377467482FD1B7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Federal Land Policy Management Act of 1976</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The land exchange under subsection (b) is not subject to section 206 of the Federal Land Policy Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1716">43 U.S.C. 1716</external-xref>).</text></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

