<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA25511-PCD-3T-HPM"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 276 ATS: Designating June 12, 2025, as “Women Veterans Appreciation Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 276</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><action><action-date date="20250721">July 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Committee discharged; considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating June 12, 2025, as “Women Veterans Appreciation Day”.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, throughout every period of the history of the United States, women have proudly served the United States to secure and preserve freedom and liberty for—</text><paragraph id="id788e70e9fc874a3c8524ad079a305a76"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the people of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id87459832537b4199b62e91a3e2280a30"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the allies of the United States;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas women have formally been a part of the Armed Forces since the establishment of the Army Nurse Corps in 1901 but have informally served since the inception of the United States military;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 2023 marked the 75th anniversary of the signing of the Women’s Armed Services Integration Act of 1948 (62 Stat. 356, chapter 449), legally allowing women to serve in all 4 branches of the military;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 3,000,000 women have served the United States honorably and with valor on land, on sea, in the air, and in space, including—</text><paragraph id="idc024aa4c95c34251ab20b92e3ff2dca4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as <quote>Molly Pitchers</quote> during the American Revolution, providing support to the Continental Army and taking their place on the artillery gun lines as soldiers fell;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb161d3b7aeb44846bfb1fb4f0e4b530f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by passing as men to serve as soldiers during the Revolutionary War, the Early Republic, and the Civil War;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0909752949d9437a9c30012461f596b5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>as doctors, nurses, ambulance drivers, and Signal Corps telephone operator <quote>Hello Girls</quote> during World War I;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcb9b98e7a72a4f5e900c5f9b121eaf2b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>during World War II—</text><subparagraph id="idff79efb11d824d768c294ad03a46d16e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as members of the Women's Army Corps (commonly known as <quote>WACs</quote>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idad3d08c4db1441e1b6edf48d637da2a5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as Women Accepted for Volunteer Emergency Service (commonly known as <quote>WAVES</quote>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8631060d1e464e3eaa99c038b828bc8d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>as members of the Coast Guard Women's Reserve (commonly known as <quote>SPARS</quote>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6a75cbb76d4342d3a71b58797a8b3660"><enum>(D)</enum><text>as Women Airforce Service Pilots (commonly known as <quote>WASPs</quote>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4fd8ff0464394b3b81bcf6f2ec80f7ce"><enum>(E)</enum><text>as nurses;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0b239b624fe44304b2524a605aedb1d4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>as permanent members of the Army, Navy, Marine Corps, and Air Force, serving as nurses, physicians, physical therapists, air traffic controllers, intelligence specialists, communications specialists, logisticians, and clerks during the Korean War and Vietnam War; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6335c8985adb42efa973594a2c4ea0fa"><enum>(6)</enum><text>as fixed and rotary wing combat pilots, surface warfare sailors, submariners, artillerists, air defenders, engineers, military police, intelligence specialists, civil affairs specialists, logisticians, and, most recently, in all combat roles in the Persian Gulf, Iraq, and Afghanistan;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as of 2023, women constitute approximately 18 percent of Armed Forces personnel on active duty, including—</text><paragraph id="id788d8234a99949ce97927e2b1b3f7ef3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>22 percent of active duty personnel in the Air Force;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc7a34b8a87de4388854b5e6945c72d44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>21 percent of active duty personnel in the Navy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2b33f601c00f41bf9dae3a67cb20393d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>16 percent of active duty personnel in the Army;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id837eabcef56146c299538d32a3f0bdc6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>10 percent of active duty personnel in the Marine Corps;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id249f24d26e734dffbc7649b00be03041"><enum>(5)</enum><text>16 percent of active duty personnel in the Coast Guard; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3bb343dca05046fd8ace4abe474bff7b"><enum>(6)</enum><text>19 percent of active duty personnel in the Space Force;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as of 2023, women constitute 22 percent of personnel in the National Guard and Reserves;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas women were critical to COVID–19 relief, including as part of the personnel in the National Guard and Reserves activated to support COVID–19 response efforts;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas women have been critical to responding to the unjustified invasion of Ukraine by the Russian Federation, including as members of the National Guard and as active duty personnel in the Armed Forces who have been deployed to contribute to foreign assistance efforts;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 13 members of the Armed Forces, including 2 women, were killed during Operation Allies Refuge, in which more than 120,000 people were evacuated in the largest civilian airlift in the history of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2024—</text><paragraph id="id80ec8fea4c38436c866705beb3db6597"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the population of women veterans was approximately 2,100,000, which represents a significant increase from 1,100,000 women veterans in 1980; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbe1f3157547c4588a26d21a4ba3dc438"><enum>(2)</enum><text>women veterans constituted approximately 12 percent of the total veteran population;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas women are the fastest growing group in the veteran population;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas an estimated 1 in 3 women veterans enrolled in the healthcare system of the Department of Veterans Affairs report having experienced military sexual trauma during their military service;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the people of the United States are proud of and appreciate the service of all women veterans, who have demonstrated great skill, sacrifice, and commitment to defending the principles upon which the United States was founded and which the United States continues to uphold;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas women veterans have unique stories and should be encouraged to share their recollections through the Veterans History Project, a part of the American Folklife Center at the Library of Congress, which has worked since 2000 to collect and share the personal accounts of wartime veterans in the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, by designating June 12, 2025, as <quote>Women Veterans Appreciation Day</quote>, the Senate can—</text><paragraph id="idd67069d141cd4f11b29bfe0f8d8a7898"><enum>(1)</enum><text>highlight the growing presence of women in the Armed Forces and the National Guard; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide2dcda8a817948d5b47e61f04f6c0ede"><enum>(2)</enum><text>pay respect to women veterans for their patriotic military service: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate designates June 12, 2025, as <quote>Women Veterans Appreciation Day</quote> to recognize the service and sacrifices of women veterans who have served valiantly on behalf of the United States.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

