<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H64E1DAA4CE65410A838D8E15C79A3815" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1718 IH: Justice Thurgood Marshall National Historic Site Establishment Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1718</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Justice Thurgood Marshall National Historic Site in the State of Maryland and provide for its administration as an affiliated area of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H94BC160652084F5BA899A8949FDBFD33" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H48DEC00186F348DF9619AD9946219C58" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Justice Thurgood Marshall National Historic Site Establishment Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC6C19295299D4D59907469CA0EFCB5DF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purposes</header> <subsection id="H52B4D7235E7C4C04B7D0C4DAC3E72389"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HD4E4942443F5452084CA70FCA53E987A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Thurgood Marshall led the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) Legal Defense and Educational Fund from 1940 to 1961, and successfully argued 29 of 32 civil rights cases before the United States Supreme Court, including the landmark 1954 Brown v. Board of Education case that ended racial segregation of public schools.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H50E9FB0684154DBD94056DA93785721A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Thurgood Marshall was appointed by President John F. Kennedy to serve as a Judge on the United States Court of Appeals for the 2nd Circuit from 1961 to 1965. He was then appointed by President Lyndon B. Johnson to serve as United States Solicitor General from 1965 to 1967.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8DADDE485E414C968A0E685DCF3487F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Nominated by President Lyndon Johnson and confirmed by the United States Senate, Thurgood Marshall became the first African American to serve on the United States Supreme Court and served as an Associate Justice from 1967 to 1991.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFBF5E6B7C3924EA680B20D32C2A0E633"><enum>(4)</enum><text>As a result of his long legal career, Thurgood Marshall is credited with ending legal segregation in America.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFEB483A7DCC2464AB4DF41BD632B0A6C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Public School 103, now better known as the Justice Thurgood Marshall School, located at 1315 Division Street in Baltimore, Maryland, was the site of Thurgood Marshall’s elementary education.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H309164F9AF9B4C169A3A1AA06DA07C11"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Justice Thurgood Marshall School is owned and operated as a museum by the Beloved Community Services Corporation, which has completed a historic restoration for adaptive re-use of the School.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H99E474321AA449988683F8959A8E1E38"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Congress authorized the National Park Service to prepare a special resource study of Public School 103 in 2019, which the National Park Service transmitted to Congress in 2023. The National Park Service found that Public School 103 met its criteria for national significance and suitability for addition to the National Park System.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF6C64DA3C35345F8B99129FB454B095B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to preserve, protect, and interpret for the benefit of future generations the significant historic contributions of Justice Thurgood Marshall by establishing the elementary school he attended as a national historic site and providing for the site’s administration as an affiliated area of the National Park System.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HF84709C13B3F491EA809C6FA5D5048C7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H41CC1D98655F4DA8A293CB523286D989"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National historic site</header><text>The term <term>National Historic Site</term> means the Justice Thurgood Marshall National Historic Site established by section 4 of this Act.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H49C1D1C9B1DC4E82BB6D50FEFEDDEBDD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>School</header><text>The term <term>School</term> means the building located at 1315 Division Street in Baltimore, Maryland, known as Public School 103, which is owned and managed by the Beloved Community Services Corporation, a nonprofit organization established in Baltimore, Maryland.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D20E53086A149C88C8E6EDEEE2BC76A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H2BB9E1422E274849849D25AA05319A79"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of the Justice Thurgood Marshall National Historic Site</header>
<subsection id="H3FEDDF7DBD2041E59168463E1176B6CC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established as an affiliated area of the National Park System the Justice Thurgood Marshall National Historic Site.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1847977E9AD14ED5A9B8400D9FFEB3BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Description</header><text>The National Historic Site shall consist of the School, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Justice Thurgood Marshall School National Historic Site Proposed Boundary</quote>, numbered 962/194939, and dated September 2024.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HE3E3D8D684934025919F6C9E63CF515E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ownership</header><text>The School shall continue to be owned, operated, and managed by the Beloved Community Services Corporation.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H96D3D3E9DFCF40EF82EC4973B112CFEB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The National Historic Site shall be managed in a manner consistent with—</text>
<paragraph id="HC7F73514641E43928D444C580BB2183F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>this Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H30D184D075EB4914A016F7991CFCBC94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE275B70F80BE40D8B4006700DD0B57B6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Management entity</header><text>The Beloved Community Services Corporation shall be the management entity for the National Historic Site.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF5CEB4B19C914B86BD29BB1EF4C40A1A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Agreements</header><text>The Secretary—</text>
<paragraph id="H0DDF8A7149F7421F9EB747C391748567"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may provide technical assistance and enter into cooperative agreements with the management entity for the purpose of providing financial assistance for the marketing, marking, interpretation, and preservation of the National Historic Site; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0C41AEB286E4AEAB854B82D700EA285"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall enter into an agreement with the management entity that delineates the roles and responsibilities for the management of the area consistent with the policies and standards that apply to units of the National Park System.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC8B98E661CE44A72988A97A4A510AA41"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Limited role of the secretary</header><text>Nothing in this Act authorizes the Secretary to acquire the property at 1315 Division Street or to assume overall financial responsibility for the operation, maintenance, or management of the National Historic Site.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HA3F0018D4F8C49F89DC0AF71A24E5636"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

