<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEE784D4E7994468695766D75F3A8DFC2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 459 IH: Securing Taxpayer Assistance during Natural Disasters Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 459</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250115">January 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To withhold bilateral, multilateral, and humanitarian non-defense foreign assistance with respect to which of the President has declared a disaster under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3868C42D505248BA92948BD6157454C4" style="OLC"><section id="H2BE5C377BBFC4BCB8829D7F4B43BF758" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing Taxpayer Assistance during Natural Disasters Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STAND Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3A26F9F931E645718FEE3FB2654E43BD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Withholding of bilateral, multilateral, and humanitarian non-defense foreign assistance</header><subsection id="HAD1E385A9C834C9BBA7B918890F15996"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal funds may be obligated or expended by the Department of State or the United States Agency for International Development for bilateral, multilateral, or humanitarian non-defense foreign assistance within 60 days of the date on which a disaster has occurred and with respect to which of the President has declared a disaster under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H6E246A81571D4822BE3EFBF06F563A0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The prohibition under subsection (a) may be waived in accordance with the provisions of a joint resolution providing for such waiver that is enacted into law after the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

