<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC2E1F3BCF018436290443E995094B2BE" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 781 IH: Expressing support for the designation of October 1, 2025, as “National Animal Rescue Day” to create awareness of the importance of animal adoption, to educate on the importance of spaying and neutering animals, and to encourage animal adoptions throughout the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 781</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250930">September 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of October 1, 2025, as <quote>National Animal Rescue Day</quote> to create awareness of the importance of animal adoption, to educate on the importance of spaying and neutering animals, and to encourage animal adoptions throughout the United States.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas millions of cats and dogs are placed into shelters every year and hundreds of thousands of healthy, adoptable animals are euthanized;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas there are between 3,000 and 4,000 animal shelters throughout the United States in need of medical supplies, blankets, towels, cleaning supplies, food, and educational materials about owning a pet;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas increased knowledge and awareness of animal rescue programs throughout the United States will significantly reduce the number of cats and dogs euthanized and reduce the number of animals returned to a shelter who have been rescued;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas loving families welcome pets to their new <quote>forever home</quote> every day, but more adoption is needed;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas lowering the number of animals in need of rescue, by spaying and neutering, can help alleviate the overcrowding of the Nation’s shelters;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas supporting families’ access to housing and veterinary care can further reduce the number of pets surrendered or abandoned;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas years of animal abandonment has left thousands of homeless pets in overpopulated shelters and rescues;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Charlie, one of the thousands of beagles rescued from a breeding facility in 2022, now has a bright future in the laps of his loving new family;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas a <quote>National Animal Rescue Day</quote> would encourage the adoption of rescue animals into loving homes; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the first Saturday in October would be an appropriate day to designate as <quote>National Animal Rescue Day</quote> to be celebrated through adoption events, festivals, and charitable giving which will increase revenues for shelters and pet adoptions: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HA5D3D87383654243B45747D90C624C99"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H3536EC9F3D254040A5BA8935F7BD9F70"><text>That the House of Representatives supports the designation of a <quote>National Animal Rescue Day</quote> to create awareness for animal rescue programs throughout the year and address the challenge of pet overpopulation through continued spaying and neutering.</text></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

