<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HC94F844F23414A709FE02C000B70DDCE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 835 EH: 9/11 Memorial and Museum Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 835</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To provide a one-time grant for the operation, security, and maintenance of the National September 11 Memorial &amp; Museum at the World Trade Center to commemorate the events, and honor the victims, of the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HE17EE60D58B44915AEEE4AE5F1831EC5" style="OLC">
<section id="H66D8BB227FEA4E1DB502A418F1C5A310" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>9/11 Memorial and Museum Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE830F8A7E4744B9A894EA5494BE1FA67"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="HEFBCFE73F2B940E4ACD8DF5C247766D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National September 11 Memorial &amp; Museum</header><text>The term <term>National September 11 Memorial &amp; Museum</term> means the National September 11 Memorial &amp; Museum at the World Trade Center Foundation, Inc., established to commemorate the events of, and honor the victims of, the terrorist attacks on the World Trade Center on September 11, 2001, at the site of such attacks.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2ABFEDFA40D94FEF887340DE254BB402"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means the official organization, as in existence on the date of enactment of this Act, that—</text>
<subparagraph id="HB4850DF71A46478684C0A4E74AAAA359"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">operates the National September 11 Memorial &amp; Museum; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2E39BABAAFC64C6BA70527D72496AFDF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code. </text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1A4455165D624F7D8361B24ECEC74BE4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H0135F44CF7B5401787A0CDBC4805AD1E"><enum>3.</enum><header>One-time grant for National September 11 Memorial &amp; Museum</header> <subsection id="H25E96423C909408CA03AA3C18F46306B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations made in advance for such purpose to the Office of the Secretary and Executive Management of the Department of Homeland Security, the Secretary shall award to the eligible entity a grant in an amount determined by the Secretary subject to subsection (c), to be used by such entity solely for the purposes described in subsection (b), if upon review of the application submitted pursuant to subsection (d), the Secretary makes a determination pursuant to subsection (e) that such entity satisfies the criteria required under subsection (f).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HF81AFC8E142C4FBD9A02CD36F7B9C1DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The one-time grant awarded under subsection (a) shall be used by the eligible entity for the operation, security, and maintenance of the National September 11 Memorial &amp; Museum.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEA1CEA2E3C634A39BEBE374900FF1AB9" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant amount</header><text>The one-time grant under this section may not be for less than $5,000,000 or more than $10,000,000.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HE60C6481B26949CEB028DF394D7EC002"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be considered for an award of the one-time grant under this section, the eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDA1AC768F8AC4DB2BC4F8378561493A9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Review; deadline for award</header><text>If the Secretary, after review of the application from the eligible entity, determines that the eligible entity satisfies the criteria under subsection (f), the Secretary shall award the one-time grant to the eligible entity, not later than 90 days after the date of receipt by the Secretary of the completed application submitted by such entity.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H203CF63F944C4C0880A732871EE849A5" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>In determining the amount of the one-time grant consistent with subsection (c), the Secretary shall consider the following:</text> <paragraph id="H858EBD31E9714CFFBFBE71E548AADAE8" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The needs of the eligible entity, and ability and commitment of such eligible entity to use grant funds, with respect to ensuring the security and safety of visitors at the National September 11 Memorial &amp; Museum.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H635FA8B9ACD54A6B92B99FB89C4D4DF1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of visitors to the National September 11 Memorial &amp; Museum who would benefit.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF5ABA058B560420BABA0D0D05103B100" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The ability and commitment of the eligible entity to use grant funds to—</text>
<subparagraph id="H186831CBB33C42E29BD72D1B4B66924D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preserve the facilities and grounds of the National September 11 Memorial &amp; Museum; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF397B3265E614CFF88F45C6364ED9FD3" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>educate future generations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF0AC776BFB6242518E991BD82CE75FEB" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The ability and commitment of the eligible entity to use grant funds to increase the numbers of economically disadvantaged visitors to the National September 11 Memorial &amp; Museum.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H73C148FD469B4558946691ABC5C00CFD" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Condition on receipt of grant</header><text>As a condition on receipt of a grant under this section, the eligible entity shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HBA8DEAC6F32A4BAA8BA0787D9E4CBE79" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide for—</text> <subparagraph id="H5D09573E975C4BE48645E997E0903D65" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">free admission to all facilities and museums associated with the National September 11 Memorial &amp; Museum for active and retired members of the Armed Forces, individuals who were registered first responders to the attacks of September 11, 2001, and family members of victims of such attacks; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9FF3A070F1CE41EE8171EFB540DB48B5" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>dedicated free admission hours for the general public at least once a week; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC23C29855BB24DB1AA72F44AF4795701" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>allow for annual Federal audits of the financial statements of such entity, including revenues associated with ticket sales, charitable donations, grants, and all expenditures on salaries and operations, which shall be subject to review by the Secretary and made available to the public.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H2E32456E56FC44C4B9484905F24ED18F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the end of each fiscal year for which the recipient obligates or expends funds made available to the recipient pursuant to this section, the recipient shall submit to the Committees on Natural Resources and Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Energy and Natural Resources and Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report that includes, for the fiscal year covered by the report, each of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H22B8901514444E6B8E9659EB81A5DDFD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information relating to the amount of grant funds obligated or expended for the preceding fiscal year.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H10961ECB507B44A3B18124F084C822F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information relating to any purposes for which such funds were obligated or expended.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H436134989EAA42A7BCF7A7FA539715DC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other information the Secretary may require to effectively administer the one-time grant program under this section, as determined by the Secretary, if not later than the last day of the fiscal year the Secretary notified such entity of such requested information.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9E501189D36D4A919555AD45AE1FB8E4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>No additional funds authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to carry out the requirements of this section, and the activities authorized by this section are subject to the availability of appropriations made in advance for such purposes.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250204" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives February 4, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

