<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25F72-STM-KK-MXP"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2672 IS: Sanctions and Accountability for Non-Compliance and Transparent Investigative Oversight for National Security in the West Bank Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2672</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250801">August 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</sponsor> (for <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>)) introduced the following bill; which
                was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee
                    on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To codify Executive Order 14115 imposing certain sanctions on persons
 undermining peace, security, and stability in the West Bank.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section commented="no" section-type="section-one" id="ida4523482ace04923b9fb74927753d94a"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sanctions and Accountability for Non-Compliance and Transparent Investigative Oversight for National Security in the West Bank Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SANCTIONS in the West Bank Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="idc0bfc0970a354229804d5baf36467226"><enum>2.</enum><header>Codification of sanctions on persons undermining peace, security, and stability
 in the West Bank</header><subsection id="id8c3b6f26854b49499e1a8db51007bbfc"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>United States sanctions provided for in Executive Order 14115 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to imposing certain sanctions on persons undermining peace, security, and stability in the West Bank), as in effect on January 19, 2025, shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id86a28ab3ffa14ac194e4d313ad47ebc3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be in effect on and after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id17608f4c87874913b8b482bad8ff14d4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">remain in effect except as provided by subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide5e02b5a2d204aa6ad3528e532793a17"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reinstatement of sanctions</header><text>Effective on the date of the enactment of this Act, sanctions imposed under Executive Order 14115 and revoked by Executive Order 14148 (90 Fed. Reg. 8237) shall be reinstated.</text></subsection><subsection id="id8788151e3d454c29b397d63615c5f3eb"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2a1f0d1daa064e1f80f4622d05a90fce"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may terminate the application of sanctions described in subsection (a) that are imposed with respect to a person in connection with activity conducted by the person if the President submits to the appropriate congressional committee a notice that—</text><subparagraph id="id6e51e4dc524d41c3b02adfe53c8ab251"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the person is not engaging in the activity that was the basis for the sanctions or has taken significant verifiable steps toward stopping the activity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5a3af5806947433298cf792b2bb2756b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the President has received reliable assurances that the person will not knowingly engage in activity subject to sanctions described in subsection (a) in the future.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide1f74015cf3b4eb3b7b74fc152bc81e1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing for notice</header><text>The President shall submit the notice required by paragraph (1) with respect to the termination of the application of sanctions with respect to a person—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb138306342b248c4a8f79416ae27d331"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided by subparagraph (B), not less than 15 days before terminating the application of such sanctions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida8f96f5ce7c44670b6d23a56ce6e962b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the event of exigent circumstances, as soon as practicable, but in no event later than 3 business days after terminating the application of such sanctions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9ee03ba6e1ea49c5ac7a46c561dea2f6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="id378cd86619734c43bddfdaea4fb168dc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1b64f24b803541688d051af496dc5281"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


