<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25A14-4WM-88-RX4"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2220 IS: Fighting for the Overlooked Recognition of Groups Operating in Toxic Test Environments in Nevada (FORGOTTEN) Veterans Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2220</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250709">July 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill;
                which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To expand presumptions of exposure by members of the Armed Forces to toxic
 substances, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="idecf1c6e73685446dae9a7aa9428a6875" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fighting for the Overlooked Recognition of Groups Operating in Toxic Test Environments in Nevada (FORGOTTEN) Veterans Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idf677555874cd47baa35be605e7c71e03"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expansion of Individual Longitudinal Exposure Record to include information
 relating to toxic exposures</header><subsection id="id5260d0eb8e29467cb1788c174847c6cc"><enum>(a)</enum><header>All exposures</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall expand the Individual Longitudinal Exposure Record (in this section referred to as the <quote>ILER</quote>) to document all toxic exposures of members of the Armed Forces, including those that occur within the United States, so it can be available for the Secretary of Veterans Affairs when such members transition to civilian life, including information relating to the following:</text><paragraph id="id3658c60405604d7e8c478244a2a9e598"><enum>(1)</enum><text>All-hazard occupational data.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb4fda9b92361495db99f9d49a9d97ce5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Environmental hazards that were known or found later to which the member was exposed, including through conducting any monitoring in an area in which the member may have been exposed.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id21a44e8b8eed42f0900a61cb74d763be"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Medical information</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall expand the ILER to include the following medical information of members of the Armed Forces so it can be available for the Secretary of Veterans Affairs when such members transition to civilian life:</text><paragraph id="id6175b0b90cb84ae5b0501a49a1e145a3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Medical encounter information relating to toxic exposures (such as diagnosis, treatment, and laboratory data).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id57d76aaa230c4fd08f776c314ff2dc56"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Medical concerns that should be addressed regarding possible toxic exposures.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id20a55d68a56d478692ba4f00680fdccc"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability to certain professionals</header><text>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall ensure that the ILER is available, for purposes of improving internal processes, to the following:</text><paragraph id="id9409c3e927b64bcf90702b0e72b823bd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Health care providers of the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3b1f9de7dd264c3e9335bc03bc1457f5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Epidemiologists and researchers of the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfb356bcfe3e640fc9d2e701552531687"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Disability evaluation and benefits determinations specialists of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2ebfd3bc1fb343499a6a20ac7647628f"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Inclusion in service records</header><paragraph id="id0a89109dfa32420d894560be132f169a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall document in the service records of a member of the Armed Forces whether such member served at a location where there was a potential of toxic exposure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcfddd59c8a594ca2bb6b639a8d076747"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Protection of classified information</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense shall ensure that service at any location that is classified is protected from disclosure and may contain simply a box to be checked to indicate that a member of the Armed Forces served at a location where there was a potential of toxic exposure.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ida55d38279a6541d5963af2bb4a92eb95"><enum>3.</enum><header>Presumption of exposure for members of the Armed Forces and civilian employees
 of the Department of Defense at Department of Energy facilities</header><subsection id="id0b13c2bedc154fd0be3e43543ae557f0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Members of the Armed Forces and civilian employees of the Department of Defense who are or have been stationed or employed at a covered facility shall be presumed to have been exposed to toxic substances.</text></subsection><subsection id="idd3cdca0c41ea4756a996c54998a9b56b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered facility defined</header><text>The term <term>covered facility</term> means any facility on the most recent list of facilities covered under the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7384">42 U.S.C. 7384 et seq.</external-xref>) published in the Federal Register by the Department of Energy.</text></subsection></section><section id="ided29e6703d134702b595da68f406c6b2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Classification of Nevada test and training range as location where contamination
 occurred and members of the Armed Forces were exposed to toxic substances</header><subsection id="id50e41106ced049278046fc38cdeb1409"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall classify the Nevada Test and Training Range as a location where contamination occurred.</text></subsection><subsection id="idd0eea5222913444eb58f5253a39b1680"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Identification process</header><paragraph id="idea16d5933a5d469f84847bbf0e9352c9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Air Force shall establish a process to identify members of the Armed Forces and former members of the Armed Forces that were stationed at the Nevada Test and Training Range since January 27, 1951.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id66aea75947ea488aa07f4aef896128ab"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Documentation</header><text>The Secretary of the Air Force shall establish a process to permit members of the Armed Forces and former members of the Armed Forces to provide documentation or evidence of their assignment within the Nevada Test and Training Range to assist the Secretary in identifying those members and former members under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfa015068c4724a6ebd4eedde2e5c65fc"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Efforts</header><text>The Secretary of the Air Force shall make all efforts to identify individuals described in paragraph (1) and shall not require members of the Armed Forces or former members of the Armed Forces to submit evidence of their stationing.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ide4c71a8815514a26a6f53e0f034ec913"><enum>5.</enum><header>Treatment as radiation-risk activities by Department of Veterans
 Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1112(c)(3) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="id97ab4aeed12f4a8f8c7b590eb6f3bfc6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B) by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb4e3441ad95344379468bcbf806a9aab"><clause id="id162a57f5788b4bda9ea327abe40c0195"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>At any time on or after January 27, 1951, onsite participation in any aspect of the development, construction, operation, or maintenance of a military installation (as defined in section 2801 of title 10) at a covered location at the Nevada Test and Training Range.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id2299be39b05c4ec79f21873260e2b533"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a1f74eb76fe41088266145915cf1e94"><subparagraph id="id7c05a6a70d3c46c7a66d55b5b7300e62"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term <term>covered location at the Nevada Test and Training Range</term> means a location at the Nevada Test and Training Range, Nevada, where there was a potential of toxic exposure.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62a9a10238524a5ca0ddcf69f97c3e35"><enum>6.</enum><header>Presumptions of toxic exposure by Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1119(c) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="iddea01dbfd6b840de824f69eadc5617e4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="ide51d18a31f2d40308e493c1b3e0af64c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as subparagraphs (B) and (C), respectively; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide514a0d355c9499b81fbeca1aacabd1c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before subsection (B), as so redesignated, the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id90ca1c38bb844fe7afef89ec1c4f2731"><subparagraph id="id8855a3d93abc460db0452c4d8f2dfb1c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on or after January 27, 1951, performed active military, naval, air, or space service while assigned to a duty station in, including airspace above, a covered location at the Nevada Test and Training Range, Nevada;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idecf491a57dc04f78ba43129fdace57a9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8673ad0d5114428f9506611cb7b75805"><paragraph id="id3b05d9c8303f44558a30d40837bc5dc9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>covered location at the Nevada Test and Training Range</term> means a location at the Nevada Test and Training Range, Nevada, where there was a potential of toxic exposure.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="id017deb4927414929ba9536af2f469e0d"><enum>7.</enum><header>Presumption of service connection by Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1120(b) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="id22212e0606104f0493ceaa23ecb46410"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (15) as paragraph (16); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9ec31a4c62ac463cb2e0f3dcfa886c63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (14) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id786014bedcfd4678a7b670846beec40f"><paragraph id="id3e9fb9f7f3674b3aa08f26e4ef1ad6fb"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Only in the case of a covered veteran described in section 1119(c)(1)(A), lipomas and tumor related conditions.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


