<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-ROM25015-4PN-J2-VT7" key="G"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 6 ATS: Expressing the thanks of the Senate to the Honorable Patty Murray for her service as President Pro Tempore of the United States Senate and to desiginate Senator Murray as President Pro Tempore Emerita of the United States Senate.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 6</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250103">January 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type> RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the thanks of the Senate to the Honorable Patty Murray for her service as President Pro Tempore of the United States Senate and to desiginate Senator Murray as President Pro Tempore Emerita of the United States Senate.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="OLC" display-resolving-clause="yes-display-resolving-clause" id="H248AF52B8427495BA464997E21643985"><section id="LEXA-Repairidfeca7eb17784456f95d343ddc5ec8d7b" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><text>That the United States Senate expresses its deepest gratitude to Senator Murray for her dedication and commitment during her service to the Senate as the President Pro Tempore.</text><paragraph id="id8e4e88442b054260917be0d1b1800269" indent="up1"><enum/><text>Further, as a token of appreciation of the Senate for her long and faithful service, Senator Patty Murray is hearby designated President Pro Tempore Emerita of the United States Senate.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

