<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H2D12E7EBF507488CA34CA90A80D89FC4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3427 EH: Water Resources Technical Assistance Review Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3427</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to review all clean water-related technical assistance authorities of the Environmental Protection Agency, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="H164B9095E62E466D956EB14AC338EBC8"> 
<section id="H79E7DC4B8CA44988AEF0FC3966D0D5EB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Water Resources Technical Assistance Review Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3404B87AC19545A887B507DA3E9A3512" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>GAO report on clean water technical assistance</header> <subsection id="HD22BA7162955490587DC7245CE7A0F68"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall initiate a comprehensive review of all covered technical assistance. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8B7E5D60F85B4EB3AD0DAE7123A93907"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Comptroller General shall include in the review required under subsection (a) the following:</text> <paragraph id="HA2AEBA10616B43B3BEC1D4E8A175FED0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of all covered technical assistance available to States, Tribes, local governments, and non-governmental organizations, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H94C8CB6731B9414B9ADB4FA6AFC8755E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the regions and populations that are served through the provision of technical assistance; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H86B9005D2742429387035821668AEB0D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a summary of the activities and actions carried out through covered technical assistance during the 5-year period preceding this Act. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5710B99A17064A23AC46A16397A2A77D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comprehensive review of how the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, through the Water Technical Assistance initiative (known as <quote>WaterTA initiative</quote>), identifies, selects, and partners with technical assistance providers to support communities, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H2D150BAD70CC40D58B213758AD284AF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the criteria, evaluation process, and contracting mechanisms used for selecting such providers;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H41F1DC3A69BC4DFFB1D42C9F5C5821B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the extent of coordination with State, Tribal, and regional partners in the selection and deployment of such providers;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7B20A444311F422AB49E640026744566"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of how such providers are matched to meet the needs of local communities, including any pre-engagement scoping activities or community consultations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H947E1FBF907D46FBB467961C013D3437"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how such providers identify communities in need of technical assistance, including economically distressed communities, and conduct outreach to such communities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB14CDA080FDB4A1797CA12FF84488AB3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of the scope and types of assistance delivered through such initiative; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF8E3FC807092458090A4A2E0D8A749CB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a list of communities that received technical assistance support through such initiative, including the type and cost of assistance received by each such community and a summary of the outcomes associated with the provision of such assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H24B80EC1D04E401DA9975E5CF9320F7B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of any duplication of covered technical assistance available through multiple programs of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5919F894F80048A98149915FEF5B045B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation of how the provision of covered technical assistance builds capacity in communities to access other water infrastructure programs carried out by the Administrator.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H32AB21AB62BC4CBD8E45FBCBC3DA4D84" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An assessment of the needs of economically distressed communities eligible to receive assistance under a clean water infrastructure program carried out by the Administrator that are not addressed through covered technical assistance.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE6C1F2EE09F74BE3819CCAFF0665740D"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation of how the Administrator carries out covered technical assistance in coordination with other Federal agencies providing technical assistance related to water infrastructure.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0950F323E5BB4361971DA5162A06EBD0"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation of how covered technical assistance supports communities in understanding, identifying, and implementing alternative and cost-effective technologies and features of treatment works that achieve long-term savings and improved outcomes in addressing water quality challenges.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB1CAEC83792D45318D513EB0FF8CFFEC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Upon the completion of the review conducted under subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a report containing—</text> <paragraph id="H10E3CEA18EEE4DF994D39E3059DFE968"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the findings of such review; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H35DB7FE9F3C24CC9B16526B6613D6169"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any recommendations to improve covered technical assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H85C643B6CD9A4ECAA9B0C3DDE3E7CD27"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Plan for compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the Comptroller General submits the report required under subsection (c), and annually thereafter for a period of 5 years, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a plan detailing any actions the Administrator has taken to comply with the recommendations contained in such a report.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H58A7FDC3CF0A43DDAA498864306C1D4D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Covered technical assistance defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>covered technical assistance</term> means a technical assistance authority, initiative, or program of the Environmental Protection Agency that is related to clean water infrastructure.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250915" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives September 15, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

