<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-REI25109-M0F-XG-D5C"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 386 IS: Designating the week of September 14 through September 20, 2025, as “Community School Coordinators Appreciation Week”. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 386</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250915">September 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating the week of September 14 through September 20, 2025, as <quote>Community School Coordinators Appreciation Week</quote>. </official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas community schools marshal, align, and unite the assets, resources, and capacity of schools and communities for the success of students, families, and communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community schools are an effective, evidence-based strategy for school improvement included under section 4625 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7275">20 U.S.C. 7275</external-xref>), as added by section 4601 of the Every Student Succeeds Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/95">Public Law 114–95</external-xref>; 129 Stat. 2029);</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community schools that provide integrated student support, provide well-designed and expanded learning opportunities informed by rigorous community-connected classroom instruction, promote a culture of belonging and safety, have active family and community engagement, and use collaborative leadership and practices have positive academic and nonacademic outcomes, including improvements in student attendance, student behavior, academic achievement, school readiness, student mental and physical health, high school graduation rates, school climate, and reducing racial and economic achievement gaps;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community schools have the potential to close economic achievement gaps, as indicated in a 2024 report;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a 2023 study found that mental health care provided through community schools addresses disparities in school-provided service and improved academic performance and student conduct, including reducing the number of school suspensions and disciplinary referrals;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a 2022 report found that community schools and the community as a whole produce a positive impact on student attendance, on-time grade progression, and credit accumulation for high school students;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community schools have a positive impact on meeting the basic needs of students, including nutritional services and access to comprehensive health services, as indicated in a 2024 report;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community schools provide a strong social return on investment, with 1 study reporting a social return of $10 to $15 for every dollar invested over a 3-year period;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community school coordinators are essential to building successful community schools and creating, strengthening, and maintaining partnerships between community schools and their communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community school coordinators facilitate and provide leadership for the collaborative process and development of a system of supports and opportunities for children, families, and others within the community that allows all students to learn and the community to thrive;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community school coordinators, through their role, deliver a strong monetary return on investment for community schools and their communities, with 1 study reporting a return of $7.11 for every dollar invested in the salary of a community school coordinator; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Community School Coordinators Appreciation Week, celebrated from September 14 through September 20, 2025, recognizes, raises awareness of, and celebrates the thousands of community school coordinators across the country and the critical role of community school coordinators in the success of students: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idfe6780fe38c244008d59a6c4745d1bb4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates the week of September 14 through September 20, 2025, as <quote>Community School Coordinators Appreciation Week</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id368aa74e935e45c39d5e026183dd019a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>gives thanks to community school coordinators for the work they do to serve students, families, and communities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida3f6eba91ccd430f8a8d98691f5d5e41"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages students, parents, school administrators, and public officials to participate in events that celebrate Community School Coordinators Appreciation Week.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

