<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KAT25327-PLK-WX-R3L"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1306 IS: To require the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service to reissue a final rule removing the gray wolf from the list of endangered and threatened wildlife under the Endangered Species Act of 1973.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1306</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250404">April 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service to reissue a final rule removing the gray wolf from the list of endangered and threatened wildlife under the Endangered Species Act of 1973.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HE53AE4BF9B3942A8A698C5C3F216C8FC"><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Reissuance of rule removing the gray wolf from the list of endangered and threatened wildlife</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC622CD977BD24AB98ACA47C672DE855C"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service shall reissue the final rule entitled <quote>Endangered and Threatened Wildlife and Plants; Removing the Gray Wolf (Canis lupus) From the List of Endangered and Threatened Wildlife</quote> (85 Fed. Reg. 69778 (November 3, 2020)).</text></subsection><subsection id="idA6E0CA0FAE5246B389E2BF588BA4C32F" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No judicial review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reissuance of the final rule described in subsection (a) shall not be subject to judicial review.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

