<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7429AE6FD527455D9D8D60EEFDF9D503" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 710 IH: Expressing support for the designation of “Community School Coordinators Appreciation Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 710</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250915">September 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of <quote>Community School Coordinators Appreciation Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas community schools marshal, align, and unite the assets, resources, and capacity of schools and communities for the success of students, families, and communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community schools are an effective, evidence-based strategy for school improvement included under section 4625 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7275">20 U.S.C. 7275</external-xref>), as added by section 4601 of the Every Student Succeeds Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/95">Public Law 114–95</external-xref>; 129 Stat. 2029);</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community schools that provide integrated student support, including well-designed and expanded learning opportunities informed by rigorous community-connected classroom instruction, and practice collaborative leadership promote a culture of belonging, safety, and active family and community engagement, leading to positive academic and nonacademic outcomes, including improvements in student attendance, behavior, academic achievement, school readiness, mental and physical health, high school graduation rates, school climate, and reduced racial and economic achievement gaps;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community schools have the potential to close economic achievement gaps, as indicated in a 2024 report;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a 2023 study found that mental health care provided through community schools addresses disparities through school-provided service and shows improved academic performance and student conduct, including reducing the number of school suspensions and disciplinary referrals;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a 2022 report found that community schools, and the community as a whole, produce a positive impact on student attendance, on-time grade progression, and credit accumulation for high school students;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community schools have a positive impact on meeting students’ basic needs, including nutritional services and access to comprehensive health services, as indicated in a 2024 report;</text></whereas><whereas> <text>Whereas community schools provide a strong social return on investment, with one study citing a social return of between $10 to $15 for every dollar invested over a 3-year period;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community school coordinators are essential to building successful community schools and creating, strengthening, and maintaining partnerships between community schools and their communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community school coordinators facilitate and provide leadership for the collaborative process and development of a system that supports opportunities for children, families, and others within a school’s community that allow all students to learn and the community to thrive;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community school coordinators, through their role, deliver a strong monetary return on investment for community schools and their communities, with 1 study citing a return of $7.11 for every dollar invested in the salary of a community school coordinator; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Community School Coordinators Appreciation Week, celebrated from September 14 through September 20, 2025, recognizes, raises awareness of, and celebrates the thousands of community school coordinators across the country, and the critical role of community school coordinators in the success of students: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H624BD0C746AC4F47A8761193FA608981"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HC5205A6688E646C59CDAAB1184290C91"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H1436AC03ECEA4B06A209121D2CD6C1CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the designation of <quote>Community School Coordinators Appreciation Week</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5AF6280311349FE980E12976E6F17C5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>thanks community school coordinators for the work they do to serve students, families, and communities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0ACDF17D33A94C6BB3BFDAE7DFAC745C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages students, parents, school administrators, and public officials to participate in events that celebrate Community School Coordinators Appreciation Week.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

