<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H972CB6089E594F59B95E7C94412E69C6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3372 IH: Law Enforcement Scenario-Based Training for Safety and De-Escalation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3372</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250513">May 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To develop a scenario-based training curriculum for law enforcement personnel, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB2DC31F4604B4A3AB6F3DD7895C29025" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H1D4FD0FA66904A39A2ACB7399E9DFDAF"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Law Enforcement Scenario-Based Training for Safety and De-Escalation Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE84BEDE395314730A44F4F54B7A05B1B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Law enforcement scenario-based training curriculum</header> <subsection id="H93A5F7921E09429B9C08D9137F5079FF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services, shall develop a scenario-based training curriculum for use in accordance with the grant program under section 3.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H55E22457E4364C7280929E56F398DC4C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Curriculum</header><text>In developing the curriculum under subsection (a), the Attorney General shall—</text> <paragraph id="H0E5405EE6EE5408CB83BA507364535DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop a scenario-based training curriculum that addresses—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6B9137356A73473085D28A0B8912B4E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improving community-police relations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H749B994383864FADB94C0F6AD1DAA8CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>officer safety;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC4269AE68AAE44F09C328DC67E4AE119"><enum>(C)</enum><text>officer resilience;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H982E367D67E0400D947060036A2CE4A9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>situational awareness;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC4B2E2F7D815488BA61CB283DC109D86"><enum>(E)</enum><text>physical and emotional responses to stress;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H096261F53A1D49D081DF0B5C03321C3F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>critical decision making and problem solving;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD0562BAC3BB646A081C096CF7618F89C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>de-escalation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6ECB7582CCA64984A773EA2647F363FF"><enum>(H)</enum><text>use of force and deadly force; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB23AF5363E97468890DA43E581C7BDE8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>crisis intervention;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7EEE88AB8F22493581D4A13EC4F2D2E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consult with relevant professional law enforcement associations, community-based organizations, and defense and national security agencies in the development and dissemination of the curriculum;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5F564A61902946728B16EEEF580D9E65"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide expertise and technical assistance to entities seeking to implement the curriculum;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF074791A1454A1BB096E69E81010B57"><enum>(4)</enum><text>evaluate best practices of scenario-based training methods and curriculum content to maintain state-of-the-art expertise in scenario-based learning methodology; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9D44EF6E80ED4C18AD7B04A06A199706"><enum>(5)</enum><text>develop a certification process for entities that have successfully implemented the curriculum.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HD62E939FB4194CFB85DFD3F16D90424C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Law enforcement scenario-based training grant program</header> <subsection id="HB6A6BB1993954704A34B10C035915A41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services, shall be authorized to make grants to States, units of local government, Indian Tribal governments, other public and private entities, and multi-jurisdictional or regional consortia to provide law enforcement personnel with access to a scenario-based training curriculum that is substantially similar to the curriculum developed under section 2.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0A0C54FB52034943AF509995A6C27379"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An applicant seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Attorney General an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7E348BA60E6E417A99237EEA0A293572"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph id="HCBB8776026D84F3B8EEFFC1CC5593432"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grantee reports</header><text>On the date that is 1 year after receiving a grant under this section, each grant recipient shall submit to the Attorney General a report on—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2EB3A861DA7C4663A1C3970ED7D123AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any benefits of, and barriers to, delivering the curriculum to law enforcement personnel; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H171313AAF8594A1EA558A97F29E7F008"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations for improving the access of law enforcement personnel to scenario-based training.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8692CE8820144927B87EC7389F3E000A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Office of Community Oriented Policing Services reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after initially awarding grants under this section, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services, shall submit to Congress a report on—</text> <subparagraph id="HE61CE2D1F66947FDA2E279D61F4A7A4B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of entities that received grants under this section;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE55DC2C4656F4CB998031D972766C76F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the cumulative number and proportion of law enforcement personnel in each State that received training under the scenario-based training curriculum described in section 2, or a curriculum that is substantially similar to that curriculum;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5D9CF4937DDB43A291DE90709D8A8DDC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any benefits of, and barriers to, delivering such curriculum to law enforcement personnel;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H042D5EA6A1C649EFAC9BDC44ABBAE26A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommendations for improving the curriculum developed under section 2; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H013E988A0FD44BA6B4C06CA03E7F8F34"><enum>(E)</enum><text>recommendations for improving the grant program under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD04C5C60D6294C408F55C72CC6D8605E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act. The Attorney General shall carry out this Act using unobligated amounts that are otherwise made available to the Department of Justice.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H3359870046F548B588FC9C890F796D60"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H489FC77CB5D34E9192EDACAE79B1C5EB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community-based organizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community-based organization</term> means a grassroots organization that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H8331A7CD3FDD4601A382385E29758045"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">works in communities to improve police accountability and transparency; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HEE88A8DC183549189A4387BB99E6F65D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has a national presence and membership.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC35EB00768B49148AF55822A55C483A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Professional law enforcement association</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>professional law enforcement association</term> means a law enforcement membership association that works for the needs of Federal, State, local, or Indian Tribal law enforcement groups and with the civilian community on matters of common interest.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8EACE6A3E2924ACBB4A3DABD9F9DA5C3" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Scenario-based training</header><text>The term <term>scenario-based training</term> means the use of live-action simulations and role playing to place law enforcement personnel in an interactive learning environment to replicate real-life scenarios or teach particular skills or techniques.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA10C825822AC488CA18944DAA36C055A" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and any possession of the United States.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

