<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD7E81D5DD8EB438FA3CDC7F6148E4437" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1468 IH: Protect America’s Innovation and Economic Security from CCP Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1468</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250221">February 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000403">Mr. Kennedy of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the CCP Initiative program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0DC6FCB813FB4F9798346C8D0132FB1B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H47D2992EECCE4747AAE0AF2CFABD17B3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect America’s Innovation and Economic Security from CCP Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCB43E3438E6942EAB6659CEC0EBEC562"><enum>2.</enum><header>CCP Initiative</header> <subsection id="HCBC17517D9354E75BB9A6C66F2888BC3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the National Security Division of the Department of Justice the CCP Initiative to—</text>
<paragraph id="H2FF73C166A64435F885BB10BCE9C02D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>counter nation-state threats to the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H728B4F67CABD453883CA021D49879EE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>curb spying by the Chinese Communist Party on United States intellectual property and academic institutions in the United States;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE0D83B1E6223407B8C2D261AA498A89C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop an enforcement strategy concerning nontraditional collectors, including researchers in labs, universities, and the defense industrial base, that are being used to transfer technology contrary to United States interests;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0746E1A6CD304702B8BF8A8398DF1220"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implement the Foreign Investment Risk Review Modernization Act of 2018 (title XVII of division A of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/232">Public Law 115–232</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 2173)) for the Department of Justice, including by working with the Department of the Treasury to develop regulations under that Act;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0D1EB0F421D4400B912772D79F7EEB90"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identify cases under the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/213">Public Law 95–213</external-xref>; 91 Stat. 1494) involving Chinese companies that compete with United States businesses; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC93749907FC64FC486B12B3406B113D0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>prioritize—</text>
<subparagraph id="H53AD1EF189A64C12B885E79A59BB8449"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifying and prosecuting those engaged in trade secret theft, hacking, and economic espionage; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB1AE1474C2464165B1DD83AB14FD8014"><enum>(B)</enum><text>protecting the critical infrastructure in the United States against external threats through foreign direct investment and supply chain compromises; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H44574845D3674DE3B75F82D70F444B7D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying Chinese Communist Party theft of intellectual property from small businesses; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H007BEA4D49AC42F58A1B43DD57A55CB9"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">investigate investments made by Chinese companies included on the Entity List maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce or the People’s Republic of China Military Companies list maintained by the Department of Defense, and report to the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of Defense on any findings of such investigations, including findings related to subsidiaries or other entities controlled by such companies, whether or not such subsidiaries or other entities are registered in or operate in the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HEA2DEBA1B3664251A26029AAB402027B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In executing the CCP Initiative’s objectives as set forth in subsection (a), the Attorney General, acting through the Assistant Attorney General for National Security, shall consult with relevant components of the Department of Justice as necessary, and coordinate activities with the Federal Bureau of Investigation and any other Federal agency as necessary.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE2448A809171469D828A43497987568D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the CCP Initiative—</text>
<paragraph id="H2197A31268154496A8486B99101EB4EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Initiative shall be separate from and not under the authority or discretion of any other Department of Justice initiative dedicated to countering nation-state threats; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H322F717440E2406D842E1AE6F2EB3811"><enum>(2)</enum><text>all resources used for the CCP Initiative shall solely be set aside for the CCP Initiative and shall not be combined to support any other Department of Justice program, including other programs and initiatives dedicated to countering nation-state threats.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H110703211D0D4C1095D68A58AFF4F114"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall submit annually a written report to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, and the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, on the progress and challenges of the CCP Initiative over the preceding year, including—</text> <paragraph id="HA8FEB9A5B805463AADBBF83BC3B0A103"><enum>(1)</enum><text>its progress in accomplishing the objectives set forth in subsection (a);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0148FE5C6EF74ABCBBC3D951A048C404"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount and sufficiency of resources provided to, and expended by, the CCP Initiative;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCECDD66E0193477D9E4CEEB178B294CE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the level and effectiveness of coordination with the Federal Bureau of Investigation and other Federal agencies;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H543182BA009940DC9AC0DB237263E71D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the status of efforts by and the financial intelligence capabilities of the Chinese Communist Party to engage in trade secret theft, hacking, and economic espionage; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF4D434115754A6D9BAB384BBC8FFE90"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the use of unmanned aircraft and associated elements (including communication links and the components that control the unmanned aircraft required for the operator to operate safely and efficiently in the national airspace system) by the CCP; </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3D2EC24C6CDF4C7D9945FFEAA3EDD180"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the impact of the CCP Initiative on those efforts of the Chinese Communist Party;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5C82422F8F1C4BD48AB67FCEF1230430"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the level and effectiveness of coordination and information sharing between Government agencies and private companies about economic espionage threats; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9B70E4CA8806436D90AD8A57CF373D17"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the economic loss to the United States as a result of hacking and trade secret theft by the Chinese Communist Party. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF72C8F6082FF4B6DB7E5C442EDEA85EE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This Act shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act and cease to be in effect on the date that is 6 years after that date.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H1AAE31BF2A5441CE966B7A0A475F8584"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>If any provision of this Act, or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, and the application of the provisions of such to any person or circumstance, shall not be affected thereby.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

