<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3AF4F98C457D46AFA13FED82E4743D30" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 797 IH: Ultrasounds Save Lives Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 797</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250128">January 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001235">Mr. Moore of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris of Maryland</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure that women seeking an abortion are notified, before giving informed consent to receive an abortion, of the medical risks associated with the abortion procedure and the major developmental characteristics of the unborn child.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5CFB53833A4141428E18A7397CB6FE94" style="OLC"><section id="HCA5CB3D5BE274AA8B608E4144DC12ED4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ultrasounds Save Lives Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H16E1C8015E584C9BBC75F099B0B061D3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirement of informed consent</header><subsection id="HEA07AE2333484D26AFE9BDD853015769"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="HFDE3CC2AFF17466EA7F67A362C510357"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement of compliance by providers</header><text>Any abortion provider, acting in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce, who knowingly performs, or attempts to perform, any abortion shall comply with the requirements of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86B77B5D31B74B46B7F15CCA7734D855"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review of medical risks and unborn health status</header><text>Except in the case of a medical emergency, an abortion provider who intends to perform, or attempt to perform, an abortion may not perform any part of the abortion procedure without first—</text><subparagraph id="H25DD8E6564F042A6A3E271EF7C69DC13"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">performing an ultrasound on the woman seeking the abortion, using whichever method the physician and patient agree is best under the circumstance, and sharing the results of such ultrasound with the woman; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0357E8C793BA48B79C385A3D2AFFC3ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>obtaining a signed Informed Consent Authorization form in accordance with this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H390AC87DF9CA4590847AD29F401EB11C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Informed consent authorization form</header><subparagraph id="HF340559B0CBA4766A57CAE0DE72A66A7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Informed Consent Authorization form required under this subsection shall—</text><clause id="HABC29C9A4E644493B8DCC7E371C8CA17"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be presented in person by the abortion provider 24 hours prior to performing, or attempting to perform, the abortion to the woman seeking the abortion; and </text></clause><clause id="H1CA2C5A1BAA746E6B93B7F405A26505B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consist of—</text><subclause id="HE22A112C9E4348B2A42E510D27D8D278"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a statement by the abortion provider indicating—</text><item id="H078524FF87764B109654A9D6524F3603"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the probable gestational age, in completed days, of the child;</text></item><item id="H9CA49F5D0AD44673800D72D76197CF5F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all medical risks associated with abortion-inducing drugs or the specific abortion procedure; and</text></item><item id="HB3A10DE322354E3FAAB70FE16C5F7321"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the major developmental characteristics of unborn children at such gestational age, including the presence of a heartbeat, the ability to react to painful stimuli, and the development of organs, appendages, and facial features;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H3C0074BCE7DA438CA125F15442A2032F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a statement by the abortion provider that an ultrasound has been performed, and the results of such ultrasound have been shared, as required by paragraph (2)(A);</text></subclause><subclause id="HB885220C958D44ABA5EEB64BB08B26D6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a statement that the requirements of this subsection are binding upon the abortion provider and all other medical personnel, that such abortion providers and medical personnel are subject to criminal and civil penalties for violations of these requirements, and that a woman on whom an abortion has been performed may take civil action if these requirements are not followed; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H4808D30815B7438E9E7732C533228752"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>an affirmation that each individual signing the Informed Consent Authorization form has filled out the form to the best of his or her knowledge and understands the information contained in the form.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93DA897397B94C51B2304085ACDB70B9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Signatories required</header><text>The Informed Consent Authorization form required under this subsection shall be signed in person by the woman seeking the abortion, the abortion provider performing or attempting to perform the abortion, and a witness.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E85BAE1CE954D9ABABC9FD4D92E7BA8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Retention of consent form</header><text>The abortion provider performing or attempting to perform an abortion shall retain the signed Informed Consent Authorization form required under this subsection in the patient's medical file.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA65F1931BDB4178A582108D342C919E"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Requirement for data retention</header><text>Paragraph (j)(2) of section 164.530 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations, shall apply to the Informed Consent Authorization form required to be placed in a patient's medical file pursuant to subparagraph (C) in the same manner and to the same extent as such paragraph applies to documentation required by paragraph (j)(1) of such section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6716BC8CD8ED442D98C4109271AEBC96"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The requirements of this subsection shall not apply if, in reasonable medical judgment, compliance with paragraph (2) would pose a greater risk of—</text><subparagraph id="H23F149F60F55465EB17FAF0FBCFA6482"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the death of the pregnant woman; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2222BBE1A9874055915FD0415AE2C059"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the substantial and irreversible physical impairment of a major bodily function, not including psychological or emotional conditions, of the pregnant woman.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE1B78BB239C44303936E2335EC03B3F7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalty for failure To comply</header><paragraph id="HDCEEB4B2A7BA4B50A30E0A786F9C83C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><subparagraph id="H851B2D3A59644F3C91C08C3D47F52C2D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Enforcement by Attorney General</header><text>The Attorney General shall commence a civil action in an appropriate district court of the United States under this subsection against any abortion provider who knowingly commits a violation of subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE22BC900C624882AFCF8F04DBC9BF18"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>In a civil action under subparagraph (A), the court may, to vindicate the public interest, assess a civil penalty against the abortion provider in an amount—</text><clause id="HDB93A05BBC794C939D89C84015F87EF0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not less than $100,000 and not more than $150,000, for each such violation that is adjudicated in the first proceeding against such abortion provider under this subsection; or</text></clause><clause id="HB462B359FB994F82B25306CCA1ADFCAE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not less than $150,001 and not more than $250,000, for each such violation that is adjudicated in a subsequent proceeding against such abortion provider under this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8ED08D52C2349F0B389397E53A094F8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>Upon the assessment of a civil penalty under subparagraph (B), the Attorney General shall notify the appropriate State medical licensing authority.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H076E26A3F03D410C98F80B454B339057"><enum>(D)</enum><header>No penalties for pregnant women</header><text>A pregnant woman shall not be subject to any penalty under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9863D4B7D2E43DDB31534AEA2946FF9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><subparagraph id="HED5E92FFAABC48649E96EE232CC7DBAC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A woman or a parent of a minor upon whom an abortion has been performed in violation of subsection (a) may commence a civil action against the abortion provider for appropriate relief. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AA4155F0D874E57978550EC353843CD" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appropriate relief</header><clause id="H9656300961854F92B06325C3E06A96A2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), appropriate relief in a civil action under this paragraph includes—</text><subclause id="H326179BCD8DF409DB8811DB79395B29E" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>objectively verifiable money damages for all injuries, psychological and physical, occasioned by the violation;</text></subclause><subclause id="H490FE36D9FF348D38040F75B0C1CAE96" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>statutory damages equal to 3 times the cost of the abortion; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HAF15497F2D4B4C1792184BD2FEC9A2C8" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>punitive damages.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HEE4BE9804BA04F369CFD5753A42A053A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No damages may be awarded to a plaintiff in a civil action under this paragraph if the pregnancy in relation to which an abortion was performed in violation of subsection (a) resulted from the plaintiff’s criminal conduct.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F9988953EBD4A538344509874E1B8F4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Attorney’s fees for plaintiff</header><text>The court shall award a reasonable attorney’s fee as part of the costs to a prevailing plaintiff in a civil action under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1447F2559224D249FAF376CB29F2344"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Attorney’s fees for defendant</header><text>If a defendant in a civil action under this paragraph prevails and the court finds that the plaintiff’s suit was frivolous, the court shall award a reasonable attorney’s fee in favor of the defendant against the plaintiff.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2972F54681EB43C8896A152A2A838CD2"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Awards against woman</header><text>In any civil action under this paragraph, no damages or other monetary relief, and no attorney’s fees except as provided under subparagraph (D), may be assessed against the woman upon whom the abortion was performed or attempted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H23C4EF4745AF4FE490041B2023B1658D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Preemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to preempt any provision of State law to the extent that such State law establishes, implements, or continues in effect disclosure requirements regarding abortion or penalties for failure to comply with such requirements that are more extensive than those provided under this section. </text></subsection><subsection id="HEDF2B7A3F87148039D28E4853F09C769"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit an abortion provider from presenting the information required under subsection (a) to a pregnant woman at the same time as acquiring informed consent for an abortion from such woman in accordance with State law, provided that the presentation of such information occurs at least 24 hours before the abortion. </text></subsection><subsection id="H6861ED36B52648A1B40F20BC4A94D820"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HACB20530A7594FF783F2CE2872E75BA8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Abortion</header><text>The term <term>abortion</term> means the use or prescription of any instrument, medicine, drug, or any other substance or device—</text><subparagraph id="HDD61EFBD97E943BB8EEE3402BD0FBF72"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to intentionally kill the unborn child of a woman known to be pregnant; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H611245B9472F4B0D84E2BB4A80B97449"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to intentionally terminate the pregnancy of a woman known to be pregnant, with an intention other than—</text><clause id="H93DBE4BA125A4F34A6AF04108F5B66C7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>after viability to produce a live birth and preserve the life and health of the child born alive; or</text></clause><clause id="HF45BAD8B74AB4337922B37C4D8927489"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to remove a dead unborn child.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DE4677F5B554A018CE881EC310F072F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Abortion provider</header><text>The term <term>abortion provider</term> means a person—</text><subparagraph id="H36C4253280234C3EBA765374B9F149A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>licensed to practice medicine and surgery or osteopathic medicine and surgery; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B3EAC915FC245EF8D8CA82CAE88C36F" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>otherwise legally authorized to perform an abortion. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB35134D547F04E49B319467209B9F16B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Attempt</header><text>The term <term>attempt</term>, with respect to an abortion, means conduct that, under the circumstances as the actor believes them to be, constitutes a substantial step in a course of conduct planned to culminate in performing an abortion.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EAFC6C5179443728042B0C36B886E09"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Minor</header><text>The term <term>minor</term> means an individual who has not attained the age of 18 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF2AA8C2635745F69C935878F9210CDC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Perform</header><text>The term <term>perform</term>, with respect to an abortion, includes inducing an abortion through a medical or chemical intervention including writing a prescription for a drug or device intended to result in an abortion.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0711C42B0D5240098D5F6238E0558C7B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reasonable medical judgment</header><text>The term <term>reasonable medical judgment</term> means a medical judgment that would be made by a reasonably prudent abortion provider, knowledgeable about the case and the treatment possibilities with respect to the medical conditions involved.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9AA0DB097EC4CEE815B88623FFE52C5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Unborn child</header><text>The term <term>unborn child</term> means an individual organism of the species homo sapiens, beginning at fertilization, until the point of being born alive as defined in section 8(b) of title 1, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADD7B69A360843D483C8E61FAB7126BF"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Woman</header><text>The term <term>woman</term> means a female human being whether or not she has reached the age of majority.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

