<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H85BDCCB22DF14CB1A79FBFD0C457E8B3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 505 IH: To impose additional duties on imports of goods into the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 505</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250116">January 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000592">Mr. Golden of Maine</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose additional duties on imports of goods into the United States.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H355C11097A144A7B8CFC3E872B3B9FC8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H15414D3E6E134E01A903A0D6CFE5608C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Imposition of additional duties on imports of goods into the United States</header>
<subsection id="HF4C85B9820DC478597C762BBD74FA627"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall—</text> <paragraph id="H576B6842E5644474936E1283C8235B14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>impose a duty on imports of any good into the United States in an amount equal to 10 percent ad valorem of the good for each calendar year beginning on or after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0C18B7AC0DD747F095103D73ECC58774"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each calendar year beginning after the calendar year referred to in paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H7F76D8D6D16C417486ADFE30EFE00DA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the United States has a deficit in the trade of goods and services generally for the immediately preceding calendar year, increase the duty imposed under paragraph (1) on such good by an additional amount equal to 5 percent ad valorem of the good; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6159B57D0B1F465F834719085D81C596"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the United States has a balance or surplus in the trade of goods and services generally for the immediately preceding calendar year, decrease the duty imposed under paragraph (1) on such good by an amount equal to 5 percent ad valorem of the good for each calendar year beginning after the calendar year referred to in paragraph (1), except that the duty imposed under paragraph (1) on such good shall not be reduced below $0.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7B11E3DECFCA4270B14D45C051194EA1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties To be considered additional duties</header><text>The duty required by subsection (a) with respect to a good is in addition to any other duty imposed by law with respect to the good. </text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

