<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA25410-2SC-LH-RY4"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>118 SRES 250 ATS: Recognizing National Foster Care Month as an opportunity to raise awareness about the challenges of children in the foster care system, and encouraging Congress to implement policies to improve the lives of children in the foster care system.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 250</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250522">May 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S438">Mr. Husted</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing National Foster Care Month as an opportunity to raise awareness about the challenges of children in the foster care system, and encouraging Congress to implement policies to improve the lives of children in the foster care system.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas National Foster Care Month was established more than 30 years ago—</text><paragraph id="idae4cfb23c9a74b25adf1dd4e7f8bfd8b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to bring foster care issues to the forefront;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida3713e0f4ae4488ba3ea71263d5357cc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to highlight the importance of permanency for every child; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0493d98a1f074433b53a1fe49aed4a95"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to recognize the essential role that foster parents, social workers, and advocates have in the lives of children in foster care throughout the United States;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas all children deserve a safe, loving, and permanent home;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the primary goal of the foster care system is to ensure the safety and well-being of children while working to provide a safe, loving, and permanent home for each child;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there are approximately 368,530 children living in foster care in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there were approximately 186,602 youths that entered the foster care system in 2022 in the United States, while more than 108,877 youths were awaiting adoption at the end of 2022;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas approximately 61,585 children entered foster care in 2022 due to parental drug abuse;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas children of color are more likely to stay in the foster care system for longer periods of time and are less likely to be reunited with their biological families;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas foster parents are the front-line caregivers for children who cannot safely remain with their biological parents, and foster parents provide physical care, emotional support, and education advocacy, and are the largest single source of families providing permanent homes for children leaving foster care to adoption;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas children in foster care who are placed with relatives, compared to children placed with non-relatives—</text><paragraph id="id430e066f23994541a7f728f7817703a3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>have more stability, including fewer changes in placements;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id77f5983ddf224d86ba608535ba338071"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have more positive perceptions of their placements;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6eba86f588ac4dc09464c7fe3f01fc47"><enum>(3)</enum><text>are more likely to be placed with their siblings; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d3bcaa278a84f69814284a263f90b5d"><enum>(4)</enum><text>demonstrate fewer behavioral problems;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas some relative caregivers receive less financial assistance and support services than do foster caregivers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas an increased emphasis on prevention and reunification services is necessary to reduce the number of children that enter or re-enter the foster care system;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas approximately 18,538 youths aged out of foster care in 2022 without a legal permanent connection to an adult or family;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas youth who age out of foster care lack the security or support of a biological or adoptive family and frequently struggle to secure affordable housing, obtain health insurance, pursue higher education, and acquire adequate employment;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas foster care is intended to be a temporary placement, but children remain in the foster care system for an average of 22.6 months;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas approximately one-third of children in foster care experience more than 2 placements while in care, which often leads to disruption of routines and the need to change schools and move away from siblings, extended families, and familiar surroundings;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas youth in foster care are much more likely to face educational instability, with a study showing that 75 percent of foster youth experienced an unscheduled school change during a school year, compared to less than 40 percent of youth not in foster care;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas children entering foster care often confront the widespread misperception that children in foster care are disruptive, unruly, and dangerous, even though placement in foster care is based on the actions of a parent or guardian, not the child;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 30 percent of children in foster care are taking not less than 1 anti-psychotic medication, and 34 percent of those children are not receiving adequate treatment planning or medication monitoring;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, due to heavy caseloads and limited resources, the average annual turnover rate is between 20 percent and 40 percent for child welfare workers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas States, localities, and communities should be encouraged to invest resources in preventative and reunification services and post-permanency programs to ensure that more children and older youth in foster care are provided with safe, loving, and permanent placements;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2018, Congress passed the Family First Prevention Services Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/123">Public Law 115–123</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 232), which provided new investments in prevention and family reunification services to help more families stay together and ensure more children are in safe, loving, and permanent homes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Federal legislation during the past 4 decades, including the Adoption Assistance and Child Welfare Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/272">Public Law 96–272</external-xref>; 94 Stat. 500), the Adoption and Safe Families Act of 1997 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/89">Public Law 105–89</external-xref>; 111 Stat. 2115), the Fostering Connections to Success and Increasing Adoptions Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/351">Public Law 110–351</external-xref>; 122 Stat. 3949), the Child and Family Services Improvement and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/34">Public Law 112–34</external-xref>; 125 Stat. 369), the Preventing Sex Trafficking and Strengthening Families Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/183">Public Law 113–183</external-xref>; 128 Stat. 1919), and the Supporting America's Children and Families Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/258">Public Law 118–258</external-xref>; 138 Stat. 2947) provided new investments and services to improve the outcomes of children in the foster care system;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas May 2025 is an appropriate month to designate as <quote>National Foster Care Month</quote> to provide an opportunity to acknowledge the child welfare workforce, foster parents, the advocacy community, and mentors for their dedication, accomplishments, and the positive impact they have on the lives of children; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas much remains to be done to ensure that all children have a safe, loving, nurturing, and permanent family, regardless of age or special needs: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id7fc5b15e911140a6a1bf70414d6a3a26"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of May 2025 as <quote>National Foster Care Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb8f3828f9dc8498cbfd37de77d5f710f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes National Foster Care Month as an opportunity to raise awareness about the challenges that children face in the foster care system;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide9aa6713595e41c28e33237b59de9c6e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages Congress to implement policies to improve the lives of children in the foster care system;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb008d35c2c2548b0896ed4f46e511c59"><enum>(4)</enum><text>acknowledges the unique needs of children in the foster care system;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id603885fb58314eaeb4599945f9ac794d"><enum>(5)</enum><text>recognizes foster youth throughout the United States for their ongoing tenacity, courage, and resilience while facing life challenges;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7a1ebcf8221c4d098a60d4b11821a081"><enum>(6)</enum><text>acknowledges the exceptional alumni of the foster care system who serve as advocates and role models for youth who remain in care;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideaf2a69b841148a984c8ae7cc5b80c4f"><enum>(7)</enum><text>honors the commitment and dedication of the individuals who work tirelessly to provide assistance and services to children in the foster care system;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id219912d5b34e4e6d9e02ff609df932ef"><enum>(8)</enum><text>supports the designation of May 31, 2025, as <quote>National Foster Parent Appreciation Day</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id81abaa830c8f472c9c15894000eaf71f"><enum>(9)</enum><text>recognizes National Foster Parent Appreciation Day as an opportunity to recognize the efforts of foster parents to provide safe and loving care for children in need and to raise awareness about the increasing need for foster parents to serve in their communities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6cb8c03249ab48bca70647b6bce81257"><enum>(10)</enum><text>reaffirms the need to continue working to improve the outcomes of all children in the foster care system through initiatives designed to—</text><subparagraph id="iddb63dda390b94e459847bd018c8e85ad"><enum>(A)</enum><text>support vulnerable families;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide5d90c77a9be4da882ce93105b51c965"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prevent families from entering the foster care system and reunite families in cases where reunification is in the best interest of the child;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb85ef505486e44ccbb6e49017ec6b0b7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promote adoption in cases where reunification is not in the best interests of the child;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3d92d80ed8654f7eb0f9989e60646613"><enum>(D)</enum><text>adequately serve those children brought into the foster care system; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0208aa2be512409798d5cc3ce0b50cf8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>facilitate the successful transition into adulthood for youth that <quote>age out</quote> of the foster care system. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

