<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF12145FF6B2740D79F66A4C19BDC8DC6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2624 IH: Halt Unchecked Member Benefits with Lobbying Elimination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2624</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250403">April 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HSO00">Ethics</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit former Members and elected officers of Congress from lobbying Congress at any time after leaving office, to prohibit the use of funds for official travel expenses of Members of Congress and legislative branch employees for airline accommodations other than coach class, to eliminate automatic pay adjustments for Members of Congress, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7C92670D2F2D493CB1DAD23813065C89" style="OLC"><section id="H5DFA919130544EDEBDB112DCA354DF5E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Halt Unchecked Member Benefits with Lobbying Elimination Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HUMBLE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5EC4F64DC7484526B6B256CB5324360F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibiting former Members and officers of Congress from lobbying Congress</header><subsection id="HA8A9BA83C718439D9230E1D8C134ED2B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 207(e)(1) of title 18, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H1D9AC29B17554412860404AC84B084C1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H8F2D98D8D4FD445193D289F9C0D37A70"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Members and elected officers of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who is a Senator, a Member of the House of Representatives, or an elected officer of the Senate or the House of Representatives and who, after that person leaves office, knowingly makes, with the intent to influence, any communication to or appearance before any Member, officer, or employee of either House of Congress or any employee of any other legislative office of the Congress, on behalf of any other person (except the United States) in connection with any matter on which such former Senator, Member, or elected official seeks action by a Member, officer, or employee of either House of Congress, in his or her official capacity, shall be punished as provided in section 216 of this title.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H6C2B27DFC2DE41AAA514DFC7CBDDBACC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 207(e)(2) of such title is amended—</text><paragraph id="H91B634A09B854650961BB133A79D5DCF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="USC">Officers and staff</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="USC">Staff</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC852360E114F44BE9ECA72D6C80E82CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>an elected officer of the Senate, or</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H583DFAAF511B4036A83B3B59B00D31E3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>leaves office or employment</quote> and inserting <quote>leaves employment</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB20FBF049B5C4EF6B7529D785746EAC7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by striking <quote>former elected officer or</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H29D2E4242CD4420988A19BDADED0929C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to an individual who leaves office on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H13F0A990A68A40F594F1DF3C2E030088"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibiting use of funds for official travel expenses of Members of Congress and legislative branch employees for airline accommodations other than coach class</header><subsection id="HACC8F97DDABD453480A3866A8CAB5007"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), no funds appropriated or otherwise made available for the official travel expenses of a Member of Congress or other officer or employee of any office in the legislative branch may be used for airline accommodations which are not coach-class accommodations.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE8E7BA8766FC4AF78407FB55006BA830"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Funds described in subsection (a) may be used for airline accommodations which are not coach-class accommodations for an individual described in subsection (a) if the use of the funds for such accommodations would be permitted under sections 301–10.121 through 301–10.125 of title 41 of the Code of Federal Regulations if the individual were an employee of an agency which is subject to chapter 301 of such title.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCF58A5A69D264F45B0C75C321EE35628"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of Construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to affect any officer or employee of an office of the legislative branch which, as of the date of the enactment of this Act, is subject to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/301">chapter 301</external-xref> of title 41 of the Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6A65CDBDB616464A924376196A1D8FCB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><paragraph id="HB518E24A608E4F8EB0D8A217A8835174"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Coach-class accommodations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>coach-class accommodations</term> means the basic class of accommodation by airlines that is normally the lowest fare offered regardless of airline terminology used, and (as referred to by airlines) may include tourist class or economy class, as well as single class when the airline offers only one class of accommodations to all travelers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC86CDD24E6364C65B1E61BBD51F8D32C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Member of Congress</header><text>In this Act, the term <term>Member of Congress</term> means a Senator or a Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A35523B864E4AECA62EE820BDCBB661"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2026 and each succeeding fiscal year.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA784915FE0634CBB80DF275212F51649"><enum>4.</enum><header>Benefits and services provided to former Members of the House of Representatives</header><subsection id="H93F4A6EBE53C42179BCF7B59E1625B3C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Benefits and services described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The House of Representatives may not make any of the following benefits and services available to an individual who becomes a former Member of the House (except to the extent such benefits and services are made available to members of the public):</text><paragraph id="HAB3D60B575264728A64C0ED5050F51E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Access to the Hall of the House.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02CA301F9A7D4D1DBE7F7695DFD98B59"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Access to athletic facilities and other facilities available for the use of Members of the House.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB531F6AB324941A2965497D20FDD2CD4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Access to the Members’ Dining Room located in the House of Representatives wing of the United States Capitol.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2680A69BD4614F3D8BA6A86BE4E0A2F6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Access to parking spaces.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H488F0B22823E4B2596567280D17C93FC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Access to material from the House document room.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6741B58F24934CBDA3407D83223669C3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Use of the collections in the House Legislative Resource Center without borrowing privileges.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H90E32C6B0F1F419D9F43761DBA01FF6F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver authority</header><paragraph id="HC7007BB228554F60868DD7B7A3D16111"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority to waive elimination of benefit or service</header><text>The Speaker and the minority leader of the House of Representatives may jointly, on a case-by-case basis, grant a waiver of subsection (a) with respect to a former Member of the House and a benefit or service described in such subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC87618EF75FE4C4D8097A7E5891A12D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication in Congressional Record</header><text>If the Speaker and the minority leader jointly grant a waiver under paragraph (1) to make a benefit or service available to a former Member, the Speaker and minority leader shall, not later than 24 hours after the waiver is granted, cause to have published in the Congressional Record a statement identifying the former Member and the benefit or service involved.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1DCFC51832AA4E4981089A3EA3C0EEE8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prohibiting Members of House of Representatives from owning individual stocks</header><subsection id="HFE1DC71EA2E445638F45A51ACAE0AADB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rule XXIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives is amended—</text><paragraph id="HAC9F5AC457394399A67765116FAA750B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating clause 22 as clause 23; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE7AF1396B884C358971B848EA0C4FB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after clause 21 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7BD6044876B948D590B38D4D6A6AB8A0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><rules-clause id="H7512C15FBC744F628E18C35DF7931223"><enum>22.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner may not own the common stock of any individual corporation.</text></rules-clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H503095EFBFBE418E8F43996D96DFB286"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect immediately before noon on January 3, 2027.</text></subsection></section><section id="H9F1450070D4A4AAAABC43E28F227DFB1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Elimination of automatic pay adjustments for Members of Congress</header><subsection id="H1F28A721D8034C78A3842EB261E07716"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (2) of section 601(a) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501(2)</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></subsection><subsection id="H638A8900FB94414A834CBBA593434BBA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 601(a)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H7C11A84196C6409097F82EE9D829DD09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(a)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>(a)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E7FE49E26FB4D9B951822D130312B89"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) as paragraphs (1), (2), and (3), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6881557DD5CB4A13926E71B22C0C78CE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, as adjusted by paragraph (2) of this subsection</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF9638F49A6BC4453968CF226E6024A24"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to pay periods beginning after the first general election for Federal office occurring after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H73C4A969369247A2AE344ACDE4AF86B1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header>Prohibiting Members of the House of Representatives from serving on boards of for-profit entities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Rule XXIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives, as amended by section 5(a), is amended—</text><paragraph id="H57402B7D64F44317BFAF648E7D9B7150"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses 19 through 23 as clauses 20 through 24, respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA23217D01A9409D9D74C69B7D8E614C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after clause 18 the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H421E128C22D245DAB8B786BDC3A56C28" display-inline="no-display-inline"><rules-clause id="HBC4537FB55B04139A1766F9B00FFA889" indent="down1"><enum>19.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner may not serve on the board of directors of any for-profit entity.</text></rules-clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

