<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9BA0CB425DFD480F9A744F60A5D79273" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3256 IH: Lieutenant General Carey Runway Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3256</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250507">May 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To name the Runway 5L/23R at Marine Corps Air Station, Cherry Point, North Carolina, the <quote>Lieutenant General Carey Runway</quote>.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAB663A896A4D44A693B5F4F311CF532A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3239D076DC2D40228CE51EF4D24919F3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Lieutenant General Carey Runway Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7BC0906347864CF8A5020CDFEBA2C7CA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="HDDC3CF4DC91F4BB690501EEDCAC3A7C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Lieutenant General Richard E. Carey retired from the Marine Corps on March 1, 1983. The General was presented the Distinguished Service Medal for exceptionally meritorious service to the Government of the United States in a duty of great responsibility as Commanding General, Marine Corps Development and Education Command, Quantico, Virginia, from November 1980 through February 1983.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE35FC6496A914208A0758FCFBB924DCF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Born January 10, 1928, in Columbus, Ohio, General Carey enlisted in the V–5 program in 1945. With the discontinuance of the V–5 program, he was discharged and enlisted in the Marine Corps and advanced to the rank of Sergeant prior to his commissioning as a Second Lieutenant in 1948. As a rifle platoon commander, he participated in combat operations in Korea, including the Inchon Landing and Chosin Reservoir, where he earned the Silver Star Medal prior to his medical evacuation to the United States after being wounded in action. In 1951, he served for a year as a company commander at the Marine Corps Recruit Depot, Parris Island, South Carolina, and then reported to Pensacola, Florida, for flight training.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H11960270D3ED428AB7FC4946424BA39B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Since his designation as a Naval Aviator in 1953, General Carey held a variety of squadron pilot and staff assignments including separate tours as an intelligence, maintenance, and material and logistics officer in both attack and fighter squadrons. He also served as the Assistant G–4 (Logistics) for the 2d Marine Division and spent one tour as the Aviation Logistics Officer, Office of the Deputy Chief of Staff for Air, Headquarters Marine Corps.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H584EF6AFF61D488BB8C2DDD4990E2528"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Additionally, General Carey had a diversified operations and planning background through assignments in that area at the squadron, group, wing, and air station levels. As a Colonel, he also served as the Battle Staff Chief in the Office of the Commander-in-Chief, Pacific and later as the G–3 Officer, Fleet Marine Force, Pacific.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B823FFA5F2D41839016A3150A61AE2F">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>His aviation command experience began in 1958 with Headquarters and Maintenance Squadron 32 while a Major, stationed at MCAS, Beaufort, South Carolina. As a Lieutenant Colonel at Cherry Point in 1966, General Carey assumed command of then Marine Fighter Attack Squadron 513. Following his assignment to the Republic of Vietnam, the General commanded Marine Air Base Squadron 13 and later Marine Fighter Attack Squadron 115 during combat operations, while operating from Chu Lai Air Base. As a colonel in 1971, he commanded Marine Aircraft Group 24, with the 1st Marine Brigade in Hawaii.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F6CE7106120443CA9FD9D5A98DC88F1"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following his advancement to Brigadier General on July 1, 1974, General Carey became Assistant Wing Commander, 1st Marine Aircraft Wing, MCAS Iwakuni, Japan. In 1975, he concurrently commanded the 9th Marine Amphibious Brigade where he directed the Marine Corps participation in the evacuation of Saigon.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0DEB38B3B33149B4BACE165018FA372D"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon his return to the United States, General Carey served as the Assistant Deputy Chief of Staff for Aviation, Headquarters Marine Corps, where he was advanced to Major General on March 2, 1976, and served there until he was assigned duty as Commanding General of the 2d Marine Aircraft Wing at Cherry Point, North Carolina, in July 1976. In June 1978 he was assigned duty as Deputy Chief of Staff, Commander in Chief, Atlantic, Norfolk, Virginia. He was promoted to Lieutenant General on October 24, 1980, and assumed duty as CG, MCDEC, Quantico, Virginia. He served in this capacity until his retirement on March 1, 1983.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8FB732D9560A49009B9C4AD6472C2D0E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In addition to the Silver Star Medal, General Carey’s personal awards and decorations include—</text> <subparagraph id="HC36DEB1775A14BA7B445105796184AE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Legion of Merit with gold star in lieu of a second award;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H05F118212B574F628B21C472A753E94C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Distinguished Flying Cross;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD20389570A334D278F5CCFAF0BA52858"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Bronze Star Medal with Combat <quote>V</quote> and gold star in lieu of a second award;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF13E3E3A44D44F35B47D0D8AA657B8AB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Air Medal with Numeral 15;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H186741CAFF354F37B580412D0E1E8AB1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Joint Service Commendation Medal;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4E00603A8D724DA1B66B67CF19FE7254"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Purple Heart Medal;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H86CE638B5B2D492491A5374855CE1CED"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Presidential Unit Citation with two bronze stars;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H32CDB16DC03B4CAFA0C299132CB8D3BD"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Navy Unit Commendation Medal with one bronze star; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB19FFD80ACD0498481ED5E0248FD4318"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Meritorious Unit Commendation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB9EBCF754964457284399DD254AAC996"><enum>(9)</enum><text>General Carey is a graduate of the Naval War College and holds a Bachelor of Science degree in Business Administration from George Washington University.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H61AE77F3D5014D96A510593FD2085424"><enum>3.</enum><header>Name of Runway 5L/23R at Marine Corps Air Station, Cherry Point, North Carolina</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Runway 5L/23R at Marine Corps Air Station, Cherry Point, North Carolina, shall after the date of the enactment of this Act be known and designated as the <quote>Lieutenant General Carey Runway</quote>. Any reference to such runway in any law, regulation, map, document, record, or other paper of the United States shall be considered to be a reference to the Lieutenant General Carey Runway.</text> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

